NARRATOR: In the criminal
justice system,
sexually based offenses
are considered
especially heinous,
In New York City,
the dedicated detectives
who investigate
these vicious felonies
are members
of an elite squad known
as the Special Victims Unit,
These are their stories,
Hey, wait, wait.
Hold on, hold on, hold on.
Let's go someplace else.
I got a better place. Come on.
Where you take
all your other girls?
Come on now. You know
I don't have nobody but you.
What's over here?
The view is better.
What's that?
It's nothing. It's nothing.
Relax. Come on now.
Relax. It's nothing.
I hear footsteps.
Look, I don't hear nothing.
What's up?
Do you want me or not?
STABLER: We want you, Leon.
Who's that?
TATE: Oh, man,
that's the sex police.
Why they want you?
It's this cop, man.
He got this thing for me
or something Iike that.
Not even out of prison
two weeks. I told you
he's not gonna stop.
Over there.
BENSON: Come here.
What he do?
Come here with me.
I didn't do nothing, man.
He framed me.
Keep right on
thinking that, Leon.
What'd he do?
How old are you?
Fourteen.
Oh, you's a Iying bitch.
Yo, man, Nashika told me
she graduated high school.
Yo, tell them
I ain't forced you.
I wanted to be with him.
Okay.
The Iaw says
you're not old enough
to make that decision.
Now, was he gonna
use protection?
We didn't talk about it.
I bet he didn't even mention
that he's HIV positive,
did he?
Bastard has the virus? Man!
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Nashika, come here.
Settle, settle, settle.
Yo, man,
you can't give that up.
I just did. What are you
gonna do about it?
Look at me. It's okay.
Nashika, have you ever
had sex with him?
Tonight would have been
the first time.
Okay, Iet's go.
So how many Iittle girls
have you had sex with
since you been out?
Yo, man, you ain't
have no right to follow me.
Hey. Hey. Don't tell me
how to do my job.
Answer the question.
So you can put me away
again for nothing?
Man, Iisten, the young Iadies
feel me, it's not my fault.
It is if they're jailbait.
They want to pleasure me,
who am I to stop them?
And if you infect them with
your HIV, it's their problem,
too, right?
Look, man, you ambushed us
before I even had
an opportunity to tell her.
I had protection.
Her protection is
me putting you back
in your Iittle cage.
Why don't you
just get off my case, man?
'Cause I don't Iike you.
AII right, well, I don't
have nothing else to say
until my Iegal aid gets here.
I'm surprised he said
as much as he did.
He has the personality
of a repeater.
He can do no wrong.
Nothing is his fault.
CABOT:
What was he in prison for?
Five years, sodomy two.
After I finally convinced
one of the numerous
underage girls
he had oral sex with
to come forward
and file a complaint.
Now he's escalating
to intercourse.
You're speculating, EIIiot.
He wasn't in the act
when you stopped him.
That's a problem.
Attempted rape two,
attempted reckless
endangerment,
because he didn't disclose
that he was HIV positive.
Where's the problem here?
We can't hold him
based on what he might do.
So we're supposed to wait
until after he infects
the girl?
She consented.
His attorney will say he was
carrying condoms
and planned to use them.
We can't prove otherwise.
We know that Leon
was about to have
unprotected sex with a minor.
Now, we cut him Ioose,
he's going to.
You got anything in your bag
of tricks, Counselor, now is
the time to pull it out.
I have something,
but I'II have to check.
And I'II have to involve
your psychiatrist.
I'II give him a call.
Get him Tate's prison
history, arrest records,
whatever you could find.
Leon's rap sheet starts
when he was seven years old.
He had 1 1 arrests
by his 13th birthday.
The record was sealed
because he was a juvenile.
Let's get them unsealed.
EIIiot, close the door.
Yeah?
I don't remember telling you
to tail Leon Tate.
I heard he was out.
Just keeping my eye on him.
Well, this squad doesn't have
enough bodies
for you and your partner
to go freelancing.
I Iike to think that we saved
a young girl's Iife tonight.
And we would need a new unit
if we were to follow
every perv
that we thought might repeat.
Leon Tate did his time.
And until somebody
makes a complaint,
he has rights.
This guy's penis is a deadly
weapon and he's got
a thing for young girls.
They got rights, too.
Until Cabot gives us
the word, you back off.
Are we clear?
We can't charge Leon Tate
with a crime,
so you wanna Iock him up
in a mental institution?
The Supreme Court
in Kansas v, Hendricks
upheld States' rights
to commit sexual predators
after their prison sentences.
Yes, Kansas and 16
other states have Iaws
specifically for that purpose.
New York does not.
We can use the existing
mental hygiene Iaw.
AII we have to do is
prove Leon Tate
has a mental illness
that poses a Iikelihood
of danger to himself
or to others.
You really want to risk
trying to set a precedent
with this case?
Leon Tate is a
sexual predator with HIV.
I think we have
a responsibility
to protect people from him
and others Iike him.
AII right. You give me
something to work with.
I'II see if the D.A.
will go for it.
Problem is even if the woman
Iies about her age,
it's still the man's fault.
Ignorance is no defense.
Nashika Morris is 14.
She's not a woman,
she's a girl.
What's a guy supposed to do,
check the girl's
birth certificate?
I'm just as opposed to rape
as everybody else
in this room,
but if she wanted to have sex,
that's her choice.
She wasn't forced.
She's a minor.
What she wants isn't relevant.
Are we interrupting?
Friendly disagreement.
Care to join in?
I came to tell you
that the D.A.'s allowing us
to move on Leon Tate.
On what grounds?
Based upon the reports
that I've read, I think
that I can make a case
that Mr. Tate has
anti-social personality
disorder.
That's what I've been
saying all along.
No empathy, no conscience,
no thought for the possible
consequences of his actions.
So he knows
what he's doing is wrong.
And he doesn't care.
Most people with HIV
act responsibly when it comes
to practicing safe sex.
Tate either can't control
or won't control his impulses,
which make him
a repeat sex offender.
Yeah, he's a sexual predator.
Now he's definitely
a danger to others.
Which is the standard set
by the Supreme Court.
HUANG: Do we know
how he contracted HIV?
Yeah, shooting dope.
He found out
when he was tested in prison.
One fix wipes away
any self-control
that Tate has Ieft,
making him even more Iikely
to have unprotected sex
with a minor.
And this is already
in the works?
We argue the motion
for a commitment hearing
this afternoon.
It would be a big help
if you could be there
in case the judge
has questions
about Tate's past.
I wouldn't miss it
for the world.
REGAL: Your Honor,
it's double jeopardy
disguised as treatment.
CABOT: Supreme Court
Kansas v, Hendricks,
civil commitment
of a sexual predator
is not punitive.
They arrested Mr. Tate
and couldn't make
the charges stick,
so they put a Iabel on him
for a one-way trip
to the funny farm.
I get the point, Ms. Regal.
ELMORE: Doctor Huang.
Yes?
Other than an
anti-social personality,
did you find any evidence
that the defendant
has a sexual disorder?
Yes.
Mr. Tate expresses his
narcissism and his anger
by having unprotected sex
with underage, powerless girls
and not disclosing
that he's HIV positive.
Detective Stabler,
when you arrested Mr. Tate,
how did you know for certain
that he was going
to have sex with the girl?
Ms. Morris told us so.
We found condoms on Tate
when we searched him.
Well, wouldn't that indicate
that Mr. Tate
planned safe sex?
Even so, the girl's a minor.
That's rape two.
Your Honor, Detective Stabler
can in no way predict
what my client
may or may not
have done that night.
Your client Iikes Iittle girls
and if we don't stop him now,
he's gonna kill one of them.
Enough.
I agree something
has to be done about
repeat sexual offenders,
but I am not gonna put
this man through a civil
commitment hearing
unless you can prove
that his intent was
unprotected sex.
Judge was afraid
to stick her neck out.
Maybe she'II change her mind
when we wheel a body
into her chambers.
Who's catching?
That would be me. What's up?
Rape. Rooftop in Harlem,
15-year-old victim
at Metro Hospital's ER.
It's Tate's m.o.
We'II take it.
Be my guest.
EIIiot, I've got two days
to finish up the paperwork
on the Wilson case
or I'm in contempt of court.
I'II go.
CRAGEN: AII right.
I don't want you trying
to pin Tate to every
sex crime in Harlem.
I met him in the park
down the block
from our apartment.
He told me he could get me
a rap audition,
that he was a promoter.
I fell for it.
Shareen, it's not your fault.
Did he tell you his name?
Andre.
He seemed nice.
Said I was smart and talented.
What happened?
He took me out
to a real restaurant.
Then he walked me home.
When we got to my door,
he said it was a beautiful
night, and that I was
aglow Iike the stars,
that we should go
to the rooftop.
He started to kiss me.
I told him to stop.
He slapped me,
pulled a knife,
ripped off my clothes,
and then he...
(CRYING)
Did he say anything
during the attack?
That I was Iucky
to experience him
'cause he was so handsome.
He was the Iove machine,
and that he was gonna make me
into a woman when he was done.
We'II be right back.
She's got a detached retina,
concussion.
Basically, he used her face
for a punching bag.
Okay, tell the doctor
that the rapist may have HIV.
Okay. Where are you going?
Back to the office.
That "Iove machine" Iine?
I've heard it before.
In '93 right after I got here,
13-year-old rape victim
Vanessa Hiltz.
Perp said he was gonna
make a woman out of her,
that he was the Iove machine.
You get anywhere on the case?
Was gonna run the DNA in '95
when they first
started testing,
but back then you couldn't
get it done unless you
already had the collar.
And you think
Leon Tate is our guy.
I contacted the victim.
She's got AIDS.
Perp sweet-talked her
just Iike Leon.
I don't know how I missed it.
CRAGEN: Well, banging your
head against the wall
isn't gonna help.
Pick Tate up and see if
his victims are in any kind
of shape for a Iineup.
I pounded on his door.
If he's in there,
he's got a bad headache.
You okay?
Yeah. I just don't Iike
some guy making my home turf
dangerous for young girls.
I thought you grew up
in Brooklyn.
Nope. About 10 blocks
from here.
Ground zero for the '68 riots.
What was that Iike?
I was six. My mother said
the only way we're
Ieaving our apartment
was if somebody
burned it down.
This your guy?
Son of a bitch is at it again.
You, come here.
Yo, come on, man.
Yo, she's 17.
checked her ID.
We didn't do nothing.
Assume the position.
See how they do?
So what's up, man?
The hood got you scared,
you had to bring
Uncle Tom with you?
You didn't mean that.
You know something?
I think you just
upset my partner.
You should apologize.
Yeah, go ahead with...
AII right, all right,
all right. I apologize,
I apologize.
You know Casanova here
has HIV?
That the truth?
Yo, man, don't believe them.
No. Is it the truth?
Yo, I got protection.
I don't care if you got
a bulletproof vest
for that thing.
You should have told me.
Oh, now there she go.
Yo, man, my Iegal aid told me
I can sue you
for telling anybody.
Yeah, so go ahead and do it.
We'II say it slipped out
while we busted you
for rape and assault.
Do what?
Yo, I ain't raped nobody.
Yeah, I'II bet you're not
the Iove machine, either.
Yo, man, what you
talking about, man?
Why y'all doing this to me?
"Doing it to me."
It's all about you, huh, Leon?
It's been a while.
It's okay, Vanessa.
Do you recognize
any of these men?
I'm not sure.
Take your time.
No coaching, Counselor.
I wish I could tell you
one of them's him. I'm sorry.
It's all right. It's
all right. It's all right.
Okay. Come on. Thank you.
(CRYING)
Okay, you ready?
They can't see you.
Help me up.
Yeah. Come on.
STABLER: Do you recognize
any of these men?
CABOT: Which one?
I can't tell.
(CRYING)
Maybe when I can see
a Iittle better.
Okay.
It's all right.
I'm taking my client home now.
Cut him Ioose.
That son of a bitch
wins again.
I'm on my way home
and this flaming shoe
hit the ground.
I Iook up and here comes
the rest of her.
Did you see
anyone else up there?
No, man, I was busy
putting out the fire.
Okay, thank you.
If you remember anything
else, give us a call.
They wake you up, too?
Yeah. I was just
Ieaving the office
when the call came in.
I had the desk page you.
Girl on a rooftop.
I figured you'd want in.
What's with fire?
Perp Iit the victim up
before he threw her off.
Who is she?
Aisha Thompson, 14.
Used to Iive about
two blocks away from here.
Tosses her off a roof.
Leon's trying to send me
a message now?
Hey.
Full thickness burns
to the body, but she was
dead before he torched her.
How?
Ligature strangulation
after she performed
oral sex on him.
We ran the Luma Light
around the scene,
she has fluids on her face.
Leon Iives
a dozen blocks from here.
THOMPSON: Where is she?
Where is she, man?
Hold up.
Yo, she's my sister.
Let him through.
Didn't know you had a sister.
Rodney. Rodney. Come on.
AII right.
You know him?
He Iooks
just Iike his father.
You used to come around
all the time
when I was a kid.
You know, your parents and I
got busy with our Iives,
fell out of touch
when I moved to Brooklyn.
How they doing?
Dad got hooked on dope,
disappeared,
and mom brought us up,
but she died two years ago,
breast cancer,
so it was just me and Aisha.
I was out all night
Iooking for her.
When did you realize
she was missing?
She went to the Iibrary
to do a project for school,
but when she didn't come home
by 10:00, I just started
calling her friends,
but nobody saw her, so...
Did she have a boyfriend?
Anybody paying
attention to her?
Aisha told me everything,
okay.
She just got accepted
to Stuyvesant. You know, that
school for the gifted kids?
She was gonna be somebody.
What are you gonna
do about this?
We got a Iine on this guy.
We think we know who he is
and we're gonna get him.
He's not gonna kill
any more girls.
How does Fin know
the victim's family?
He grew up with Rodney
and Aisha's mother.
This has got Tate
written all over it.
We need a warrant
for his apartment.
CABOT: Do you have evidence
it was him?
We believe he beat up
Shareen White
when he raped her.
Maybe this time
he didn't wanna Ieave
any witnesses.
It's not enough.
And he's missing
and the victim fits Tate's
profile and she was raped
on that rooftop.
And murdered and set on fire,
neither of which
Tate has ever done.
We don't know everything
Leon Tate's done.
Now, how are we doing
on getting his records
unsealed?
Motion's in, but it's gonna
take some time.
We don't have time.
We need the information now.
Corporation counsel
would have prosecuted Tate
because he was a juvie.
Maybe somebody there
remembers him.
I keep my notes
on all my own cases.
The day I start this job,
they put that Iittle bastard's
overstuffed file
right on my desk.
Our shrink pegged him
with anti-social
personality disorder.
Yeah, well, that sounds mild
compared to the psych
evals I read back then.
Said Iittle Leon
was a serial killer
in the making.
Based on what?
Based on his Iove
of torturing and killing
the neighbors' pets.
Two when he was just seven,
and that's just for starters.
FIN: What happened?
Kiddie probation.
In other words, nothing.
My Iuck I got a judge
sympathetic to the kid.
His sheet says he was back
six months Iater.
Hey, I argued
he should be put away,
but Judge BIeeding Heart
wanted me to exhaust every
possible treatment option.
Don't tell me, His Honor said
Leon could be rehabilitated?
Until his Iast arrest,
which I handled
five years Iater.
What made the judge
change his mind?
Leon torched
the treatment facility.
Nobody else would touch him.
Leon set fires?
Nine out of his 11 collars
are for arson.
The ACC who prosecuted says
Tate told the psychiatrists
he killed puppies
to see what it felt Iike.
Add the pyromania
and Leon scores
two out of three
on the triad of sociopathy.
Bed-wetting would make him
three for three.
So Tate shows a reckless
disregard for Iife from
the time he was seven.
And he had five years to
think about what he was gonna
do when he got out.
So why didn't he kill
the first girl he seduced?
HUANG: Rape is about anger,
but I'm not sure it's
the women that set him off.
I think following him
might have made his anger
boil over.
Oh, so Aisha Thompson's death
is our fault?
Well, that's the way he's
gonna play it every time
he kills, until you find him.
So we should have
just done nothing, right?
I'm profiling,
I'm not accusing.
CRAGEN: AII right,
where are we?
Three shifts on Leon's crib
around the clock,
no sign of him.
Tate have any friends
or relatives he might
be holed up with?
His mother moved
from the address in his file.
Nobody could tell us
where she went.
AII right. Well, Iet's
just check his phone records
from prison.
If you were away
for five years,
you'd call your mother, too.
If he's not with her,
have his building canvassed.
John, start pulling every rape
and sexual homicide of girls
that fit the type Tate Iiked.
AII five boroughs.
How far back?
Let's start with 10 years.
This guy is
serial killer material.
He might have sweet-talked
a Iot more girls
than we know about.
You come to take
another five years
from my son?
When was the Iast time
you saw him?
You should know,
the way you've been
following him around.
Mrs. Tate,
when was the Iast time...
You sent him to prison
because some 14-year-old
hussy told him she was 21.
So it was her fault?
Girl never Ied you on?
A girl was murdered
Iast night.
He didn't kill anybody.
I told him to stay away
from those girls.
Well, Leon's not taking
your advice,
because he was with one
when I saw him two nights ago.
I don't know
why he's the way he is.
I tried to raise him right,
gave him plenty of Iove.
Now he's got this HIV.
I don't know what happened.
Mrs. Tate,
if he contacts you...
I'm afraid that he is
shooting dope again.
Why do you think that?
He said you were dogging him,
and he wasn't sure
he could handle
going back to prison.
Did he tell you that
when you saw him?
Last night.
What do you want with me?
FIN: You seen Leon Tate?
I mind my own business.
Why don't you try
knocking on his door?
We did.
Then I guess I can't help you.
AII right. Well,
if you see him give me a call.
Where to now?
Well, Leon Iikes rooftops.
Spent a Iot of time
on my rooftop
when I was a kid.
It was safe back then.
Doing the wild thing
with your girlfriend?
You know, when you Iive here
you can't afford
a vacation to Aruba,
so you went to
"Isle of Aroofa," tar beach.
PIus the guys
Iike to come up here
'cause this is where
the girls would come hang out.
I grew up in Queens.
AII I ever wanted
was the excitement
of the city.
Sounds Iike
all you ever wanted was quiet.
We should've traded places.
Large family in a
small apartment. I used to
come up here at night, too.
Used to Iook at the view
and the Iights
in the distance, think.
About the meaning of Iife?
That I had to get off
that rooftop.
Well, well, Leon, I guess
you wanted to get off
the rooftop, too.
Who you talking to?
Check this out.
It's Leon.
Took a taste and OD'd.
He could have been up here
since Iast night and nobody
would have seen him.
ME says he's been
down at Ieast 18 hours,
but he still could have
murdered Aisha Thompson.
Guy OD's two weeks
out of prison.
Talk about bad karma.
Well, maybe for Leon.
For his potential victims
it's all upside.
Yeah, thanks. Maybe not.
FIN: What?
Another rooftop, another body.
Guy came up to feed
the pigeons, found her.
Anybody else up here
besides him and the victim?
Nobody.
Thanks.
How old is this one, Doc?
I'd say no more than 16.
Raped before she was killed.
Any ID?
Nothing on her.
Perp did a real number
on her face.
With what?
Brick.
Pieces of it
broke off in her skull.
This was on her
right index finger.
May help ID her.
Well, if it's Leon's work,
he's improvising.
It couldn't
have been Leon Tate.
What are you talking about?
The victim's still in rigor.
Probably killed this morning.
Tate was dead by Iast night.
EIIiot...
I wanted it to be Leon.
Everything fit.
We wasted time.
Another girl's dead
because I went down
the wrong road.
You happy now?
Mrs. Tate,
I'm sorry about Leon.
Don't you dare
say you're sorry.
You're glad he's dead.
He didn't kill those girls,
but you killed him anyway.
You murdered him.
Mrs. Tate, Detective Stabler
was doing his job.
My son was innocent.
Your son was gonna
kill somebody with his HIV.
We had to stop him.
We didn't put
the needle in his arm.
You didn't.
But you all stick together,
don't you?
Who's our victim?
Tiffany Purcell, 14.
Mother ID'ed her ring.
Fin, thanks for taking my back
with Mrs. Tate.
Leon was scum.
He was gonna kill
some innocent girl
if you didn't stop him.
We're checking every parolee
in the Iast two years
who was ever collared
for anything violent
against women.
None of these m.o.'s
are the same.
STABLER: The pattern's
in the victimology.
AII the victims are black,
young, good students,
never been in trouble.
This is no wild-eyed psycho.
Your perp is most Iikely
well-educated, attractive.
He seems trustworthy.
He has good social skills.
Every time he cons a girl
into submission, he's proving
how much smarter he is.
Okay, that could explain
why he changes Iocations
and m.o.'s.
That's part of his strategy.
He knew how much harder
it would be for you guys
to put his pattern together.
He was right.
What about this victim
that he set on fire?
Something about her
sent him over the edge.
Maybe she
physically injured him
or she said something
that would trigger
that Ievel of violence.
You mean Iike challenging
his manhood?
Any challenge
to his sense of control.
That's what this is all about.
These men often have wives
or steady girlfriends
who are submissive.
They seek
unconditional approval.
Well, my old man
never approved
of a single thing I ever did.
I don't go around raping
and killing young girls.
This perp was told that he
was no good enough times
to think that it was true.
AII any of these girls
has to say is "stop" and
that's Iikely to set him off.
A rape and two murders
in one week tells me
we're on borrowed time
before he kills again.
Get all the
victims' descriptions
of the perp. Make a composite.
We've got company.
I'II take him.
I thought you had him, man?
We were wrong.
We're gonna get him.
You aren't doing
a damn thing, are you?
What, 'cause it happened
north of 96th street?
You can save that
for somebody else, okay?
I know your family.
We're from the same place
and we're the same color.
Fin.
What happened?
Another girl.
BENSON: What do we got, Doc?
Cause of death
is Iigature strangulation.
Some kind of thick shoelace,
maybe from a sneaker.
Dead about 12 hours.
Raped?
And she put up a fight,
tried to resist.
She's got finger-size bruises
on the inside of her thighs
where he pried her Iegs apart.
This wacko's out of control.
Well, I can't tell you
it's the same wacko
until I compare the DNA.
I've known her
since she was a baby.
It's horrible.
Tina was a sweet girl.
I try to keep
the building safe.
What do you know
about Tina and her family?
Her parents are nice,
responsible people.
They're never Iate
with the rent, took care
of their apartment.
Do they know?
Her mother does.
She's downstairs.
Father sails on cargo ships.
They're trying
to reach him now.
Did you see Tina Iast night?
Sorry.
We're gonna need you
to take us down
to her apartment.
I sent Tina to the store
on the corner
for some milk and bread.
Do you remember what time?
Around 10:00 Iast night.
We walked out together.
I work graveyard
at the post office.
This is gonna kill her daddy.
Was she here
when you came home
this morning?
I did a couple of hours
overtime. I assumed
Tina went to school.
Does she ever have
any friends over
while you're at work?
No, only when I'm here.
How about boyfriends?
Tina is very shy around boys.
She said some kid at school
had a crush on her.
That's all I know about.
Who would do
something Iike this?
I'II be just a minute.
Piece of paper in her room
had some numbers on it.
I'II call them
and have someone
run them down.
Her mother give you anything?
Tina's Iast stop
was the corner store.
CLERK:
Yeah, she did come in here.
I was getting ready to close.
She come in with anybody?
No.
Some guy
did come in behind her.
They started talking.
This him?
This guy had a shaved head
and no beard.
You ever see him
in here before?
I just started
working here Iast week.
What'd they talk about?
I didn't hear,
but they was talking
and Iaughing and stuff
Iike they knew each other.
They Ieft together, too.
FIN: Thanks, man.
AII right.
Shaved head? One of
my tenants just went for
the cue-ball Iook.
Which one?
Malik Harris. 3B.
Shaved his beard, too.
When?
Last few days.
Didn't even recognize him.
MUNCH: Malik Harris?
That's what it says on my
birth certificate, but I'm
known professionally as King.
We wanna talk to you, Malik.
You gonna invite us in?
Now is not a convenient time.
TANYA: Who's there, baby?
Nobody that concerns you.
I guess we're interrupting.
I told you I was busy.
Sweetie.
Baby, I was just wondering...
You see I'm speaking
to these officers?
What do you want?
Are you aware
of what's going on upstairs?
I haven't been out,
enlighten me.
A girl was murdered
on the rooftop.
Who?
Tina Dupree. You know her?
Yeah, I seen her around. Damn.
MUNCH: Somebody saw you
with her Iast night.
On the corner at the store.
I walked her home.
Little girl Iike that
shouldn't be out so Iate.
Can you tell us where you were
the rest of the night?
Baby, now you may dialogue.
We ain't Ieft the apartment.
We been busy.
You know what I am saying?
"Baby, now you may
dialogue"? PIease.
He was the Iast person
to see her.
Pretty big risk
if he's our serial killer,
striking where he Iives.
Unless Tina was a victim
of opportunity.
Harris goes to the store,
sees her, walks her home,
knows her mother
works at night,
father's out of town.
Yeah, police just putting on
a big show for us, that's all.
Just what we need.
I got this. You got a problem?
Yeah, that you cops
don't give a rat's ass
what's going on up here.
You don't think so?
Well, we're here.
You know who's not here?
The press, the TV news.
If you got any beef,
you got beef with them,
not us.
They can't make money off us.
They don't care. Word up.
Don't tell me. Tell them.
Why don't y'all give them
a call, all right?
Meanwhile, does anybody have
any information
that could help us?
Okay, people, please go back
to your business,
and Iet us do our job.
Not you.
Why do you wanna make this
harder on yourself
than it already is?
Aisha was all I had Ieft,
all right? Now some scum
took her away,
and I'm supposed to stand here
and watch you not catch him?
What's harder than that, man?
Checked the phone numbers
we found
in Tina Dupree's room.
One belongs to a girlfriend.
The other, Malik Harris.
Harris have a rap sheet?
Never arrested, but came up
on the computer as a victim
of vehicular assault.
Hit by a car in '94.
Right after the third murder.
His Iegs were shattered,
almost Iost them.
Hospitalized in rehab
for nearly a year,
spent the next two Iearning
how to walk again.
So Harris
was only out of action
for three years.
Our perp waited seven.
He gets
social security disability.
From '97 to Iast year,
his checks were sent
to an address in Detroit.
Harris has a sister
who Iives there.
Get Detroit Homicide
on the phone, see if they
have any unsolved killings
matching our victim profiles.
Fin, my office, now.
I just got off the phone
with the Deputy Commissioner
for public information.
Now, he wants to know
why one of my detectives
is bad-mouthing the media
up in Harlem.
I was just telling them
the truth.
What the hell
were you thinking?
That those people were right.
That's not your
judgment to make.
If these girls were
murdered in the Village
or the Upper West Side,
the media would be
all over it.
1PP would issue a task force.
Five black girls
aren't even on their radar.
Are you finished?
No, I'm just getting started.
This is no different
than any other investigation.
No? An East
Side socialite disappears,
we got 50 cops on it.
BIack girls
start getting executed,
we got four cops.
That sounds equal to you?
Look, I know
where you're coming from.
No, you don't know
where I'm coming from.
There's no way you can know
Don't you dare presume to know
what's in my head.
No matter what you say,
Captain,
you're not black
and you're not from the hood.
SIow down.
That crowd
could have turned ugly.
I diffused it.
Cragen didn't know that.
Who you defending? Him or me?
Both of you.
Just take a deep breath.
No time for that.
Where are we going?
I'm going to meet
an informant. AIone.
FIN: I'm busy.
This better be good.
BENNY:
How about a Iittle respect.
Time is money,
and I'm Iosing it
talking to you.
What the hell are you doing
back there? Sit up Iike a man.
Yeah, I get seen with you,
my customers go elsewhere
for their merchandise.
You got something
for me, Benny,
or did you just come here
to run your mouth?
Word's out you're Iooking
to jam up King.
Where you hear that?
I got sources just Iike you.
What do your sources
know about him?
That King's a
rap promoter wannabe.
Manages a few unknowns,
but doesn't have
the goods to make it big.
He uses the rap Iine
mostly to pick up women.
So far you're boring me.
How about he buys his coke
and dope from one of
my corner boys?
Now you're talking.
Where's he get his cash?
King's a kept man.
Smooth-talks one of his Iadies
into paying for his Iifestyle,
till they wise up, dump him.
What's in this for you,
Benny?
I don't Iike him.
Consider it a freebie.
Harris admits to walking
Tina Dupree home,
and we got witnesses
that saw them together.
That doesn't mean
he killed her.
We took the composites
from all the rapes
and had the artist
remove the hair.
That's Malik Harris dead-on.
A judge isn't going to give us
a search warrant
based on that.
What about a Iineup?
We risk tipping our hand.
I got an informant,
a drug dealer I busted
a few years ago.
He says his boys sell
Malik Harris dope and coke
on a regular basis.
Well, write the warrant
for the drugs only.
That'II allow you to search
almost everywhere.
Anything you find
on top of that is gravy.
(SINGING RAP SONG)
I can't talk to you right now.
I'm cutting a track here.
Yeah, maybe you should be
recording jailhouse rock.
Man, what are you
talking about?
You're under arrest.
For what?
Possession of narcotics
in the third degree.
What?
We tossed your crib.
What you gonna do?
Make her a star
and then kill her, too?
What is up with that?
You're putting me through
all of this for some
recreational pharmaceuticals?
You Iike big words, King?
How about execution
or Iethal injection?
What, you gonna give me
the death penalty
for a Iittle cocaine
and heroin?
Your handiwork. Remember?
Poor girls.
And you think that I
have something to do
with killing them?
You were the Iast one
with Tina before she was
found dead.
Feel free to dialogue.
I told you I walked her home.
Anything after that
I'm not accountable for.
And, of course,
you've met my Iovely alibi.
Who'II say anything
once you doped her up.
I am innocent.
Then you won't mind
taking a Iittle trip with us.
Open wide, please.
This'II only take a moment.
What are you doing?
Just taking
a Iittle DNA sample
to prove your innocence.
I can't allow that.
You got something to hide?
It violates
my religious tenets.
I'm a Jehovah's Witness.
FIN: Prove it.
He doesn't have to.
He says it,
I can't take the sample.
We haven't been
properly introduced.
I'm King.
We should get together
sometime under circumstances
more conducive.
You fill in the blanks.
HARRIS: She's choice.
Don't you ever want to...
Your thoughts
aren't very religious.
Well, we all worship
in our own way.
(HARRIS GROANS)
You know how much
those cost, man?
Sorry about that.
Let me get that for you.
Oh, man. Shoot.
Partner, you gotta be
more careful.
Don't worry.
We'II replace them
by tomorrow morning.
Frames are from Italy.
You have
our sincerest apologies.
Most people secrete oils
right onto the Ienses.
The cells I found
that were usable
were on the nose pieces.
So what's the verdict?
His Majesty's DNA is a match
on all six murders
and eight rapes.
Got him.
Thanks.
CABOT: This motion to suppress
is totally without merit.
Malik Harris's right
to genetic privacy
was violated.
The police have gotten DNA
off of coffee cups,
Iipstick, telephones,
even a suspect's spit
on the street.
AII of it upheld in court.
People discard coffee cups
and spit voluntarily.
Detective Tutuola
assaulted my client
and stole his glasses.
When Mr. Harris's sunglasses
fell, he demanded
the detectives replace them.
He discarded them,
which makes them fair game.
So what we're saying here
is that the police,
at any time,
can obtain a person's
genetic code?
The DNA obtained by the police
conclusively Iinks
the defendant
to the murders
of a half a dozen
teenage girls.
What about their rights?
Mr. Harris's guilt
or innocence
isn't the issue here.
How the police gathered
the evidence is.
Your Honor,
reasonable deception
on the part of the police
has been upheld
by the Supreme Court.
Yes, and if the police
had tricked Mr. Harris
into giving up his sunglasses,
we'd be out of here.
They forced him,
that's coercion,
the DNA is out.
The DNA is all the police have
tying my client
to these murders.
Then I have no other choice
but to drop the charges
against Mr. Harris.
And when your detectives blame
the judge, tell them that
they're the ones that blew it.
No, no, no.
We didn't screw up.
We got Harris off the street.
Your judge Iet him go.
What did you expect?
A Iittle justice.
Then maybe you
should have done better.
We got you all the evidence
you needed.
If you'd done it Iegally,
this wouldn't have happened.
AII right, come on. This isn't
getting us anywhere.
What do we have Ieft?
Possession three
on the drugs that we found
in his apartment.
Is there anything
we can do with that
to keep him off the street?
First offense,
Harris'II make bail.
Just gonna give up?
I will ask for remand,
but the judge
will never go for it.
And I can't
mention the murders.
Harris gets out,
we stick with him.
I want all four of you
in the courtroom
for the arraignment.
Don't Iet him
out of your sight.
If he so much as sneezes,
I want the KIeenex.
JUDGE: Remand, Ms. Cabot?
On a third degree
possession charge?
CABOT:
Mr. Harris provided the drugs
to young women.
The People believe
he is a danger
to the community.
Counsel approach.
Ms. Cabot,
I have 40 more cases
on the docket
and you're wasting my time
on this frivolous garbage?
Your Honor,
it is the People's position
that we...
You screwed up
your murder case
and now you want me
to do your dirty work for you.
Not gonna happen. Step back.
Bail is set at $2,000,
cash only.
Next case.
Let's go.
Son of a bitch!
You killed my sister, man!
JUDGE: Order. Officer.
He's a cold-blooded murderer.
Officer. Officer,
clear the court!
Bastard bit me!
Bring it. Come on, bring it.
Remove that man!
Officer, order.
AII right, we'II take him.
We'II take him.
Order!
THOMPSON: You'II take me?
Yeah, you're under arrest
for assault.
Whoa. Hold it.
He gets away
with murdering my sister,
and you taking me?
(POLICE SIREN WAILING)
Harris,
Iet's see your hands, now.
You're under arrest.
It's over, Your Highness.
You ain't got nothing on me.
Just taking
a bite out of crime.
Just Iike you took a bite
out of Rodney Thompson's arm.
And Ieft your DNA.
Thought you were
smarter than that.
Fin?
Counselor?
You and Rodney Thompson
put on quite a performance
when you Ied him out of court.
What are you talking about?
Setting Harris up
by telling Thompson
the only way we were
going to get Harris's DNA
is if he attacked him.
Thompson's not a perp.
I can't force him
to do anything.
No, but you could have
given him the idea.
Did you?
You really want to know?
No.
It was a setup.
We arranged
for your client
to bite Rodney Thompson?
I don't think so.
Bit yourself in the ass
with your big mouth
this time, King.
This is entrapment.
CABOT: Ask your attorney.
She'II tell you it's not.
I just heard from Detroit.
Malik's DNA.
Matches four homicides,
five rapes,
all during the time
he was Iiving with his sister.
I want a deal.
FIN: You want a deal?
How about right before
we execute you
for killing those girls,
I bring you your Iast meal?
How's that?