NARRATOR: In the criminal
justice system,
sexually based offenses
are considered
especially heinous,
In New York City,
the dedicated detectives
who investigate
these vicious felonies
are members
of an elite squad known
as the Special Victims Unit,
These are their stories,
Detective Stabler,
you stated under oath that
you tested everyone
who had any personal contact
with Leslie Bello.
Is that correct?
Yes.
Did you test Mr. Hernandez,
her teacher?
No.
No?
Did you test her bus driver,
Mr. Campbell?
No.
Well, did you test the plumber
who fixed the bathroom drain
when Leslie was home
sick from school?
No.
So, in fact,
everyone who could've
been alone with Leslie
was not tested.
Leslie did not identify
the plumber as her rapist.
And 8-year-olds,
they never Iie.
Objection.
Withdrawn.
No further questions.
Redirect, Your Honor.
Detective Stabler,
whom did Leslie Bello
identify as her rapist?
Her grandfather,
Frederick Bello.
Thank you.
Was it scary?
Piece of cake.
AII you gotta do
is tell the truth.
Will you come with me?
Well, you know, I can't,
but I'II wait right here
until you finish.
Leslie Bello?
Is he in there?
Yeah, but he can't hurt you
anymore.
Just Iook at the person
who's talking to you
and answer their questions,
okay?
Morning, EIIiot.
Hey, how'd it go?
They Iet him walk.
You're kidding me.
Grandfather rapes
his granddaughter,
no big deal,
even though he was
the only one in the house
with gonorrhea.
Who the hell do they think
gave it to her?
Juries screw up.
Whole system's screwed up.
It's a Ioad of crap.
MAN: It's a rape-homicide,
Victim's Jennifer Walton, 25.
The body was discovered
by her friend this morning.
The Iandlady Iet her in.
Any signs of forced entry?
No, but take a Iook.
Did some damage.
That's only the beginning.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
How did it end?
Found her tucked into bed,
hands bound behind her back
with pantyhose,
face pummeled,
throat slit and raped.
Any fluids?
Too much blood to tell,
but there is
perineal bruising.
We'II test the sheets
for semen.
FIN: Look at this.
A romantic psycho.
And I thought my day
couldn't get any worse.
MUNCH: How do you spell that?
EDNA: D-U-M-A-S.
How well did you
know Jennifer?
We're both dog Iovers.
We'd exchange stories
sometimes at the dog run.
Did she ever mention
a boyfriend?
Last month she said
she was going away
for a weekend with
someone named David.
She asked me to take care
of her Iittle puppy, Max.
I bet he wants his breakfast.
Did you ever meet this David?
Well, not formally,
but I saw him sometimes
standing outside her door
right there.
What's he Iook Iike?
Tall, graying hair.
He brought her flowers,
so I figured it was him.
What kind of flowers?
Begonias and daisies,
roses.
He stop by Iast night?
I think they were fighting.
About what?
He was yelling so Ioud.
Something about
she was trying
to ruin his Iife.
I should've
checked up on her.
(DOG WHINING)
STABLER: What store?
Wheaton's Department Store.
We planned to meet for drinks.
When?
Around 9:00.
8:30 she called my cell,
said a friend
stopped by from work
and she'd be Iate.
She mention a name?
No, but I heard
a man's voice
in the background.
What'd it sound Iike?
Did he have an accent?
Did he sound angry?
I don't know.
What about Jennifer?
Was she upset,
nervous?
I'm not sure.
Is there anything
you're sure about?
We only talked for a moment.
EIIiot.
We'II be in touch.
Looks Iike
she was entertaining.
One glass with Iipstick.
Our perp a teetotaler?
Neat freak.
Found the other glass
in the kitchen
on the drying rack
along with a carving knife,
both washed totally clean.
So much for evidence.
Well, we've got blood.
Probably Ianded
the first blow here.
Then he dragged her
from the couch
into the bedroom.
STABLER: Surprised he didn't
shampoo the rug.
Victim's clothes
folded nice and neat.
Buttons are all gone.
After he ripped them
from her body.
Bag them all.
There's no sign of
a struggle here.
The blow must've stunned her,
maybe even knocked her out.
So, he Iays her on the bed,
and he ties her up.
He beats her
and he rapes her.
I'd say you're Iooking
for a Iefty.
He drew the blade
across her throat,
slicing the Ieft carotid,
sending the spray
against the wall.
Kitchen knife Iooks
good for the weapon.
When he's finished with her,
heads for the bathroom.
Hey.
Hey. Found traces of blood
in the sink
and also around
the shower drain.
Okay.
So, he showers.
He gets dressed.
He washes the wine glass
and the knife,
strolls out the front door,
takes his dirty towels
with him.
You got it all figured out.
At Ieast I'm trying.
Check the drain traps.
Hear that?
Get the tub and the sink.
You're thinking
crime of passion?
Really did a number on her.
Hell of a Iot of rage.
But he wasn't out of control.
Still had the presence of mind
to clean up after himself.
Maybe that's because
the violence is actually
soothing to him.
You see, the initial outburst
triggers a flood of serotonin
to his brain,
which calms him
while he acts out his anger.
The more he maims,
the better he feels.
Exactly, and then once
his rage dissipates,
he's gentle, he's Ioving.
He tucks her into bed.
He folds her clothes,
puts a flower on her pillow.
So, what are we
Iooking for?
Well, he wooed her
before he killed her.
He's intelligent, articulate,
maybe even charming.
Any Ieads on the boyfriend?
EIIiot and I are heading
to Wheaton's to follow up
on her visitor from work.
Munch, Fin,
stick with forensics.
As meticulous
as this guy was,
Iet's hope he Ieft something
behind in all that carnage.
Multiple facial
and mandibular fractures.
Knocked out four front teeth,
two embedded
in the soft palate.
Any idea what
he beat her with?
His fists,
by the bruise patterns.
He could have cut himself
on a broken tooth.
I'II canvas the ERs
for hand injuries.
Anything else?
Traces of spermicide,
most Iikely from a condom,
but no semen,
and something odd.
Two circular incisions
on her chest
where the dermis was excised.
What's his game?
I don't know,
but the hell
this woman went through,
death was a blessing.
DARCY: You gotta find
whoever did this,
We're Iooking for someone
who might be able to help.
A guy by the name of David.
You mean David Stedman?
He work here?
He's the manager
in Women's Shoes.
Were he
and Jenny involved?
He's a married man.
Not that it ever stopped him.
Stopped him from what?
Chasing women.
He's shameless.
Even after Tammy filed
that harassment suit.
Who's Tammy?
She worked in Cosmetics.
She told him
she had a boyfriend,
but he wouldn't back off.
She finally had to transfer
to the Brooklyn store.
Is that when David
turned his attentions
to Jenny?
Yeah.
He started
coming around on breaks,
asking her to Iunch.
I warned her,
but she insisted
they were just friends.
But you didn't believe that?
It's impossible for David
to be "just friends"
with a woman.
Is he working today?
Up the escalator
and on your right.
Look what this shoe does
for the Iine of your Ieg.
Very sexy.
I don't know.
They're awfully expensive.
But you're worth it.
David Stedman?
Be right with you.
We'd Iike to talk to you now.
I'm with a customer.
She'II understand.
I think you better
talk to them.
What happened to your hand?
I broke a knuckle.
How?
Banged it against a door.
She really must have
pissed you off.
Who?
Jennifer Walton.
Neighbor saw you
go into the apartment,
heard you two arguing.
You get off
on beating up women?
Make you feel good?
I never touched her.
BENSON: Well, we saw
the hole in the door.
Is that what this is about?
'Cause I'II pay for
the damned door, okay?
What set you off there,
shoe boy?
She was gonna file
a complaint with my boss.
She said I was harassing her.
That's a bad habit of yours,
harassing the Iadies,
isn't it?
I only asked her to dinner.
You murdered her.
What?
She's dead?
No more dancing.
EIIiot.
You tried to get
into her pants,
and she wouldn't go for it,
so you smacked her.
No.
No? Then, tell me
what happened, huh?
EIIiot.
Huh? Just tell me
what happened.
She Iaughed at you,
'cause you couldn't
get it up?
No!
EIIiot, knock it off.
She made fun of
your manhood,
and then you decided
to teach her a Iesson,
so you pounded it into her,
and then you raped her
and you sliced her throat.
No, I punched her door.
EIIiot.
You raped her.
You sliced her throat.
She threw me out, I swear.
What time?
Yeah.
7:00.
No, witness puts you there
at 8:30.
No.
No. I was at the hospital
by 8:00.
You don't believe me,
call the ER at Mercy General.
What are you doing?
You itching for a Iawsuit?
Just cutting through the crap.
He's calling his Iawyer.
Well, God bless the Iawyers.
EIIiot, hey,
it's my ass, too.
Don't worry about it.
I'II make sure it's covered.
David Stedman,
signed in 7:47 p.m.,
discharged 1 2:52 a.m.
What took so Iong?
It's a busy night.
And he would've gotten in
sooner if he hadn't kept
hitting on me.
I saw his wedding ring.
Every time he made a move,
I dropped him
to the bottom of the Iist.
Great.
Thank you.
So, we start over.
Face pummeled, 5-inch Iac
to the throat.
How deep?
Carotid partially severed.
BP thready. 70 palp.
Ran four units of saline.
WOMAN: Take her to 3.
We're on it.
What?
That was Munch calling
from the crime scene.
I think we just met
victim number two.
(WOMAN CHATTERING
OVER PA SYSTEM)
Celia Mitchum, second victim,
25, teacher's aide
at Thornton EIementary.
Landlord found her
tucked into bed,
hands tied, face beaten,
throat cut.
After which
the perp took a shower,
did the dishes
and Ieft a white rose
on her pillow.
Just Iike the other one.
Have you seen this MO before?
Not around here.
We're checking with VICAP.
He's got his act down.
He's too organized
to be a first-timer.
And he knows what he Iikes,
blonde, blue eyes, petite,
both worked with children.
Mother fixation?
I'd say more Iike
a romantic ideal.
He shared a bottle of wine
with Jennifer.
He Iit a candle.
What about Celia?
Having coffee,
munching on some chocolates.
Don't forget the roses.
White roses.
The symbol of innocence
and purity.
Unfortunately, no woman
fulfills his fantasy.
So, his frustration
just keeps escalating until
he can't contain himself.
What else?
He tailors his approach.
Wine for Jennifer,
chocolates for Celia.
This means that
he studied them.
He possibly knew them.
He's white, educated,
probably middle-management.
Why didn't you pick up
on this before?
'Cause the pattern
didn't emerge until
the second victim.
How Iong's he
been doing it?
Long enough to perfect
a pretty sophisticated MO.
Five, maybe 10 years.
You'II have to go a hell of
a Iot farther back than that.
HAWKINS: EIIiot.
John. What do you need?
A few minutes with your boss.
Detective Hawkins?
Captain Cragen.
Come on in. EIIiot, join us.
Who the hell is that?
Wyatt Earp.
Shut the door.
You two know each other?
I took his class
at the Academy.
AIways had him
figured for Homicide.
I guess he had other ideas.
What's this about?
Detective Hawkins has
some information he thinks
bears on your serial killer.
Okay.
You remember
the SoHo Strangler?
Roger Berry, early '80s.
Beat and raped his victims,
and then he strangled them.
You put him away.
He's out.
Paroled six months ago.
Well, our guy doesn't
squeeze their throats.
He cuts them.
Tucks them into bed?
Yeah.
Leaves a white rose
on their pillow?
Okay, maybe we got a copycat.
I wouldn't count on it.
We never released
that Iittle detail
about the rose
or the fact that
he tied his victims' wrists
with a Navy slipknot.
Berry was a biter.
Still is.
Only now he cuts the bite
marks off their chests,
so you can't match them
to his dental records.
Roger's had a few years
to sweat the details.
Okay, well, thanks a Iot.
We'II check it out.
You can ride with me.
Brass called this morning.
Detective Hawkins
has a Iot of experience
with Berry.
He's been temporarily
reassigned here.
Oh, so, now I need
a babysitter?
It's no reflection on you.
This isn't right, Captain.
It's how it is.
Yeah.
His name's Roger Berry.
I miss one
damn parole hearing,
and the morons Iet him
walk on good behavior.
I see you've met everybody.
Hawk's a real take-charge
kind of guy.
What makes you think
it's Berry?
Fits his signature.
I read up on the first victim.
What've you got on the second?
Scene wiped clean,
except for a contact Iens
on the bathroom floor.
Victim's med records
says she's 20/20.
Roger's got Iousy eyesight.
Where exactly do we
find this Roger?
His PO's got him working
at a flower shop on 32nd.
They sell white roses?
Check it out.
BENSON: Benson. Yeah.
We'II take Roger's apartment.
Okay. That was the Iab
with forensics.
So, go.
EIIiot and I can take
care of ourselves, can't we?
Coffee cups, chocolates,
roses, silverware.
Wasn't able to get anything.
Same nothing
as the first crime scene.
He did use the same
Navy slipknot on both victims.
What about the contact Iens?
Contact Iens.
Whoever Iost it is Iucky
he didn't walk into any walls.
We calibrated the prescription
at 20/150.
Any DNA on it?
No, but we found hair samples
in the drain traps
from both apartments.
They didn't belong
to either victim,
but they matched each other.
The killer.
Good news is the barb
was still attached
to one of them.
If there's enough DNA,
we can run it against
the sample they took
from Roger Berry
when he was paroled.
Now all we have to do
is find him.
See you.
Your partner
always so friendly?
Well, she just
doesn't Iike you.
Wail till she gets to know me.
Here we go.
Hey, Roger,
it's your old buddy, Hawk.
Open up.
Roger. Probably out
walking his dog.
You got a warrant?
Don't need one.
PO's prerogative.
Well, I don't see
a parole officer,
unless that drunk
we stepped over
has got a badge.
He'II be here.
You sure
this is Roger's apartment?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, well, our shrink said
our guy's middle-management.
Oh, he did, did he?
Oh, he did,
and he also said that
he's meticulous.
Meticulous?
Check the bed.
Hospital corners.
"Happy birthday. Love, Mom."
We got a pair
of running shoes.
You think she knew
we were coming?
Well, well, Iookie here.
Guess he didn't have time
to put them in his scrapbook.
Jennifer Walton
and Celia Mitchum.
You're Iate.
Hey, cross-town traffic's
a bitch.
Detective Stabler,
Eddie Tobias, Roger's PO.
How you doing?
Where's our boy?
You were supposed
to be keeping track of him.
He wasn't at work today.
Home was the next best bet.
When he's in trouble,
he usually runs to Mama.
She still in that shotgun
house out in Queens?
Couldn't pry her out
with a crowbar.
The neighbors tried to
when they found out
what her Iittle boy did.
Thanks, Eddie.
CIose the door
on your way out.
(CAR DOOR CLOSING)
You.
That's right, Mrs. Berry.
It's me.
I got nothing to say.
Your boy's at it again.
He raped and killed
two more women.
You're trespassing.
Where is he?
I'm not gonna Iet you
railroad him
Iike you did before.
Roger confessed.
You tricked him.
He didn't know
what he was doing.
He knew exactly
You stole 18 years
of his Iife.
(COUGHING)
Ma'am, he surrenders himself,
he gets a fair shake.
I give you my word.
You're all Iiars!
I find out you're hiding him
again, I'II run you in
for accessory after the fact.
You don't scare me.
It's gonna be a Iot easier
if you give him up now.
Roger keeps running,
he's Iiable to get hurt.
Go to hell!
You trying to kill her?
No. She's tougher
than she Iooks.
Last time, she hid Roger
in her basement
for three weeks,
meanwhile two more women
wound up dead.
Sure as hell
ain't gonna help us now.
You think she would?
Sometimes finesse
goes a Iong way.
Finesse is for fairies.
Look, I don't care
how many strings
you pulled to get here,
but you're working my case.
My case.
So, from now on,
we do it my way,
you got that?
You hungry?
What?
Roger used to eat
at this restaurant every day
about the same time.
Thought we'd grab a bite.
You hear me?
Yeah.
But if I don't get something
in my gut before Iong,
I'm gonna pass out.
You drive.
(CAR DOOR CLOSING)
Oh, yeah. Roger.
He started coming in
a few months back.
Orders the same dinner.
Cheeseburger and a root beer.
Takes it to
his favorite table.
STABLER: Yeah, he's got
a standing reservation?
Well, you know,
he's a Iittle off.
It's gotta be that table
or nothing. He'II wait an hour
for people to Ieave.
So, I put a Iittle sign up,
save him the trouble.
How are the cheeseburgers,
still the same?
Big and greasy.
HAWKINS: I'II take two.
One for me
and one for my partner.
My treat.
To drink?
Double bourbon. Neat.
Beer. A bottle of domestic.
We'II have our burgers,
nail our perp and be home
for the 11:00 news.
You're awfully cocky
for someone who's been
striking out all day.
Well, Roger's a creature
of habit. He'II be here.
Whatever you say.
You wanna talk about
that bug up your ass
or just Iet it fester?
I just don't Iike
grandstanders.
I thought you were gonna
say grandfathers.
That was a tough one to Iose.
That jury sent him home
to rape that kid
all over again.
You make your case?
I had him nailed.
Then you did your job.
Well, that's not good
enough anymore.
Well, it has to be,
because that's all there is.
I told that Iittle girl
everything was gonna be okay.
And I told the parents
of Roger's victims
he'd rot in prison.
Well,
at Ieast you put him
away for 18.
Yeah, well, at Ieast
you gave that Iittle girl
a few days' peace.
We never win this war, EIIiot.
(SIGHING)
Just so tired of Iosing.
Then what're you gonna do?
Huh?
Quit?
I don't know.
AII that's required for evil
to triumph is for good men
to do nothing.
Here's to a few good men.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Stabler. Yeah, John.
STABLER: Really?
Well, we'II Iet you know
if he shows up here.
Wasn't a total bust
at the flower shop.
The owner told Munch
that Roger made deliveries
to Jennifer Walton's
apartment building a week
before she was murdered.
That's the way
he accessed his victims
Iast time around.
He also said that
Roger got fired
for threatening a customer.
Our boy's Iate.
Sometimes he gets caught up
watching the boats.
Yeah, where?
Pier 41.
Damn.
Hey, who's gonna pay for this?
Roger?
It's me, Hawk.
Turn around real slow,
and we'II handle this
Iike men, all right?
Stay away from me.
Can't do that, Roger.
I won't go back there.
That's not an option, Roger.
No.
Roger.
I won't.
No.
(GRUNTING)
Come on, Roger.
No, I won't go back!
Get up.
No!
Damn it, Roger.
(GRUNTING)
Hold still.
(ROGER GASPING)
Your collar.
Roger Berry,
you're under arrest for
the murders of Jennifer Walton
and Celia Mitchum.
No.
You have the right
to remain silent.
No.
If you give up that right,
anything you say can...
We almost Iost you, there,
Roger.
I don't want to talk to you.
I don't really want to
talk to you, either,
but we've got some Ioose ends
we gotta tie up.
Where were you
night before Iast?
It was my birthday.
I was with my mother.
AII night?
After we ate cake,
I went home.
What time?
Lights out by 10:00.
You stop by Celia Mitchum's
on the way home?
Who's that?
That's that nice Iady
you brought flowers to
day before yesterday.
I bring flowers
to Iots of nice Iadies.
Yeah, but this one
you killed, Roger.
No.
(CLEARS THROAT)
What about Jennifer Walton?
I didn't kill anybody.
Then why'd you cut their
stories out of the paper?
See here?
My mom gave me those.
She said, "Be careful."
You was gonna try
to put me back in jail.
Roger, you're not going back
if you didn't do it.
You Iie just Iike he Iied.
Here we go.
You said
if I signed that paper,
I could go home.
We don't send murderers home,
we send them to prison.
Now, admit it, Roger,
you took those girls flowers.
No.
You pretended to be
their friend...
No. No.
...and then you raped them
and killed them.
No!
(SOBBING)
I want my mom.
Your mama can't help you now,
boy.
Hawk.
You're going back to jail,
and this time
I'm gonna see to it
they strap you down
and put a needle in your arm.
No.
I saved your sorry ass
so you can die my way.
My way!
Hawk.
STABLER: Stay here.
I want my mom.
Cut him Ioose?
BENSON: The DNA's not back.
We've got nothing
to hold him on.
It's Roger's signature.
It's the killer's signature.
Meaning what?
The guy's
borderline retarded.
You think he's capable?
Roger's smarter
than you think he is.
You give me some time
alone with him,
and I'II have him singing
a different tune by Iunch.
Nobody's talking
to Roger alone.
His mother reached out
to Legal Aid.
He's Iawyered up.
And with no DNA,
we've got no grounds
for arrest.
Well, while you all sit around
with your thumb up your ass,
I'II take Roger's mug
out to recanvas.
You remember, police work.
It's hard to make
a case for a copycat
when the signature wasn't
released to the press.
There is another explanation.
Roger Berry's not
the SoHo Strangler.
Hit the archives,
take a fresh Iook at
the old strangler files.
If this strangler's been
out there all this time,
he must have Ieft a scent.
Hawk would never admit that
he's wrong, especially if
he hears it from a woman.
He's old-school.
He's a drunk.
I talked to a cop
at Manhattan South.
They said that nobody
will ride with him.
Well, maybe they don't
have the guts.
Well, maybe they just
want to stay alive.
Maybe they should shut up
and do their...
I'm just telling you
to watch your back.
Sorry, Detectives,
the files already
been checked out.
Under what name?
Detective John Hawkins,
Manhattan South Homicide.
Son of a bitch,
he's covering his ass.
Wait a minute. I'II handle it.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
ROGER ON TAPE:
I didn't mean,,,
John, it's EIIiot.
You in there?
HAWKINS ON TAPE:
You just wanted her
to stop screaming,
I didn't want her
to scream,
You tied her up,
grabbed her by the throat,
I don't,,,
HAWKINS: It's open.
Damn it, Roger,
Stop screwing around,
I want the truth,
If I say it,
can I go home?
Tell me what happened,
Okay,
Okay, what?
I grabbed her,
You raped her,
I raped her,
Then you put the flower
on her pillow and left,
I gave her the flower
and left,
You left her dead,
Dead,
Just spending some quality
time with my old friend,
the SoHo Strangler.
You and Roger?
Found a neighbor
that alibied him.
Puts Roger at home
when Jenny and Celia
were killed.
I don't need any DNA
to tell me the rest.
We'II get the guy.
You know, when I first caught
this case, I had my shield
only for one year.
Wanted to show everybody
what a kick-ass cop I was.
Six murders Iater,
I'm still drawing blanks.
So, as usual,
the media's up our ass,
talking about taking me off.
Then we catch a break.
A neighbor sees
a flower delivery man Ieaving
Larissa Cutler's apartment.
I go down to the flower shop,
search his truck,
strike the mother Iode.
Women's underwear, porno,
the same kind of rope
used to tie their hands.
You made your case.
Not without a confession.
I wanted that so bad.
I put Roger in the box
and I grilled him
over and over and over,
till I convinced myself
he'd been
in those apartments.
I fed him every detail
of the case.
And then I told him that
if he signed that confession,
he'd go home to his mother.
Poor dumb son of a bitch
believed me.
You have a chance
to make this right.
I took 18 years
from an innocent man.
God knows how many women
died because of it.
You can't make something
Iike that right.
Okay, so,
what are you gonna do?
Quit?
You wanna drink yourself
to death? I can't stop you.
But what are you
gonna tell the parents
of those girls?
You made a promise to them.
If you're the man
that I think you are,
you'II keep it.
Hawk.
Hawk!
You don't have to shout.
I think I found something.
Believe me,
I've been over that stuff
till my eyes bled out.
If there was anything to find,
I'd have found it.
Arthur BIessard?
Huh?
Do you remember a guy
named Arthur BIessard?
Yeah.
He's one of the neighbors
that ID'd Roger.
Ann Chilsen's date book
three weeks before
she was murdered.
She had an appointment
with her tax man. "AB."
I'II be damned. Come on.
It's a Iong shot.
Everything's a Iong shot
till you connect the Iast dot.
What are we Iooking for?
These are my notes
on the strangler case.
I used to sketch faces
to keep the interviews
straight in my head.
Son of a bitch.
Who's this?
Artie BIessard.
Guy was blind as a bat.
Like the guy who Ieft
his contact on Celia Mitchum's
bathroom floor.
The Iast dot.
We traced the MO
from the 1983 strangulations
to the current murders.
VICAP came back
with 12 more hits
from five different cities.
Arthur BIessard's
employment history
puts him in the vicinity
of seven of those murders.
They show the evolution
of Arthur's MO over time.
We're still contacting
Iocal PDs, but all we can
come up with is
Chicago is where he began
to mutilate his victims
to hide the bite marks.
And he started slitting
throats in Atlanta.
BENSON: In every case,
the signature matches.
So, where is this
Arthur BIessard now?
Well, he quit his job
at some storefront tax outfit
in Hartford Iast month.
Hawk is out checking
with the Feds,
see if they have any info
on subsequent employment.
AIready done.
Where?
26 Federal PIaza.
The bastard's working
for the IRS.
His desk is right over here
in the corner.
Where the hell is he?
Probably out in the field.
He's one of
our busiest auditors.
Oh, really?
Excuse me.
What?
Hey.
Hey, what are you doing?
Don't you need
a search warrant?
Got it covered.
HAWKINS: Here we go.
Jennifer Walton.
Celia Mitchum.
He's using their tax return
as a dating service.
Employment, marital status,
home address. He's even got
their photos from the DMV.
Got an appointment book.
Beverly Parsons.
34 1/2 West 23rd Street.
5:00 p.m.
It's 4:45.
HAWKINS: This is it.
(GLASS SHATTERING)
STABLER: Police! Don't move.
Oh, my God!
Hi, Artie. Remember me?
Spread your Iegs.
What is this?
Arthur BIessard,
you're under arrest
for the murders
of Jennifer Walton
and Celia Mitchum.
Murder?
Did he hurt you?
No, I cut myself
when I dropped the vase.
Artie was helping me
clean it up.
Yeah, Artie's a real neat guy.
And a hopeless romantic.
Since when is it a crime
to bring a Iady flowers?
You got a date
with me now, boy.
BEVERLY:
Artie first contacted me
a week ago
about irregularities
on my tax return.
I'd just moved here
from Ithaca
and couldn't afford
to fly in my accountant,
but he said that was okay.
He thought the discrepancies
could be cleared up
without much trouble.
And then,
so, you met with him?
At his office.
He seemed really nice.
He'd found more problems
with my return,
and when he saw
how nervous that made me,
he offered to take me
to Iunch.
I felt sorry for her.
You know,
audits can be nerve-racking.
But when you're in a new city
and no family or friends,
it can be
downright terrifying.
You give that kind of
personal attention
to all your audits?
We're not all
soulless bureaucrats,
Detective.
He called me at the hospital,
I'm a pedes nurse,
and said he'd accidentally
double-booked.
He apologized and insisted
on making it up to me
by taking me to dinner.
Dinner was her idea.
Well, aren't there...rules
against fraternizing?
Her audit
was winding down,
and she seemed Iike
a nice enough girl.
So, I said, "What the heck?"
That's when things
got weird.
He started asking me
a Iot of questions
about my personal Iife,
and then tonight he showed up
at my apartment with flowers.
I shouldn't have Iet him in,
but I thought
I could Iet him down gently
without screwing up my taxes.
So, why'd you come back,
Artie? Temptation too great?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Come on.
Roger Berry.
I put him away
for what you did.
His parole gave you
carte blanche
to murder again.
You knew he'd be
the prime suspect.
This time we've got
DNA evidence, Artie.
You know
what that means, Artie?
It means we've got you.
This is crazy.
You know what's crazy, Artie?
Sitting in your 8x10 cell
eating your Iast meal.
Or walking down the hallways
to that Iittle room
with the gurney.
Are you trying to
make me confess?
You want to save your ass,
don't you, Artie?
I'm not going to Iie.
We can tie you
to both victims.
I did their taxes.
In their bedrooms?
That would be
a breach of ethics.
Keep it up, Artie.
Keep it up,
and I swear to God,
I'II put your head
through that wall.
I'II be sure and tell that
to my Iawyer.
STABLER:
I didn't say anything.
We searched Artie's apartment
and found a Iens case
with a single contact.
AIso found a receipt
from Jean's FIowers.
The same flower shop
where Roger works.
It's obvious
he was setting Roger up.
Any Iuck with Artie?
He Iawyered up.
Can we hold him?
Unfortunately,
we have nothing
to hold him on.
What about the flowers
and the contact?
Circumstantial.
Well, what about the DNA
from the hair?
He will argue
he was an invited guest.
That's a stretch,
isn't it?
CABOT:
He had Iegitimate business
with both victims,
just as he did with Beverly.
Circumstantial or not,
we've made cases on Iess.
This time we have to contend
with history. Roger Berry,
SoHo Strangler.
Roger didn't do it.
His convictions are a matter
of public record,
which provides
a very compelling argument
for reasonable doubt.
He had access, opportunity,
and according
to his arrest file,
the same signature.
So, Artie just walks?
If we take this to trial
and he's acquitted,
he gets a Iifetime pass.
So, unless we can tie him
more definitively
to these murders,
the answer is yes.
Wait a minute.
What about the old murders?
Artie wasn't
as experienced back then
or nearly as neat.
You thinking he might have
Ieft a deposit?
It's 18 years ago,
but those evidence boxes
are still at Pearson PIace.
VARGAS:
We went over everything
with a fine-tooth comb.
The rope, Iingerie,
fingerprint slides,
all useless.
What about the bite marks?
Only subcutaneous bruising
of petechiae. Nothing we could
match to a suspect.
There's gotta be something.
We took a closer Iook
at this bed sheet.
It belongs
to the first victim,
Marcia Johnston.
The bookstore clerk.
VARGAS: Correct.
According to the inventory,
a mixture of blood and semen
was typed from this spot.
We were able to extract
enough DNA to run a panel.
The only problem is,
is the sample is mixed.
Meaning what?
Meaning we need DNA
from both the suspect
and the victim
to make an accurate analysis.
But the victim's been dead
and buried for 18 years.
Unbury her.
No. I won't allow it.
Let Marcia rest in peace.
I know how difficult
this must be for you,
Mrs. Johnston, but...
No, you don't.
There isn't a day goes by
I don't think
about my daughter.
There was a time
I couldn't even do that,
because I couldn't bear
the thought about
the horrible way she died.
I finally got to the point
where I could Iook
at her picture
without breaking into tears.
Mrs. Johnston,
I put the wrong man away
for 18 years
for your daughter's murder.
Now I've gotta
carry that burden
along with the deaths
of all the other daughters
since then.
I promise to put
Marcia's killer away.
I can't do it
without your help.
How many others?
Seven that we know of.
If I don't get it
right this time,
there's a man out there
that's gonna keep on killing.
What exactly will you
have to do to her?
We need to extract
a sample of DNA for analysis
from one of her bones.
And there's no other way?
Unfortunately,
Marcia's our Iast hope.
My Iast hope.
(POLICE SIREN WAILING)
BIessard's gonna be
awfully surprised to see us.
I can't wait to see
that son of a bitch's face.
Get the back.
(RATTLING)
Arthur BIessard, open up.
Police.
One, two, three.
(ARTHUR PANTING)
Hawk?
Hawk!
(ARTIE SCREAMS)
Hawk, don't do this.
Don't do what, partner?
STABLER: You know
this isn't right.
We both know
the system sucks.
This way,
it's just natural selection.
(SCREAMING) No! PIease!
STABLER: Hawk, you do this,
you're no better than he is.
He sure as hell
won't kill anybody else.
This is no way to end it.
Come on.
He's an evil man, EIIiot.
And all it takes for evil
to triumph is for good men
to do nothing.
(SCREAMING)
ARTHUR: PIease! No!
You gonna make an old drunk
do all the work?
Give me a hand.
Your collar.
Arthur BIessard, you're
under arrest for the murders
of Marcia Johnston,
Jennifer Walton
and Celia Mitchum.
You have the right
to remain silent.
Anything you say can
and will be used...