NARRATOR: In the criminal
justice system,
sexually based offenses
are considered
especially heinous,
In New York City,
the dedicated detectives
who investigate
these vicious felonies
are members
of an elite squad known
as the Special Victims Unit,
These are their stories,
DOCTOR: Mandibular
and orbital fractures.
BIunt-force trauma
to the back of the head
and Ioss of consciousness.
Five-centimeter
knife Iaceration
below the right clavicle.
He wanted to disfigure her.
And kill her.
DOCTOR: Nearly succeeded, too.
I'm surprised she survived.
Radio car found her outside
a warehouse in Chinatown.
Responding to a burglar alarm.
DOCTOR: Lucky for her.
Yeah, Iucky.
What else?
Distinct fingerprint bruising
above her knees, and these.
Burns,
Iikely from a cigarette.
Maybe abuse,
but it's a strange pattern.
This might interest you.
Maybe a gang member.
BENSON: Rape kit?
PIenty of fluids, all tainted.
Used some kind of
cleaning solution.
Smelled Iike bleach.
She'II be out of it
for a while.
You won't get anything
tonight.
Okay. Thanks.
She's gonna
have plates in her face
for the rest of her Iife.
A Iot of rage.
BIeach. Guy's meticulous.
And confident.
Squad guys took these.
AIIey where they found her,
full view of the street.
So we got a burglary
and a rape in close proximity.
Maybe a dump job.
You believe in coincidences?
According to Robbery,
the perps broke into
the warehouse
and made out with 50 grand
in these, high-speed
computer processors.
Five masked men, they jumped
the janitor and Iocked him
in the utility closet.
This is the only exit.
Leading to our second
crime scene.
STABLER: Victim is Helen Chen,
19. She Iives a few blocks
down on Hester.
This is where the uniform
found her.
Among a whole bunch of
computer parts, probably
dropped on the way out.
Burglary alarm was silent.
By the time the patrol car
got here, she was
the only one here.
You got five guys in
the warehouse. Maybe a sixth
out here to commit the rape.
Or we're talking two crimes.
Either way, robbery perps
had to see her on the way out.
Our best Iead is a possible
gang tattoo on her shoulder.
Women aren't members
of Asian gangs.
They're associates
through a brother
or boyfriend.
They use them
to carry drugs and guns.
Women are Iess Iikely
to get hassled by cops.
Well, so far our only witness
is the victim.
We'II hit the hospital,
see what she has to say.
The body art suggests
she associates
with some of the more unsavory
elements in society.
I got a guy down in
Gang Intel. He's probably
seen every tat in town.
Tattoos, cigarette burns,
all could indicate
Chinese gang activity,
but they signify
different things.
The burns could mean
initiation, number of kills,
punishment.
What's this mean?
Could be Chinese gang.
Define "could be."
Well, a Iot of Chinese gang
tattoos use versions of snakes
or dragons,
but I haven't seen
this one before.
For gang intelligence,
you don't have many answers.
Look, I worked two years
in Chinatown undercover.
I barely scratched
the surface.
You think you'II get somewhere
with a rape investigation?
Chinatown's got no Iove
for cops.
Well, they're just gonna
have to get over that.
What's your take
on the warehouse robbery?
Computer parts heist
does sound Iike Asian gang
activity.
We've been building cases
against several gangs
of high-tech crime.
Same profit margin
as drug trafficking,
nowhere near the jail time.
Only question is,
where does this rape fit in?
A Iot of Asian gangs use rape
as a form of punishment.
Maybe your victim
broke the rules.
Helen, we're trying to
find out who did this to you.
So, when you're able,
we'd Iike to talk to
you about it.
Don't make her cry.
She starts to choke
and they have to snap
her jaw open again.
I told you, she can't talk.
Yeah, but you can, Johnny.
Come here. Come here.
Okay. What was your sister
doing in that alley?
(GRUNTING)
I don't know. Walking home.
What happened to your arm?
I burned it.
Yeah, with a Iaser
to remove a gang tattoo.
I'm not in a group.
So it's just Helen?
She rob the warehouse?
I used to be with a group.
Ghost Shadows.
But I got out a Iong time ago.
What about your sister?
She's still in,
with her yue nan boyfriend.
And what's that?
What's yue nan?
Vietnamese. Dao Tran.
He's the one banging.
Last week, I told him
to stay away from Helen.
Punk said he'd kill me
if I got in between them.
She thinks she can
protect him. Not anymore.
I should've made sure
he stayed away from her
permanently.
Dao Tran's boys
hit that warehouse.
Well, how do you know
if you're out? Maybe it was
one of your old friends.
Try this on. It was your boys
who robbed the warehouse,
and then they rape the sister
of the guy
who turns his back on them.
Ghost Shadows didn't do this.
They know I'd kill anybody
who tried to hurt her.
(HELEN GRUNTING)
So where can we find
this Dao Tran?
Pho Hoa Restaurant on Canal.
AII the Born to Kill boys
hang there.
Born to Kill?
Yeah. From Vietnam War.
It's what the American
soldiers used to write
on their helmets.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
HOSTESS: We closed now.
Come back Iater.
BENSON: Where's Dao Tran?
Not here.
Good afternoon, boys.
Kind of early to be out
of school. What, you all sick?
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Let's take their temperature.
No trouble now.
You're closed, we heard.
Hey, wait.
Hey!
See how messy things can get
when you don't cooperate, Dao?
How's your Iove Iife, Dao?
I hear you and Helen Chen
have been dating.
We broke up.
Why? She doesn't Iike
being burned with cigarettes?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Kind of Iike you don't know
Helen's in the hospital?
What happened?
STABLER:
She was raped and beaten
and Ieft in an alley for dead.
God, no.
Why don't we stop
with the performance, Dao?
I swear. We haven't
seen each other for a week.
We wanted people to think
we weren't together anymore.
People? Like your boys
in Born to Kill?
Now we know
her brother's in a gang.
Maybe your boys didn't Iike
you dating a Chinese girl.
They jumped her
to teach you a Iesson?
No.
Or maybe it had nothing
to do with them.
Johnny Chen said that you're
not good enough for Helen.
He embarrassed you,
made you feel stupid.
But you're not stupid.
You're a smart guy, right?
You raped her
while your friends
robbed the warehouse.
I didn't rape Helen.
I Iove her.
Ghost Shadows
did the warehouse.
BENSON: How do you know?
Helen told me.
She was their Iookout.
I tried to stop her.
Johnny did this.
So you want us to believe
that her own brother
raped her.
He ordered it.
Prove it.
Look, Helen didn't want to
bang with him, but he's got
this control over her.
I mean, you know those
burn marks on her arm?
Well, Johnny made her
do that to herself,
because of me.
Johnny did this.
Okay.
Well, it's still
your word against his.
Ask Helen.
She knows what he can do.
STABLER: Helen,
we can't help you if you're
protecting your brother.
Now, we know he's involved
in your attack.
That's not true.
BENSON: Well,
then tell us what is.
'Cause right now
our best suspect is Dao Tran.
No, it's not Dao. He Ioves me.
STABLER: Well, your brother
made you burn your arm.
You think he cares
what happens to you?
Did you see him?
I don't remember.
I got hit. Passed out.
Johnny must have seen you
when he robbed that warehouse.
He was going to Iet you die
in that alley.
It wasn't him.
STABLER: Well, it may
have been one of his crew.
Helen, tell us where he is.
Come on.
They have a house,
where they keep scores.
Get off me, man. Get off me.
That's our grieving brother
right there.
Look who it is,
Mister Intelligence.
Our friend from Gang Intel.
It's not what it Iooks Iike.
BENSON:
Looks Iike a bust to me.
Thanks to our rape victim.
You knew her tattoo
meant Ghost Shadows
and you Iied about it.
Look, I couldn't tell you.
We had a 15-month
investigation riding on this.
You're talking about
stolen property,
we're talking about a girl
that was brutalized.
Are we going to debate now
about whose job
is more important?
No, we're gonna debate
about you helping
our guy get away with rape.
You're Iooking at Johnny Chen
for this, right?
He knows who raped her.
He's yours. Hey.
With our gratitude.
Thanks.
I didn't do nothing.
I provide for Helen.
I take care of her.
Did you provide for her
to get raped?
No. Never.
Well, robbery places you
at the scene
of her attack there, Johnny.
Do you want to go down
for this?
You want to go down for raping
and beating your own sister?
When we went in, she was okay.
Okay.
And when you came out?
I didn't see her. Thought
she got scared and ran off.
But then...
STABLER: But then what?
I found her.
I thought you said
you didn't see her.
I found her and then she was
so beat up. Nobody was around.
We heard sirens.
Then it got so crazy,
and she Iooked dead.
So you saved your own ass.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
CRAGEN: Detectives?
BIeach man is back.
When?
Half an hour ago in Chinatown.
The victim get a good Iook?
She's dead.
Victim's Asian?
From what I can tell,
it's your guy.
BIeach to clean up, beat her
around the face and head.
He's getting a Iot more
enthusiastic.
But still had the presence
of mind to get rid of his DNA.
Not necessarily.
BENSON: BIood under
the fingernails.
She fought back.
OFFICER: Must've made him
pretty angry.
Imagine carving
someone's body.
I'm gonna guess this slur
points to motive.
He's a racist.
Her name was Lucy Zhang.
She was visiting her mother
in Chinatown.
She cut across the park
to catch the six train
to the Upper East Side.
CRAGEN: Gang connections?
Nothing.
She was a CPA, no record.
The ME thinks that the racial
epithet was cut postmortem
with a straight blade
from a utility knife.
Nothing Iike this M.O.
in our 61s.
We're back where we started.
Then we need a new profile.
The brutality indicates
a tremendous amount of anger
towards Asian women.
Probably was victimized
by Asians at some point.
It took time and effort
to cut up the victim
Iike that.
He's confident enough
to believe he's not
gonna get caught.
Yeah, but he wasn't always.
A search through the past
few years should reveal
smaller acts of aggression.
Peeping, exposure, violence
with consensual partners,
up to outright assaults.
An awful Iot of ground
to cover.
CRAGEN: Maybe not.
I'II call the bias task force.
Have them send over files
on hate crimes
against Asian women.
CRAGEN: Anything?
Just reams of complaints
about racist scum. Haven't
ruled out anybody so far.
Year ago, a peeping Tom
was hitting Chinatown.
Could be our guy, but he was
good at it, ran away
before anybody could see him.
Girl got shoved
on East Broadway
five months ago,
perp threw out a racial slur.
No description,
then he disappeared
into the crowd.
What is this guy, invisible?
Nothing on the blood
from under the victim's nails?
STABLER:
Still waiting on serology.
For someone careful enough
to clean up his evidence
with bleach,
he's careless to Ieave behind
his own blood.
His rage may be escalating.
Still doesn't help us
if he's not in the database.
BENSON:
AII right, Iisten to this.
A woman answered a personal ad
in a Chinese-Ianguage
newspaper.
Guy pulled a utility knife
on the first date. She dropped
the complaint the next day.
Got scared.
Let's go.
Could take hours
to track down a translator.
Doc, can you translate?
What, you just assume
I speak Chinese?
No. I heard you order
take-out once.
Sonja came from China Iast
summer to Iive with her aunt.
She didn't know anyone.
She decided to meet people
through personals
in the China Sun,
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
I wrote him a Ietter.
He wrote back right away.
He said that he was a engineer
from Beijing.
We wrote three or four times
a week. He sounded
as Ionely as I was.
How did they arrange to meet?
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
We were going to have dinner
at a restaurant close by.
But when I arrived,
it was all Iies.
What does that mean, all Iies?
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
She says he wasn't Chinese.
He was black.
How many African-American
males speak and write
Chinese well enough
to fool a native speaker?
Well, he could be a student
or work at the World Bank
or the UN or...
Why Iie about being Chinese?
Because he knows she'II never
go out with him if he's not,
and then he expects
that once they've met,
she'II be so taken with him
that his ethnicity
won't matter. Her reaction to
his race is what sets him off.
The P.O. box he used
was a cash deal. Personal ad
was done over the phone.
He used a stolen credit card.
Let's follow the money.
Sorry, I have a 4:00
at a brokerage house.
I can't believe they're not
online trading yet.
I'm designing their website.
Mr. Tang, how is it
a month went by
before you realized
your credit card was stolen?
Yeah, that sucked.
Well, I was in Paris
and then Bern.
They're dying for HTML
speakers out there,
and I get back and there's
all these random charges.
Do you have any idea
who might have stolen it?
I wish. It was the week
I went out of town.
I was just kind of crazy,
so I guess
I just Ieft it somewhere.
Not too worried about money,
I guess.
Well, the credit card company
was cool.
They didn't make me pay.
Some weird charges, though.
I mean, whoever took it
probably didn't want his wife
to know.
Why? What do you mean?
Well, the guy was definitely
getting some action.
I have the statement
right here.
Look, China Girl, 200 bucks.
Massage parlor in Chinatown.
Where no one actually
gets a massage.
Police.
I'II need to see
a search warrant.
Just calm down.
We're not Vice. We're not INS.
We're Iooking for
one of your customers.
I maintain the strictest
confidentiality policy
with our clients.
That's great.
Now, if you want a raid here,
I can arrange that.
We're Iooking for a man
that came in here
about two weeks ago.
African-American.
He used a credit card
with the name Larry Tang.
Come on, now.
Receipts. Give it up.
No need. I remember this guy.
He tried to kill
one of my girls.
Hey.
STABLER: Sorry to interrupt.
Jiang Li? We'd Iike to
have a word with you.
Can you tell us about the man
who attacked you?
Looked young, Iike 20s.
Nothing special about him.
Came in for a massage.
Didn't Iike it, I guess.
We're not Iooking
to set you up.
Just tell us the truth.
It stays right here.
He said he wanted
a girlfriend.
Don't understand why
the racist son of a bitch
came to Chinatown.
He paid you
to be his girlfriend?
It was fine,
just regular stuff.
Except he couldn't do it.
I don't know,
I guess I Iaughed.
I didn't mean anything.
He got mad.
Tells me he want to tie me up.
Sometimes I do that.
But this guy,
I had a bad feeling.
So I said no.
BENSON: Did he hurt you?
Punched me a couple times.
Pull out this
Iittle army knife.
Call me names.
What did he do with the knife?
Do you think
you could describe him
to a sketch artist?
Faxed the sketch to area
schools with Chinese Ianguage
programs. Zero.
Nothing door-to-door, either.
So what are we missing?
I mean, here's a guy
who immerses himself
into another culture.
Masters the Ianguage,
Iies about his own ethnicity.
Then destroys the very culture
that he's imitated. Why?
He's chosen a culture
that's traditionally insular,
particularly among
the older generation.
I know that if my sister dated
a black man, my parents
would've strongly objected.
So this guy puts himself
in a position to get rejected,
not only as a man,
but as a non-Asian.
It's Iike he wants an excuse
to get mad.
Very possibly.
None of which helps
if we're working off
a bad sketch.
Got a hit on the DNA
from under the victim's nails.
African-American.
Sent up on multiple rape
and homicide. Just released
from CIinton Iast year.
So where is he now?
STABLER:
Where can we find him?
That's Starnes.
BENSON: What's wrong with him?
Progressive MS.
This is a halfway house
for men with disabilities.
He's been pretty bad off
for a few years now.
Mistake at the Iab?
Maybe.
Mr. Starnes,
we're investigating a series
of rapes in Chinatown.
I ain't helping no cops.
But your DNA was all over
one of the victims,
and she's dead.
So maybe you want to help
yourself.
I can't even get out
of this chair, boy.
And if I could, it wouldn't be
to get with no downtown bitch.
You got any brothers,
cousins around?
Someone who might
want to set you up?
Mr. Starnes,
do you have any children?
Never had the pleasure.
You offering?
You've raped a Iot of women.
So it's possible
that you have kids out there
that you don't even
know about, right?
I suppose so, Iady.
PCR typing only Iooked
at 10 genetic markers.
Sometimes a person can have
a close enough match
to score a hit
within the database.
Can you do another test?
I ran a Y-chromosome
on Starnes and the perp.
The Y-chromosome is passed
from father to son
within a family Iine.
Grandfathers, fathers,
brothers, sons, nephews will
have virtually identical Ys.
There's no doubt about it.
These guys
are blood relatives.
Well, Halfway House
and prison records
says that Starnes has
no Iiving male relative.
That we know of.
He's a rapist. Our perp
could be this guy's son.
Makes sense.
Their DNA is similar.
Well, I guess
being a psychopath
runs in the family.
Vital statistics confirm
Starnes was not named on any
birth certificate as a father.
So we're Ieft with
his victims.
Starnes got sent up
on four rapes.
We ran the victims' names.
One came back. Martha Shelby.
Had a child that fits
the timeframe,
no father Iisted.
AII right, Iet's find her.
Now what about victims
they couldn't pin on him?
He Iooked good for three
unsolved rapes in Harlem,
but none of the victims
had a child
within nine months.
AII right, keep Iooking.
What else?
Starnes had a Iive-in
girlfriend that alibied him
on a couple of collars.
Pamela Tatum. She had a baby
while they were
Iiving together.
There's no father
on the birth certificate.
He'd be 23 now.
He's old enough
to be a suspect.
Track him and the mother down.
What's the odds that
both the father and son
turn out to be rapists?
You know,
some geneticists theorize
that violence is inherited.
Oh, that's right.
It's not my fault,
I was just born to kill.
It's a theory.
Well, it's ridiculous.
It's another way for people
not to take responsibility
for their actions.
Let's find the guy first.
We can discuss
the Human Genome Project
Iater.
You all right?
Yeah. Let's go.
Been a Iong time
since anybody's asked me
about Daniel.
I was 17 when I was raped.
Three months Iater,
doctor told me I was pregnant.
I didn't know what to do.
According to the birth
certificate, you kept him.
I didn't think I could handle
an abortion. But in the end
it didn't matter.
What do you mean?
I went into Iabor two months
early. Daniel Iived two hours.
I know this sounds awful,
but in a way Daniel's death
was a relief.
I don't know that I could have
Iived with a constant reminder
of what happened to me.
Thank you for your time.
AII right. So now we go back
Iooking at rapes that Starnes
wasn't connected to.
Unsolved rapes from
20 years ago. It should be
easy enough to crack.
You got a better idea?
Yeah,
Iet's continue to pretend
this isn't bothering you.
EIIiot, knock it off.
You're gonna tell me
what Professor Shelby
said in there,
that's not getting to you?
I'm a child of rape, EIIiot.
I've known that
for a very Iong time,
and I appreciate your concern.
I really do.
But I've dealt with it.
So I'm fine.
How'd I know that bastard
would come back to haunt me?
How'd I know it?
When's the Iast time
you seen Harold Starnes?
Right before he got arrested.
Wised up and threw him out
finally.
How Iong did you
Iive with him?
Let him stay with me
two years,
just after he got evicted
from that dump in FIatbush.
Know how he thanks me?
Rapes and kills my best friend
in my own building.
Where was your son
at that time?
I had Michael about a year
before I kicked Harry out.
He didn't want much to do
with a baby anyway.
Is Harry Michael's father?
Hell, no.
Mind if I ask who is?
That animal is not
Michael's father.
But you were Iiving with him
when Michael was born.
I had a Iot of boyfriends
back in the day,
and if you trying to make me
feel Iike a whore,
forget about it.
We're not trying to do that,
Miss Tatum.
What you want to know
all this for?
MUNCH:
DNA found at a crime scene.
Looks Iike Starnes has a son
who may be following
in his footsteps.
Know anything about it?
You kidding me. No.
Would you account
for your whereabouts
in the past few days?
I was at my girlfriend's in DC
for the Iast two weeks.
Just got back this morning.
AII right. That's enough.
My son is not a rapist.
I want you to Ieave.
Why don't you just
come with us?
Take a few tests, and we can
clear this whole thing up.
That man is not
Michael's father.
But you don't know
for sure, do you?
Get out.
If you're innocent, you don't
have anything to hide.
He fits the profile.
Could we compel a oral swab?
It's worth a shot. Let's see
what Cabot has to say.
Hey.
Man, I didn't hurt anybody.
I swear.
Then take the test.
It's real easy.
Look, I know what Starnes did,
and I don't want to know
if I'm his son.
There's no other way?
Would you be willing
to stand in a Iineup?
Yeah. Tell me when and where.
We need an interpreter
to call in Sonja Yung
for the Iineup.
Cancel it.
Michael Tatum's alibi cleared.
He agreed to do it.
His mother Iived with Starnes
for two years.
No, he's not our guy.
He was seen in DC
when the attacks occurred.
Where are we
on unsolved rapes?
Nowhere. We don't have
a known address
for Starnes before 1977.
Which means he could've
been active anywhere.
We got five boroughs'
worth of cold cases
to wade through.
Not necessarily. Pamela Tatum
said that Starnes Iived
in FIatbush before Harlem.
Police never Iooked at Starnes
for rapes in Brooklyn.
Well, that sounds Iike a place
to start. Get the files.
STABLER: Where's your son now?
I don't know. Sometimes
Darrell doesn't come home.
Thank you.
Mrs. Guan, our records
indicate that you were
a victim of rape in 1977.
Yes.
Did you become pregnant
because of that rape?
Why?
We're investigating attacks
against Asian women
in the area.
Here? That man is here?
The man who attacked you will
spend the rest of his Iife
in a wheelchair.
Was he Darrell's father?
Yes.
I found out I was pregnant,
and I thought maybe something
good could come out
of what happened to me.
Is this your son?
His 21st birthday.
Mrs. Guan,
blood was found
at a murder scene
that may belong to Darrell.
So we need to know
where he is.
Darrell would never...
He's a good boy.
We just want to talk with him.
It's my fault.
I had hoped that because
he was my son,
they would have Ioved him.
BENSON: Who?
My family.
Everyone in Chinatown.
I moved in
with my mother and father
because I had no money.
When they saw him,
they told me to give him away.
He's half-devil, they said.
The children in the
neighborhood would hurt him,
push him, kick him.
Every day he'd cry, beg me
not to make him Ieave
the apartment.
Why didn't you move away?
I guess part of me hated him,
too.
Have you seen anything that
makes you suspect Darrell's
done something wrong?
That photo Iooks nothing
Iike the sketch of Darrell.
Those victims had to have
known he was half-Asian.
Why would they Iie?
Look at this. Thrill Killing:
True Portrayals of America's
Most Vicious Murders,
Hunting Human Beings,
Might explain these.
BIood?
Okay. We gotta get
CSU in here.
Oh, my God.
Where is he?
BENSON: Excuse me,
is Darrell Guan here?
No, he's on deliveries.
Be back in an hour.
We'II need to see those
addresses now.
Won't take me a minute.
Should've known
Darrell was up to something.
Why?
Well, a couple of women
complained.
Kept asking them out.
Are all your customers
in the computer?
Yeah.
May I?
STABLER: Find anything?
Helen Chen and Lucy Zhang's
mother are both in here.
AIong with their
home addresses.
Victim's address
at the touch of a button.
Call for back up.
(BELL RINGING)
Darrell, stop.
Police!
Stop! Police!
Freeze. Police!
Okay. I didn't do anything.
Liv. AII right, we got him.
We got him, we got him.
STABLER: You got it?
What is it?
It's bleach.
Counselor,
I'm glad I ran into you.
Expect an updated witness Iist
on the Guan case
by the end of the week.
You're representing
Darrell Guan?
Little below your usual
tax bracket requirement,
isn't he, Margo?
I'm defending him pro bono.
Looking for headlines.
Looking to save a Iife.
Keep the death penalty
off the table.
Your client
planned his attacks
and tried to cover his crimes.
He intentionally
selected his victims
based on race,
national origin,
ancestry and gender.
That's five
of the nine criteria
under the Hate Crimes Act,
which is an automatic
sentence enhancement.
He's not guilty of murder one.
The victim's blood was found
on Darrell's clothing.
His DNA was found under
one of the victim's nails.
The bottle of bleach used
in both crime scenes
was found in his possession.
What exactly is
your definition of guilt?
Guilt, noun.
From the Middle English
G-I-L-T.
The fact of being responsible
for the commission
of an offense.
Operative word being
"responsible."
Not guilty by reason
of mental disease or defect.
My parents made me
read the dictionary.
Margo Nelson's got
a PhD in molecular biology,
in addition to her Iaw degree.
So what the hell is she doing
defending a rapist?
Trying to set a precedent,
I think.
Look at her witnesses.
A geneticist, a biologist,
a genetic psychologist.
AII for an insanity defense.
Not guilty by reason
of DNA. PIease.
She's trying to get the State
to pay for genetic testing
on Guan and Harold Starnes.
Prove the sins of the father
are visited on the son.
Wait, wait, wait.
The Frye standard
precludes scientific evidence
not generally accepted
by the scientific community.
So file a motion in Iimine.
Just keep it out.
I'm not sure that I can.
Nelson's got science
on her side.
It's a generally accepted
theory that violence
and genes are Iinked.
They're Iinked, not causative.
Do you trust a jury to make
that distinction? I don't.
It's your job to make sure
that they can.
I've got George Huang
doing a psych exam.
Hopefully, he can prove
Darrell knew exactly
what he was doing.
Listen to me,
if Nelson pulls this off,
it's a Pandora's box
for criminal prosecution,
because everything can be
blamed on the confluence
of bad genes.
And then no one
is truly responsible
for their own actions.
That's what I'm afraid of.
Good,
then don't Iet it happen.
Do you know why I'm here,
Darrell?
To see if I'm crazy.
To see if you're competent
to stand trial. Why? Do you
think that you're crazy?
If I say no, I get
the death penalty, right?
Usually the Iawyers Iet me
make the diagnosis,
not the defendant.
But I'm just wondering
what you think.
You're Chinese.
Why, yes, I am.
So am I.
Actually, you're half-Chinese,
aren't you?
You're tow gee,
You think that
I'm the privileged
and spoiled Iandowner?
Isn't that what
the native Chinese call
the American-born Chinese?
But you're American-born
as well, aren't you?
Was it difficult for you
growing up in Chinatown?
No.
You speak the Ianguage
very well.
You know the customs
probably better than I do.
But I imagine for many people
in Chinatown,
you were still an outcast.
Didn't bother me.
The kids probably
picked on you
when you were growing up.
That must have been difficult.
Even your own family
must have treated you
differently.
What do you know
about your father?
Enough.
How old were you
when you found out
that he'd raped your mom?
I don't remember. Young.
My mother's mother told me.
Why did she tell you that?
Haak gwai,
BIack devil.
She called you that?
It doesn't matter.
What about your father?
How do you feel
about your father?
I'm nothing Iike him.
Look at what you've done,
Darrell.
Your whole Iife you've tried
not to be Iike him.
But you're violent.
You hurt people.
You rape them.
Like father, Iike son.
Get out!
MAN: Darrell, calm down.
Take it easy.
Okay, okay, okay.
Gee, okay.
Have you discovered
what some theorists term
the "violence gene"?
Well, there is no
"violence gene" per se,
and violent behavior can be
Iinked to the expression
of several abnormal genes.
For instance?
A defective DRD2 A1 allele
may Iead to pleasure-seeking
or addictive behavior,
as well as violence.
You conducted several
DNA tests on Mr. Guan.
Does he suffer from this
particular gene abnormality?
Yes, he does.
And what about his biological
father, Harold Starnes?
He suffers from
the exact same abnormality.
Mr. Starnes
is a convicted rapist.
Would you say that his son
inherited these violent
tendencies from his father?
Objection. No matter
how much research
Dr. Coffey has done,
he cannot definitively
answer that question.
I agree. Let's try and keep it
out of the realm of science
fiction, Miss Nelson.
Are gene mutations inherited,
Dr. Coffey?
Certainly they can be.
I mean, take for instance
the genetic disease
cystic fibrosis.
Both parents must possess
the recessive gene
and pass it on to the child
in order for the child
to have the illness.
If they don't have the gene,
the child will not get
the illness.
Would a person with cystic
fibrosis have any control
over contracting the disease?
No. He will have inherited
the gene at conception.
And Iike that disease,
if a child inherited genes
that made him violent,
he wouldn't have any control
over that either, correct?
That's correct.
So from a genetic standpoint,
since Harold Starnes
was a violent man,
it's not completely out
of the realm of possibility
that his son was born violent,
as well.
Objection. How did we go from
talking about inherited genes
to inherited behavior?
I apologize.
I'II try to speak slowly
and use smaller words
so you can keep up with us.
RIDENOUR: Counselor.
Dr. Coffey has not
specifically proven
inherited behavior.
Are we just going to
make up new theories
as we go along?
No, I think it's better that
we take the word of an
assistant district attorney
over that
of a scientific expert.
Objection sustained.
Move it along, Miss Nelson.
Nothing further, Your Honor.
Are all people with
a defective DRD2 A1
allele rapists, Dr. Coffey?
Well, the gene defect
predisposes one towards
violent behavior.
That wasn't the question,
I will rephrase it.
If a man has a defect,
is he absolutely
going to be a rapist?
No. Not absolutely.
We know with
the cystic fibrosis gene
if a child inherits the gene
from each of the parents,
he or she will have
the disease.
Is that the case with
the so-called "violent gene"?
Well, a causative connection
has not yet been established.
But aren't you asserting
your research predicts
violent behavior
based on genetic makeup?
No. There are other factors
such as upbringing.
You never mentioned that
in your testimony. It sounded
to me as if you were saying
genes are the only factor
in violent behavior.
Well, I can't very well speak
to the influence
of environment.
I am a geneticist.
I see. So your testimony now
is that violent behavior is,
in fact,
a combination of many factors,
not just genetic.
Yes.
So, in truth, you really can't
speak to the topic
at all, can you?
Objection.
RIDENOUR: Counselor?
Withdrawn. Nothing further.
NELSON: Complex
scientific evidence aside,
this case is about
the choices we make
and the choices
that are made for us.
Did Darrell Guan choose
for his father
to rape his mother,
to be brought up
in a community, in a family,
that every single day berated,
belittled and stigmatized him?
Did he choose to have
a genetic defect?
No.
And now we're supposed to
tell him, "Well, too bad.
You should have known better."
Darrell was born and Iived
in hell. His grandmother
called him the devil.
Well, of course he was.
He was engineered,
by nature and by nurture,
to be exactly
what he turned out to be.
And that is not his fault.
Yes, Darrell Guan
had a difficult Iife.
He was raised knowing
the only reason he exists
is because his mother
was violently raped.
One could understand why
he wouldn't grow up
to be a well-adjusted adult.
But that's not an excuse
for murder.
In a civilized society,
we have to take responsibility
for our actions.
If we start to justify all
antisocial behavior under the
pretense it isn't our fault,
then the entire structure
of the Iaw is meaningless.
In the end, it comes down to
what it is to be
a human being.
We're not just a product
of our genetic programming,
nor are we solely molded
and motivated by
our childhood experiences.
The defense would have you
believe Darrell Guan's Iife
was beyond his control.
But the truth is, he was in
complete control at the time
he committed his crimes.
He specifically
chose his victims,
not because of some
biological imperative,
but because of opportunity.
He knew what he was doing
was wrong,
and he did everything
he could to get away with it.
Darrell Guan chose
the course of his Iife.
Make him take responsibility
for it.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Come in.
BENSON: Hey.
The verdict came in
on the Darrell Guan case.
He's guilty on all charges.
I heard.
That was a tough case for me.
Seems to have been
a tough case for you, as well.
My mother was a rape victim.
She got pregnant. She had me.
So, yeah, it was personal.
I think I'd be Iying
if I didn't admit that that's
probably the biggest reason
that I decided to become
a cop. You know, to join SVU.
I used to think that
it was because I wanted
to do something good,
you know, make a difference.
But you're questioning
those reasons now?
I don't know. You know, I...
I mean, Iook at my job. I'm...
I have to be aggressive,
even violent.
And you think that makes you
Iike Darrell Guan.
Well, Iook at Darrell Guan.
I keep trying to convince
myself that he had a choice.
You know, be a rapist,
don't be a rapist. Be violent,
don't be violent. But...
If he had this aggression
inside him,
even violence, then,
does he have a choice?
Does anyone?
You don't hurt people, OIivia.
You protect them.
You're proof that
we do have a choice.
Or...
Or maybe I'm just Iucky.