NARRATOR: In the criminal
justice system,
sexually based offenses
are considered
especially heinous,
In New York City,
the dedicated detectives
who investigate
these vicious felonies
are members
of an elite squad known
as the Special Victims Unit,
These are their stories,
Damn it to crap, Brody.
We're only a day
behind schedule.
Yeah, well,
I got drywallers starting.
So I suggest you shift
your Iazy ass into high gear.
Catch the hell up.
Maybe you should think twice
before insulting a man
wearing a tool belt.
Yeah, you know,
if you weren't married
to my sister...
What the hell is this?
That wasn't here
when we Ieft.
CONTRACTOR: Son of a bitch.
The Iittle girl's body
was discovered by the general
contractor and a carpenter
at 6:53 a.m.
This our point of entry?
Yeah, one nail holding a piece
of plywood. Didn't take
a Herculean effort.
And they both
handled the sword,
so it's contaminated.
She was killed with a sword?
No stab wounds,
but hematemesis indicates
internal bleeding.
BIunt force trauma.
Bruises, sternum to toe.
With this?
We'II check it
for trace evidence.
Looks Iike it was made here
out of floor scraps.
Is this the victim's braid?
Looks Iike it.
I'd say cut with a knife,
not scissors.
Restraint marks on the wrists
and ankles. Where's the rope?
Didn't find any.
Signs of sexual abuse?
Extensive bruising
and swelling in the pelvic
region. I'II run a kit.
What's her name?
Any idea who killed her?
AII right, guys, please.
That's enough. This way,
ma'am, please. Come on.
I went in to check on my...
I understand.
...my Iittle girl.
But Cassie wasn't
in her bed, and I...
How old is your daughter?
She's five.
She's my foster daughter.
Okay.
Can you describe her for us?
She's black. She got her hair
in Iittle braids.
She's, Iike, 40 pounds.
Why don't you come with me,
okay?
WOMAN:
Excuse me, sir. Pardon me.
Sound Iike we have an ID?
Yeah, it's bad.
Excuse me.
Excuse me, Captain Cragen,
can you give us anything?
We'II have a statement
shortly.
JANE: Oh, my God! No!
Victim is Cassie Adams,
aged five.
She was found beaten to death
at a construction site
across her street.
FIN: Someone snatched her
right out of bed.
Foster mom said they'd
been having problems
with her sleepwalking.
Is there a foster dad?
Everything but.
Foster mom,
foster grandmother,
the victim's two sisters.
I believe the grandmother
has a foster kid of her own.
Full house.
What's this, a sword?
Yeah, with the victim's braid
attached.
Some kind of ritual killing?
Or a gang symbol.
There's a crew on 149th Street
that wears a Sword
of Damascus tat.
Could be the prop
of some whack job.
Or an ex-con.
This is basically
a big old shiv.
Well, Iet's start with known
pedophiles in the area.
Canvass the block.
Let's find out
who had access to that site.
Oh, and check out this
address. It was on the victim.
We ran it, but there's
no phone connected.
Want us to interview
the foster family?
Benson and Stabler
are there right now.
(SWORDS CLANGING ON TV)
ELECTRONIC VOICE: Level 7,
Tanya, now when did you
Iast see Cassie?
When I went to bed.
Okay.
GIenn, honey,
turn that thing down.
WHITLEY: Grandma.
And did you hear anything
Iast night?
No.
(SOBBING)
STABLER: We're good?
Yeah.
Which one was Cassie's bed?
The bottom bunk.
Tanya has the top.
And Whitley's
is three feet away.
AII they know is she was gone
when they woke up.
Well, we'd Iike to take
everyone down to our precinct.
Fewer distractions,
they might remember something.
They have been through
so much. The dad died in jail.
The mom used to drag them out
panhandling.
She'd use them as sympathy.
Mother still in the picture?
No. Supervised visits.
We'd meet her at McDonald's
every two weeks.
It always really upset Cassie
for days after.
When was the Iast visitation?
Day and a half ago.
And it's only the mom
on these visits?
She brought her boyfriend
the Iast time.
Made the girls
very uncomfortable.
FIN: Do you know
a Cassie Adams?
How's that concern you?
Take that as a yes.
Why are you asking
about my daughter?
Child Services
didn't contact you?
About what?
We're very sorry to have to
tell you this, but your
daughter Cassie is dead.
No.
No! God, no! No, no, no!
No! No! No!
Anger management
an issue with her?
At ACS, yeah, man.
She was fighting Iike hell
to get them back.
So having a close friend
snatch one back
isn't out of the question.
You know, girl doesn't want
to go, puts up a struggle.
Accidents happen.
Why you talking to me
Iike I'm a suspect?
Account for your whereabouts
Iast night
and I'II adjust my tone.
I play sax at Harvel's.
I just got Tashandra a job
waitressing there,
and we were both there
until 3:00 this morning.
Tashandra Iives here with you?
Officially,
she's still at the shelter,
but she's spending nights.
Then why was Cassie
carrying this address?
I don't know.
You gotta ask Shandra.
I always wrote down
where I was for her.
It was a comfort.
I need to be with my babies.
They're okay.
They're with the detectives
trying to sort this out.
You know, Cassie's
my middle child, but she was
always the mother hen.
And I don't know
what Whitley and Tanya
are going to do without her.
How Iong have you been apart?
Ten months.
I'II get them back now,
won't I?
It's up to
Children's Services.
But it's their fault.
They stole my kids.
I thought if I had my girls
with me, I could protect them.
You tell them
that I need to protect
the two that I got Ieft.
That's not my call.
You have to take me
to see them.
I'm sorry, I really can't.
PIease.
PIease, don't make me
have to go to them and beg.
PIease.
Liv's upstairs with
the eight-year-old sister,
Wong's got the three-year-old,
and I'm running out of rooms.
I'II put up a "Do Not Disturb"
sign. Talk to the boy
in observation...
You Iousy bitch!
MUNCH: Tashandra...
What did you do to
my daughter? What did you do
to my daughter?
MUNCH: Tashandra, please,
this isn't helping.
How could you Iet this happen?
Calm down, ma'am,
okay, calm down.
No, no, I want to see
my daughters. Whitley! Tanya!
My office here. Let's go.
Here's your juice.
So Tanya, can you tell me
what happened Iast night?
I don't know.
Well, when you went to bed,
who was in the room?
Whitley and Cassie.
Tanya, we know that Cassie
Ieft the room Iast night,
but do you know how?
No.
Hey, GIenn,
tell me about Cassie.
She was always bugging me
to use my PIayStation,
but she was too Iittle.
I wish I had Iet her now.
It must have been hard
for you, all of a sudden
having three sisters.
No.
I Iike being a big brother.
Do you?
You Iook out for them?
I try to.
Did you ever go over
to the construction site?
Yeah.
How about Cassie?
She's not supposed to cross
the street by herself.
She'd ask me to take her.
Why?
She Iikes to talk
to one of the workers.
Did you and Cassie ever go
to the building site
without GIenn?
Mmm-hmm.
And when you guys
would go over there,
who would Cassie talk to?
Danny.
Who's Danny?
He's nice.
The other ones chased us away.
Oh. How is Danny nice?
He gave us gum
and showed us stuff
in the house.
CONTRACTOR:
Gotta be Danny Marston.
MUNCH: You don't mind him
conducting his Fun Time
Learning Emporium
on company time?
Hey, Danny's one of
the hardest workers I got.
Guy that's good with kids
must have a bunch of his own.
Not yet.
But he coaches Little League
and he volunteers
in a bunch of youth programs.
Where's Danny now?
I had to send my whole crew
home after you declared it
a crime scene.
Where's he hang his hardhat?
My secretary can give you
his address.
If he's not at home,
try the Youth Rec Center
on 123rd.
Guy's a saint.
MUNCH: Danny Marston?
Yeah.
Steal a minute
of your time?
Sure.
Hey, keep it going guys.
Little girl was found dead
at your place of work.
We understand that you and her
were buddies.
God, it's tragic.
I mean, she came around
every day.
Budding architect, asking me
hundreds of questions.
See, he wasn't being
inappropriately friendly,
he was schmoozing up
a future boss.
Inappropriate?
Listen, the kid never had
a father figure.
I mean,
most of the kids I work with
are in that situation.
You make toys
for all of them?
I made her a Iittle airplane
out of scrap.
Took all of two seconds.
What?
Where were you Iast night?
Home.
FIN: Can anyone verify that?
No.
Why would they need to?
Maybe we should finish this
down at the squad room.
We're in the middle
of a game here.
You really want to
do this in front of them?
Damage their Iittle psyches?
Andre, take over here.
I am not a pedophile.
And I refuse to stop helping
kids in need just to avoid
being Iabeled one.
I didn't do it.
Tell me how
I prove a negative.
Tell the truth.
You've never seen anyone
at that construction site
after hours?
I never even thought of it
until I started getting
the third degree.
I Ieft my thermos there
Iast week.
When I went back, a couple
of kids had broken in.
Vandals?
No.
Who?
Cassie and an older kid.
Listen, I know it Iooks bad,
but I'm sure
it's just coincidence.
What is?
They both had sticks.
When I went in,
they were sword fighting.
You need to describe
this older kid to us.
A white boy she's always with.
I think his name's GIenn.
Her foster brother?
He had access to the home
and to the crime scene.
And he did fail to mention
that his sister's murder site
was also
their secret playground.
This family is still grieving
the Ioss of one child.
We're gonna need
a hell of a Iot more
before we take away another.
It could be that he had
motive. He was an only child,
a Iittle slow.
Three younger, cuter sisters
move in, attention
gets split four ways.
Fourteen years old,
raging hormones.
Look, before you place
this kid on death row,
Iet's see if we can place him
at the crime scene.
Why do we always
get stuck with Iooking for
the needle in the haystack?
Takes me back to
the Easter-egg hunts
of my youth.
You're Jewish.
Your parents hid eggs?
My point exactly. AII those
futile hours of searching.
Now, if you were still
a bright-eyed Iittle kid, what
would that Iook Iike to you?
A deathtrap.
You're pathetic.
That's the coolest fort ever.
You had a traumatic childhood
too, huh, Sherlock?
Mother Iode. Comic books.
Walkman.
Penknife.
That Iook sharp enough
to cut off a braid of hair?
If it is, you win
the chocolate bunny.
GIenn's been sent
to the Guidance Center
many times.
Fights?
Yeah.
He's a bully?
On the contrary.
He's the one bullied.
This is where he spends
half his day with the other
Special Ed students.
You know,
I've talked to GIenn. He's...
He's borderline.
He's a Iittle slower
than the average student,
a Iittle bigger,
and he won't fight back,
which makes him
a constant target.
That's gotta get to him.
It did once.
He threw a chair
across the room.
It exploded into pieces.
Are you doing anything
to protect
these targeted kids?
GIenn has a rich fantasy Iife
that he retreats to.
Whenever I try to discuss
his problems,
all he'II talk about is
this Camelot-type video game.
Camelot? Like, jousting?
Sword-fighting?
That kind of thing?
Yeah. His teachers have tried
to interest him in books
with similar mythical themes,
but there's something
about this game.
Graphic violence.
Read his case file.
It's nothing new.
GIenn was one of our
saddest cases.
It's a miracle he's adjusted
as well as he has.
Abuse?
While his mother was out
prostituting herself
for drug money,
the boyfriend was at home
molesting GIenn.
Sometimes he'd resort
to objects.
And when did you get him?
Not soon enough.
The abuse started at two.
We got him at four.
If you'd seen the emptiness
in that boy's eyes.
Did he bounce around
for a Iong time?
On that front he was Iucky.
We placed him
with Dorothy Rudd right away.
She's had him ever since.
She ever have any troubles
with him?
Not that I know of.
Women Iike Dorothy
are hard to find.
With a Iot of these kids,
the families have no idea
what they're getting into.
Still, with GIenn's
background,
weren't you at all concerned
about placing three
young girls in the house?
No.
My case worker met with
the boy, and he seemed
very excited about it.
Stainless steel.
Mass-produced.
Swiss Army knock-off.
Standard issue for any boy
over eight. Anything making
this one unique?
Say, maybe some kid carving
his initials in the handle?
Oh, better.
Ten-point gem.
I ran it, but he's not
in the system.
System doesn't
include juvies.
The size and shape
are consistent with a boy
on the Iarge side or a woman.
AIthough given these,
I'd stick with a Ionely,
frustrated adolescent.
An outcast with $4-a-day
cheese puff habit.
You Iift those
from the comic books?
Corner of every page.
The girl didn't die
from a paper cut.
Anything else on the knife?
Just a hair caught
in the fold.
It's the one on the Ieft.
The one on the right's
the victim's.
It's identical.
Which puts Cheese Puff Boy
at the crime scene
the night of the murder.
Now you've just got that
one Iittle hitch.
What's that?
The sword is not
your murder weapon.
But she was hit with it.
See the imperfections
in the wood?
With this Ievel of impact,
it would have picked up fiber
or soft tissue evidence.
Maybe he wiped it clean.
Pattern doesn't match.
BIeeds spread their mass out
differently depending
on the weapon.
These came from something
perfectly cylindrical
with no rough edges.
Broomstick?
Baseball bat? What?
Heavier than a broomstick,
narrower than a bat.
There was a pile of copper
piping at the crime scene.
Maybe.
Whatever it was, it was hefty
enough to cause these.
Subcutaneous bruises,
multiple fractures,
metacarpals, tibia, humerus.
STABLER: What killed her?
BIed out from a Iacerated
Iiver. A slow death.
Rape kit results in yet?
There were no fluids.
I found no evidence
of penetration.
I thought you said you did.
I said there was swelling.
It was from the beating.
Anything else?
Look at the different hues
from the trauma.
The most recent are
erythematous with welts.
The purplish areas with
extravasation were already
forming hematomas.
Meaning that she was beaten
over an extended period
of time.
At Ieast 1 2 hours.
Did you notice any bruises
on Cassie
when you put her to bed?
No. But she was...
Neither of us put her to bed.
She was already asleep
when we got home.
You were out?
Just for a few hours, yeah.
Where were you?
Delia Nathan's,
right up the street.
We play cards every Tuesday.
Why didn't
you mention this before?
Because it was a Iot earlier
in the evening.
We checked in on her
when we got home.
BENSON: Who was babysitting?
GIenn.
No, he didn't do
anything wrong.
She was tucked soundly in bed.
GIenn ever play rough
with the girls?
Well, he Iiked to wrestle.
He's big for his age,
and sometimes he didn't know
his own strength.
He did. He did play rough
with them sometimes.
We're going to need to
speak with GIenn.
GIenn?
GIenn, honey, please...
GLENN: Just a minute.
ELECTRONIC VOICE:
Kill the Gorgon
or the princess shall die,
Hi, GIenn.
What are you playing?
GLENN: Come on, come on.
One more Ievel.
DOROTHY: GIenn, stop.
This is serious.
They need to talk to you now.
EIIiot.
Right down to the braid
of hair.
GIenn, we found your sword.
The one that you Ieft
with Cassie.
STABLER:
Okay, what's a Gorgon?
Gonna be okay, GIenn.
Can you tell us what happened
that night?
(MUMBLING)
Got to help her...
Save Cassie...
Were you watching the girls?
Cassie. Cassie. Cassie.
BENSON: GIenn.
GIenn, do you know
how Cassie got hurt?
STABLER:
Were you playing games?
Gorgon. Gorgon killed her.
PIease,
I know he didn't mean to.
It had to be an accident.
Mrs. Rudd...
Tell them, GIenn.
Tell them it was an accident.
(SHOUTING)
It was...
It's those video games.
DOROTHY: Stop it.
You're hurting yourself.
(SCREAMING)
BENSON: GIenn.
DOROTHY: You're hurting him!
You're hurting him!
How's GIenn doing?
Psych unit at Hillview.
You read the report?
Yeah. Agitation, aggression,
paranoid delusions.
Your boy had
a psychotic break.
AImost took our
two-way with him.
His mind didn't short-circuit
for no reason. He's clearly
under tremendous pressure.
Guilty conscience?
Need to confess
versus self-preservation.
That'II make you crazy.
MUNCH: Damn it!
ELECTRONIC VOICE:
You have lost,
Pathetic. Give me that.
Show you how to do this.
Maybe we should rethink
the squad room video arcade.
GIenn retreated
into that game.
Well, considering what he went
through his first four years
of Iife, who wouldn't?
Not to mention the physical
and emotional abuse
he's taken at school.
Let's just make this case.
The Super Mario Brothers
up there can re-canvass.
You two, go visit the boy.
BENSON: Mrs. Rudd.
What are you doing here?
We need to see GIenn.
No, you don't.
You stay away from him.
That's okay. You know what?
Why don't we sit down?
Tried to get him a snack.
Stuck.
It's his favorite.
How's GIenn holding up?
I've never seen him Iike this.
GIenn is...
He's a sick boy.
And if we do this right,
we can make sure wherever
he goes, he gets help.
Maybe I was too old
when I took him in.
I thought I was up to it.
But I was being selfish.
It's just...
I Iove having kids around.
Mrs. Rudd, you do understand
that we need to talk to GIenn.
Doesn't he have any rights?
Yes, he does,
but he's a juvenile.
You can waive Miranda for him.
I don't know.
The Iast time you questioned
him, he was so upset, I...
No, I think I should
talk to a Iawyer.
Mrs. Rudd...
No, I can stand.
I don't need any help.
ELECTRONIC VOICE:
Level Thirteen,
(ELECTRONIC VOICE SPEAKING)
Game's over. Looks Iike
Dorothy's going to Iawyer up
the kid.
How Iong have you been
playing that game?
Your Captain's
found his calling.
He made it to the final Ievel.
I defeated the Gorgon,
freed the forest
from evil demons,
and rescued the dying princess
from her dungeon.
Princess? Nice.
Oh, wait till you hear
how he Iifted the spell
she was under.
A sword
and a Iock of her hair.
It gets better.
I carried her
to the secret cave,
I tied the hair to the sword
and placed it at the entrance.
She's as good as new.
So if we follow the game,
then GIenn killed Cassie
and then tried to save her?
Killer's remorse?
What doesn't track is GIenn
identified with the boy hero,
not the Gorgon.
Wait, what exactly
is a Gorgon?
Are you familiar with Medusa?
GIenn's monster's a woman.
MUNCH: Captain!
That was Jane Rudd.
Guess who just
snatched her two other girls?
I was in the kitchen
when Tanya got in from school,
and she comes in and she says,
"Oh, Whitley,
it's time to go."
And I said,
"Hey, go where, honey?"
And that's when I saw them
standing in the doorway...
Are you talking about
Tashandra and her boyfriend?
His name was Duke.
I don't remember
his Iast name.
That's okay, we do. Why don't
you have a seat, Jane?
We already have people
covering their home
and their work.
We've given out their
descriptions to every bus
and train station.
Don't worry about it.
We're gonna find them.
Did they say anything
that might tell us
where they were heading?
AII she did was curse at me.
God, I wish my mother
had been here!
They do this?
Oh, God.
BENSON: Did they hurt you?
Oh, God. Oh, God. Oh, my God.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
(JANE WHIMPERING)
Benson.
Great. We're on our way.
Ticket agent at Port Authority
recognized the girls.
They Ieft two minutes ago
on a bus to Atlanta.
JANE: I'm sorry.
(POLICE SIREN WAILING)
Everyone remain seated.
We'II have you on your way
in a minute.
In the back on your right.
Sir, come with me, please.
I'm sorry, babe.
Come on.
Tashandra...
PIease just Iet us go.
Just Iet us go, and I won't be
any more trouble to you,
I promise.
You know that's not
the way it works.
You can say
you didn't find us.
I understand that you just
want your kids back, but this
is not the way to do it.
Trust me,
this needs to end now.
Let's go.
Cassie was murdered.
Did you just expect me to
sit by and Iet the same thing
happen to my other two?
STABLER: That doesn't mitigate
what you did.
Trespassing, assault,
kidnapping.
BENSON: Minimum,
you're Iooking at
custodial interference.
That's a felony.
I didn't have a choice.
They were in danger. I had to
get them out of there.
That woman murdered
my daughter.
Mrs. Adams, I understand
that you're under
a Iot of pressure.
Tanya told me.
What did she tell you?
Not a Iot.
But that's only because
that woman had her too scared.
She finally Iet on that Cassie
got beaten all the time.
By whom?
Momma Rudd.
We put them back with Jane.
May we see the file?
You know, there are over
500,000 kids in foster care.
It's not easy trying to find
a place for all of them.
Do you realize that a serious
allegation has been made
against her?
By Tashandra Adams.
It's about the only thing
she hasn't tried.
STABLER: What's this Ietter
from the BIuebell Agency?
That was a reference check.
Jane had two foster kids
before the Adams girls.
This other agency removed
them. Two months Iater,
she came here.
Why were they removed?
Seems Jane "experienced
difficulty understanding
her role as a foster parent."
What does that mean?
The children were found
with soiled clothes.
Jane missed appointments
with her case worker.
But she was new.
But the Ietter goes on to say,
"We recommend that no more
children be placed with her."
You felt comfortable
placing three Iittle girls
with this woman?
We had her take
a parenting seminar.
A seminar?
And she moved back
in with her mother.
That was a provision.
Dorothy Rudd
has a Iong history with us.
Still, it was Jane's care
that you put them in.
Believe me,
if the BIuebell Agency
had sensed any real danger,
they would have taken steps
to have her decertified.
GRANT: We worded that Ietter
very carefully.
Phones call out, too. Did you
ever think of reporting Jane
to the state hotline?
The violations we had evidence
of weren't that extreme.
The woman's a hopper.
A what?
The city contracts out to 73
private foster care agencies.
We're not interlinked.
When we turned her down,
she had 72 more chances.
And you're sure she's unfit?
Yeah, I've been
in this business 20 years.
I interviewed Jane personally.
The woman's not stable.
CABOT: We can't go after Jane
based on a case worker's
bad feeling.
We have Tanya's
revised statement.
Obtained after Tashandra
took them.
They're tainted.
It'II never hold up.
We haven't talked to
Dorothy yet.
If she turned a blind eye
to the abuse,
then she'II protect
the daughter
over the foster son.
Then we gotta get to GIenn
now, before she gets
a Iawyer. AIex?
There is king for a day.
What, another video game?
It's where we get
a Iaw guardian appointed
who will play ball.
He'II Iet us talk to GIenn,
provided everything the boy
says is off the record.
And any Iaw guardian
will do this?
It might take a Iittle
sweet-talking.
CRAGEN: Hey, GIenn.
You know why I'm here?
I heard you were the guy
to see about video games.
You ever play Swordquest?
That's my game.
Mine, too.
I made it to Ievel 13.
Bagged myself a Gorgon.
I hate the Gorgon.
Is that who took Cassie
to the cave that night?
No.
It was me.
Why?
To protect her.
Who was hurting her?
GIenn.
It's my job to help kids
who have problems
with Gorgons.
You have one in real Iife,
don't you?
Who is it?
You don't have to worry.
Remember? I'm a Ievel 13er.
She'II never get past me.
What is it, GIenn?
The Gorgon.
What's going on here?
I had no idea what a horrible
influence that video game was.
FIN: Actually,
it's very educational.
The monster in it is based on
Greek mythology.
A Gorgon, one of three sister
monsters with snakes for hair
and the ability to turn anyone
that Iooks at them into stone.
Stones can't talk.
Why would GIenn
call you a Gorgon?
His imagination.
If I'm guilty of anything,
it's of being too protective
of my children.
Come again?
I know I should have
turned GIenn in
when he first told me.
But he's my son.
You're a good mother.
But if you want to help
your son,
we have to know
the circumstances
that Ied up to it.
You have to understand,
GIenn Iives in a world
of his own creation.
FIN: In his mind,
he was rescuing Cassie.
Yes.
MUNCH: From what?
What was going on with Cassie
that he felt
she needed rescuing?
Cassie is prone to violent
tantrums. She'd been
out of control for two days.
Since seeing
her biological mom.
When she came back
she was saying
horrible things.
I couldn't get her to sleep.
When I finally did,
she wet the bed.
Next day, more tantrums.
With hypertension, that kind
of stress can't be good
for your blood pressure.
I've taken in 12 children
over the Iast years.
They all come damaged. Starved
for Iove and discipline.
You had to discipline Cassie.
We can understand that.
I had to send her
to the "time out" chair.
MUNCH: Did you hit her?
I spanked her.
With what?
My hand.
But poor GIenn
always wanted to rescue
a damsel in distress.
He was, from being beaten
to death.
It was GIenn who killed her.
He must have really knocked
her around when he moved her
over to that house.
That's what killed her.
The thing is, Cassie had
rope burns on her wrists
and ankles.
GIenn didn't tie her up.
No.
That was Jane.
BENSON: Thirteen broken bones.
We know about
the "time out" chair.
I told her to be good
or something bad would happen.
I told her.
STABLER: She just wouldn't
Iisten.
No, she was so headstrong.
She was always talking back.
She wouldn't do
as she was told.
And, oh,
the incessant questions,
it'd get to anybody.
So you tied her up.
She couldn't even
fend off the blows.
AII Cassie had to do
was be a good girl.
Is that too much to ask?
Like you were
when you were Iittle?
STABLER: What happened
when you weren't a good girl?
She used to do the same things
to you, didn't she?
Well, she wants the perfect
child, obedient and grateful.
She won't accept
anything Iess.
Jane, it's still not enough.
She tried to pin
this whole thing on you.
No, she didn't.
BENSON:
Oh, Jane, yes, she did.
We have a signed statement
saying you were the one
that tied Cassie up.
My mother made me tie her up.
Jane.
I never hit her, never.
Not once, ever.
But you knew
what was gonna happen.
How could you bring children
into that house?
I didn't want to.
I didn't want kids.
BENSON: Your mother
made you do that, too?
No, she wanted to be
a grandmother.
So you took in foster
grandbabies for her to abuse.
Jane, what happened to Cassie?
Cassie always fought her.
Told her she hated her,
told her that
she was gonna tell.
She said the beatings
were not gonna
keep her quiet anymore.
So my mother
beat her
all day Iong.
She used her cane, didn't she?
Counselor,
I got some more ammunition
for you on the Rudd case.
Warner says Dorothy's cane
matches the wound patterns,
and we found the rope
in the apartment.
Good. Jane just cut a deal.
Well, not too cherry,
I hope.
Five to ten,
conditional on her testimony
against her mother.
She's an accessory,
so her testimony needs
to be corroborated.
Well, you got GIenn.
Who's currently
in a psych ward.
Did you guys have any Iuck
tracking down
other foster kids?
Benson and Stabler did
find one. Definitely abused.
He can't face Dorothy.
Well, that's one down.
Dorothy's had a dozen
over the years.
Who have scattered to
the four corners of the earth.
Once they turn 18,
the system doesn't
want to know from them.
Good night.
Hey, honest opinion.
Can I put GIenn on the stand?
Well, I talked to his doctors.
He doesn't have any organic
mental illness, but I don't
think he's strong enough.
What if I prep the hell
out of him?
Unless you get this kid where
he feels completely safe,
you'II be putting him
at further risk.
That's where the judge
will be?
Yeah.
You want to try it out?
Now, the courtroom
will be full of people
supporting you.
There'II be your Iaw guardian,
and your friend,
Captain Cragen,
and I will be at that chair
right there.
Will my mom be here?
Dorothy will be at that table
right there,
but she can't talk to you
and she can't touch you.
Are you sure?
Do you remember
what the Court Officers do?
Keep everybody safe.
Now, the other attorney
is allowed to ask you
questions,
but you just have to answer
them honestly, okay?
Okay.
You know, GIenn,
if this is too much for you
or you decide you don't want
to do it, you don't have to.
You understand?
But it's to help Cassie,
right?
Yeah.
Then I want to do it.
When did your mom put Cassie
in the yellow chair?
Early in the morning.
And why that chair
in particular?
It's for punishment.
What had Cassie done wrong?
GIenn, what had Cassie
done wrong?
She peed in her bed.
What was her punishment?
She had to drink
Iots and Iots of water.
Until?
She wet her pants.
Was that the end
of her punishment?
No.
What happened next?
She was begging for help.
I needed to save her.
She was...
GIenn, just take your time.
I needed to help her.
Cassie was hurt.
Your Honor, I object to the
blatant ongoing intimidation
tactics by the defendant.
I didn't do anything.
Liar!
You beat her.
You beat her the whole day.
I took you in when no one
else wanted you!
Cassie was crying,
and you kept hitting her.
She tried to run away
and you made Aunt Jane
tie her down.
She was so Iittle.
You were supposed
to protect her.
But you beat her
with the cane all day.
You killed her.
Who died?
Dorothy Rudd.
PIease tell me you're kidding.
Just got a call from Rikers,
massive heart attack.
Bitch didn't even suffer.
CRAGEN:
Anybody else feel cheated?
Prosecution abated by death.
It sucks.
That's it. No vindication,
nobody pays.
Jane'II do a couple of years.
SIap on the wrist.
Her deal is done.
What about the foster agency?
They signed Cassie's
death warrant the day
they placed her there.
No Iaws on the books
will Iet me prosecute them
even if they knew
the house was unsafe.
Tashandra Adams knew.
And you know
what bites the most?
She still doesn't have
her kids back.
Of course reunification
is our objective.
But she hasn't
met the criteria
of her discharge plan yet.
I checked. A Family Court
judge ruled that these kids
could be paroled to Tashandra
as soon as she obtained
appropriate housing.
Which she has not done yet.
Part of your obligation
is to help her do that.
I know what my job is.
And I know mine.
Enforcing criminal sanctions
against agencies Iike yours
that knowingly place
their wards in unsafe homes.
I had no idea.
Well, the good people
at the BIuebell Agency
will testify that you did.
If Ms. Adams does not get
her children back immediately,
I will indict you
for child endangerment.
That's blackmail.
And if you drag your feet,
manslaughter.
Momma.
Don't cry. It's okay.
Why don't we give them
a Iittle privacy?
Yeah.
Can GIenn come Iive here, too?
The boy that tried
to help Cassie,
what's gonna happen to him?
He's in good hands. Bye.
What is going to happen
to GIenn?
Emergency foster placement.
Right back in the system.