NARRATOR: In the criminal
justice system,
sexually based offenses
are considered
especially heinous,
In New York City,
the dedicated detectives
who investigate
these vicious felonies
are members
of an elite squad known
as the Special Victims Unit,
These are their stories,
(PANTING)
Hurry, Mama!
Hurry.
Mijo, run.
Tell them. Go!
Whoa! What's the rush?
My brother.
He's been shot.
Where is he?
They're coming.
Give him to me.
No, he's my baby.
I'II take him inside.
I got a gunshot wound here!
Hurry!
Prep trauma one.
Page surgery
and tell OR to stand by.
Doctor,
please save my baby.
Save him.
There's no exit wound.
Let's go. Forget trauma.
Oh, my God,
don't Iet him die.
Save him.
He's in good hands.
PIease!
Let's take
a Iook at you.
Mommy. Mommy.
Officer Jones is gonna
take you for a snack
while I help your mom.
No. No. No!
I'm staying with her.
Post two, notify NYPD
for a GSW victim.
No, no.
No police, please.
Ma'am,
your son has
been shot.
We have to
call the police.
Now,
what is your name?
Lupe Rodriguez.
And your son who's wounded?
Jorge.
PIease,
go and check on him.
PIease.
Mommy.
He's gonna be okay.
Baby, he's gonna be okay.
GUARD:
The kid's Iucky.
Still critical,
but the docs say
he should make it
through surgery.
Where's the mother?
In the waiting room
with her older son.
Real shaken up.
Where is she?
She's gone.
She had the kid
in her arms.
Came from
over there.
I carried him in,
bleeding all over the place.
Did you search
the building?
Yes.
Didn't even wait to see
if her son was dead or alive.
You're from
Special Victims?
Yeah, we handle
the child abandonment cases.
Now, Jorge,
how's he doing?
Just out of surgery.
And the mother
was acting strange?
She freaked
when she heard me
call the cops.
Jorge was shot once
in the Iower abdomen.
Any idea
how old he is?
Five, maybe six.
What are his chances?
We got the slug.
Didn't hit any major
arteries or organs.
He'II recover
from this,
but he's got
bigger problems.
Bigger problems
than getting shot?
Chest film showed
multiple healed
rib fractures,
so I ordered
a skeletal survey.
Found even more
healed fractures.
His Ieft ulna, humerus,
one on each side of his face.
STABLER: Doctor said the kid
had the crap kicked
out of him for years.
And nobody in that ER
recognized him?
Or the name.
No Jorge Rodriguez
or anyone
matching those injuries
having been treated there.
Mother gave
a phony home address
and social security number.
I mean, Lupe's probably
not even her real name.
So they're new in the area,
or the mother hit
a different hospital
every time
the boy was injured.
Makes it harder
to pick up on the abuse.
Could be she's protecting
a boyfriend
who thought the kid
was an inconvenience.
How about the victim
or his brother were
playing with a gun?
STABLER: He was shot
with a 9 mill.
No stippling
or powder burns.
Bullet was still
inside of him.
He had to be shot from
some kind of distance.
Great, so we got false ID
on the victim and the mother,
no perp, no weapon.
Do we at Ieast
have a crime scene?
Checked communications
and the Iocal precinct.
No reports of any shootings
around the time
the boy was brought in.
Well, that woman
couldn't have run very far
carrying 50 extra pounds.
Cab or car service
would've dropped them
right off at the
emergency room doors.
CRAGEN: Fin, John,
check with transit
just in case.
After that, call every ER
in the five boroughs.
See if anyone
remembers a child
with our John Doe's
old injuries.
Chances are, this family Iives
somewhere near that hospital,
and those kids had to
go to school somewhere.
STABLER:
Do you recognize this child?
It's Miguel Ramos,
one of our first graders.
What happened to him?
BENSON: He was shot.
Oh, good Lord.
How is he?
Critical, but the doctors
expect him to recover.
That must be why
Luis is absent today.
Luis is Miguel's brother?
Yeah.
One of our fifth graders.
Both good students. Quiet,
never cause any trouble.
We're Iooking
for their mother,
but she gave a phony name
and address at the hospital.
That must be a habit of hers.
The Ietter I sent
to their home Iast week
came back today.
No such address.
Phone number's
out of service, too.
That's why I was
Iooking for Luis
this morning.
Her name is Maria.
Maria Ramos.
522 Cherry Street.
That's in the middle
of the East River Park.
Now, she would have
had to show proof
of her current address
to register the boys, right?
Yeah. I have a copy
of her Iease.
I mean,
she enrolled the boys
Iast month.
Everything seemed
in order.
It's a standard form.
She could have bought it
at any stationery store
and forged it.
Okay.
Is there a father?
No. Not in any
of the paperwork.
Must be out of the picture.
What about an emergency
contact number
or a place where she works?
No. Just a home number
but I know she has a job.
Luis takes Miguel
to a youth center
on Essex Street
every day after school.
Thank you.
PENZA: Miguel and Luis
are regulars.
We try to keep
these Iatchkey kids
off the street
and out of trouble.
How did it happen?
That's what
we're trying to find out.
Are there any friends
that we can talk to?
Yeah.
Hey, Kevin?
Take over for a minute.
McDONALD: What's up,
Mr. Penza?
These detectives need
some information.
This is Kevin McDonald,
he's one of our counselors.
McDONALD:
How can I help you?
Tell us about
the Ramos brothers.
Two great kids.
Luis is one step away
from his red belt.
He's got a mean
flying side kick.
You ever see
their mother
pick them up from school?
Yeah. She was here yesterday.
Comes by once a week.
The rest of the time, Luis
is more Iike Miguel's father.
Makes sure nobody
messes with him.
Anybody know
where they Iive?
I walked Miguel home one night
when Luis was out sick.
BENSON:
Nobody named Ramos on here,
STABLER:
I Iived in a building
for four years,
never put my name
on the buzzer.
I'II ring the super.
Liv,
what's that Iook Iike?
Ricochet mark.
Goes all the way
down the building.
Shooter either got him
going into the building...
Or coming out.
There's no blood
on the stoop
or the sidewalk
STABLER: I don't see
any blood on the walls.
Doesn't Iook Iike
there's any
in the street, either.
But there's some
over here.
Trajectory of the slugs
show the weapon
was fired at a Iow angle.
Someone crouching down
across the street?
Yeah.
More Iikely a drive-by.
We found more slugs
than shells.
So some of the shells
might've ejected
into this car.
Or rolled into the sewer.
That's not all.
Angles of the slug marks
on the building
get more and more blunt
from the stoop to the alley,
so the car had to stop.
BENSON: So the shooter
fired at somebody
coming out of the building,
then escaped
into that alley.
Might explain these.
Skid marks.
Yeah,
and they're fresh ones.
Stopped the car, peeled out,
he Ieft that behind.
Sideswiped him.
Silver car, black paint.
AIso fresh.
Peter,
get a shot of this.
PETER: Got it.
We'II get
the chemistry set out,
match the paint
to the manufacturer.
How Iong before you get us
a make and model on that car?
For you two,
give me a day.
BENSON:
Any Iuck on the canvass?
Hear no evil, see no evil.
Zero witnesses.
We found
the kids' apartment.
They Iive
with Grandma.
Last night when I came home,
the boys weren't here,
so I thought maybe Maria took
Luis and Miguel for the night.
Well, they Iive here,
but Maria doesn't?
Last month,
she shows up at my door
and asks me
to take care of the boys.
(SOBBING)
It was the second time
that I see them in two years.
BENSON:
Where is Maria staying?
I don't know where.
With some friends.
But she said that
it was temporary
until she find a place
of her own.
Why would anyone
want to harm them?
Last year, Maria called me.
She was arrested...
with drugs
I gave her the bail money,
because she told me
that her boyfriend
could never find out.
When she came here
with my grandsons,
I asked her if she was
back with the drugs
and she swore to me
that it was all behind her.
But I knew
she was in trouble.
Maria's boyfriend,
do you know where he Iives?
In the Bronx.
They Iive together.
We'II need that address.
You said that you tried
to reach Maria,
but you couldn't.
This is her telephone number
where she works,
some restaurant,
in case the boys got sick.
Two other detectives
were here yesterday
asking about Maria.
Don't you people communicate
with each other?
That would be
much too efficient
for a bureaucracy Iike ours.
The detectives say
where they were from?
No, but they were
undercover.
Looked more Iike
drug dealers than cops.
FIN: What did you tell them?
MANAGER:
Maria had a day off.
I didn't know
where she was.
She scheduled
to work here today?
She didn't show up.
Not Iike her at all.
Hard worker, good attitude,
until today.
But if she don't call me,
I got to Iet her go.
MUNCH: She seem uneasy
about anything Iately?
Yeah, two days ago,
she was working the grill.
Some customer comes in
and calls her by name.
She makes Iike
she doesn't even
know the guy,
and then she said
she was sick,
(PHONE RINGING)
and she had to go home.
Okay, if you see her...
Yeah, don't worry,
I have her paycheck.
She'II call me.
Hello?
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Yes?
Police.
I'm Detective Stabler.
This is my partner,
Detective Benson.
You are?
Fredo Garcia.
How can I help you?
We're here
about your family.
Did something
happen to them?
BENSON:
When were they Iast here?
About a month ago.
I was away on business.
Came back, they were gone.
Can you tell me
what this is about?
Miguel was hurt.
Did she do it?
Why would you say that?
Maria has a crazy temper.
I came home one night,
she was hitting Miguel.
I warned her
if she did it again,
I'd call the cops.
I guess
that's why she Ieft.
But you didn't
report them missing?
I Iooked for them myself.
Didn't have any Iuck.
She wanted to Ieave me.
I figured, what am I
gonna do to stop her?
BENSON: How Iong
were you two together?
Two years.
And she gave you
no indication where
she might've gone?
Didn't even Ieave a note.
If you find them,
would you tell them
I'd Iike her and the boys
to come back?
Sure will.
He's so concerned
that Maria beat Miguel
but doesn't ask
what happened to him.
Wonder what Fredo
does for a Iiving.
Somebody's dealing
out of here.
Could explain
Maria's drug problem.
Last year Maria was
busted with a dozen
dime bags of heroin
and $1,000 cash.
Possession
with intent to sell.
First offense,
D.A. knocked it down.
She did a year
on probation.
None of this jibes
with a woman
slinging burgers
to support her kids.
We figure out their movements
the day of the shooting?
The kids went to school
and the youth center as usual.
Maria picked them up.
We don't know where
she was before that.
Yeah, we're thinking
they all went
to Maria's mother's place,
even though
it was just Miguel
who got shot.
From there,
they ran the three blocks
to the hospital.
CRAGEN: Well, what about
the ex-boyfriend?
Munch is running
a rap sheet on him now.
Now Fredo's story is,
Maria Ieft because
he threatened
to call the cops on her
for beating up
her boys.
Maybe Miguel can tell us
what happened.
He's asking
for his mother.
BENSON: What's going on?
Doctor told me
not to say anything.
What happened?
Miguel is dead.
They just told us
that he was awake.
Complications from surgery?
Pillow over his face.
He was smothered.
I was checking his vitals.
He was stable, awake, alert.
I walked out
to get a peds
blood pressure cuff.
I was only gone five minutes.
AII right.
Now, when you were
in there
did Miguel say anything
about the shooting?
He asked for his mother
and his brother, that's all.
Okay,
think really hard.
You remember seeing
any strangers on the floor?
Just some visitors
and a maintenance man.
Oh, my God.
What?
The maintenance guy.
He passed the Nurses' Station
as I was going back to Miguel.
I said, "Hi"
and he just kept walking.
Someone I haven't seen before.
Can you describe to us
what he Iooks Iike?
Hispanic, average height,
dark hair.
Okay. We'II need you
to describe him
to a sketch artist.
I'II tell my boss.
Good.
Let's go.
Pair of patrols found
a maintenance worker's uniform
in the men's room
on the first floor.
Nurse saw him
just before
she found Miguel.
Does the mother's
ex-boyfriend
Iook good for this?
We'II have the nurse
work with the sketch artist.
AII right, Iook,
I want everybody
who works in this hospital
interviewed quick.
Miguel's mother and brother
could be next.
Look Iike you could
use some caffeine.
Twelve-hour sack time
would be a Iot better.
Sketch of your guy.
Anything back
from the Iab, yet?
Dozens of prints taken
from the hospital room.
No word yet
if it matches anyone
in our system.
Results are in
of the sideswiped car
from the scene
of the drive-by.
Your shooter drove
a black '98 Lexus.
Must be a couple
of thousand of those
in the Tri-State Area.
Why don't you guys
catch an hour or two
up in the crib?
We'II cover for you.
Thanks.
It's gonna have to wait.
What's the problem?
That was Maria Ramos' boss.
She's going to
pick up her check.
Manager just gave me
the heads up.
Wake up call,
she's at the counter.
Neither did we.
What?
OIivia said
she didn't see her coming in.
Who's that?
MUNCH: Not Maria.
On the way out.
Leather jacket.
Orange pants.
We got her.
You want us
to take her?
No, not yet. Let's see
where she Ieads us.
Looks Iike she's heading
for the bus stop.
You think she's just
bringing that check to Maria?
Think that'd be too easy.
Hey, Luis.
Luis. Let's go.
COLON: Leave him alone!
Let go of me.
I didn't do anything.
BENSON:
Luis, you're not in trouble.
Listen to me, we're cops.
We're here to help you.
What's going on here?
Let's start
with your real name.
Annie Colon.
Annie Colon,
why are you picking up
Maria Ramos' paycheck?
She asked me to.
Where is she?
I don't know.
She slept on my couch
for the Iast week.
Then Iast night
she said she had to Ieave,
told me to
give her check to Luis.
You Iying to us?
I'm telling the truth,
I swear.
Luis,
where's your mother?
That's a tough guy,
he doesn't wanna work with us.
I'II tell you what,
you want to play it that way?
Let go of me.
What are you doing?
BENSON: We're taking him in.
No!
For what?
He's 10 years old!
He's truant.
LUIS: Stop. Let go.
Luis, we wanna help you.
But you have
to help us, too.
Why was your mom scared
to pick up her own paycheck?
STABLER:
You Ieft your Iittle brother
in the hospital, why?
Did you see Miguel?
Yeah, we saw him.
Now, Iook, we know
you and your mom
are in trouble,
and we wanna protect you,
but we've got
to talk to her first.
Luis, tell us where
you and your mom are staying.
No. I'm not telling you.
That kid's hanging tough.
Can we hold him?
For cutting class?
As a material witness.
We know he saw something.
We put him in the system,
they put him
in juvenile detention,
which just
terrifies him further.
He didn't do anything.
Let's try harder.
Poor kid doesn't even know
about his brother.
Luis have anything on him?
A few bucks,
slip of paper
with the word "Liberty"
written on it,
a school subway pass,
and transit says
most trips
originate from
the Lawrence Street Station.
N and R trains in Brooklyn,
near the Fulton Mall.
They could be
staying near there.
CRAGEN: Then that's where
we Iook for Maria.
Start with every place
that has Liberty
in the name.
Haven't seen anyone
Iike that around here.
Anyone move into the building
in the Iast few days?
No. No new tenants
in six months.
Okay. Thanks.
We've been to
Liberty Apartments,
Liberty Hotel.
There's a Liberty Avenue exit
off the Van Wyck in Queens.
You know,
this is gonna take us
at Ieast a month.
Maria must be going
out of her mind
wondering why Luis
hasn't come home.
What's next on the Iist?
Liberty Knick Knacks.
If Liberty's not
the name of the place
where she's staying,
well, maybe it's where
she's got a new job.
I'm not seeing anybody.
Right there.
BENSON: Maria.
Go down that aisle.
Can I help you?
Maria Ramos?
You get away from me.
Calm down, Maria.
We're the police.
We need you
to come with us.
Why? Why?
You Ieft Miguel
in the hospital.
Well, I had to.
What's wrong?
My baby,
is he okay?
Let's talk privately.
No, no, no, tell me.
What's going on?
Well, tell me,
how is my baby?
Miguel's dead.
What are you talking about?
He's fine.
He's in a good hospital.
We're sorry, Maria.
No, no, no! You're wrong.
You're so wrong. He's fine.
The doctor told me
he was gonna be okay.
Why don't we
talk somewhere else?
No. PIease, please.
Sorry.
No, you're not sorry.
You never help us. Stop it!
Does Luis know about Miguel?
BENSON:
We haven't said anything yet.
MARIA: Where is he?
I have to tell him.
He's here. Safe.
Let me see him.
Maria, Luis is going
to a shelter
until we can place him
in a foster home.
You can't take him
away from me. He's my son.
BENSON: So was Miguel,
but where were you
when he needed you?
I Ioved him.
It's a hell of a way
to show it,
Ieaving him
in that hospital
Iike that.
I thought
he would be safe there.
From the person
who shot him,
or whoever used him
as a punching bag?
STABLER: Healed fractures
in both arms and ribs.
He had a broken nose.
His jaw was cracked twice.
Was it you?
I never Iaid a hand
on my kids.
Her word against his.
Whose word?
STABLER: Fredo.
You talked to Fredo?
He knows I'm here?
He knows Luis is here?
How did Fredo
treat your kids?
He Ioved them.
BENSON: So why don't
you want us to talk to him?
Maria,
someone beat up your boy.
Now if it's not you,
then it must be Fredo.
You've got to stop
covering for him.
We can protect you and Luis.
You just don't get it.
I can't.
CABOT: Fredo has her spooked.
How many times
have we seen this,
Counselor?
Woman trapped
in a violent relationship
and doesn't want
to press charges.
Yeah, but she Ieft him.
That takes courage.
And no doubt
pissed off the bastard.
CRAGEN:
Now he wants revenge,
so he shoots her kid.
But he doesn't count
on Miguel surviving,
so he sends somebody
to the hospital
to shut him up.
That seems pretty extreme
for a family squabble.
Unless that's not
all this is.
John, any Iuck?
No rap sheet
under the name
Fredo Garcia.
Check with Narcotics
Task Force.
If this guy's a player,
they got to know about him.
I just got off the phone
with them.
I asked about Fredo,
guy says they never
even heard of him.
Then he starts
questioning me
Iike he doesn't think
I'm a cop.
The only thing
he didn't ask me
was whether I wear
boxers or briefs.
Sounds Iike
they know something
they don't wanna share.
I'II call my office
and see if anybody
knows anything.
Thanks.
Any other back doors
we can open?
Fin bolted
a couple of minutes ago,
didn't say where.
That usually means
a covert meeting
with one of his operatives
in the drug netherworld.
What did Maria say?
Nothing.
We're gonna have
to talk to Luis.
Let me take a run at him.
I speak 10-year-old.
AII right.
You didn't finish.
Was the burger okay?
Full.
Sorry. I didn't mean
to treat you Iike a baby.
Just the way
I was brought up.
My mom, you know,
she'd kind of
hover over me.
Just the opposite of you
and your mother.
What do you mean?
When I was your age,
I wasn't allowed
to ride my bike
around the corner.
You, you pick up
your Iittle brother
at school every day,
ride the subway alone.
You're a pretty
independent guy.
Yeah, someone's got to do it.
I have a Iot of respect
for you, Luis.
I Iive by myself.
I only have myself
to worry about.
You take care
of your mother,
your brother.
I didn't do that too well.
What makes you say that?
Miguel got shot.
That's not your fault.
Yes, it is.
My stomach hurts.
You don't have
to be scared, Luis.
I don't want
to talk about it.
Talking can be good.
Make you feel better.
It'II get you into trouble.
You don't have to keep
everything to yourself.
He'II hurt my mom
if I say anything.
Luis, Iook at me.
Your mom turns to you
for help, doesn't she?
We take care of each other.
I'm a detective. I want
to take care of you, too.
I can't do that
unless you talk to me.
But I promised her
I wouldn't.
Your mom's confused, Luis.
She needs your help.
You can't protect her
unless you tell me
what Fredo did.
I saw one of Fredo's men
in the car where
the shots came from.
What do you want
with me anyhow?
Fredo Garcia
mean anything to you?
You trying to get me killed?
I'm out of here.
Don't move.
If the guy's in the trade,
why don't I know
anything about him?
He's new,
since you stopped
being a narc.
Keeps a Iow profile,
my own personal mantra.
Here's my mantra.
I scratched your back,
now I got a major itch.
Unless you want
to be keeping a Iow profile
in some cell in Rikers.
You got to watch my back.
Talk!
Two years, Fredo's got
the dope market cornered.
How?
By killing off
the Iocal competition.
Joey Stapleton
was the main supplier
in the Bronx
till Fredo capped him.
How'd he take over
the building?
He hears we had this talk,
I'm a dead man.
Listen, the evidence
I have on you
is good for two years.
He forced out
some of the tenants
and paid off the rest.
Moved in with some woman
and her kids.
It's a nice Iittle front
for him.
I wouldn't want
to be that bitch
right now, though.
Why not?
Word is,
he's got a hit out on her.
For ratting him out
to you cops.
Fin's guy says
Fredo charmed his way
into Maria's Iife,
into her apartment.
He used
the whole damn building
for his drug business.
BENSON:
While the rest of his rats
crawl around the city.
We're ready.
BENSON: Let's do it.
It may be the only way
to nail Fredo.
How's Miguel?
(SPEAKING IN SPANISH)
No!
MARIA:
It's not your fault, Mijito.
No,
It's Fredo's fault,
I told them,
No, no, no!
Tell them you lied,
Tell them!
Please, he takes it back,
He's a child, You tricked him,
You made him tell you lies,
Mom!
Luis, please,
listen to me,
No, Mommy, tell them,
Tell them it was Fredo,
Don't be afraid,
(SPEAKING IN SPANISH)
STABLER: Fredo's not just
some jealous Iover Maria's
trying to escape from.
He happens to be
one of the city's
biggest drug Iords.
As Iong as she and Luis
are breathing,
they're in danger.
We can keep them
in protective custody.
Safest bet
is to get them
out of town.
I need them here
to prep the case,
go before the grand jury.
Now we're talking
about a hotel.
We got no budget
for witness protection.
Any chance the D.A.'s office
can pony up the bucks?
You know how it works.
You pay before indictment,
we pay after.
Come on, 1PP's down
our throats on money
ever since the attacks.
Help us out here.
I'II see what I can do.
In the meantime,
try to find someplace
that isn't The PIaza.
What about
Miguel's funeral?
Crime Victims Board
will pay.
And we do the arrangements.
Find a church as far away
from her neighborhood
as you possibly can.
Immediate family
and us only.
MARIA:
I was in love with Fredo,
He was wonderful.
Until I came home
from work one night.
He was at my kitchen table
with his friends,
cutting heroin.
Where were the boys?
Watching them.
I told Fredo to stop,
and he hits me with his gun
and tells me
to never embarrass him
in front of his friends.
Later he apologized and said
he wouldn't do it again.
It usually gets worse.
He started to beat
Miguel and Luis, too.
Then he would beg us
to forgive him.
Bring us presents
and promise
he will never do it again.
Until the next time.
Maria, did you ever
try to Ieave before now?
I had no place to go,
no money.
He would only give me
enough to buy food
and spend the rest on himself
and other women.
But, Maria,
you were arrested for drugs.
Were you using?
I never used.
Never.
Fredo degraded me.
He made me carry his drugs
inside of me
so the police
wouldn't find them,
forced my boys to run drugs,
told me he would kill them
if we didn't do
as we were told.
But you stayed.
Something must have
made you realize
that you had
to get away from him.
One day,
Fredo took Luis' baseball bat
and beat a man unconscious
while Luis and I watched.
I knew we could be next.
Your boss at the restaurant
said that somebody
recognized you.
That's how Fredo
found you, isn't it?
It was the man
I delivered the dope to.
He runs Fredo's operation
in Brooklyn.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
STABLER: Everybody decent?
Yeah, come in.
You Iook so handsome.
We ready?
Yeah.
PRIEST:
We'II start in just a moment.
Gracias, Father.
BENSON:
What are they doing here?
Said it couldn't wait.
Detectives Milton...
And Tatum, yeah,
from the Bronx.
What's the problem?
She didn't tell you?
BENSON: Tell us what?
Oh, my God.
She and her son Miguel
witnessed Fredo Garcia
off one of his competitors,
a dealer named
Joey Stapleton.
I mean, she came to us,
but disappeared before
we got her statement.
Fredo's men follow you,
and that's how he found me.
Maria, it's time to start
telling the truth.
Yes, we did see it.
We saw how Fredo
killed that man,
and I did call the police.
But I run when they said
I had to testify in court.
I couldn't face Fredo.
(GUNSHOT)
FIN: Down! Down! Maria's hit!
Shots came from the back.
Stay with them!
10-30. We got shots
fired at the church
on Broadway and 177.
We got a civilian down.
We need an ambulance now.
(SIRENS BLARING)
Police! Freeze!
Show us your hands!
Show me your hands.
Show me your hands!
BIack Lexus
with silver paint scrapings.
I've been Iooking
for one of these.
BENSON: Look at this.
It's good enough
to fool the manager
at Maria's restaurant.
STABLER:
Where'd you get that?
Shove it.
I'm sorry?
You know something?
Running your mouth Iike that,
you're gonna wish
you'd shot me.
What's your answer now?
No answer. Come on.
How bad?
She got it in the arm.
Okay, Iet's get her
out of here.
MAN: This way
over here, please.
You can't keep us safe.
You can't help us.
We will never be safe.
Go.
MUNCH:
Do you recognize anyone?
NURSE: Number three.
Where do you
recognize him from?
He's the one I saw passing
the Nurses' Station
wearing the
maintenance man's uniform.
He killed Miguel Ramos.
You didn't see him
kill anyone.
We're not in court.
Thank you.
Thanks.
CABOT: Maria's turn.
Number three.
His name is Eddie Fuentes.
FIN: Where do you
recognize him from?
He works for Fredo.
I saw him driving the car
when Miguel was shot.
Driving? He wasn't
one of the shooters?
You can't Iead her
Iike that.
Okay, Maria,
if Fuentes was driving,
who shot Miguel?
Fredo. From the back seat
of the car.
My client wishes to exercise
his right to remain silent.
He'd better say something
if he has any hope
of staying alive.
Staying alive?
Miguel was
a murder witness.
Killing him in that hospital
means a needle in your arm,
Eddie.
You can't prove
I did that.
Moron, we got a witness
places you 10 feet
from Miguel's room
just before they found him
with a pillow over his face.
Your '98 black Lexus
Ieft skid marks
and paint scrapings
at the scene of the crime.
STABLER: And we matched
the slug in Miguel to the one
you put in his mother.
That's attempted murder
of another witness
and six cops.
And if you think
the jury is going to care
that nobody actually
saw you smother Miguel,
I can assure you,
they won't.
I don't talk for nothing.
Murder one,
Iife without parole.
What kind of deal is that?
CABOT: The kind that
keeps you breathing.
You give us Fredo,
we take the death penalty
off the table.
(WHISPERING)
You gotta protect me.
We'II keep you
out of the general pop.
Fredo...
It was all his idea.
I told him he was crazy,
that doing the kid
in the hospital
was too risky.
Why'd he want Miguel dead?
Miguel and Maria.
They saw him
whack Joey Stapleton.
Fredo gave me
60,000 to hit them.
How did you find Maria
and her boys?
First time,
we followed her
to the diner
where she met
those two cops.
We Iost her when she split,
so we followed the cops.
(CHUCKLES)
They Ied us
right to the church.
Followed us?
That's crap.
Fuentes Iies
and the deal's off.
He's Iooking at death row.
Even he's not that stupid.
We need to
interview him.
No, he's our catch.
He already rolled on Fredo
for your case.
Now, who told you
that we had Maria?
Narcotics Task Force said
you were asking questions.
Someone in your own squad
told us about the funeral.
And your going there
almost cost us Maria and Luis.
Not to mention
four of my detectives
and your own sorry asses.
Come on,
Iet us talk to the girl.
You want in,
you follow my orders.
BENSON: Did you go
to Maria's hotel first?
Before the church.
Which means Fredo could know
we have Maria and Luis there.
We gotta move them.
You wanna talk to Maria?
We work together
to protect her,
and you two just drew
the graveyard shift.
MARIA: Where's this new hotel?
Rockland County.
You can't take us there.
I don't drive,
and we'II be trapped
in that hotel,
and Luis needs
to be in school.
Maria, you're gonna
have to trust us.
The only way that
we can keep you safe
from Fredo's people
is to get you
out of this city.
You have Eddie Fuentes.
Let Luis and me go.
I'II be back to testify.
That's what you told
the other detectives
before you ditched them
and took off.
I did what I had to do
to protect my family.
You almost
got yourself killed.
PIease, get in.
I never should have
gone to those cops
or talked to you.
We could have disappeared,
and Miguel would
still be alive.
I killed my own son
because I didn't know
what to do.
Let us help you.
You can't help me.
He could be
one of Fredo's people.
Or him, or them, or anybody.
You can't stop them.
If you just work with us,
we can protect you.
That's what
the other cops said
and Iook what happened.
I'm not testifying
against Fredo.
Listen to me,
as Iong as you're out there,
you're a threat to Fredo.
He can't afford
to Ieave you alive.
He'II never Ieave you alone.
Now, you refuse to testify,
we'II subpoena you.
If you still refuse
to testify, you go to jail
and you Iose Luis
to a foster home.
Then take him!
Put him in someplace
where they can never find him.
We can't Iive
Iike this anymore.
CABOT: She has to testify.
Well, you can't blame her.
Fredo killed Miguel
because Maria talked
to the Bronx detectives.
Maria doesn't nail him,
he wins.
You'd cut her Ioose?
I'm just saying that
we're part of her problem.
She thinks
that we're punishing her
by making her
a moving target,
and she's right.
She's in more danger
having us around.
Is there any way to do this
without Maria and Luis?
They saw Fredo shoot Miguel.
Maria watched him
murder Joey Stapleton.
CRAGEN: We have Eddie Fuentes.
He's a co-conspirator.
Without corroboration,
I can't even indict.
You know,
if we were the Feds,
we could give her
a whole new identity,
new Iife.
No honor among thieves.
Fuentes squealed Iike a pig.
Gave up Fredo's operation
including the Iayout
of Fredo's crib
complete with all
the escape routes.
Maria's not talking
till we get Fredo
out of the picture.
FIN: We'd better do it quick.
They go to the
grandmother's house to get
Luis' asthma medicine.
Luis fakes sick.
Maria and Luis
go into the bathroom,
close the door behind them,
and Maria bolts out
the fire escape.
Tatum and his partner
Iost her.
Couple of square-badge
security guards
wouldn't have fallen for that.
Yeah, we better pick up Fredo
before he finds out.
Decision time,
Counselor.
I'II wake up a judge.
The warrant will be
for the drugs only.
What you want, man?
Trying to get a taste,
player.
4:00 in the morning, man,
we're closed.
Open up.
Yo, you rob for that?
Do you really care?
You gonna turn down
this business?
Yo, I've never
seen you before, man.
I ain't never seen
you before, man. Come on.
Inside. Follow me.
You trying to take me off,
man? You in big trouble.
Shut up. Police.
We're all clear.
MAN:
Police! Don't move.
(GUNSHOT)
(SCREAM)
Police.
We've got the building
surrounded.
Open the door slowly
and throw the gun out.
WOMAN: Get out!
I'm taking care of this.
Maria.
Maria, it's Detective Stabler.
Are you all right?
MARIA: Go away.
Do it.
(MAN YELLING)
STABLER:
Maria, put down the gun.
The bitch shot me!
(SPEAKING IN SPANISH)
Maria, Maria,
he's never gonna
hurt you again.
Now give us the gun.
Shoot her!
I didn't do anything!
You killed my son,
you bastard!
Don't Iisten to him.
Listen to us.
Killing him won't
bring Miguel back.
Maria, you have another son.
Think about Luis.
MARIA: He will be safe.
STABLER: But he won't
have a mother.
Now just put down the gun,
and this will all be over.
Come on, Maria,
make Luis proud.
Come on, Maria.
How bad?
It's killing me.
That's good.
It's just the knee.
I'II call EMS.
FIN: Where's Luis?
He's at my mother's house.
He was going for the gun,
the one he keeps
in the bedroom.
The bitch is a Iiar.
Shut up.
Maria, calm down. Calm down.
Look at me.
Where did you get the gun?
On the street.
I bought it.
Come on.
AIex, this is a big mistake.
Maria bought a gun
with our money.
To protect herself
and her son.
To assassinate
her ex-boyfriend.
(DOOR OPENING)
What's going on?
AIex wants to
indict Maria.
For what?
Attempted murder.
Are you kidding me?
Fredo terrorized Maria
and her sons for two years.
That doesn't give her
the right to become
a vigilante.
This isn't about revenge,
AIex. It's self-defense.
No, OIivia, Fredo's gun
was two rooms away.
Unless Maria had
reason to believe
her Iife was
in immediate danger,
she had no justification
for shooting him.
How about
extreme emotional distress?
Doesn't apply here.
Maria knew exactly
what she was doing.
She dropped Luis off
at her mother's.
She ditched
the Bronx detectives.
She bought the gun,
and she went to kill Fredo.
We put her in that position
because we couldn't
protect her.
No one could guarantee
Maria's safety 100%.
Look, she is scared
for her Iife and her boy's.
Maria committed a crime.
Which we are
partly responsible for.
AIex, cut her a break.
I have to enforce the Iaw.
Maria is your only eyewitness
to Fredo executing
Joey Stapleton.
Convict her
and her credibility is shot,
along with your murder case
against Fredo.
The Iaw is not
always about justice.
Your words, remember?
Maria didn't kill anybody.
But, Fredo, Fredo's got
two bodies to his name
that we know about.
We don't Iop
his head off now,
he will kill again,
and if anything happens
to Maria or Luis,
it's on you.
Get on the bus, Mijo,
Okay.
Take care of yourself,
Luis.
LUIS: Bye.
Would you tell my mother?
That you've Ieft town, yes,
but not where you've gone.
You'II have to call us.
I will.
Thank you.
STABLER: Good Iuck.
(BUS ENGINE STARTING)
He murdered her child.
She'II be back.