NARRATOR: In the criminal
justice system,
sexually based offenses
are considered
especially heinous.
In New York City,
the dedicated detectives
who investigate
these vicious felonies
are members
of an elite squad known
as the Special Victims Unit.
These are their stories.
So what kinds of things
do you Iike to draw, Chloe?
Cats.
Cats?
I Iike cats.
You know, your teacher
showed me a really
great picture that you drew.
Is that your family?
Uh-huh.
Are you
in this picture?
That's me
and that's Mommy
and Kyle.
You Iook sad
in this picture.
Are those tears?
Why are you crying?
Kyle is your brother?
He's my half-brother.
Oh, 'cause
you guys have
different moms, right?
We have the same daddy.
Daddy?
There's no daddy
in this picture.
Where's he?
He's out of town.
Is that
why you're sad?
No.
Okay. Chloe,
are you sad
'cause someone's
hurting you?
I don't know.
Usually Chloe's
very happy, outgoing,
but Iately
she's been withdrawn.
And I've noticed
some bruises
on her Iegs.
Okay, once
Detective Benson's
finished talking with her
we'II need to take her
to the hospital
for an exam.
The father's
a Iittle high-strung.
What do I tell him?
We'II send an officer
here to meet him,
bring him to the hospital.
What do you mean,
high-strung?
A yeller. You know,
corporate mogul type,
Lawrence Fuller.
Fuller Telecom?
Yeah.
Guy's name
is on my cable bill.
Well, you should probably
also know that Chloe's
mother is GIoria Stanfield.
The actress.
She did a few movies
about 10 years ago.
So you're asking
for discretion.
No, I'm just giving you
fair warning.
They're both a handful.
Chloe, your mom
and Kyle Iook
really happy here, huh?
How come you're
the only one
that's sad?
Because Mommy
Ioves Kyle
more than me.
I bet she Ioves you
both the same.
She reads him stories
all the time,
but not to me.
Where does she
read Kyle stories?
In his room.
They close the door
and I'm not allowed.
You never
went in there?
Not one time?
It was because
I heard noises.
I thought
Mommy was crying.
What were they doing?
They were
playing in bed.
They didn't have
any clothes on.
The colposcopic exam
didn't reveal any signs
of sexual abuse.
Anything that indicates
straight physical abuse?
Some bruises
on her shins.
Pretty typical
for a five-year-old.
Scan showed healed wrist
and tibia fractures,
but she doesn't remember
how she got them.
You talk
to the parents yet?
Actually, we're gonna wait
till we speak with Chloe.
Yeah, well, I think that's
her father, and he Iooks
Iike he wants to go.
Are you the detectives
who brought my daughter here?
Is she all right?
She's fine, Mr. Fuller.
Why don't we go someplace
where we can discuss it
more privately?
School tells me
I have to go
to the hospital.
No one tells me why.
Is Chloe hurt?
No. No, but there was
some concern
at her school.
Concern about what?
She said some things
that might indicate
problems at home.
What kind of problems?
Actually, we were hoping
that you could help us
with that.
When did Chloe
break her wrist
and her Ieg?
When she was three.
She fell off a slide
in a playground.
Is that what this is about?
It was an accident.
You dragged her
to a hospital for that?
We brought her here
based on a picture
she drew at school
and statements
she made to
Detective Benson
which seemed to
describe a sexual
relationship between
your wife and your son.
What are you
talking about?
What kind of picture?
Your daughter said
she'd seen them sleeping
in the same bed together.
Are you out of your mind?
She's his mother.
BENSON: Do you think that
Chloe made it up?
She had to. I...
Where's your wife
now, Mr. Fuller?
Our house in the Hamptons,
antique shopping.
Have you ever seen
any behavior that
confirms Chloe's story?
I don't think so.
But you damn well better believe
I'II be finding out.
Sir, it's really
best if you allow us
to investigate.
You investigate all you Iike.
I'm taking Chloe home.
Kyle Fuller's school
records describe a normal,
well-adjusted kid,
till the second grade
when his mother was
killed in a car accident.
Not surprising
he had a tough time.
In the fifth grade
his behavior got worse.
Loss of appetite,
sudden outbursts,
fighting.
That was the same year
his father married
GIoria Stanfield.
Well, it could be
adjusting to a stepmother.
Or the stepmother
pulled a Woody AIIen
way back then.
Proving that's the only way
we're gonna charge her
with statutory rape.
It's not illegal to have
sex with a 17-year-old.
He turned 17 Iast month.
You don't think
it's Iikely that the abuse
started Iong before that?
Doesn't matter what
I think if they're not
breaking the Iaw.
Even if the abuse started
yesterday, she's still
essentially his mother.
She's taking advantage
of her control over him.
Unless he's a normal teenager
who's just happy to be
banging an actress.
Look, if nothing else,
that environment
is unhealthy
for that Iittle girl.
Well, this all depends
on whether we believe
what she's saying is true.
BENSON: And I do.
Kids her age
don't usually make up
things Iike this.
When is the mother
due back in town?
Anytime, if she gets word
we're Iooking at her.
She's gonna want to circle
the family wagons.
Well, I'd Iike to know
if we have a complaining
witness before that happens.
Fin, you and John
go talk to Kyle.
If he is a victim, he may
want to know there's something
he can do to stop it.
You know, a family
Iike this probably has
plenty of hired help.
Something's going on
in that house,
they'd know about it.
AII right, discretion,
everybody.
The Ionger we keep this
out of the papers,
the better.
Kyle Fuller.
Can we talk to you
alone for a minute?
I'II see you guys Iater.
Yeah.
What's this about?
You talk to
your father today?
No, I won't see him
till tonight. Why,
did something happen?
He's fine.
How things going
for you at home?
Okay. Why?
Get along with
your mother?
My stepmother?
She's all right.
Why are you asking
about her?
One of our detectives
talked to your sister Chloe.
We're with the
Special Victims Unit.
One of the things
we investigate
is child abuse.
You think Chloe's
being abused?
FIN: No, not Chloe. You.
She told you that?
She said you and your
stepmother sleep
in the same bed. Is that true?
Okay, wait.
Wait. If you think
that we're sleeping together,
Iike, having sex,
that's just sick.
I mean, GIoria's been
my stepmom since I was,
Iike, 10.
And you don't wanna
get her into trouble.
We understand that.
No. It's just that
there's no way that
we're sleeping together
or having sex
or anything.
I mean, if that's
what Chloe told you,
Iook, I'm sorry, I really am.
I'm sorry you came down here
and wasted your time,
but it's just not true.
Okay?
Detectives,
I've told you three times,
my employment contract
includes a
confidentiality clause.
Meaning
you know something,
you just can't say.
That's not what I mean.
Do you get along with
Ms. Stanfield?
She's an excellent employer,
and that's all I will say.
Well, what do they
pay you for
a gig Iike this?
That's none
of your concern.
I'II bet there are
a Iot of under-the-table
cash transactions.
Is that true?
Well, we could find out.
Drop a dime to the IRS,
have them go through
your undeclared cash income
with a fine-toothed comb.
That would jam her up for,
what, about three years?
Minimum.
We find truth in
what Chloe is saying,
your boss is going down.
You'd better
decide right now.
You want to join her?
I saw them together once,
a few weeks ago.
Doing what?
I walked into the room.
She was kissing Kyle.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
It wasn't the way
a mother kisses her son.
Benson.
It was only a moment.
I hardly saw anything.
It sounds Iike
you saw plenty.
BENSON: Thanks.
GIoria Stanfield's
back in town.
At her Iawyer's office.
Our presence
is kindly requested.
Sorry to keep you waiting,
Detectives.
You must know my client,
GIoria Stanfield.
Heard a Iot about you.
GLORIA: I'II be with you
in a minute.
She wanted to clear
this matter up as soon
as she got back to town.
STABLER: How were
the Hamptons?
Dull.
I know the other detectives
already spoke to Kyle.
He told you the truth.
I am not having
a sexual relationship
with my stepson.
What more
can I tell you?
You think Chloe
Iied about it?
I think she
makes up stories.
She's a child.
Well, then,
why do we have
other adult witnesses
who describe
a pretty passionate kiss
between you and your stepson?
I kiss everyone,
Detective.
The simple fact
is you're investigating
the misconception of
an imaginative five-year-old.
Where do you think
Chloe got these ideas from?
Television, probably.
My old movies,
for that matter.
You know, this is
really ridiculous.
Chloe draws a picture,
and everyone blows it
out of proportion.
I would never do anything
to hurt my stepson.
No complaining witness,
no physical evidence of abuse,
no independent verification
other than an
uncooperative housekeeper
who saw a stepmother
kiss her stepson.
And no indictment
based on a
kindergartner's art project.
There's something
going on in that house.
That woman's wrong.
We're gonna need more
than your gut.
I can contact my counterpart
at Children's Services.
At the very Ieast,
they can start
a file on GIoria.
I just got a call
from a patrol
out of the 22
responding to
a domestic disturbance
at the Formby Day School.
What happened?
GIoria and her husband
are fighting over
who's taking the daughter.
You Iet me take
my daughter home
right now
or I will slap a Iawsuit
on you so fast...
Don't Iet him near her.
You see
how angry he gets.
Shut up.
She raped my son.
God knows what she did
to my daughter.
Our daughter.
Look, you don't deserve
to be a mother.
You're disgusting.
Yeah, make up
some more stories.
Everyone knows it's so you can
get out of child support
when I divorce you!
I'm gonna kill you
if you touch my children!
Mr. Fuller!
I don't want to hear
another threat Iike that.
Now, am I clear?
Yeah.
You say I'm the abuser.
He hits me and he hits them.
You should investigate that!
You two
can fight this out
in Family Court.
Until then,
your children will be
in the custody of the state.
What?
You can't do that!
If we think your children
are in imminent danger,
we certainly can.
If they keep at it,
bring them in
for disorderly conduct.
FULLER: Oh, no, no, no.
Chloe, sweetheart.
Wait a minute.
Baby.
FULLER: No.
It's okay.
This is kidnapping!
Munch, I need you to do
an emergency removal
of Kyle Fuller.
Pick him up at his school.
(SCHOOL BELL RINGING)
You guys are friends
of Kyle Fuller, right?
You seen him?
He Ieft already.
What are you guys
investigating?
Kyle get along okay
with his family?
His stepmom?
Yeah, he and GIoria
got along really well.
How do you know?
Well, everybody knows
about GIoria.
She's very open.
What, is she putting out
for all his school buddies?
Not that. She just Iikes
having guys around.
She doesn't mind,
you know,
if you Iook at her.
Yeah, it's Iike she's
wearing clothes, but you can
totally see through them.
And she's always giving
everybody backrubs.
And what does
Kyle think of all this?
He digs it.
It's not his real mom,
so who cares?
It sounds Iike you think
there's more going on
than just backrubs
and peep shows.
I don't know
if he's banging her,
but I wouldn't be surprised.
Where's the Iittle one?
ACS placed her
with an aunt
and uncle in the area.
Well, Iet's all hope
insanity isn't
a family trait.
Any Iuck with Kyle?
No. Not at home,
not with friends.
Munch and Fin are still
out Iooking, and your day
isn't over yet.
Doorman called it in.
No witnesses.
Nobody heard a struggle.
Where's the rest
of the Addams family?
MIA.
Forced entry?
Door was ajar,
Iocks intact.
Whoever did this
knew the security code.
There's no apparent robbery.
Bashed in
his skull, Ieft.
BIow to the back of the head's
probably what did it,
but he's got impact
wounds to the torso,
thighs, forearms.
Went down fighting.
Murder weapon Iooks Iike
it's cylindrical, two
or three inches in diameter.
MUNCH: Like a baseball bat?
That'd do it.
I found it
under Kyle's bed.
I'II bag it for prints.
Fin's talking to
the doorman to see
if Kyle Ieft in a hurry.
Mr. Fuller came in
around 8:00.
After about 20 minutes,
Ms. Stanfield Ieft,
then Kyle about
15 minutes Iater.
Did you notice
anything unusual
about either of them?
Ms. Stanfield
was in a hurry,
but that's typical.
Kyle. I guess
he seemed a Iittle upset.
Where are
the other entrances?
Back and side doors,
but they're all Iocked
and hooked up
to the alarm system.
And no one enters
without signing in.
Pretty quiet today.
Nobody out of the ordinary.
Just guests of the tenants.
Okay. I'm gonna
get this back to you, okay?
What's going on?
Your father was killed.
Somebody attacked him
in your apartment.
I'm sorry.
Where's GIoria?
Well, I was gonna ask you
the same thing.
You're taking
your father's death
kind of well, though.
Come on.
It's my day off.
I stopped by
to check on
Ms. Stanfield
and the front door was open.
I came in,
found Mr. Fuller.
Why were you
checking on
Ms. Stanfield?
She called
after you took Chloe.
She was so upset.
I wanted to make sure
she was all right.
You know where
she was calling from?
I assumed here.
There was no one else
in the apartment.
She couldn't have done this,
Detective. It's not possible.
MUNCH: How'd you get
that shiner?
At school, in Phys Ed.
It Iooks Iike
you got punched.
Thought it might be
your dad.
MUNCH: Is that what happened?
He started to hit you
and you defended yourself?
No.
I didn't kill him.
Any idea who did?
Where'd you go tonight?
For a walk.
MUNCH: Why?
Because I felt Iike it.
Your dad and stepmom
were home
before you Ieft.
That's gotta be a pretty
contentious relationship
these days, huh?
I don't know anything
about it.
Okay, you went out
for a walk.
Where'd GIoria go?
She didn't kill him.
FIN: Well, how do you know?
You went out for a walk.
I just know.
How many school uniforms
do you have?
About six.
Where's the one
you wore today?
I changed when I got home.
BIood stains kind of clash
with the school colors, huh?
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Detectives.
Hold off
on the questions
for a minute.
Why?
Kid Iawyered up.
Mr. Schaefer,
if you'II follow me
to interrogation.
You're not worried about
a conflict of interest there,
Counselor?
Ms. Stanfield
is a suspect also.
If charges are filed,
Kyle obtains new counsel.
Until then,
no conflict.
Who's representing you?
I'II answer any questions
you have without
my attorney present.
I'm gonna advise you
against that.
No. Really, it's okay.
I haven't got anything
to hide.
Right this way.
I have no idea what happened.
I went to a hotel tonight.
STABLER: Why?
You saw my husband
at the school.
Do you honestly think
I wanted to be anywhere
near that man?
BENSON: Well, then
why go home at all?
Well, Detective Benson,
to get my things.
My stepson was there.
I tried to explain to him
what was happening.
Kyle got so angry,
and then Lawrence walked in.
They started fighting.
Lawrence got physical,
as usual, pushed him.
I couldn't stand it
anymore so I Ieft.
You Ieft your husband
to push around your stepson?
How would I stop him?
Believe me, I've tried.
It only makes things worse.
Will the hotel
confirm your story?
The Sienna.
They'II tell you
when I checked in.
Is that all?
One more thing.
Was your husband
still breathing
when you Ieft?
I didn't kill him.
I have no reason.
Well, actually,
I could think of a couple.
Custody of the kids.
Inheriting his money.
Lawrence made me sign
a prenuptial agreement.
He always believed
that I was a gold digger
at heart.
The money goes to
Kyle and Chloe in trusts that
I am not allowed to touch.
So when you Ieft
Kyle and his father
were still fighting?
Kyle didn't do this.
But you'd already Ieft,
so you don't know
that for sure.
Look, I will answer
any questions
that you have about me,
but I just Iost my husband
and my daughter.
I'm not gonna help you
frame my stepson.
CABOT: Anyone Iook good
for the arrest?
Well, one's covering
for the other.
I'm just not sure who.
The murder weapon was found
under the boy's bed.
I'm guessing GIoria Stanfield
doesn't have a baseball bat.
Well, doesn't mean
she didn't borrow it.
Kyle came back
to the crime scene.
If he killed the guy,
why the hell
didn't he stay away?
Maybe to pick up
the murder weapon.
Only one set of prints on it.
Kyle Fuller's.
Arrest him.
We have been more than
cooperative, so if you're not
planning on arresting Kyle...
Stand up.
Why?
Because we're planning
on arresting you.
For what?
The murder
of Lawrence Fuller.
Come on, Iet's not
make this any harder.
You have the right
to an attorney.
You want my advice,
don't take one that's
on your mother's payroll.
You're making a mistake.
My son is innocent.
You're the only
other suspect,
so if you got a confession,
now's the time to give it.
I'II have him out
by morning.
Kyle, don't say
anything.
I won't.
I'm getting you a Iawyer.
I'II take care of everything.
Don't tell them
anything.
CLERK: "Docket ending 137.
People v. Kyle Fuller.
"One count
Murder in the Second Degree."
Trevor Langan for
the defense, Your Honor.
JUDGE: How do you plead?
Not guilty.
I'II hear the People
on bail.
The defendant has
unlimited financial means
at his disposal
and no business
or familial responsibilities.
We consider him to be
a flight risk and request
remand, Your Honor.
He is a 17-year-old boy
with strong ties
to his stepmother
and his five-year-old sister.
CABOT: Who is currently
residing with relatives
at the behest of the state
pending an ACS investigation
of the stepmother.
LANGAN: AII the more reason
he's not a flight risk,
Your Honor.
CABOT: The defendant
is charged with
viciously beating
his father to death
with a baseball bat.
This is a first arrest.
He is no hardened criminal.
Bail is set at $1,000,000,
and we'II also hold onto
Mr. Fuller's passport
for the duration
of the trial.
(GAVEL BANGING)
JUDGE: Next case.
Let's move it along.
CLERK: "Docket ending..."
Take him
all of five seconds
to come up with the cash.
He didn't pull
this off alone.
Find me some evidence and
I will charge GIoria Stanfield
as a co-conspirator.
First place
I'd Iike to Iook
is her hotel room.
I can't send you
on a fishing expedition.
The judge is going to
want to know
what you're Iooking for.
Kyle's school uniform.
If he was wearing it
when he killed Fuller, it's
gotta have blood all over it.
He had to stash it
somewhere.
I'II get a warrant.
GIoria Stanfield's room,
please.
I'm sorry,
I can't give
that out.
This says
you can.
I can give you the room,
but she's not in right now.
Well, do you know
where she went?
DESK CLERK: I arranged for
a car to JFK. They didn't say
where they were going.
They? She had
her son with her?
He was young,
but I'm sure
he wasn't her son.
Not the way
they were acting.
Anything from
the passenger manifests?
We're calling on domestic
flights. There are over 70
airlines that fly out of JFK.
Well, there's no activity
on her credit card,
so if they flew,
they must've paid cash
for the tickets.
Departed on FIight 1647
to Dulles, 11:00 this morning.
DC? What the hell
they doing there?
Thanks.
They're already back.
They Ianded at JFK
two hours ago.
The other officers
have already searched
the room.
How many times
do you need to see it?
Till we find
what we're Iooking for.
Don't worry about it.
The warrant's
still valid.
The guests may be inside.
You know what?
Let's surprise them.
BENSON: NYPD.
Come on out, Kyle.
KYLE: Don't come in here!
We got a warrant to search
this room, and we're going
to start with the bed.
Hey, you forget that
Iittle detail about
not Ieaving this jurisdiction?
You blew it, buddy.
We didn't do
anything wrong.
BENSON: Yeah, you did.
So get up, get dressed,
and have your Iawyer meet you
down at the station.
We don't have to say
anything to you.
We're married now.
Where's Kyle?
In a cell at the courthouse,
waiting for a judge
to revoke his bail,
send his ass to Rikers.
Explain this to me.
You're questioning my client
because she was in bed
with her husband?
Who, up until yesterday,
was her stepson.
You want to tell us again
how you never abused him,
GIoria?
SCHAEFER: He's 17 years old.
It's not abuse.
You expect us to believe
that she waited until it was
Iegal to sleep with him?
Well, unless you have evidence
to the contrary,
you have to believe it.
I never abused him.
We're in Iove.
You're in Iove with a boy
you've raised since
he was 10 years old?
Sweetheart,
that's not Iove,
that's pedophilia.
Nothing happened
until after he was 17.
A month ago.
You must've given him
one hell of a
birthday present, GIoria.
I'II take
the blame for it.
I was Ionely.
My husband was never home.
He hadn't touched me
in over a year.
Kyle knew I was hurt.
He only wants me to be happy,
and I want the same thing
for him.
What happened between us
may be wrong in your eyes,
but we can't help
the way we feel.
The detectives will explain
to you that you've done
nothing wrong at all.
You're not blood-related.
There's no crime.
So the widow Stanfield
marries her stepson
right in the middle
of a murder investigation.
Now neither one of them
has to testify against
each other in a court.
It's a huge coincidence.
Spousal privilege protects
the sanctity of marriage,
Detectives.
Well, it also protects them
from telling the truth about
who killed Lawrence Fuller.
During the course
of their investigation,
SVU detectives discovered
the defendant
Ieft his jurisdiction,
violating the conditions
of his bail agreement.
This was obviously
not an attempt to skip bail,
Your Honor,
as evidenced by the fact
that my client was on his way
back to New York
before the detectives
knew he was gone.
The sole purpose
of this trip was to travel
to the state of Virginia,
which allows non-residents
to obtain marriage Iicenses
without waiting periods
or blood tests.
He skipped town
to get married?
Virginia also allows
a person
under the age of 18
to marry with the permission
of a Iegal guardian,
despite the fact that
the defendant was, in fact,
marrying his Iegal guardian,
his stepmother,
GIoria Stanfield,
currently under investigation
for child abuse and murder.
None of this is relevant
to the matter of bail,
Your Honor.
But it is relevant
to the defendant's trial.
This marriage is an attempt
to abuse spousal privilege
and circumvent the very
investigation which may Iand
the defendant in jail.
Whether or not the defendant
intended to avoid prosecution,
he violated
his bail agreement.
Bail is revoked.
Defendant is remanded.
Congratulations
on your nuptials,
young man.
CABOT: Get anything
from the blushing bride?
She's sticking
to her story.
Nothing happened
until after
he turned 17.
Cut her Ioose.
We sure the marriage
is valid?
According to the
Virginia State Attorney's
office.
There is nothing on the books
preventing a minor
from marrying a stepparent.
It's perfectly Iegal.
And newsworthy.
Did GIoria Stanfield
abuse her children?
Is the district attorney
planning to indict her
for her husband's murder?
CABOT: We have no comment.
Hey, does GIoria Stanfield's
pregnancy
have any effect on
the child abuse allegations?
Who told you that?
I'm not
at Iiberty to say.
Let me talk to you
a second.
Hey, hey, hey...
Right over here.
I won't reveal my sources.
You know what?
Don't give me
this intimidation crap.
First Amendment, kids.
I'm a journalist.
For the National Probe.
That's a real
respectable publication.
You guys are just pissed
because I got the goods
before you.
What'd you do?
Stake out her
doctor's office?
Bribe some receptionist
for her medical records?
AII I'm saying is,
she's knocked up.
Three months along.
And that stepson of hers
is the father.
How do you know that?
Because she brought him
with her to the appointment.
Use your brains, honey.
Why else would
she marry the kid?
Heard you're gonna be
a daddy. That true?
Don't answer that.
Why the hell not?
Whatever his answer is,
it doesn't incriminate him,
just his mother.
GIoria is my wife.
Look at him.
Know what that is?
Fatherly pride.
FIN: Kid's yours, then?
My client has no way
of knowing the paternity
of GIoria Stanfield's child.
But it's possible,
right?
Ask him something
he can actually answer
or we're done.
Did she tell you
that was your baby?
Is that why you got married?
Anything GIoria told me was
after we were married.
That means
I don't have to
answer your question.
Thank you, Detective Benson.
And they say chivalry's dead.
You shopping for
your husband's funeral
or maternity clothes?
Little bit of both.
We wanted to offer
our congratulations
to you.
And you're bringing me
a present.
Yep. Paternity test
paid for by the state.
Why?
I think
you can guess.
So you can prove
I had sex with Kyle
before he was 17.
Do I have a choice?
You can wait
until the baby is born.
We can get a court order,
but that means you have
six more months of visits
to Iook forward to
from Detective Benson
and myself
just to make sure
you don't get Iost.
Contact my attorney.
He'II set up the test.
Congratulations.
It's a boy.
Not what we
wanted to know.
Makes the paternity testing
a Iot easier.
Only have to compare
the Y-chromosomes.
Got Lawrence Fuller's
DNA from the morgue.
He and Kyle
have the same Y.
Then so should
the baby.
No. Chromosomes
don't match.
Benson.
Somebody else
is the father.
Thanks.
You're not gonna
believe this.
GIoria Stanfield
is in the hospital.
She's been raped.
DOCTOR: Came in by ambulance
about an hour ago.
Contusions to her thighs
and upper arms.
Rape kit
was positive
for fluids.
She Iose
consciousness?
Awake for the whole thing.
He hit her hard.
Bruising's pretty severe.
No sign of trauma
to the baby.
We're keeping her overnight
for observation.
Thanks.
Who did this to you,
GIoria?
I don't know.
You gonna tell us
some stranger just crawled in
through your window?
Forget it, GIoria.
You know who did it
because you were
sleeping with him.
Every word
out of your mouth
has been a Iie.
Now, you want our help,
you give us his name
and you give it to us now.
Frank Barbarossa. I did...
I had a stupid fling with him.
I ended it months ago.
I thought he was over it,
and all this time
he was just thinking up
ways to hurt me.
He the father of your baby?
Mmm-hmm.
When he found out
that I married Kyle,
he went crazy.
I really did think that Kyle
killed his father. I was just
trying to protect him.
But now you think differently.
You think this
Frank murdered
your husband.
Yes.
He said it was my fault.
That if I keep
playing games with people,
sooner or Iater
that I was going to
have to pay.
And that
if I couldn't understand that,
that he would
do the same thing to me
that he did to Lawrence.
Frank Barbarossa?
Who are you?
Police, Frankie.
You're under arrest.
What are you
arresting me for?
Raping GIoria Stanfield.
Rape? Wait a minute.
She was raped?
And beaten, tough guy.
That why you pump iron?
So you can mess up women?
No, no,
you guys are making a mistake,
you're making a mistake.
I didn't... I didn't rape her.
I didn't rape her.
Then I'm glad we got
your DNA so we can clear
your good name.
FIN: No record.
The guy's a personal trainer.
Three of his clients Iive in
GIoria Stanfield's building.
She one of them?
No.
But he was there
the night of the murder.
Doorman didn't mention it
because Barbarossa's
in the building all the time.
He checked in at 7:30,
out by 9:10.
To see who?
According to this,
one of his clients,
Greta Zabor.
But she says
the training session
ended in an hour.
Which Ieaves half an hour
unaccounted for.
What happened to GIoria?
Ah, one of those guys
who Iikes to relive it.
Yeah. AII right.
Legs, arms.
Didn't touch
the face, though,
because what fun is it
to rape a movie star if you
can't recognize her, right?
Oh, my God.
What's the matter, Frankie?
You can't stand
the sight of
your own work?
No, I didn't do this.
I Iove her, okay?
I would never Iay
a hand on her.
Where were you
Iast night?
FRANK: I was home.
Anyone confirm that?
No, no. I Iive alone.
Look, why do you guys think
this was me?
Because she fingered you.
FRANK: What?
MUNCH: She said that
you raped her
then threatened to kill her
Iike you killed her husband.
No, that's a Iie.
Read her statement, Frank.
We got you.
FIN: And we got your DNA
to match to the rape kit.
That alone will get you
12-and-a-half to 25 years of
personal training at Attica.
No, man. It ain't gonna match,
because I didn't rape her.
Of course
there's a murder conviction.
That's another 25-to-Iife.
Your parole officer
hasn't even been born yet.
Look, I'm telling you guys,
I didn't kill anybody.
Think about this,
Frankie.
The jury sees you,
the schmuck trainer
to the rich and famous.
You're jealous,
you want what they have.
So you knock up the actress,
kill the husband
and set up the son.
We got officers going through
your place right now.
You think they're gonna
find anything?
Did you throw away
those shoes
you were wearing
when you killed
that guy?
I hope so, because
blood is really
hard to rub off.
FIN: Damn near impossible.
That Iying bitch.
Tell me about it.
That bitch!
I'm gonna kill her!
Sit down!
No. No, you get me a Iawyer.
You get me a Iawyer.
I don't say anything.
Legal Aid's backed up.
Frankie won't have
representation
until tonight.
It doesn't matter. Once the
DNA comes back, no Iawyer's
gonna get him out of this.
Got the LUDs
on Barbarossa's cell.
Something interesting.
He got a call the night
of Fuller's murder at 8:40.
There's a missing half hour.
He's still someplace
inside that building.
Where was the call from?
BENSON: Pay phone
in the deli across the street.
Odds are it's one
of two people,
GIoria or Kyle.
They were both out of
the apartment by then.
I doubt Kyle's gonna call
his wife's boyfriend.
It was her.
She calls Barbarossa
minutes before
he kills her husband.
Why?
Find out.
FIN: You know this woman?
Yeah, yeah. Seen her
in the neighborhood.
Real diva, that one.
She ever been in here?
A few nights ago.
I asked her for
an autograph, she acted
Iike I was stalking her.
Screw her.
She's not that good
of an actress anyway.
What'd she come
in here for?
Made a phone call
on the payphone,
then she watched out
the window
for a few minutes,
made one more call,
then Ieft.
What was going on
out the window?
I think she was waiting
for somebody
to come out of the building
across the street.
You happen to eavesdrop
on those phone conversations?
No, man.
And I tried.
Thanks.
We got your message.
There's something wrong
with our DNA sample?
What did you do
to my sperm?
BENSON: Not a thing.
Somebody did, because
there's no way it came off
a rape victim. Look at this.
See how the tail
of each sperm is
bent at the tip?
Yeah. What does
that tell you?
This sperm was frozen.
So, unless your guy
was shooting
through ice cubes,
there's no way this semen
could have come from a rape.
Do we know
whose sperm it is?
Oh, it's your guy.
Frozen or not, the DNA
from the rape kit matched
the DNA from his towel
which matched
the paternity test.
There's another thing.
The presence of spermicide
from the rape kit sample.
Like from a condom.
That GIoria saved
after she had sex
with Frank Barbarossa.
She freezes it,
she plants it on herself
to set him up for rape.
And murder.
You drop the rape charges,
he'II plead to murder two,
minimum sentencing
recommendation.
Why should we do that?
Because he's gonna give you
GIoria Stanfield.
He agrees to testify
against her, assuming
we can corroborate his story,
and you've got a deal.
Go ahead.
The bitch set me up.
Frankie, just tell her
what you know, okay?
I'd have done
anything for her.
I didn't care about
the money and all that.
I killed the husband,
but I did it because
GIoria told me to.
CABOT: How did she
set up the murder?
She called me that night,
and she said he was crazy,
and that if I didn't do it
right then, that he was
going to kill her.
Did she pay you?
That's not why I did it.
She said she was afraid
for her Iife.
He used to knock her
and those kids around
all the time.
If he was out of the way,
that we could be together,
but he'd never Iet her go.
Telling you about her
abusive husband doesn't mean
she asked you to kill him.
Well, how the hell you think
I got in the apartment?
She gave me
the security code.
That doesn't
prove anything.
Why the hell not?
Because you were
screwing her,
so she could have
given it to you
at any time.
Yeah, but she made up
a rape to frame me.
That proves that
she's a Iiar,
not a murderer.
The kid's baseball bat.
She told me where it was
and she told me what to do
with it when I was done.
It was her idea
to set him up, too.
Mr. Barbarossa,
with your statement
you are the only person
going to jail for this murder.
I need something
I can prove.
Well, I guess she's gonna
get away with it.
We arresting her?
Nothing he said definitively
points to GIoria.
This might.
Dumped the payphone
from the deli.
That other call
that GIoria made
went to Kyle Fuller's cell.
Wonder what that
conversation entailed.
"Honey, get out of the house.
Your father's about
to get murdered."
Would explain
why he's sitting in Rikers.
He thinks she did it,
he's protecting her.
You get Kyle
to testify to that,
we've got corroboration
and an indictment
against GIoria.
When's Kyle
getting released?
I'm bringing Barbarossa's
confession before a judge
tomorrow morning
to formally drop the charges.
Kyle's a free man by noon.
And a dead man.
He cashes in that trust,
GIoria's got no reason
to keep him around anymore.
My client's being released
within the hour, Detective,
so I'm not quite sure
what we're doing here.
You know why
they're dropping
the charges?
Because I didn't
kill my father.
They tell you
who did?
Some guy that worked
in my apartment building.
No, not some guy.
Your stepmother's
boyfriend.
You think you can just
make up these Iies
and I'm gonna believe you?
You've been
sitting in prison
for one reason,
your stepmother
set you up for murder.
That's not true.
Kyle, think about it.
The weapon was
your baseball bat,
hidden under your bed.
And whose idea
was that?
It was your
stepmother's.
GIoria is my wife.
Who's having
another guy's baby.
STABLER: Results of
her paternity test.
See for yourself.
Kyle, there's no reason
to protect her anymore.
She doesn't deserve it.
It's not true.
Can't argue with DNA.
BENSON: She had
her boyfriend
kill your father.
And he did it because GIoria
told him that they would
Iive happily ever after.
She said the same thing
to you, didn't she?
But you couldn't kill him,
and so she got someone else
to do it.
But she wanted
to get married to me.
It was her idea.
So you wouldn't testify
against her.
But I would have
protected her.
She didn't have to Iie.
She called you that night
before you Ieft the apartment.
What'd she say to you?
She told me to Ieave.
That she was gonna take care
of everything, and that after
that night we'd be together.
She told me she Ioved me.
Hey, can I have
your autograph?
What, are you
following me?
We heard you made
an appointment.
Family planning services.
You're getting rid
of the baby, too.
Guess nobody's safe
around you.
Hey.
What are you doing?
Sweetheart, I told you
why I can't have the baby.
We agreed that this was
the best thing for us.
Right.
KYLE: But you said
it was mine.
Which proves
we were having sex
before I was 17.
Kyle, this is for us.
No, it's not.
Look, I know
the baby isn't mine.
So if you wanna kill it,
go ahead.
I don't care anymore.
Kyle, please.
Just tell me something.
This whole time
we were together,
this whole year,
was it all
part of your plan?
Make me Iove you
so I would do
whatever you wanted?
Absolutely not.
Because if it was,
you didn't have to do that.
You didn't have to pretend.
I already Ioved you, GIoria.
I can't remember
when I didn't.
I do Iove you, Kyle.
We're married.
That's why I don't wanna have
another man's baby.
Look, I only Iied to you
because I thought you were
too young to understand.
It was my mistake.
I will not Iet that
happen again.
I had my Iawyer do this.
It's for you.
BENSON: Petition
for divorce, GIoria.
You're gonna be
a free woman.
Not for Iong, though.
You're under arrest
for murder.
You don't know
what you're doing, Kyle.
No.
I know exactly
what I'm doing,
Mom.