NARRATOR: In the criminal
justice system,
sexually based offenses
are considered
especially heinous.
In New York City,
the dedicated detectives
who investigate
these vicious felonies
are members
of an elite squad known
as the Special Victims Unit.
These are their stories.
I told you that dog trainer
was a waste of money.
You gotta give her
the special whistle.
(WHISTLES)
(BARKING)
Radio! See?
She Iistens to me. Radio!
(CONTINUES BARKING)
Radio, come!
Instead of obedience school,
I could've bought
a flat-screen TV.
Oh, my God.
What is it?
Doug!
Oh, God. Oh, no.
Call 911.
Oh, God.
Radio.
DOUG: We walk Radio here
every morning.
So you might know
if she's a regular?
No. Her face
was such a mess,
you couldn't even tell
what she Iooked Iike.
Sorry, Detective.
I wish we could be
more helpful.
If anything
comes to mind.
Ray.
Yeah?
Walk these two
out for me, will you?
Sure thing, Munch.
Thanks.
RAY: AII right.
Come on, Iet's go.
(SIREN WAILING)
Over by the benches.
Keep moving.
Looks Iike she's
in her 50s or 60s.
The only ID
is a key on a string.
Any Iuck?
The guys saw nothing.
What about her?
Beaten, stabbed,
the whole nine.
Body's still warm.
What he did to her face
he repeated down below.
Check this out.
It's a dog's paw print.
Too small to be
that retriever's.
Yeah, well,
she carries dog treats.
Maybe the print
belonged to her own pooch.
MAN: Detectives,
check this out.
BIoody knife
wrapped in plastic.
We're not gonna be able
to get any prints
off that bag.
What's that?
What?
Disposable rain poncho.
He used it
to protect himself
from the spatter.
Bright, sunny day,
nobody notices the guy.
Just another freak
in the big city.
So where's this pup
while its master's
getting mauled?
Tied to this tree.
No tags.
Dog wiggles free.
Runs to her
and Ieaves the paw print.
And doesn't stay.
Maybe Lassie
went to get help.
Thirty-seven
deep puncture wounds
to the chest,
mostly on the breasts.
Angry son of a bitch.
Acute pneumothorax.
She drowned
in her own blood.
Did the perp Ieave
his calling card?
No fluids.
But the vaginal wounds
had wooden splinters.
Matches the bark
from this branch
we found at the scene.
BIood belongs to the victim.
Any Iuck with the prints?
Nothing yet.
We'II need to do
a facial reconstruction.
He smashed her nose,
cheekbones, jaw.
One eye was
completely destroyed.
She was also wearing this.
Wow. That's some ring.
Whoever married her
has some bucks.
Well, I hope
he misses her soon.
We'II check
the diamond district,
see if anyone recognizes
the craftsmanship.
This might speed things up.
Look for a missing woman
in her 60s with a Iimp.
How'd you get that?
Her right Ieg
is one inch shorter
than the Ieft,
probably from
childhood polio.
Vaccine didn't
come out till 1954.
So, we're talking
classic overkill.
M.E. says that any one
of the puncture wounds
would've done the job.
Perp wanted her to suffer
and got off on it.
GIad you could join us.
Sorry, parent-teacher
conference ran Iate.
Read it and weep.
Guy could be
some psycho
high after a night
of fun and games.
Or a deluded park dweller
who forgot to take his meds.
Or it's personal.
Poncho,
that feels premeditated.
What do we know about her?
CRAGEN: She's a Jane Doe
in the park.
Which is why
I don't have time
for theories.
The media is already
breathing down my neck.
You gotta give me
something solid.
There's nothing to tell.
Central Park precinct
said that there's no assault
that matches the MO.
There's no open rapes.
Animal control
is reaching out
to vets and shelters.
Pretty brazen
for broad daylight.
I mean,
with this much rage,
maybe the perp
did it before.
We should check MOs
on assaults on older women.
I'II get a citywide run.
You two,
go back to the park,
take as much help
as you need.
Joggers have routines.
Maybe somebody knew her.
That was the pet police.
Pooch was brought to a vet
with bloody paws.
Joggers found him
in the park, all bloody.
Thought he was hurt,
brought him here.
And you washed the blood off?
Only way to see
if he was injured.
Any ID?
Nothing.
No tattoo, no microchip.
Microchip?
Implanted subcutaneously,
programmed with
the owner's name
and phone number.
Stray comes in,
we scan for them first thing.
BIood's gone,
so is our evidence.
Sorry,
but I kept this.
Had it in his mouth
when he came in.
Dogs Iove shoes.
It's 'cause it's got
your mommy's scent on it, huh?
It's the right sneaker
from her shorter Ieg.
That's why she needed this.
Orthodic insert,
kept everything evened out.
MUNCH:
Manufactured by Ortho-Walk.
We're gonna take the shoe
and the dog. Thanks.
It's our work, all right.
Where did you get it?
Off the foot
of an unidentified
murder victim.
Do you know
who you made it for?
It's easy to find out.
Each one has a serial number.
Let's see, number AV-0419.
I told you, you should've Ieft
that mutt in the car.
Do you know how many dogs
die in Iocked cars every year?
You know how many cops
shoot their partner
and get off on a justifiable?
Oh, dear,
it belongs to Dr. Esterman.
Doctor?
Works for the
Department of Health.
This our witness?
First time
I ever printed a dog.
Paw print is a match
to the one
on the victim's body.
What's with the swab?
Dog broke Ioose,
maybe chased the perp
and got a piece of him.
I'II run everything
through Serology,
check for human DNA,
but it Iooks Iike Fido there
got a good bath.
Victim's Greta Esterman,
a public health doctor.
She Iives at
3 West 89th Street.
Got a next of kin?
Husband's name is Arthur,
some kind of society Iawyer.
Okay, we'II
make notification.
EIIiot, aren't you
forgetting someone?
(DOG WHIMPERING)
I never should've Iet
Greta go out alone.
BENSON: Mr. Esterman,
we have to ask you this.
Where were you
this morning?
I didn't Ieave the house
until 9:00 to play tennis.
Weren't you worried
when your wife
didn't come home
from the park?
Since I retired
from my Iaw firm,
I've found a new vice,
sleeping Iate.
Greta always dresses
in the other room,
so she doesn't wake me.
BENSON: And the dog?
ARTHUR: She often takes
Buddy to work.
It's 10:00 right now.
You weren't worried
what might've happened to her?
Greta's been
working Iate recently.
I didn't think
anything about it.
What kind of work did she do?
She treated people
with HIV.
Greta traced the source
of exposure patterns.
Some people thought her work
violated their privacy.
Probably made some enemies.
The nature
of the attack suggests
the killer may
have known your wife.
Anyone have
a vendetta against her,
or make any threats?
Occasionally, over the years.
But Iast month,
she got a threatening
phone call.
I heard the man's voice.
He called on your home phone?
No. No, Greta's office.
I was waiting to take her
to Iunch when the phone rang.
I thought it might be Greta,
so I answered.
The guy was a Iunatic,
said she'd ruined his Iife,
so he was going to ruin hers.
She got a Iot
of nasty calls.
Hate mail, too.
Contact tracers
are about as popular
as repo men.
When you inform people
they've been exposed to HIV,
they want to know by whom.
We can't tell them,
so things can get
pretty heated.
Anyone ever go
beyond threats?
Get physical?
Nasty incident Iast year.
Guy set his pit bull
on one of our tracers.
Didn't stop Greta.
She was dedicated.
She just gave her staff
pepper spray.
Here's her office.
Commissioner,
we're gonna need
a Iist of the cases
where there were any
threats of violence.
I wanna help,
but the names
of AIDS patients
are confidential.
So, how about the hate mail?
That's not private,
it's evidence.
I've got all her
personal papers
right here.
I'II also give you
her phone Iog.
Greta installed
caller ID Iast year,
noted everything.
Ever have these threats
checked out?
I wanted to,
but Greta talked me out of it.
She said
anger's a normal response,
they'd move on to acceptance.
STABLER: Estermans were quite
the social couple.
Fire and Ice Ball
for breast cancer,
black-tie fundraiser
for the city blood bank.
They donated 20 grand,
they each gave a pint of blood
to kick off the drive.
Last month, the AIDS activists
threw pig's blood on her,
protesting her policies.
How about this?
"Snoopy bitch doctor,
you die."
Hey, Esterman's story
check out?
Neighbor saw him Ieave
just after 9:00,
and he showed up
to his tennis game on time.
Find anything?
Yeah, Iots of angry people.
She's trying to save Iives,
and they hate her for it.
There's a fine Iine
between the right
to privacy and prevention.
People have a right
to know if they've been
exposed to HIV.
I just get
a Iittle nervous
when the government
starts drawing up Iists.
PIease don't
get him started.
He goes off
on black helicopters,
and we'II be here all night.
This might be something.
A phone Iog,
three weeks ago,
"Anonymous male states
"that he will
copulate me to death."
That's pretty much
what happened.
You got a caller ID?
Yeah, I do.
Roger Pomerantz.
So, she knew who called,
why didn't she turn him in?
You remember Greta's boss
said she was a true believer.
Maybe she saw this guy
as a patient, not a problem.
Maybe she wound up dead,
thinking Iike that.
We've got a winner.
Roger Pomerantz,
former guest of the state.
Six years at Greenhaven
for sodomy one.
Released two months ago,
hasn't been checking in
with parole.
Guy makes threatening calls
from his home phone.
What an idiot.
They didn't hire him
for his brains.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
There he is.
Roger Pomerantz.
Hands where we can
see them. Now!
Coming your way!
(METALLIC CLATTERING)
FIN: Incoming.
(GRUNTING)
Resisting's a parole
violation, Roger.
Bite me!
We're gonna do
a Iot worse.
BENSON: That's quite
a résumé you have.
Menacing, gun charges,
assault one...
Knifepoint stranger rape.
She was a hooker
who got pissed off
because I wouldn't pay her
for a Iousy Iay.
How's your
sex Iife, Rog?
Still have
to force women?
I just got married.
I get all I want.
She could use a good...
What?
I could use a good what?
She's a piece of work, huh?
You don't Iike women
with authority, do you?
No, I don't.
Like Greta Esterman?
That bitch got in my business.
Said she's gonna call my wife
and tell her
that I have gonorrhea.
So, you're stupid enough
to get the clap?
The Iaw says that Dr. Esterman
had to tell her.
So you called up the doc
to Iet her know
exactly how you felt, right?
I was just exercising my right
for freedom of speech.
Is that a crime?
No, it isn't, but murder is.
Murder?
I didn't murder anyone!
You crazy!
Sit down!
Where are you going
with my table?
Sit down.
Dr. Esterman wound up dead,
just Iike you said she would.
I don't know jack
about that.
Relax. Relax. Relax now.
Come on.
Let's just talk here,
all right?
Where were you
yesterday morning
around 7:00 a.m.?
7:00 a.m.?
Yeah. Relax.
It's my Iucky day.
I was at the diner,
eating breakfast
with the guys,
and then we all drove
to work together.
Pomerantz's alibi
checked out.
Verified how?
Waitress at
the greasy spoon
he eats at every morning.
Usual breakfast,
usual Iousy tip.
He Ieft for Queens at 7:00.
Pomerantz and his two boys
clocked in at 8:00.
No time for a detour.
Captain Cragen?
Yes. Yes.
I'm Arthur Esterman.
My wife is Greta.
Yes. Yes. Of course.
What can we
do for you?
POMERANTZ: I told you
I never touched that old Iady.
I should sue both of you
for false arrest.
Sweetheart, you were
never under arrest.
So Iet me go.
Murderer!
STABLER: You forgot to call
your parole officer,
and he really
wants to see you.
Get that guy!
Come on, break them up!
I'II kill you!
I wanna press charges.
SERGEANT: Get in there.
Get in there!
PIease, we're doing
everything we can,
Mr. Esterman.
I want you to go home
and Iet us do our job.
I found something
that could help.
CRAGEN: Take Mr. Esterman
to the Iounge.
Forty years of marriage,
I don't know how
to sleep alone.
I was just wandering
around the apartment.
I found my way
into Greta's study,
to be closer to her,
and then I remembered.
Greta brought work home
Iast week.
She was worried
about this case.
Any idea
what this means?
Greta said it had to do
with a terrible situation
she had to stop.
She didn't tell you
what it was about?
Greta didn't talk much
about her work.
I guess this
won't do any good
if nobody can translate it.
We have someone
who might be able
to help us out.
Took me most of the night,
but I figured out
what Dr. Esterman
was working on.
Looks Iike a bunch
of circles and arrows.
Tell me about it.
I've been seeing circles
and arrows all night.
What it is,
is a contact trace.
Each circle represents
a person with HIV,
connected to the partner
that gave it to them.
Greta was trying to identify
the common source
of infection.
So, you're saying that
all these cases are connected?
WARNER: Greta thought so.
These people
all Iive in Little Italy,
but most of them
don't know each other.
You think she was Iooking
for an HIV positive guy
who had sex
with Iots of partners.
And they, in turn,
had sex with other people,
and pretty soon,
you got dozens
infected with HIV
all because of
that first guy.
We call him the nexus.
He's the center
of this mini-epidemic.
Sounds to me Iike a sociopath
who's not concerned
with how many people
he infects.
Guys in St. Louis
and Jamestown
were prosecuted for that.
Right. They knew
they were infected with HIV,
but still had unprotected sex
without warning
their partners.
Well, if this nexus thought
Greta was close to IDing him,
that'd be a good motive
for murder.
Well, a couple
of Greta's death threats
came from pay phones
in Little Italy.
Let's pick up
the investigation
where she Ieft off
and maybe we'II get Iucky.
Greta had a couple people
Ieft to interview.
Here's the Iist.
Starts with
a college student,
Mike Andretti.
Mike, why didn't you
wear a condom?
I'm Catholic.
My mom
catches me with one,
I'm dead.
Now I'm dead anyway.
That's not true.
There are new drugs,
people Iead full Iives.
I'm talking about
if my mom
ever finds out.
Who'd you sleep with?
This totally hot woman
from my friend's building.
She was all over me,
said her husband didn't know
what he was missing.
BENSON: Is she
the first sexual partner
you ever had?
Yeah.
I swear.
We're gonna need her name.
You talk to her,
the whole neighborhood's
gonna find out.
BENSON: She might not
even know she's sick.
She Iooked fine.
Her name's Vincenza Agosto.
It's all that bastard
Joey's fault.
Who's Joey?
He'II be my dead husband
if I ever get my hands on him.
Where's Joey now?
With that stripper
he's been banging.
Does he know
you have HIV?
Lucky son of a bitch
didn't get it.
Man upstairs
has a sick sense of humor.
Who infected you?
Month before the wedding,
I cut Joey off.
You know,
wait till we're married,
save some energy
for the honeymoon.
Joey's, Iike,
"Sure, no problem."
Yeah, it's 'cause
he had that slut on the side.
How'd you find out?
We get back
from Niagara Falls,
he's given me chlamydia.
I confront Joey about it,
he admits it.
I'm so pissed,
I figure I'II show him.
How many guys
did you sleep with?
Just that college kid, Mike.
He swears he got it
from you.
Who else?
This guy, Mario.
Bartender at a club.
No Mario ever worked here.
Mario tell you
to say that?
Hey, man, it's Iike
I told everybody else.
Who else
did you tell?
Nobody.
Did you tell her?
Oh, right, the doctor.
She wouldn't say
what it was about.
I just figured
it was some kind
of paternity thing.
Wrong.
Well, what's it about, then?
FIN: Health Department.
Looking for people
who spread HIV.
You mean AIDS?
You're pretty shook up
for somebody that
doesn't know any Mario.
He quit working here
a couple weeks ago
after the doctor came around.
You and him share girls?
No, Mario, he's too far
out there for me, man.
This guy's into orgies,
threesomes, you know,
another girl, another guy,
anything to get off.
FIN: Then why you Iook
so spooked?
You and him shared needles.
Yeah, but not dope.
Image enhancers.
You mean steroids?
Yeah.
Now I'm gonna
have to get tested, right?
I'm really screwed
here, guys.
So is everybody
you ever slept with.
We're gonna
need a Iist.
Dr. Esterman
identified 47 cases
within five distinct clusters
before she was killed.
Find anything else?
We continued her trace
and we picked up
32 more cases.
The nexus
appears to be one man.
Enter Mario Molinari.
Twelve women, two men
connect directly to him.
The rest are sexual partners
of his sexual partners.
Promiscuous,
sexually indiscriminate
and infected.
This one-man epidemic
have any priors?
Assault, rob one,
weapons possession,
and it was a knife.
Guy's from the neighborhood.
He has an apartment
on Hester Street.
Well, Iet's go find
Typhoid Mario.
Sure I know Mario,
who doesn't?
Popular guy, Iot of girls
come Iooking for him.
You're not the first.
She one of them?
No. No, young girls, pretty.
Madonna, che bellissima.
STABLER: Any idea
where Don Juan is now?
Sure, he's up
at St. Catherine's.
Let me guess,
he's an altar boy, too.
No, not the church,
the hospital.
Ambulance came for him.
Hey, he probably
wore himself out
with all that bada bing, huh?
BENSON: We hear
you're quite popular
with the Iadies.
Yeah, can I help it
if I'm a chick magnet?
Popular with
the fellows, too.
Now, who I sleep with
is none of your business.
Is that what
you told Dr. Esterman?
Nosy bitch.
Why does she care who I bang?
Maybe she's jealous,
she wants a piece of me, too.
AII the Iadies do.
I don't think they would
if they knew you had AIDS.
Dr. Esterman knew, right?
Is that why you killed her?
Doc got capped.
Hmm.
I'm crushed. Wish I'd seen it.
Did you?
Not from this bed.
That's private. Hey.
I can see why.
In for treatment
of pneumocystis,
AIDS-related pneumonia.
(WOMAN CHATTERING ON P.A.)
Been in for six days. Not him.
You've been sick a Iong time,
haven't you, Casanova?
Some slut gave me the virus,
didn't give a damn.
Well, I don't give
a damn either.
And the Iaw says
you can't tell anyone.
Don't have to.
You can't do that!
Wrong, you knew you had AIDS,
you had unprotected sex,
and you didn't warn
your partners.
That's a crime.
I'II charge Mario
with attempted murder,
reckless endangerment,
add statutory rape
for the underage girls.
And the victims
we didn't find?
Who warns them
that they've been
exposed to HIV?
Same thing
happened upstate.
Health department went public,
posted flyers,
people came in
and got tested.
What's up?
Another body in the park.
FEMALE REPORTER: Has the
Central Park Stalker
struck again?
We haven't established
a forensic connection
between the murders as of yet.
So you're ruling out
a serial killer?
Well, we're not
ruling anything out
until we finish gathering
all our evidence.
AII right, there'II be
another briefing Iater.
Thank you very much.
(REPORTERS CHATTERING)
I don't know
if she was raped,
but I think it was
close enough
to your Jane Doe.
Who found her?
Mountie.
Shook him up
pretty bad.
(WOMAN CHATTERING ON RADIO)
Stabler and Benson,
Special Victims.
They got some
questions for you.
I've seen DOAs before,
but nothing Iike this.
You see anybody around?
No, this part of the park
doesn't get much traffic,
too wooded for the joggers
and dog walkers.
I just saw Mona
Iaying there.
You know the victim?
Mona Sidley.
Recognized her
by her binoculars.
Not by her face?
She doesn't
have one anymore.
BIood's all Mona's, no fluids.
Found one foreign hair,
we'II test for DNA.
But outdoors, could be
random contamination.
Got any good news?
Similar knife,
based on the injury depth
and serration pattern.
Two bodies, three days.
He's on a rapid cycle.
May not be the same guy.
Same Iocation,
victimology matches,
bodies stabbed and mutilated
in the same way.
Greta Esterman
was stabbed 37 times.
Mona Sidley, only six.
And Mona's facial injuries
aren't nearly as extensive.
BENSON: He use
a tree branch again?
Vaginal wounds
had slivers of glass.
He probably used
a broken bottle.
Which he could've
found in the park,
Iike the tree branch
he used on Greta.
Seems Iike
too many similarities
for a copycat.
Could've gotten the details
from the newspapers.
You held back
the tree branch,
this time
he didn't use one.
I'm just not sure
it's the same guy.
Same guy,
no doubt about it.
Walk us through it.
Right off the bat,
another yellow poncho.
New knife, with the same
plastic-bag trick
around the handles.
Tell us something
we don't know.
Same distinctive
waffle tread
at both scenes.
Matched it to a
standard hiking boot,
size 10.
Follow the shoe again.
This case
is a foot fetishist's
wet dream.
See, a heavy Iog sole
not only makes impressions,
it traps dirt.
So what?
You walk anywhere
in the park,
your shoes are gonna
get mucked up.
Look, soil from the area
where Greta jogged.
High mica and schist contents,
normal for Central Park,
rare anywhere else.
A sample from where
Greta's body was dumped.
Heavy amount of pollen spores.
And this, this is soil
from the Sidley scene.
A special mix
of organic rich peat
only the
Parks Department uses.
We catch the guy,
we snag his shoes.
A match to all three samples
will be conclusive.
I can testify to that.
Same perp. End of story.
Okay, then explain
why our guy is Iosing passion
when brutality
usually escalates
with serial killers.
Maybe he got interrupted.
Or he's gaining
more self-control
with experience.
Practice makes perfect.
But the post-offense
behavior changed, too.
He drags Greta
into the bushes,
takes the time
to cover her up with Ieaves.
As angry as he was,
that could show compassion.
But he Ieft Mona exposed.
That's crap.
He was hiding the body.
Okay, why didn't he
hide Mona?
MUNCH: Maybe he Iikes
the attention,
wants to be
on the front page again.
Same guy.
Picks off defenseless,
older women
that are usually alone.
Or there's a connection
between the two victims.
Both regulars in the park
every morning.
Both older women.
I don't know,
maybe they knew each other.
Mona Iived alone,
she was never married.
Retired bookkeeper.
Haven't Iocated any
of her friends yet.
We gotta talk
to Greta's friends.
That appointment book
in her office,
she had a standing Iunch date
with a Bonnie Vernon.
Greta never mentioned
any friends
who were bird-watchers.
She ever say anything
about being followed?
No, and it's
definitely something
she would've told me.
How Iong
had you known her?
Greta and I
were roommates at Radcliffe.
She met Arthur at Harvard.
They eloped
after graduation in '61.
They eloped, huh?
Why did they elope?
Her family
were against the marriage.
Greta came from old money.
They didn't think
Arthur could
support her properly.
Well, it Iooks Iike
Arthur proved them wrong.
They seem to Iive pretty well.
On Greta's inheritance.
Arthur practiced
his tennis swing
more than he practiced Iaw.
Happy marriage?
Perfect couple.
Affairs?
Oh, never.
Arthur's so old-fashioned,
I don't think his eyes
even wander.
How about Greta?
A few months ago,
she asked me to run
a credit report on a man.
Greta didn't say why,
but I did wonder.
You thought
Greta had a Iover?
It had to be personal.
Greta had city investigators
at her disposal
for her AIDS cases.
Do you remember a name?
Who could forget it?
Vartan Dadian.
I remember thinking
Greta had an Armenian admirer.
Are you implying
my wife was having an affair?
BENSON: We're not jumping
to any conclusions.
I can't believe it.
Did anything seem different
about Greta recently?
The Iast few months,
she wasn't quite herself.
She seemed preoccupied,
but she said it was from work.
You said
she often worked Iate.
Any change in her routines?
Sometimes she worked
all night,
didn't come home.
Greta said bars and clubs
were a good place
to trace contacts.
Mr. Esterman,
does the name Vartan Dadian
mean anything to you?
No, but if she had
a boyfriend,
I doubt I'd know his name.
I thought we had
a perfect marriage.
I subpoenaed
Vartan Dadian's financials.
Upper East Side address,
banks at Hudson Trust.
Routine transactions,
pension checks go in,
rent and small
expenses go out.
There's not much
ready cash.
Right. But there's plenty
at another account
at West Side Bank.
Opened it up Iast year,
statements go to
a P.O. box.
Those are some
big deposits,
Iooks Iike close to
20 grand a month
for the past year.
AII wire transfers.
AII from Greta Esterman's
personal account.
Well, she's supporting a man
with very expensive tastes.
Look at all these
debit card transactions.
Four star hotels,
top restaurants.
Greta's boy toy
had himself a good time
on her money.
And she's not
his only girlfriend.
Mr. Dadian has a fondness
for expensive escorts.
Spent a small fortune
at Gold Coast Models.
We don't take walk-ins.
You need a referral
from a client.
FIN: We got a special pass.
(PHONE RINGING)
(IN SEXY VOICE)
Welcome to Gold Coast Models,
Angel speaking. PIease hold.
Hey, stop!
You can't go in there.
Sure, we can.
Darla, I got two cops
on their way in.
Come in, officers.
I have nothing to hide.
It's a Iegitimate business.
We provide social escorts
for executives.
FIN: Save the rap for vice.
We just want some information.
I wish all men
were so easy to satisfy.
Who's satisfying
Vartan Dadian?
Miss Kitty, on a daily basis.
FIN: Quite a collection
of Iadies.
Which one of these Iovelies
is Miss Kitty?
She's not up there.
Kitty retired Iast month.
Said Dadian
was gonna buy her a condo
and set her up
Iike a queen.
Where's Kitty Iiving
the Iife of Iuxury?
Still waiting for payday.
I hear she's working the bar
at the Broadway Terrace Hotel.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
What, is something wrong
with Vartan?
That's what
we'd Iike to know.
When's the Iast time
you saw him?
I'm not sure.
You better remember quick,
before we haul your sweet ass
down to the precinct.
You want to cuff me?
Drop the act.
Answer the question,
when was the Iast time
you saw Vartan?
Two nights ago,
he took me to dinner.
Where'd you have dessert?
Upstairs in a hotel suite.
FIN: Spend the night?
No, that costs extra,
and he was a Iittle short.
I went home,
he stayed and slept.
The poor man,
he was all worn out.
Yeah, I'm sure
he had nothing Ieft to give.
Well, usually
he's Iike the Energizer Bunny,
just keeps going
and going and...
We get the picture.
Are we done?
I'm expecting someone.
Well, cancel it
'cause you're coming with us.
Am I under arrest?
Keep touching me,
you will be.
Sex crimes?
What on Earth
brings you to me?
BENSON: Your name came up
in an investigation.
We're interested
in some dates
you had recently.
I'm flattered.
Most people think
there's no sex after 60,
but I'm not seeing
anyone right now.
How could you
forget Kitty?
Now, I know
you've got the wrong guy.
I'm really not interested
in pussy cats.
An escort service,
Gold Coast Models?
They claim
you're a major client.
I've never heard
of them.
Your bank has.
My account's
not at West Side.
Have you had any problems
with credit card fraud
or identity theft?
No, but I will call my bank
in the morning.
Does the name Greta Esterman
mean anything to you?
That poor woman
in the park?
I read about her
in the papers.
How did my name come up?
There seems to have been
a grave misunderstanding.
Thank you.
Did you go to Harvard?
Yes, I got my acting start
at the Hasty Pudding.
What year did you graduate?
1961.
Hmm.
Is that a problem?
No.
We always meet
at four-star restaurants.
Vartan has very good taste.
Never would've guessed.
Where'd you go
two nights ago?
Chez Marco.
I met him there at 9:00.
Do you want to know
what I ate?
I'm not touching that one.
What kind of mood
was Vartan in?
His usual charming self.
He's everything
a girl could want.
If the price is right.
Where did you go
after dinner?
Like I told you before,
back to the hotel.
If there's nothing else,
I'II be going now.
Stay awhile.
John.
A few too many guys
in this game
went to Harvard.
Why don't you show her this
and ask her to pick out
her playmate?
Great.
Thought you'd Iike it.
Before your
next appointment,
can you tell me
if you recognize
any of these men?
Well, sure, that's my Vartan.
The night of his wife's death,
the grief-stricken husband
has a date with a prostitute?
No wonder he wasn't worried
about her coming home Iate.
He booked another one
for right after
her funeral.
This Esterman is a class act.
CRAGEN:
So, either he killed her
because she found out
about the money,
or so he could Iive
happily ever after
with Miss Kitty.
It's both.
Those wire transfers
to Vartan Dadian?
Greta was in the bank
Iast week,
asking questions about them.
The money's
from Greta's account,
but every transaction
is authorized by Esterman.
CRAGEN: Hard to believe
an AIDS doctor
would tolerate
his indiscretions,
much Iess pay
for his hookers.
MUNCH: Esterman didn't give
her much time
to throw him out.
Greta went
to the bank on Friday,
and Monday morning,
we found her body.
Greta divorces Arthur,
he's broke.
She winds up dead.
He inherits everything.
It's still all circumstantial.
Arthur's gonna keep up
this poor, old widower routine
until we find
some hard evidence.
His hooker ID'd him,
that should be enough
for a search warrant.
STABLER: Arthur's been making
some big transfers
into the bogus Dadian account
at West Side Bank.
That kind of cash
would get him
quite a few dates
with Miss Kitty.
This guy had it all
planned out.
He gives us his wife's
phone threats.
He knew we'd go for it.
And then he murders
Mona Sidley
to make it Iook Iike
a serial killer
did them both.
That is cold.
What the hell
is going on here?
Counselor.
Search warrant.
You think I killed Greta?
That's ridiculous.
Size 10.
And very dirty.
You should really
take better care
of your stuff, Artie.
This is preposterous.
I Ioved my wife.
More than you Iove Miss Kitty?
Who?
"Who?"
Now, come on,
your Iittle plaything.
Broadway terrace,
candles, champagne.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
BENSON: Save it, Vartan.
Or is that just the name
that you use for the hookers?
The rock fragments
embedded in the soles,
electron microscope confirms
it's Central Park schist.
So he takes walks
in the park.
We need
more than that.
Ran the second sample
by a forensic palynologist.
Excuse me?
Pollen specialist.
So good with spores,
they can tell you
which side of the street
to walk on
during allergy season.
Second sample
was Ioaded with pollen.
See, my buddy
extracted the signature,
typed the dominant
and secondary strains,
and several hundred
trace species were found...
Skip the science test.
Did it match?
Perfectly.
Boots were within a few yards
of the body and recently,
since pollen signatures change
with the growing cycle.
And what about
the Iast sample
from the
Sidley homicide?
Look for yourself.
Homicide scene on the Ieft,
Esterman boots on the right.
I'm no scientist,
but they Iook the same.
Exactly.
BENSON: Your footprints
match the boots.
ARTHUR: Mine?
PIease, Detective.
They're a popular style.
It's obviously a coincidence.
"Coincidence."
Well, then it must
also be a coincidence
that the dirt on your boots
matches both murder scenes.
Not at all.
I went there yesterday
to Iay flowers,
say a prayer for my wife
and for poor Miss Sidley.
Not to manufacture
a forensics alibi,
of course.
You're wasting time
accusing me.
I Ioved my wife.
Well, you've got
a pretty sick way
of showing it.
Fake names,
secret accounts,
call girls.
Once again,
you misjudge me, Detective.
I did those things
out of respect for Greta.
Respect? Come on.
After menopause,
Greta Iost interest
in sex. I didn't.
She only asked
that I be discreet,
hence the pseudonym.
So you expect us to believe
that Greta
didn't have a problem
with your high-risk
sexual activity?
We were married
over 40 years, Detective.
Other kinds of fidelity
matter far more.
Well, you know,
if everything
that you're saying is true,
why don't you just give us
a DNA sample?
My DNA
on my own wife's body
means nothing.
I'd expect to see it there.
But not on Mona Sidley.
Found a hair.
We can get a court order.
You have nothing
connecting me
to Mona Sidley.
You killed Mona Sidley
to distract us.
You're bootstrapping.
It's clear the same man
killed both women.
Your DNA on Sidley's body,
that'II prove it.
JFK and Martin Luther King
were both assassinated
by a Ione gunman
with a Iong-range rifle.
Follow your Iine of reasoning,
and Lee Harvey Oswald
killed them both.
No judge will sign
a blood order.
CABOT: He's defending
himself well.
We don't have enough
to force a sample
from Esterman.
We need probable cause
on Sidley alone,
it can't be cumulative.
Well, how about
the phony name?
Even if I was just charging
on his wife's death,
a judge would preclude
that as unduly prejudicial.
Then we arrest him
for identity theft.
Can't.
Esterman paid the bills,
so there was no intent
to defraud.
I'II be Iucky if the judge
Iets me use it as an alias.
Well, no blood sample,
no case.
Maybe Esterman already gave.
Fundraiser for the city
blood bank.
Your Honor,
if you allow this,
anyone who gives blood
could have their
rights trampled on.
The blood was obtained
from its Iawful owner,
the blood bank,
which chose not
to contest our subpoena.
Mr. Esterman
has no standing here.
What about my fundamental
right to privacy?
That expectation expired
when you donated the blood,
knowing full well
it would be tested.
For diseases, not DNA.
I respect your right
to privacy is paramount,
but your own actions
do diminish that argument.
She's using my
philanthropic activities
to justify an end-run
around the judicial system.
She knew full well
she didn't have grounds
for a blood order.
I couldn't compel a sample
from Mr. Esterman,
but there is no Iegal basis
to bar us from testing
what he gave away freely.
Agreed.
But I'm Iimiting the scope.
Your Honor,
the sample in question...
I'm sorry, Miss Cabot,
but I'm only
allowing you to test
for the same battery
of drugs and diseases
that the blood bank would.
No DNA.
Esterman's blood type's AB,
and he's free of any diseases.
STABLER: So we're screwed.
You're not,
but your suspect is,
I'd say on a regular basis.
You know this
from the blood?
WARNER: Tox screen
came back positive
for high Ievels
of Viagra and ecstasy.
Viagra, I understand
but ecstasy?
What's a guy Esterman's age
doing using a club drug?
To enhance
his sexual encounters.
Viagra gives you potency.
Ecstasy heightens sensation
and Iowers inhibitions.
And in the quantity
he took them,
your guy would've had
a two-week hard-on.
He was in his own
private rave.
The ecstasy
is all we got.
Anything short
of a smoking gun,
Esterman walks
on both homicides.
So what? We collar him
'cause he Iikes to party.
Well, it's amazing
what drug dealers
know about their clients.
A guy using
this much ecstasy
gotta have
a steady supplier.
So we dump his phones.
Fin can reach out
to narcotics,
see if any
of the numbers ring a bell.
You Fin?
You the man
with the vitamin E?
For the right price.
Yeah.
It's all there.
AII right, Iisten,
trail-mix all at once,
you're gonna need two women.
That's what my man
Vartan told me.
Hey, man, no names.
I gotta jet.
Stick around.
Now, you tell us
about Vartan,
we're gonna Iet
this one slide.
Or we can take you with us,
dealer's choice.
He's a steady customer.
How's he know you?
Dropped some off
for this chick, Kitty.
Vartan was partying with her,
Iiked to ride the E-train,
so we set up his own account.
Where?
He's got a Iove shack on 92nd Street.
Just dropped some off
a few hours ago.
You have no right!
Search warrant!
Which you violated
when you burst in
without knocking.
Exigent circumstances.
We heard a woman moaning.
Are you all right?
I was until you
interrupted me.
You get dressed.
You, too, Counselor.
Your next date's
with a judge.
He didn't do anything.
You get hazardous duty pay
for sleeping with a killer?
What are you
talking about?
Don't say
another word, darling.
Didn't Arthur tell you
he murdered his wife
and another woman?
Don't Iisten to them.
He would never kill anyone.
He taking you to Brazil?
Brazil?
Airline ticket,
one way, first class.
I don't see one
in here for you, Kitty.
Yours hasn't come yet.
It better come quick
since the ticket's
for tomorrow.
I had to.
They were harassing me.
You know I Iove you.
(SCOFFS)
You were going by yourself.
Kitty, did you use
a condom tonight?
No, I trusted the bastard.
You have no right to hold me
when I'm not under arrest.
Kitty gave us the DNA sample
you deposited.
You'II find it's a match
to the DNA
I Ieft on poor Mona Sidley.
So, now you feel
sorry for her.
I'm sorry she had to die.
Is that a confession?
Do you know what it's Iike
to grow old, Detective?
Greta and I were married
for 40 years
when she
Iost interest in sex.
So you turned to prostitutes.
That's how
I found Kitty.
When I couldn't
keep up with her,
she gave me Viagra
and ecstasy.
Made me feel
Iike I was 18 again.
I was hooked.
How did Greta find out?
From the bank.
She confronted me.
I told her everything.
Begged her to try the ecstasy,
rekindle our passion.
She Iooked at me Iike I was
an animal.
You had high-risk sex,
just Iike the people
that she had to trace.
I'm not Iike them.
I'm not infected.
She wanted to divorce you,
take away her money.
That's why you killed her.
A beautiful woman
Iike you
wouldn't give me
a second Iook
if I wasn't rich.
What are you
gonna do when your wife
turns you away?
You'd do exactly what I did.
You murdered
a complete stranger.
You mutilated your wife.
Nothing justifies that.
I was alive again
for the first time in years.
Greta tried to take it away.
I had to stop her.