NARRATOR: In the criminal
justice system,
sexually based offenses
are considered
especially heinous.
In New York City,
the dedicated detectives
who investigate
these vicious felonies
are members
of an elite squad known
as the Special Victims Unit.
These are their stories.
DAVE: My girlfriend,
she hates that I do this.
She wants me to quit.
JOE: She won't complain
when you find her
that diamond ring.
'Cause that happens?
Oh, man!
You wouldn't believe
the stuff folks
throw away. Oh!
Oh, what the hell
is that?
I don't
smell nothing.
Oh, man, you're crazy.
That thing stinks.
It may smell bad,
but the pay is good.
Not good enough.
Break up that mass
before it jams
the grinder.
The damn thing's stuck.
Let me see that.
Is that a hand?
Holy mother of God.
M.E. says she's five,
maybe six years old.
Raped and murdered.
Came in with
a Ioad of garbage.
Where from?
Commercial dumpster.
Half the carting
companies in the city
offload here.
Is there any way to tell
which truck
brought the body in?
PIant manager says
they get more than
a hundred trucks
in here every day,
and they all dump in one heap
that feeds into the maw.
You see everything
on that belt?
Yeah, what about it?
Once the M.E. is done,
I want you to bag up
everything on it.
Swell.
WARNER: Cause of death
was Iigature strangulation.
And the sexual assault?
Injuries to the genitalia
show no signs of healing.
Raped close
to the time of death,
but that was a while ago.
Her skin is shriveled.
Mummification?
Exactly.
The body was stored
before it was dumped.
I'II know more
after an autopsy.
It'II be tough
to make an ID
with her face
damaged Iike that.
Definitely post-mortem,
probably from the
garbage truck blades.
She was a fighter.
Take a Iook at this.
BIonde hair.
Maybe she got a piece of him.
I sure hope so.
STABLER: Tell me
you've got his DNA.
Sorry. The blonde hairs
that were found in her hand
turned out to be synthetic.
From a wig?
Maybe.
I'm sending the fibers
over to the Iab
to be checked against
the FBI database.
We at Ieast know
how Iong ago she died?
Based on
the insect activity,
I'd say between
six and eight weeks ago.
Judging from
the mummification,
the body was kept
in a cool place.
Can we get an ID
from the dental records?
I doubt it. Look at this.
There's so much tooth decay,
it's unlikely
she ever saw a dentist.
We'II definitely need
a facial reconstruction.
I'II send the body to our
forensic anthropologist.
He'II also try
to raise fingerprints.
So that's it?
Except for a few details
that will break your heart.
Displacement of her
front teeth
suggests she sucked
her thumb.
And she Iiked jumping rope.
BENSON: How'd you get that?
The scuffed toes.
I ruined enough pairs
when I was her age.
A five-year-old
kid disappears
and nobody reports it?
We checked her dental x-rays
against every missing
five-to-seven-year-old
African-American girl
in the Tri-State. No match.
Someone snatches your kid,
you call 91 1.
Unless you don't want
anybody to know
that your kid's gone.
So we're thinking this girl
was raped and killed
in her own home?
If the perp is a parent,
it explains why
there's no report.
And if she's not in school,
she's the perfect victim.
Nobody outside the family
would even know she's missing.
We don't even know
where she's missing from.
The garbage might tell us.
The Iab should have
gone through it by now.
OIivia, EIIiot, quicker we get
her picture out there,
quicker somebody
recognizes her.
DR. CONSTANTINE:
Meet Cherish Doe.
STABLER: What, Jane Doe's
not good enough?
It's too impersonal.
A cute Iittle girl
with braids
deserves something better,
don't you think?
Femur Iength,
plus the Iack of
epiphyseal plate fusion,
I'd say Cherish can't be
more than six.
So were you able
to get prints?
Still working on it.
Do you want to share?
The fingertips
were too shriveled.
So you cut her hands off.
I disarticulated them.
They're soaking
in embalming fluid
to reinflate the tissue,
hopefully enough
to roll a print.
TREVOR: You guys
owe me big time.
You find an address
in all that swill?
No, but I did find
an unusual amount
of fast food wrappers,
coffee cups,
fish scraps
and stained cotton balls.
-Cotton balls?
-From a nail salon.
Yeah, which apparently
shares a dumpster
with a burger joint,
a coffee shop
and a fish market.
That Ieaves, what,
only a couple dozen places
for us to check out?
How many city blocks
we gonna have to walk?
None, if you can manage
to drag your asses
over to the computer.
I've plugged you
your coffee shops,
burger joints,
fish markets, nail salons
into the zoning
and business permit databases.
You still think Big Brother
isn't watching us?
Now we eliminate areas
where all the variables
don't coexist
in close proximity.
Well, the garbage
plant's way uptown
and the manager says
they only pick up dumpsters
from north of 96th Street.
No problem.
In goes the information...
And out comes one Iocation.
1 23rd and Lenox. There we go.
Bingo! Burger Land.
Nail salon.
There's Letty's
Coffee Shop
and the back
of the fish market.
Why do we always get
the trash detail?
'Cause we're the right men
for the job.
PIus we've got the will
and we got the skill.
BIoody bed sheet.
You think the bastard
wrapped her body in it?
Mmm-hmm.
AII those windows up there,
maybe somebody saw him.
CSU have any Iuck
with the dumpster?
FIN: The blood type
on the bed sheets
match the victim.
That's it.
MUNCH: Nothing on
the canvass, either.
Maybe our car will improve
once we get these
on the street.
WOMAN ON TV:
Police today are searching
for the killer...
Looks Iike somebody
beat us to it.
...of this little girl,
found in this
Upper Manhattan garbage plant.
The only clue
to the killer's identity,
Iong blonde hairs
found in the victim's
lifeless grasp.
How the hell
did they get that?
Somebody gave them the fiber.
That detail was our hold-back.
Now when every nut in town
starts making
false confessions,
we got no way
to screen them out.
BENSON: We must've passed out
a couple hundred flyers.
Nobody recognized her.
Are we wrong thinking
she's from the neighborhood?
Maybe he is.
He stored her body
for a month or two,
he dumps her in a place
close to his house.
I mean, where's he
gonna go with her?
Sounds Iike
he's in his comfort zone.
Paroled sex offenders?
We checked.
No pedophiles
registered in the area.
Who says he's registered?
We don't even know
if the perp's a stranger
or the Iittle girl's parent.
Or some transvestite
wearing a blonde wig.
MUNCH: We canvassed.
Nobody remembers seeing
a Iittle black girl
with a guy with blond hair.
Well, I guess that Ieak
to the media paid off.
Community Relations
just called,
there's a candlelight
vigil tonight for Cherish Doe.
How many times
have we collared predators
at their victims' funerals?
Let's flush him out.
Make sure he sees us,
maybe we'II see him.
(CHURCH BELLS RINGING)
REV. ALLASTAIR: Cherish Doe,
we gather here
to remember you.
A sweet, innocent child,
stolen from life too soon.
We stand here tonight
as your family,
until your own family
is found.
It's all clear
over here. EIIiot?
We will not forget.
Nothing on this side.
And we will not rest
until justice is done.
I call upon you
to search your memory
and your conscience.
Anything you recall
will be welcomed
by the police.
Thank you for your support.
We need every single lead
that you can provide.
Now if you recognize
Cherish Doe, please call us.
NYPD has set up
a confidential tip line.
We don't need your names,
but we do need
your information.
MUNCH: Did you get
anything yet?
MORALES: So far, no hits
on the facial recognition
software.
FIN: What's your database?
AII known sex offenders
citywide whose victims
were under 10.
Huang's suggestion.
Yeah, but there's no guarantee
his mug shot's in there.
I mean, some guys
molest dozens of kids
before they're caught.
Your positive
attitude's a real joy.
What's up with that
Iady in the blue?
Why is she Iooking
around Iike that?
Zoom in on that Iady,
right there.
MORALES: Got her.
Something ain't right.
I'II be right back.
REV. ALLASTAIR: Cherish Doe,
you walked among us
as a stranger. But now
we call you our own.
You are our daughter.
Detective Tutuola.
Can I help you?
I can't find my daughter.
Okay, Iet's go to the front
and make a missing
child announcement.
No, no. I don't mean here,
not tonight.
When?
I don't know when.
I'm not sure when.
Okay, okay. What's your name?
Violet Tremain.
I saw Cherish Doe on the news,
I had to come here...
She may be my Iittle girl.
She Iooks just Iike my Nina.
I just came back tonight.
I was gone
for five months upstate.
FIN: Doing time?
No, I...
I was in rehab.
I'm not a crack addict,
if that's what you think.
I'm a painter
and I do graphic design
to pay the bills.
I'm not judging you.
We were in a car accident.
My husband, Nina's father,
was killed and...
I messed up my back
and I couldn't work
without painkillers.
I got hooked,
but I'm clean now,
four months.
ACS took your daughter away.
I knew if I put Nina
in foster care
I might not get her back.
So I Ieft her with a neighbor.
Well, that shows
a Iot of trust
to Ieave your daughter
with a neighbor.
Mrs. Hawkins was Iike
a grandmother to Nina,
she watched her
ever since she was a baby
and never took a penny.
She Ioved Nina.
You check in on her?
I couldn't call from rehab,
so I wrote Ietters.
I started to worry
when a Ietter I sent
Iast week was returned.
And then I saw the news.
And you checked out of rehab.
No, I just Ieft.
I called Mrs. Hawkins,
the phone was disconnected.
I called another neighbor,
she said Mrs. Hawkins
was dead.
She passed away six weeks ago.
And no one knew
what happened to Nina.
Sit down.
You've got to tell me
more about Nina.
How old is she?
She's five.
Her birthday was Iast month.
She's smart.
She can't wait
to start school.
She's playing all the time.
The child has a Iot of energy.
She Iike to jump rope?
Yeah, all the time.
What about the dentist?
When was her Iast checkup?
A couple of years.
I freelance
and my husband didn't...
He didn't have
dental insurance.
It's my Nina, isn't it?
We don't know that for sure.
Well, I have to see her.
No, no...
No sense in getting ahead
of ourselves, okay?
Somebody probably
took her in
and didn't know
how to get in touch with you.
Then we have to Iook for her.
It's after 12:00.
There's nothing
we can do right now.
How can I get in touch
with you tomorrow?
I don't know, I haven't
figured that out yet.
Don't worry,
I'II take care of that.
Violet's telling the truth.
"Junkies Iie all the time."
Your words.
You didn't talk to her.
Then Iet her see the body.
The child had no face.
No mother can handle that.
MUNCH: Sounds Iike
you're Iacking
a Iittle objectivity.
Why? 'Cause I'm not
handling things your way?
The department
doesn't have a budget
for Violet's hotel room.
You're paying for it,
aren't you?
So what?
Well, I guess
she is kind of cute.
Look, somebody knows
who took Nina
after Mrs. Hawkins died.
We've gotta canvass
her neighborhood. Let's go.
I still think you ought to
Iet her view the body.
Are you coming or what?
How do you even know
she has a kid?
Maybe she's using Cherish Doe
for a handout.
I pulled the
birth certificate myself.
So back off.
Lover's quarrel?
Gonna be a domestic dispute
if Munch don't get
out of my face.
Look, why don't Fin and I
go canvass
Mrs. Hawkins' building?
Good idea. We got dozens
of new Ieads in Iast night,
Munch and I will prioritize
and assign them out.
Come on. Let's go.
OId Iady died
a month and a half ago,
heart attack,
on her way home
from the market.
Nina with her?
Smart Iittle girl,
called 911 from a payphone.
Here it is, 3B.
FIN: Who cleaned
this place out?
Salvation Army.
You called them?
Mrs. Hawkins' daughter did.
Said everything
in here was junk,
told me to Iet them in.
Okay, and what about Nina?
Mrs. Hawkins' daughter
take her?
Yeah, right.
She said just because
her mama took in strays
didn't mean she had to.
Said the child
was my problem.
FIN: You try to reach
Nina's mother?
Violet never said
where she was going.
What could I do?
I had to send her
to Child Welfare,
hope for the best.
AII Nina could tell me
was that her mother went away.
Mrs. Tremain
didn't Ieave any names
or phone numbers
of any of her relatives.
Under the circumstances,
we had to classify Nina
as an abandoned child.
Nina's mother
didn't abandon her.
She voluntarily entered
into a rehab program.
Well, then she
should have come to us
instead of Ieaving her child
with an elderly neighbor
in failing health.
We could have placed
Nina voluntarily
while Violet was away.
Your agency doesn't
always make it easy
for parents to get
their children back.
Well, children are often
better off in foster care
than they are being
raised by addicts.
Violet's cleaned up
and she wants
her daughter back.
Yeah. Well, that's for
the courts to decide.
Mrs. Tremain's
gonna have to prove
that she can provide
a stable home environment
before we can release Nina.
Where's Nina Iiving?
I won't release
that information
if you're planning
to take the mother
on an unauthorized home visit.
You see the resemblance
to Nina Tremain?
This Iittle girl was raped,
murdered and tossed
in a dumpster.
Don't get in my way, Iady.
I placed her
with Thelma Price.
BENSON: Mrs. Price?
Yes?
I'm Detective Benson.
This is Detective Tutuola.
We'd Iike to talk to you
about Nina Tremain.
She's not here.
FIN: Where is she?
I don't know.
Ask Children's Services.
They said that they
placed her with you.
You don't believe me?
Take a Iook.
That child was nothing
but trouble.
Hyperactive, no manners,
always making a mess.
Well, when did they take her?
Must have been
over a month ago.
Then why did
Nina's case worker
tell us you had her?
Hell if I know.
That woman is Iazy.
Never makes a home visit.
Well, I find it hard
to believe Mrs. Preston
would forget to tell us
she took Nina.
She didn't take her.
It was some white guy
with dark hair.
Did you get his name?
I told you it was a month ago.
You expect me
to remember that?
BENSON: When was the Iast time
you saw Nina Tremain?
I'm gonna have to
check the file.
You got a memory problem?
I think it was Iast week.
Wrong answer.
It's possible
that I missed a visit.
Or more than one.
Even if I did,
it's hardly a police matter.
Wrong again.
Well, when you can't
make a visit,
you ever send
a colleague to cover?
A guy, maybe?
No, never.
No, then can you explain
why your records say
that you visited her
Iast Tuesday,
and Thelma Price says
you didn't.
That woman's a Iiar.
You're the Iiar, Iady!
Hey, I want my union rep.
BENSON: Yeah?
Well, why don't you tell
your union rep
that Nina Tremain is missing
and that you haven't seen her
in six weeks.
You were responsible
for this child's safety,
and you didn't even bother
to check on her.
This is not my fault.
Whose fault is it?
Do you know
what my job is Iike?
How big of a caseload I have?
There's no way
I can see every child.
If you're Iooking
for sympathy, you're barking
up the wrong tree.
Thelma Price was a good
foster mother.
I thought Nina
would be all right.
How could they Iet someone
just walk off with my child?
We don't know, but we're doing
everything we can to find him.
Now I need your help.
Anything.
Do you have something
with Nina's
fingerprints on it?
We draw together all the time.
I keep her pictures with me.
I guess it's Iike
having her here.
PIease be careful,
they're all I have.
We'II take good care
of them, I promise.
Violet, is this
Nina's handprint?
Yeah.
We made that together
Iast Thanksgiving.
The mother
authenticates that it's
the child's handprint.
Will it work?
Let's see.
The anthropologist
sent the hand over,
it's finally ready to print.
Couldn't ask for better.
People did their jobs,
this wouldn't have happened.
Sorry guys,
prints don't match.
Are you sure?
Not even close.
So Nina's not the dead girl.
Nina Tremain
might still be alive.
Two Iittle girls,
Iook Iike sisters,
from the same neighborhood,
tell me that's a coincidence.
Same guy that killed Cherish
might have Nina.
Are we sure it's the same guy?
He's got dark hair
when he took Nina
and a blonde wig
when he killed Cherish.
Well, maybe he played dress-up
before he killed her.
Maybe it's not even
a blonde wig
we're Iooking for.
I gotta tell Violet
that Cherish Doe
isn't her daughter.
Cherish's real name
is Susie Marshall.
How'd you get that?
Computer kicked out a match
to a KidPrint card on file.
Grandmother had her printed
during Safety Week.
I always thought
this day would come,
but not to hear
my grandbaby is dead.
I thought it would be Ronnie.
Who?
My daughter. The junkie.
That's why you were
taking care of Susie?
Ronnie'd ask me
to baby-sit her for a night
and disappear for months.
Then she'd come home
clean and sober,
and beg me to give Susie back.
And this Iast time I agreed,
because I thought that Ronnie
had finally
straightened herself out.
When did you Iast see
your granddaughter?
About five or six months ago.
Weren't you worried
because it had been so Iong?
Honestly, I was relieved.
Ronnie came by and told me
that a man from Child Welfare
had taken her away.
A perfect stranger
shows up at your door,
says he's a social worker,
and you just
turn over your kid
without a second thought?
Predator profiles his victims,
the kids come from
a chaotic household,
he knows they're not
gonna question him.
Posing as a social worker
is the perfect cover.
Well, that's true for Nina,
but ACS has no record
of contacting Susie Marshall
or her mother.
There's gotta be
another connection.
Well, take your pick.
Our perv either knows the kids
or their mothers.
What do we know
about the fathers?
Well, we know
Nina's father is dead
and Susie's father
went back to Jamaica.
We got a rap sheet
on Ronnie Marshall yet?
String of arrests,
collared for shoplifting
three years ago.
Last known whereabouts,
strung out on the street.
Then we got to go back
to Violet.
Show her pictures
of Ronnie and Susie.
Maybe she can
connect the dots.
VIOLET:
I'd remember this girl.
She Iooks just Iike my Nina.
I'm sorry.
FIN: How about this woman?
That scar.
I've seen her before.
Where?
An NA meeting.
I remember thinking
someone cut up her face.
Which NA meetings
did you go to?
Five o'clock
at the Community Center,
St. Virgil's on Tuesdays,
a few others
when the urge hit.
Well, the whole point of NA
is total confidentiality,
it's first names only.
They're not gonna talk to us.
I bet they'd talk to you.
What do you mean?
Your story might convince
a 12-stepper to open up.
FIN: You in?
What's he doing?
I'd do anything
to get my baby back.
Whatever it takes
to find Nina.
I'II do anything
I can to help.
But I'm not
gonna put a civilian
in the middle
of a criminal investigation.
Whatever you're thinking,
don't.
Violet's our only way in.
Violet would be acting
as an agent of the police.
Any evidence she obtains
could be excluded in court.
We're not Iooking
for evidence, Counselor.
We're Iooking for a Iead.
Nina Tremain
might still be alive.
We're talking about
violating the confidentiality
of a drug treatment program.
AIex, I tell people in AA
things I wouldn't want
my best friend to know.
Now I'd be the first
to agree with you
but I don't see how making
an appeal could hurt.
I would prefer
to get the information
through Iegal channels.
I'II get a subpoena.
CRAGEN: For what?
NA doesn't keep
membership Iists or records.
You want to tell that woman
you care more about the Iaw
than the Iife of her child?
She's Iiving a parent's
worst nightmare.
You think I really
had to run a number on her?
AII right.
But the only way we do this
is the right way.
Open meetings only.
Disclose your presence
and don't Iet Violet
out of your sight.
The Ninth Step says,
we have to make amends
to those harmed
by our addiction.
Well I... I harmed my baby.
Because I got high,
I couldn't take care of Nina,
and some monster
kidnapped her.
I have to find
Ronnie Marshall.
I think
she's been here before,
and she might
have some information.
Ain't that against the rules?
The only way I can get
my Iittle girl back
is with your help.
I have to find Ronnie.
This is her picture.
The same freak
who stole my Nina
murdered her daughter.
Time is running out.
If you know anything,
I am begging you to tell me.
Hey, what's the rush?
None of your business.
No, trust me,
it's my business.
I got nothing to say.
Then why are you running
Iike a Iittle scared rabbit?
I don't know nothing
about no missing kids.
But you do know
Ronnie Marshall.
I don't have to
tell you anything.
I respect
people's confidentiality.
How about respect
for the dead?
You think Ronnie
wants to attend her own
daughter's funeral?
This is for real?
It's not a scam?
You got my word.
I don't know, man,
people won't trust me
if I talk to a cop.
We never talked.
A place Ronnie and I
used to get high.
The Starlite Lounge.
Oh, yeah.
Ronnie used to come in.
Used to?
A while back.
Threw her out
for shooting up in the can.
Haven't seen her since.
Do you know
where we can find her?
I don't get personal
with the customers.
They pay, they drink,
they Ieave.
Any customers talk to Ronnie?
Only guys
who were drunk enough
to think
she Iooked good.
She'd go with a Ieper
for the price of a fix.
Any Iepers around here?
(DANCE MUSIC PLAYING)
Hey, Pat!
You banged that
skanky chick once, right?
Ronnie?
The one with the scar?
Don't remind me.
This bitch boosted my wallet.
You go to her place?
Woman's shelter
don't allow guests.
We did it in a alley.
You know which shelter?
FIN: You see Ronnie anywhere?
VIOLET: No.
Wait. There she is.
This is Ronnie.
Ronnie Marshall?
Leave me alone.
I have a couple more hours.
Wake up, Ronnie.
Who the hell are you?
I'm a cop.
I didn't do nothing.
Who's she?
I'm Violet.
I'm Iooking for my daughter,
and I need your help.
Cost you twenty bucks,
I'II help you all you want.
We've got no time for games.
We think the same man
took your daughter.
No.
No. Social worker
took my baby.
That man
wasn't a social worker.
Oh, no? Who was he?
Look, I'm sorry,
but Susie's dead.
We found her body
two days ago.
She's better off.
That's how much you care
about your Iittle girl?
Come on, get your ass up.
Come on. Let's go.
You Iook Iike crap, Ronnie.
When are you
gonna Iet me out of here?
Orange juice.
You're gonna need it.
What do you want from me?
Description of the man
who took Susie
for a sketch artist.
I can't remember
back that far.
Can I go now, huh?
Look, I found your works.
You don't cooperate,
I'm gonna bust you.
What is your problem?
Your daughter's dead
and there's not one cell
in your junkie body
that gives a damn.
That man who took
my daughter was right.
I'm not fit to be a mom.
Susie deserved more than me.
Now she's gone,
and there's nothing
that I can do
that's gonna change that.
You could help us save
this other Iittle girl.
Make it right for Susie.
We got to get
a description of this guy.
You can do this.
(CRYING)
Thelma, Ronnie worked this up
with a sketch artist.
Does this Iook
Iike the man
who took Nina?
That's him.
There's got to be a connection
between this guy
and the three of you.
So both Ronnie and Violet
went to the same NA meeting.
Thelma, have you
ever been to one?
Never.
Maybe it wasn't the meetings,
but where they were held.
Ronnie and I
both went to St. Virgil's.
FIN: You go
to that church, Thelma?
No, First Baptist.
How about Haven House?
Never been there.
Ronnie, can you think
of anyplace else?
Anywhere at all?
Not really.
Come on, think.
Where did this guy see you?
Maybe at the Community Center
on Eighth Ave.
I stopped in there
a couple times.
I go there for Bingo Night.
Nina Iiked their playroom.
Oh, God,
I went to meetings there.
I took Nina with me.
He cut his hair
and shaved his beard,
and he never wore glasses,
but it could be Terry Jessup.
Who's that?
He worked here.
Quit a few months ago.
How Iong have you
known him?
Oh, most of his Iife.
He was a Iocal kid.
Just about grew up here.
Had a mother who was unstable.
Went on and off her meds.
ACS ever remove him?
Well, we called them
several times,
once when he had
a terrible burn
on his hand.
But, you know,
he told them
it was an accident.
What did Terry do here?
CIeaned up, you know,
took out the trash,
small repairs.
He used to fix
the broken toys.
That was his real passion.
So he was around
the kids?
He had quite
a doll collection.
He Ioved showing it to them.
Strange hobby
for an adult man,
collecting dolls.
He inherited them
from his mother.
Terry called them his Iegacy.
We're gonna need
to talk to Terry.
Do you have
an address for him?
I can't imagine
that Terry's in trouble
with the police.
Do you recognize
this Iittle girl?
That's Cherish Doe,
from the news?
Her real name
is Susie Marshall
and the other one
is Nina Tremain.
Oh, my God.
You do recognize them.
Just to say hi.
I can't believe it.
Did you ever see Terry
around either one of them?
No.
But he did pay
special attention
to the kids
with tough home Iives.
He said that they
needed extra Iove.
Damn it! We're too Iate.
Here we go.
The paper's
three months old.
Jessup must have taken off
after he kidnapped Susie.
He's got to have another place
where he stashed Susie's body
before he dumped her.
Got something over here.
Polaroid?
Susie Marshall.
Yeah, dressed up
Iike a Iittle doll.
Dolls are idealized
representations
of men and women.
They're pure,
perfect and sexless.
Terry Jessup
is Iike a child
who uses dolls
to act out his fantasies.
But he's a grown man
and his fantasies are sexual.
And he feels guilty
about being attracted
to children
and so he turns them
into dolls.
Which works for a while...
Until he gives in,
he has sex with the doll,
but then it's not
a doll anymore,
so he kills it.
Why stash the body?
Again, out of guilt.
And then when he finds
a new playmate,
he just discards the Iast one.
STABLER: Talked to your friend
at Bellevue,
got me the psych records
on Jessup's mother.
Diagnosed with
severe depression
with intermittent
bouts of mania.
She'd go around having
sex with dozens of men
and then go on
these spending sprees
buying nothing but dolls.
Give you anything on Jessup?
Well, the shrink said
that she was
intermittently abusive
and seductive towards him.
Perfect way
to raise a serial killer.
I talked to a couple
of Jessup's neighbors.
The stress of his mother's
death a year ago
pushed him over the edge.
He became reclusive
and explosive.
I just got off with CSU.
No forensic evidence
either Nina or Susie
were in Jessup's apartment.
Well, to keep
the girls prisoner,
Jessup would have
needed privacy and isolation.
STABLER: He snatched
both girls in the 'hood,
dumped Susie back there.
If he's following a pattern,
Nina's got to be nearby.
TREVOR: Check this out.
Moving in?
My own doll collection.
Fibers came from
a Madame Charlotte doll.
Very exclusive.
CRAGEN: Well, how exclusive
is their distribution?
Only three stores in the city.
Sure, I've known
Terry Jessup for years.
Not a Iot of guys
are into collecting,
but his money's good.
When was the Iast time
you saw him?
Oh, it's a couple
of months ago.
He came in to buy
the new Princess AIexis.
Craftsmanship,
that's what Terry cares about.
Only perfect dolls
in mint condition.
We need an address for him.
I send mailings
to preferred customers
whenever a new
Madame Charlotte comes out.
Here we go.
2555 Eighth Avenue.
That's his old apartment.
Avid collector Iike Terry
surely sent you
a change of address.
No.
But he called
a couple of weeks ago.
Pre-ordered a Virginia Belle.
Left a number for me to call
when it came in.
917 area. Cell phone.
Call Terry and tell him
his order came in.
Terry, I'm sorry.
(SOFTLY) He just came in.
What's wrong?
After I called you,
I opened the box.
The shipment was damaged.
Would you take
a Princess Renee instead?
You know
I don't collect Renees.
The workmanship's shoddy.
How about
a 50th anniversary Nicolette,
Iimited edition?
Okay, but I still want
the Virginia Belle.
Promise. I'II call you.
Okay.
He's on the move.
STABLER: Police!
Let's see your hands.
Don't hurt me.
Don't move.
Where is she, Terry?
What?
On your knees.
Nina Tremain,
where is she?
Nina?
Tell us where Nina is,
before I take
your punk ass head off.
I don't know.
STABLER: Hey, Terry.
Terry!
Where's the top sheet?
Did you use this to wrap up
Susie Marshall's body?
Terry!
PIease don't hurt my dolls.
PIease don't.
Tell us where Nina is.
She's not here!
Get his ass up.
We ran Iine-ups.
We got positive IDs
from Thelma Price and Ronnie.
Nice job.
I don't need a confession
to win this case.
But we do need one
to find Nina Tremain.
Any chance
she's still alive?
Warner couldn't pin down
the exact time
of death for Susie.
AII we know is that
he kept her breathing
between two and four weeks.
And we're at
the four-week mark
with Nina right now.
If he killed her,
he'd be agitated.
He'd be on the prowl
for his next victim,
instead, he's in there
sleeping Iike a baby.
You know what?
Why don't you all
take a Iittle walk
while Terry and I
get better acquainted.
Now, he's not going
to respond to threats.
He's very Ionely.
Dolls and children
are his only companions.
He needs a friend.
Your dolls are beautiful.
I had Iots of dolls,
but never ones
as nice as yours.
Girls are Iucky.
They can play with dolls.
Boys aren't supposed to.
I had dolls.
You did? What kind?
You know,
GI Joe, Batman...
Those are action figures.
Terry, I hear that your mother
started your doll collection.
She Iiked beautiful things.
I inherited them
when she died.
And you Iove them very much.
They were her most
precious possession.
Now they're mine.
She can't take them
away from me.
BENSON: Your mother
didn't want you
to have the dolls?
She'd hit me
if I touched them.
She said that I'd break them.
"Boys are too rough.
Boys can't be trusted
"to handle fragile things."
But sometimes,
when she was really happy,
she'd Iet me dress them up.
I was very careful
not to break them.
I bet you take
really good care
of those dolls.
And I hear
that you fix them, too.
Yeah, I can fix anything.
I'm really good with my hands.
Man, that burn
must have hurt.
It was an accident.
BENSON:
Did your mother do that?
She Ioved me.
But Iittle boys are wicked.
Little boys need discipline.
But your mother
had no right to hurt you.
Little children deserve
to be Ioved.
Bad mothers shouldn't bring
Iittle children
into this world.
Susie Marshall
have a bad mother?
She was a crack whore.
Susie was sad all the time.
I Iet her play with my dolls.
Is that why
you took her, Terry?
So she could play with you?
In the Center,
she Ioved my dolls,
but then she didn't want
to play anymore.
She just wanted to go home.
And that must've
made you mad.
She broke one of my dolls.
I told her not to,
I told her that she'd be sorry
but she wouldn't Iisten.
That's when Susie got hurt?
I don't want to talk
about it anymore.
Where did you keep Susie?
I can't tell you.
BENSON: Okay, Terry. Okay.
Well, then
Iet's talk about Nina.
No.
Terry, Nina has
a good mother.
No, she doesn't.
I saw her Ieave Nina
with that evil woman.
I saw that woman
yelling at Nina.
Terry, Nina's mother
came back.
She misses her
and wants to see her again.
I know what
you're trying to do.
You're trying to trick me.
Terry, where is Nina?
Where is Nina?
Where is she?
He's completely dissociated.
Just give him some time.
We don't have any time.
It's too Iate.
VIOLET: Detective Tutuola.
Violet, what are you
doing here?
Fin called me. He told me
that you have the man
who took Nina.
We have a suspect in custody.
Who won't talk.
I've got to see him.
Give us a minute.
I thought we were working
this case together
and you called Violet
without telling me?
You got another way
to get Jessup to talk?
Putting Violet and Jessup
together is a bad idea.
She was strong enough
to go to those NA meetings.
We prep her correctly,
I know she can handle it.
Back me up, Doc.
Jessup thinks he's saving Nina
from an abusive parent.
If you challenge his delusion,
he might break.
And if this doesn't work,
the guilt
will destroy Violet's Iife.
A dead child's gonna
destroy her even more.
Nina's gonna die
if we don't do something.
You sure you can do this?
Yes.
No matter what he says,
you have to be
stronger than him.
I'm ready.
Hello, Terry.
Do you know who I am?
Nina's mom?
That's right.
My name is Violet.
You ran away.
Nina was so sad.
I was sad, too.
I missed her very much.
But I Ieft to help Nina.
I was no good to her
the way I was.
That's why
Violet came back, Terry.
She came back for Nina.
It's too Iate.
FIN: No, it's not.
Nina needs her mother.
Make it right.
Nina's a good girl.
Yes, she is.
I'm a good mother.
Do you Iove her?
Yes.
With her gone,
it's Iike a knife in my heart.
I have another place.
Bastard's playing us.
Maybe not. Trap door. EIIiot.
Nina?
It's okay, baby.
I'm a police officer.
(GROANING)
I got you. It's okay, baby.
You okay, baby? Look at me.
Look at me, baby, Iook. Okay.
I'II get you out of here.
I miss my Mommy.
I'II take you home.
She'II be all right.
Mommy?
Thank you.