NARRATOR: In the criminal
justice system,
sexually based offenses
are considered
especially heinous.
In New York City,
the dedicated detectives
who investigate
these vicious felonies
are members of an elite squad
known as
the Special Victims Unit.
These are their stories.
We should get
Out Of Africa.
Sarah,
this isn't gonna work.
Okay, fine. Die Hard.
No, I can't
do this anymore.
What, rent a movie?
You and me.
I told you I didn't want
a serious relationship.
You knew this
from the start.
You are such
an incredible bastard.
Hey, don't pretend
Iike I didn't tell you
this a month ago.
(GUN FIRING)
Oh, my God! Oh, my God.
He's shot! Help!
John.
WOMAN: Somebody,
call the cops!
Somebody, help!
I got him! I got him!
Oh, my God!
Somebody, please!
My sister!
Somebody, do something!
Call somebody!
Somebody! Why isn't anyone
doing anything?
Dave Duethorn,
boy detective.
Guess they'II give
that gold shield
to anyone.
Yeah.
They gave one to you.
At Ieast I earned it.
Don't flatter yourself.
We got a double?
Could be a triple.
Bus took the six-year-old,
Rebecca Kurtz,
to the hospital.
Doesn't Iook good.
She get hit out here?
Inside the store,
with her older sister Missy.
Pretty shaken up.
E.R.'s gonna
check her out.
Is this our shooter?
Bystander.
John Marcum. Walking in,
took one in the chest.
Poor bastard.
Should've stayed
home and watched TV.
That's the stick up kid.
Name's Eric Campbell.
Three witnesses saw him
come in wearing a ski mask,
gun in hand.
Tells everybody to get down,
"Show me the money."
So he's standing
over at the register.
The victims are
both over there.
Something spooked him.
Witness says someone
dropped a tape.
Probably the Iittle girl.
He fires, hits the kid
and the guy outside.
AII right,
who shot him?
CIerk. A kid named
Joey Field.
AII right.
Well, where is our hero?
On the bus,
being treated for shock.
Name's Dave Duethorn.
I'm a detective.
How're you feeling?
I guess I'm okay.
Compared to him.
I can't believe
I killed someone.
Well, think of it
as customer service.
Where'd you get
the piece?
The owner.
He keeps a Ioaded gun
under the counter.
I just...
I guess I wasn't
thinking.
AII right, all right,
take it easy.
I wasn't...
It's okay, it's okay,
all right.
It's a good thing you got him
before he could shoot anyone
else. Understand?
Yeah.
AII right.
Fascitelli,
take the kid home.
I got him.
Come on, Iet's go.
That was the hospital.
Little girl's
on Iife support.
Are you ready for this?
Gonorrhea?
Found it when they
checked her out. They're doing
a rape kit now.
Any chance
she'II survive?
Bullet sliced
an artery in her chest.
Medics resuscitated her
en route, but her brain's
toast.
No oxygen
for 10 minutes.
Where are the parents?
Waiting room.
They know about
the gonorrhea?
Figured I'd Ieave
that to the sex police.
We were renting a video.
Becca was so scared.
I kept trying to
make her be quiet.
We were just
renting a video.
Calm down, calm down.
Take a couple
of deep breaths.
It's all right.
Take it easy, take it easy.
They told me that
I can't see my sister,
and they won't
tell me anything.
I mean, is she dead?
No.
I don't believe you.
I want to just...
I need to be
told the truth.
Rebecca's on
Iife support.
Are my
parents here?
I really need
to be with them.
They're with your sister.
You think you can handle
a couple of questions before
we take you upstairs?
Yeah.
Any other siblings?
No.
You and Rebecca
got along really well?
My parents made me baby-sit
her after school,
but I didn't want to.
I just wanted to hang out
with my friends.
I just wish I hadn't been
such a brat about it.
Becca didn't...
She didn't want a movie.
I made her come with me.
Your parents both
at work today?
Mom's an accountant.
Dad does this...
Some stockbroker
thing at home.
Dad ever take
care of Rebecca?
Usually. But today
he had an appointment.
Your dad and Rebecca
spend a Iot of time together?
After school,
he takes her to the park,
to the zoo.
You know, places Iike that.
She's daddy's Iittle girl.
MUNCH: Like you were
when you were her age?
I wish.
I was more Iike daddy's
Iittle punching bag.
Nobody did anything?
Social workers came,
took me away.
The Kurtzs adopted
me when I was 12.
They're never gonna
forgive me for this.
Hey.
I just spoke with Munch.
It seems that Daddy
and Rebecca had
a very close relationship.
They collect
the swabs yet?
Doctor did a preliminary
genital exam.
He's gotta do a colposcopy
to confirm the rape.
STABLER: Thank you.
Excuse me.
Where are you going
with my daughter's clothes?
I'm Detective Stabler.
This is my partner,
Detective Benson.
We need them
for evidence.
What evidence?
I thought the bastard
who shot her was dead.
STABLER: He is.
Well, I don't understand.
Well, honey,
Iet the police
do their jobs.
Could we have a moment
with each of you?
I can't Ieave her.
Can't this wait?
Why don't we step outside?
It'II just take a moment.
If anything changes,
I'II come and get you.
(MONITOR BEEPING)
The doctors say that
Rebecca's brain dead.
That she'II
never wake up.
I'm very sorry.
We'd given up trying
to get pregnant,
so we adopted Missy.
And Rebecca
was our miracle.
Your husband must
have been thrilled.
We all were.
Missy had
a Iittle sister.
Peter just...
He stayed home,
working so he could...
Oh, he couldn't get
enough of them.
Why would God
bless us Iike that
and just take her away?
Look, did something
happen to Missy?
Because the other detective
said she was all right.
No, no, she's fine.
They're actually going
to bring her by soon.
PIease wait. I gotta figure
out how to explain to her
that this wasn't her fault.
She's been
through enough.
Well, then I will
get her a ride home.
Is there somebody there?
Yeah, my family's
coming in from upstate.
She won't be alone.
Look, Detective,
what aren't you telling me?
There's no easy way
to say this.
Rebecca's been
sexually abused.
(SOFTLY) What?
We're still investigating,
but the doctor said
that she'd tested
positive for gonorrhea.
Oh, God.
How could this
be happening?
In these kinds of cases,
it's typically
somebody who knew the victim.
Well, then it must
have been at school.
I mean, she's there
most of the day.
I understand that you're
her primary caregiver?
Yeah, I...
You're accusing me
of hurting Rebecca?
Sir, we're not
accusing anyone.
Yes, you are.
You think I raped
my daughter.
Mr. Kurtz.
It's my job
to rule everyone out.
Now, you'd really help us out
if you'd consent
to a gonorrhea test.
You go to hell.
Rebecca's social
calendar was packed.
She had ballet twice a week.
She took piano Iessons
at home.
Taught by a 75-year-old
grandmother.
We checked her and
the ballet teachers.
AII clean.
And the school?
That's where we're
off to right now.
Dad agree to
the gonorrhea test?
He told me
to shove it.
But under the circumstances,
I might've said
the same thing.
Your gut says
he's clean?
Yeah.
He came across as
a devoted family man.
Quit his job so
he could stay home
with the kids.
I wish I could do that.
Yeah, but unlike pops,
you got no priors.
BENSON: What for?
Sexual abuse.
Missy filed a complaint
against Peter Kurtz
5 years ago.
Well, Iet's find out why.
Missy told her teacher
that Peter Kurtz abused her,
and we Iooked into it.
What'd you find?
That she was mistaking
normal affection
for sexual advances.
Define normal.
Oh, a kiss on the cheek,
a hug.
That's as hot and
heavy as it got.
So she doesn't know
the difference between
a good touch and a bad touch.
Not surprising,
considering the hell
the girl came from.
Missy told us that her
biological father beat her.
And raped her.
And if that
wasn't bad enough,
crack bastard pimped
her out to his friends.
I hope you spread
the short eyes Iabel
through the prison yard.
Didn't have to.
He died Iast year of AIDS.
Fortunately,
Missy tested negative.
So Missy's complaint
against Peter Kurtz
just went away, huh?
They don't just
go away, Detective.
We got her some counseling,
and she recanted.
How deep did you
dig on the Kurtzs?
Foster agency
checked them out.
Put them through
orientations,
parenting classes,
surprise visits.
They jumped through
hoops to adopt her.
I wish all my Missys wound up
with parents Iike them.
(SCHOOL BELL RINGING)
Rebecca is a sweet
Iittle girl. Great student.
Everyone here
is devastated.
We've had to
bring in counselors
to talk to the kids.
Aside from her
homeroom teacher,
did Rebecca have contact
with any other adults here?
Art, music,
phys ed instructors. Why?
Mr. Curtis,
the reason
that we're here
is because Rebecca
has gonorrhea.
My God.
You don't think that
one of my people...
We would Iike to test
the employees here.
I can't invade
their privacy.
I'd be opening up
the school to a Iawsuit.
Well, not if they volunteer.
It's actually
a very quick procedure.
I'II call a meeting
for the staff.
But if they refuse,
you'II have to go
through other channels.
Is there anything else?
(PHONE RINGING)
STABLER: Excuse me.
Yeah, one more thing.
Have you noticed
any behavioral changes
in Rebecca Iately?
A few weeks ago, her teacher,
Mrs. Leas, said she
had trouble focusing.
And I've had to call home
about incontinence.
How many times?
Twice.
But I didn't
think anything of it.
It's not uncommon
for first-graders.
What did the Kurtzs say?
Well, they knew about it.
Rebecca's been
wetting the bed, too.
They were taking her
to see the doctor.
Thank you.
We'II be in touch.
(CLEARS THROAT)
That was the Captain.
He wants us back.
Why? What's going on?
The Kurtzs want to pull
the plug on Rebecca.
BENSON: They haven't
done the rape exam yet.
Rebecca's parents want
to donate her organs.
They wait much Ionger,
they won't be usable.
Can't they do
the exam post-mortem?
M.E. says once
there's no blood flow,
tissue deteriorates
and we could Iose
our evidence.
She tested positive
for gonorrhea.
Isn't that enough
to prove our case?
Not if we want to prove
that she was also raped.
We need every bit
of evidence we can get.
AIex, this bastard
should die in his cell.
Can you buy us
some time?
I'II try.
ROGER: This is inhumane.
The People's request
for a temporary
restraining order
only prolongs
Rebecca's suffering.
A colposcopy is invasive
and unnecessary.
Ms. Cabot, has a pelvic exam
been performed yet?
Because of the victim's age,
a specialist is required
to determine whether
or not she was raped.
The Kurtzs want
something good
to come out of this.
Now, there's an 8-year-old boy
at Children's Hospital
in Philadelphia.
He's at the top of
a transplant Iist for a Iiver.
Rebecca Kurtz is a match.
And this boy can't wait
until the examination
is complete?
The clock is ticking,
Your Honor.
For someone in
Rebecca's condition,
after 24 hours,
microvascular collapse
begins to occur,
causing blood clots
which irreparably
damage the organs.
The People certainly
don't wish to exacerbate
the Kurtzs tragedy, but...
Then, don't.
If that Iittle boy in Philly
doesn't get Rebecca's Iiver,
he won't Iast another day.
And this additional
evidence is so critical
that the People are
willing to jeopardize
the Iife of another child?
Our responsibility is to find
who committed the rape
and prevent this crime
from happening again.
Mr. Kurtz, my heart goes out
to you and your family.
But it is my duty to see
that justice is done
on behalf of your daughter.
And since we can't
un-pull the plug,
I'm afraid I have no other
choice but to grant
the restraining order.
I'm sorry.
You got your
restraining order.
Why don't you
Ieave us alone?
Mr. Kurtz, the Iast thing
that we want to do
is inflict any more
pain on your family.
We need to find out
what happened to Rebecca.
Do you have children,
Detectives?
I have four.
Then how can you
put us through this?
If one of my children
were sexually abused,
I'd want to know who did it.
What do you
want from us?
Test your family
for gonorrhea.
You Iook Iike crap.
I didn't sleep all night.
I kept checking in on my kids.
Well, you should
have called me.
I didn't sleep, either.
Anybody page you?
No. Why? What's up?
Rebecca Kurtz
died this morning.
They do the transplant?
Kid in Philly is in
surgery right now.
AIex woke up a judge
to Iift the T.R.O.
as soon as they
finished the colposcopy.
And?
And she was
raped repeatedly.
What about the gonorrhea?
Family's clean.
Well, it's a good thing
we put them through hell,
then.
Well, much as I hate
to say this, dad could
have been treated.
Test comes up negative
if the doctor's
given you antibiotics.
You should know better than
to ask me any
questions about a patient.
And you should know
that you have to answer them
if you have any information
about Peter Kurtz abusing
his daughter.
What are you
talking about?
Rebecca Kurtz
had gonorrhea.
My God.
I didn't know.
The school said
that you saw her
for wetting the bed.
You don't usually test
for STDs on a six-year-old.
She didn't complain
of any symptoms.
Failure to report child abuse
is a crime, Doctor.
It wasn't her father.
Peter didn't do it.
STABLER: How do you know that?
I just did
Peter's physical.
His urine was clean.
Why'd you test it?
Because I wanted to make sure
Peter hadn't abused Missy.
Missy has gonorrhea?
I treated her two weeks ago.
Missy, we need to
talk to your parents.
Do you know who
raped my sister?
We think you do.
We know you
had gonorrhea.
We're trying to plan
a funeral here.
Don't you people
have any decency?
It's not their fault,
Daddy. It's mine.
No one could ever blame you
for what happened.
He raped me and he raped
Rebecca, and I couldn't
stop him!
Missy, what are you saying?
He just...
He told me he would kill me
if I ever told anyone.
Who? Who, honey?
Who was it?
Missy, there's nothing
he can do to hurt you anymore.
It was Joe, my boyfriend.
Missy, why didn't you tell me?
I was afraid.
Where can we find him?
He Iives with his parents
on Park, and he works
at Movie Madness.
The clerk from the store
where Rebecca was shot?
MISSY: He made me
bring her there.
Why?
Becca had said that
she was gonna tell
what he did to her.
I told Joey,
I said to him,
I said that there was no way
that he could ever
go anywhere near her.
But he said that he
would kill both of us
if we didn't show up.
It was a set up?
Missy says that Joey Field
and Eric Campbell
were friends.
She didn't know that Campbell
was the shooter until they
pulled off his ski mask.
Joey orchestrates
Rebecca's murder,
he burns his friend
so he can't talk,
makes himself
Iook Iike the hero.
But even with Missy's
testimony, all we can
get Joey on is rape.
BENSON: He murdered
three people.
And to prove it,
we need physical evidence.
Joey Field has no priors,
and you can bet
he's gonna have
top dollar representation.
Why?
His father is Malcolm Field.
Of Prescott, Field and Browne.
Deep pockets and a Iot
of friends in high places,
including the new D.A.
Here's Eric Campbell's sheet.
Two theft, three assaults.
It's not a big Ieap
to murder.
But still, it takes
a special kind of scrote
to be shooting
an innocent kid.
Yeah. The kind who
does it for money.
Which Joey could've got
from his rich Iawyer daddy.
What does your boss
want to do with this?
My Iieutenant says
it's your call.
AII right.
Well, we started this mess,
we'II take it from here.
Missy'd have
kept her mouth shut,
it would've been
the perfect crime.
You don't know there's
a trampoline in the room,
you're not going to dust
the ceiling for prints.
Well, the crime Iab thought
it was a robbery gone bad,
just Iike the rest of us.
We tell them what happened,
maybe they'II
help us prove it.
AII right, call them.
You make the notification
on Eric Campbell?
Yeah, to his father.
He Iives in a bottle
over in AIphabet City.
Take Munch.
Pay him a visit.
They're in for
a real treat.
What do you think you're
gonna find that the other
cops couldn't?
So you don't mind us
taking a Iook around then?
Whatever.
Eric talk about
his friends?
I don't think
he had any.
Loser Iike him,
he's better off dead.
Yeah, well,
you set a fine example.
Yeah, well, I didn't teach him
to rob stores and shoot
Iittle girls.
No robbery.
That Iittle girl's
shooting was a hit.
He killed that
kid on purpose?
You seem surprised.
He was more of a Ioser
than I thought.
Looks Iike a stereo
showroom in there.
Your Ioser son been flashing
around money Iately?
He didn't flash it,
but he sure knew
how to spend it.
Mind if we take a Iook?
Knock yourself out.
This must've fell off
the back of some truck.
Actually, paid cash
for it Iast week.
TV, DVD player,
answering machine.
No new messages.
Old messages.
(BEEPS)
JOEY: Eric, you there?
Pick up. Pick up the phone.
ERIC: Hey, Joe, I'm here.
JOEY: Got what you need?
ERIC: Yeah, I got it.
What time?
JOEY: 3:00.
ERIC: Don't worry,
I'll be there.
Shooting happened
right after 3:00.
That conversation,
they could've been
planning to meet for
a game of tiddlywinks.
I think I can prove they
had something else in mind.
Witnesses put Eric Campbell
at the register when he
demanded the money.
He turned and fired,
missed Rebecca,
and hit John Marcum
outside the store.
But when he fired
the second time and hit
Rebecca, he was standing here.
And you know that how?
I fired the murder weapon
at these pieces of oak tag
from ten, five
and three feet away
to figure out where
Eric was standing.
Then I compared the results
to the gunshot
residue on Rebecca's shirt.
So Eric was three feet away
when he shot Rebecca.
He moved forward.
Because the first shot
was too high.
He had to deliberately
move closer and aim Iower.
It's the only scenario
that matches the evidence.
(DOOR BELL RINGING)
Hey, Joey Field.
Yeah.
We're Detectives
Benson and Stabler.
Is this about
that Iittle girl?
Yeah.
Did she make it?
No, I'm sorry,
she didn't.
Can we talk to you
out here for a minute?
What for?
The Mayor's office sent us.
They want to give you
an award for heroism.
We just need to
fill out the paperwork.
Who is it, Joey?
It's the cops, Dad.
They want to give
me an award.
Joey, get back in here.
Joey Field, you're under
arrest for the murders
of John Marcum...
MALCOLM: What are you...
...Eric Campbell
and Rebecca Kurtz.
What murders?
I didn't do anything.
Look, I'm an attorney.
Where the hell's
your arrest warrant?
Don't need one.
He stepped outside.
You tricked me.
Reasonable deception.
Ask your dad about it.
MALCOLM: Joseph,
don't say a word! I'II be
right down to get you out!
You have the right
to remain silent.
If you give up that right,
anything you say
can and will be used
against you in a court of Iaw.
Be nice if we could Iisten.
It's pretty convenient having
a father who can double
as your attorney.
Looks Iike Joey would
rather have somebody else.
Malcolm Field's
record is good,
but I don't think even he
can get his son out of this.
Joseph had no idea
Eric Campbell was going
to hold up that store.
You have no case.
Excuse me?
How many more people
would that bastard have killed
if my son hadn't stopped him?
Your son raped a six-year-old
and murdered three people
to cover it up.
We have the forensics
to prove it.
If Joey would Iike to share
anything, Counselor,
now would be the time.
If you're Iooking
for a confession,
you can forget it.
No, we'II take our
chances with the jury.
"People v. Joseph Lee Field.
Three counts murder
in the First Degree,
"two counts rape
in the First Degree."
Counsel, approach.
What the hell's
going on, Malcolm?
People are making
a big mistake.
That may be true.
But do you think
you're the best person
to represent Joey?
Your Honor seems very well
acquainted with the counsel
and his defendant.
Relax, Ms. Cabot.
I'm sorry, Malcolm.
We can't help you
out on this.
Step back.
Mr. Field,
how does your client plead?
Not guilty, Your Honor.
SELIGMAN: Bail, Ms. Cabot?
Considering the ease
with which the accused
could flee the jurisdiction,
the People request remand.
Your Honor,
you have my word as
an officer of the court,
the defendant will
remain under my
personal supervision.
With all due respect
to Mr. Field, his son
is facing a capital charge.
He shouldn't be
on the street.
Under the circumstances
I have to agree.
Defendant is remanded
without bail.
(GAVEL BANGS)
SELIGMAN: Next case.
Before Missy agrees
to testify against Joey,
her parents want a guarantee
that you won't prosecute her.
Prosecute her?
She's a victim.
Yeah, and two weeks from now,
you could charge her
with rape one
for delivering her sister
to the man who raped
them both.
Roger, you know us
better than that.
ROGER: Oh, hey, I trust you.
But not your new
good old boy D.A.
I mean, what's to keep Branch
from throwing her in prison
to make an example?
Stop blowing smoke
up my ass, Roger.
I'm just defending my client.
What do you want?
Immunity.
Come on. We're giving
you Joey Field
on a silver platter.
Are you sure she
won't be too scared
to take the stand?
Not if it gets
him the needle.
We'II send you the paperwork.
Good Iuck putting these
witnesses on the stand.
They took one Iook at Eric
in the ski mask,
and they ducked for cover.
You ready for some more?
What's this?
Malcolm Field's motion
to suppress the recording
on Eric's Campbell's
answering machine.
On what grounds?
Authentication,
illegal search.
It was Campbell's home.
Field doesn't have standing.
We still have to respond.
He could bury me in paperwork
for the next decade if he
thinks it'II save his son.
Hey, guess who
Joey Field's father is calling
as a defense witness.
Oh, sure. Who better
to testify that no witnesses
corroborate Missy's story.
Not to mention
his son's a hero.
Bastard's gonna hang me out
to dry in front of the jury.
This just keeps
getting better.
Well, here's more good news.
What's wrong?
It's from the Iab.
Copy of a tape Fin and Munch
found when they searched
the Fields' home.
We got a real problem.
Come on, Joey.
Do it already.
Can't we just
leave her and go?
No. She is knocked out.
She won't feel it.
Missy, look, okay,
I don't want to, okay?
MISSY: No, it is not okay.
MISSY: You like that?
JOEY: Yeah.
Yeah? You want
a little more?
Then you'll do
what I say.
If Missy Iied
about being raped,
who do you think
really planned these murders?
JOEY: I'm not saying anything.
CRAGEN: We watched
the tape, Joey.
Joseph, you have
to tell us the truth.
Your girlfriend set you up.
She said you raped her
and her sister.
She's blaming you
for the murders.
You're Iying.
She would never do that.
She Ioved me.
You don't understand.
You could get
the death penalty.
We know she
made you do this.
You don't know anything.
You never have.
Missy and Rebecca
both had gonorrhea.
So what?
The doctor gave you
a physical when you
got here,
and you tested negative.
Do you know what that means?
I don't give a damn.
Well, either you were treated,
or Missy has been sleeping
with someone else.
I don't believe you.
Do you really want to
protect somebody who
was cheating on you?
She'd never do that.
Well, then how did she
and Rebecca get gonorrhea
and you didn't?
She got it from somebody else,
and then she gave it
to her sister.
Can't you see what
she's doing to you?
I met Eric at the video store,
and he introduced me to Missy.
I just... I'd never
been with anybody Iike her.
It's Iike being high.
My brain just stopped working.
What did Missy
do to Rebecca?
She would drug her,
and then she would...
She would do things to her.
And one time,
Rebecca woke up.
Said that she
was going to tell.
And you had to kill Rebecca
to keep her quiet.
No. No, I told Missy
I didn't want to.
And she said that Eric
would do anything for money.
So she paid him,
and I told him what to do.
Whose idea was the robbery?
Missy's. See, I mentioned once
that my boss kept a gun under
the counter.
She said she'd drop
some tapes to make noise,
make it Iook Iike
Eric had freaked out.
And then, he would shoot...
He would shoot Rebecca,
and then I would shoot him,
and nobody could trace it
back to us.
(SOBBING)
Tell me this isn't
as bad as it seems.
Oh, it is.
And Missy's immunity
is etched in stone?
We can't touch her.
We're screwed.
Branch okayed the death
penalty motion on Joey Field.
Great.
AIex.
Give it a rest.
She played us, Liz.
This office,
the police, her own parents.
Missy used Joey to murder
her own sister, and now
she's killing him, too.
We dealt ourselves
this hand, and it's
all we've got to play.
Maybe not.
You can't reverse
Missy's immunity.
A judge can.
No judge is going to give us
a second chance.
Unless someone else
makes the argument for us.
Mr. Field,
we need your help.
What, to execute
my son?
To reverse Missy
Kurtz's immunity.
Well, Missy's immunity
helps my case.
You can't put her on
the stand because you
know she'II Iie,
and without her,
all your physical evidence
is circumstantial.
Do you really think
a jury is going to care?
Look, Missy's the only one
who can testify to motive.
A jury's going to
want to hear that.
A jury is going to
want to punish somebody
for the rape and murder
of a six-year-old child.
Your son is the only person
sitting at the defense table.
I did such a good job
as a father,
my son despises me.
He won't even
Iet me save him.
You still can.
The D.A. is willing to take
the death penalty off
the table. Work with us.
What are we doing here?
My client has immunity.
PETROVSKY: I agree.
I've seen the tape,
but it doesn't
change anything.
The evidence turned up
after immunity was imposed.
That's not our problem.
It is our problem.
Your Honor.
You know I can't
reverse immunity,
Mr. Field.
Unless it violates
my client's due process
right to a fair trial.
People v. Osorio.
Osorio isn't on point.
Sure it is, Judge.
The People can't put
Missy Kurtz on the stand
without suborning perjury.
That means my client can't
confront his accuser,
which is a violation
of the Sixth Amendment.
Ms. Cabot?
The People made a mistake.
We're not going to deny it.
How about you
colluding with the defense
to railroad my client?
You gonna deny that?
That may be the case,
Mr. Kressler, but you'd have
a hard time proving it.
You can't do this.
I can. And I am.
The immunity agreement between
the People and Missy Kurtz
is void.
Thank you, Your Honor.
Stick around, Ms. Cabot.
(DOOR CLOSING)
Aren't you going to thank me
for cleaning up your mess,
AIexandra?
Mr. Field made
a valid Iegal argument.
Which you handed him.
I'm tired of you
manipulating my court
to suit your needs.
I'm keeping this
case for trial.
When can I expect to see
an indictment on Missy Kurtz?
We'II begin working
on the rape immediately.
And the three murders?
Insufficient evidence,
Your Honor.
We're just not ready to...
You're telling me that you
jeopardized my judicial
record, and you're not ready?
You sure as hell better be.
By tomorrow.
A search warrant
for the Kurtz's home.
PIease, find me something.
Why? Because some judge
put you in the jackpot?
Sorry.
I'm not blaming anyone.
Is Missy in interrogation?
STABLER: Yeah,
with her Iawyer.
Let me see if I can
get myself out of this.
She must've really
pushed Petrovsky's buttons.
Yeah, while Missy
pushes everyone else's.
Including her parents.
You arrested Missy?
Mr. Kurtz, Mrs. Kurtz,
why don't we go someplace
where we can talk?
RAQUEL: Why? Are you going
to arrest us, too?
Excuse me.
What's going on here?
You couldn't build your case
against this animal,
so you go after Missy?
Joey Field.
Joey Field raped Rebecca
because Missy told him to.
The murders were Missy's idea.
Missy was raped
by that bastard.
I'm afraid the evidence
proves otherwise.
What evidence?
I want to see it.
We really don't want to make
this any harder than it has
to be.
What could be harder?
Show them.
You like that?
Yeah.
Yeah? You want
a little more?
Then you'll do what I say.
That's enough. Turn it off.
Turn it off!
AII right.
Why?
We Ioved that girl
from the moment she
came into our home!
That bastard gave
them both gonorrhea?
No, Mr. Kurtz,
he didn't.
Joey never had it.
My God. Missy gave it
to Rebecca?
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
How didn't we see?
Because Missy made
sure that you wouldn't.
What do we do now? What now?
We need your help.
Joey says Missy
paid Eric Campbell
$1,000 to shoot Rebecca.
Any ideas where
she could have gotten
that kind of money?
Missy murdered Rebecca
just as surely as if she had
pulled the trigger herself.
Now, whatever you know,
you can't Iet her
get away with this.
PETER: What she did
was reprehensible.
But you've
gotta understand.
We've just Iost
one daughter.
You can't ask us to help you
take the other one.
So we here
to talk a deal?
Why? Your client
want to plead?
Sure. How about
sexual misconduct?
On an A misdemeanor?
Your client worked
in concert with Joey Field.
Then she raped her sister,
then she murdered her sister
and two other people.
You can't prove that
she killed anybody.
We have you on tape
abusing your sister.
You both had gonorrhea.
We checked your parents'
phone records,
and you and Eric Campbell
spent a Iot of time chatting.
It's all circumstantial.
Not when Joey Field ties it
together on the stand.
Joey's not going
to testify against me.
He Ioves me.
Joey told us everything.
He knows you've
been sleeping around.
ROGER: He's a Iove-crazed
teenager.
When Rebecca threatened
to tell her parents,
Joey couldn't bear the thought
of Missy Ieaving him,
so he hired Eric Campbell
to murder Rebecca,
and then he murdered
him to shut him up.
He did what Missy
told him to do.
And after a jury hears that
Missy was repeatedly raped
by her biological
father and his friends,
do you think they're going
to hold her responsible
for any of this?
So, Missy still thinks
she's got us over a barrel?
She's right.
I can't mention
the murders at trial,
and even her calls
to Eric Campbell
don't definitively
prove it was her idea.
And Kressler puts
Joey Field on trial,
it's he said, she said.
He's setting her up to plead
not guilty by reason of mental
disease or defect.
Let's call a psychiatrist.
I'II send Huang over
to Rikers to see her.
Tell me about your
biological father.
You read the file.
I want to hear it from you.
My mother died
when I was five.
They said that's
when my father started
having sex with me.
What do you remember
about the abuse?
It hurt.
But as Iong as I cried,
I didn't get hit.
How did it feel when they
took you away from him?
At first, I was glad.
Then after they moved me
the third time, it didn't
make any difference.
The Kurtzs adopted you.
That must have
made a difference.
Yeah, right.
The Kurtzs wanted
their own kid.
Once Rebecca was born,
they didn't want me
around anymore.
They just kept me
out of pity.
That's not what
they told us.
Yeah, well.
People say they Iove you,
but they really don't.
Joey Ioves you.
Joey Ioves sex.
He was ready to face
the death penalty for you.
But he didn't, did he?
He's out for himself,
just Iike everybody else.
Missy has flat affect,
minimal insight,
and no capacity for empathy.
So she's a sociopath.
That doesn't make for
a Iegit psychiatric defense.
Kressler will spin it
as untreated post-traumatic
stress disorder
with dissociative features.
Her early childhood
was severely traumatic.
Without immediate
intensive therapy,
no way she could form
healthy attachments.
By the time
the Kurtzs adopted her,
it was too Iate.
So Missy's mad, not bad,
and Daddy takes the rap.
Missy didn't get the therapy
that she needed.
That's not her fault.
HUANG: Well, it doesn't
excuse her behavior.
Missy knew what she
was doing was wrong.
She just didn't care.
It's too bad
her father's dead.
I'd Iove to prosecute him.
MUNCH: Look at this.
Where have you two been?
Searching
Eric Campbell's room.
Whatever Missy paid him
must've burned a hole
in his pocket
at the electronics store.
We know whether Missy
has her own money?
Couple of hundred
in her checking account,
no recent withdrawals.
Same with the parents.
Missy probably
never even asked them.
You're a teenager,
you need some quick cash
and you can't ask
your parents,
what are you gonna do?
You're either gonna
borrow it or steal it.
Or sell something valuable.
Or give something
to the hit man
in Iieu of cash.
Something jog your memory?
We found a half a pawn ticket
in Eric Campbell's room.
Dated two days
before the murder.
AL: Where'd you get this?
FIN: A dead man.
How'd he get dead?
Somebody shot him.
You got any more questions,
AI, or you gonna show us
the merchandise?
Today's your Iucky day.
Is it real?
You kidding?
This is white gold.
The chain Iooks the same.
Half a karat
of pav diamonds.
Look at you.
A connoisseur.
It's gotta be worth
at Ieast $3,000.
Dumb punk who brought it in
gave it to me for a grand.
There's even an inscription
on the back.
CABOT: "To Missy with Iove,
from Mom and Dad."
What's this?
Jewelry your client
gave to Eric Campbell.
Payment for his services
as a hit man.
So?
We have a sworn statement
ID-ing Eric as the man who
pawned this pendant.
Joey stole it
and gave it to Eric.
A jury is never going
to believe that, Missy.
You can't prove it
didn't happen that way.
Do you want to
explain it to her?
What can we do here?
Joey got Eric
to kill Rebecca.
Joey shot Eric.
Joey's going to get
the death penalty.
No. We made a deal with Joey.
Joey is going to plead guilty
and go to prison after he
testifies against you.
You are getting
the death penalty
for murdering your sister.
She wasn't my sister.
Rebecca was an innocent,
six-year-old child.
You think I'm
supposed to feel sad?
Scared?
I don't.
You can't kill me.
I'm already dead.
Ms. Cabot.
Missy's Iawyer told us
the D.A.'s going
for the death penalty.
I know.
Well, there's gotta be
something you can do.
I'm sorry, Mr. Kurtz.
It's out of my hands.
Ms. Cabot, killing her
won't bring Becca back.
It is my job to
speak for the victims.
Ms. Cabot, can't you see
how damaged Missy is?
Yes. Yes, I can.
Well then,
why can't you just
put her in prison?
Because I have
to follow the Iaw.