NARRATOR: In the criminal
justice system,
sexually based offenses
are considered
especially heinous.
In New York City,
the dedicated detectives
who investigate
these vicious felonies
are members
of an elite squad known
as the Special Victims Unit.
These are their stories.
AII right,
I got the pick.
Switch! Switch!
I got you.
What you got?
LYNN: Help me!
Help me!
Help me, please!
My God.
Help me!
Lynn, what's wrong?
He's not breathing.
My baby's not breathing.
Tuck, call 911.
AII right.
Hurry up!
Jawan!
Oh, my God!
(SOBBING)
Baby's name
is Jawan Hauser,
10 weeks old.
EMS brought him in
a couple of hours ago.
How's he doing?
On a respirator,
his pulse is weak.
Kid was probably
oxygen deprived.
We won't know the extent
of the brain damage
until he wakes up,
if he ever does.
We talking shaken baby?
Body scan's negative
for healed fractures.
Head CT normal.
No bruising
or retinal hemorrhaging.
So, you must have
brought us in here
for a reason.
I was concerned
when he came in.
EIevated heart rate,
shallow respirations,
dilated pupils.
Sounds Iike an OD.
You're right.
Tox screen's positive
for cocaine.
Someone doped this kid up.
Cocaine?
And you think
I gave it to my baby?
We're not jumping
to any conclusions.
Because I'm black,
Iive in the projects,
so I must be
doing drugs, right?
Why don't we calm down?
That's not what we're saying.
My mother was a junkie.
I never touched that dope
in my Iife.
I worked my ass off
cleaning houses
to keep me and Jawan
in that apartment.
I need you to tell me
exactly what happened.
I picked up Jawan
from his daycare after work,
brought him home.
I fed him,
but he wasn't very hungry
because he went
right to sleep,
so I put him
in his crib.
When I checked on him,
he was hardly breathing.
Is Jawan dead?
No. No. No.
But the doctors say
that the cocaine Iooks Iike
it was mixed in
with the baby formula.
Oh, God.
How did that happen?
Well, we need
to find out fast.
Where'd you buy
the formula?
At the store.
Which store?
I don't remember.
Lynn, you gotta
Iisten to me.
You do not want
to be responsible
for that poison being fed
to another baby.
It was my fault.
I borrowed it.
From the people
that you clean for?
I was short on money,
so I had to.
I swear, I was gonna
give it back.
Oh, my God.
You have to call them.
They have a 4-month-old boy.
Thank God
I got your message.
Tommy and I
just got back
from the park.
I was about to
feed him.
Baby Growth
is the brand we use,
but you said
someone poisoned it?
I can't believe
she would do
something Iike that.
Well, we can't take
any chances.
My God, if I had
given it to Tommy...
I keep all the formula
in here.
Mrs. Pfeiffer,
we're gonna need to do that.
Sorry.
Do you remember how many
cans you had Ieft?
Six. I buy it by the case.
BENSON: I count five.
Lynn must have taken
the missing can.
LAURA: I never noticed.
Mrs. Pfeiffer,
it's urgent that we know
where and when you bought
this baby formula.
My husband got it
a couple of days ago.
Gentry's Market on Columbus.
We took every can
of formula
off the shelves at Gentry's,
tested each one.
AII clear.
What about the ones
in Pfeiffer's pantry?
Four, perfectly
normal Iiquid,
and the other one
had the same chemistry
as the stuff fed
to Jawan Hauser.
Cocaine-Iaced
baby formula.
I wouldn't call it formula.
It's 90% pure Iiquid cocaine.
That purity probably came
from south of the border.
I've never seen it
smuggled this way before.
Take a Iook, solder plug.
That's where
they drained the formula
and refilled it
with Iiquid coke.
Seal it up,
glue the Iabel back on,
ship a couple of cases
to los Estados Unidos,
nobody's any the wiser.
They gotta have Iabs
on both sides
of the border
to turn it into Iiquid,
then back into powder.
And how'd this end up
on some store shelf?
I can't help you there,
but the manufacturer can.
Baby formula's closely
regulated by the FDA.
Each can has a Iot number
and expiration date on top.
You can find out
where it was made
and purchased.
I called the FDA.
They're gonna issue
a CIass I recall,
highest priority.
AII the FDA can do
is ask the company
to pull the product.
Not when it involves
infant formula.
Then they have the authority.
How're we doing?
Every can of Baby Growth
in the market
and every clean can
at the Pfeiffers'
was made
at the Atlanta plant.
And the two bad cans?
Lot numbers
weren't even close.
Why? Because
they were manufactured
at the Baby Growth plant
in Mexico. Juárez.
Cartel country.
So, our friends
get it down there,
replace the Spanish
Ianguage Iabels
with ones in English,
and then they smuggle it
up here.
Yeah, the question is
how did those two cans
from Mexico
end up in
the Pfeiffers' closet?
Well, what do we know
about the Pfeiffers?
She's home with the baby.
The husband's name is Derek.
He's a stockbroker,
works at a firm
called Chandler Hinton
down on Wall Street.
Well, that wouldn't be
the first time
some big shot,
hard up for cash,
moonlighted in
the drug biz.
Derek Pfeiffer sounds
Iike our perfect candidate.
Credit report in the dumper.
Filing for bankruptcy
when he miraculously erases
$300,000 in debt.
Sudden windfall?
Benson.
Yeah, Iike the kind you get
from a big drug shipment.
Who says crime doesn't pay?
Yeah.
That was the hospital.
Jawan Hauser died
a half-hour ago.
That's depraved
indifference murder
for whoever smuggled that coke
in those formula cans.
Go talk to Pfeiffer.
If you don't Iike
what he has to say,
bring him in.
I really appreciate
you guys getting that stuff
out of my house
before something bad
happened.
That's no problem.
We just gotta figure out
how it got in your house.
That's easy.
I bought it.
Problem is, there
wasn't another bad
can in that store,
which means
the only two cans
of Iiquid cocaine
on the Upper West Side
were in your pantry.
I wish
I could help you guys.
MUNCH: Take any trips
out of the country
Iately, Derek?
Say, Iike, down Mexico way?
I have clients
all over the world.
That's okay,
you don't have to tell us.
We can check with Customs.
I just got back
from Mexico City
on company business.
Look, it's not good
for me to be seen here
talking to you guys
Iike this in the office.
What a coincidence.
We were gonna suggest
that you come down
to our office
and continue
this discussion.
I'm not going
anywhere with you.
Sure you are.
Or you'II be seen
wearing steel when we
drag you out of here.
Is this really necessary?
I have five client meetings
this afternoon.
Believe me,
that's the Ieast
of your problems.
STABLER: Uh-oh.
What's the matter?
I smell a rat.
Big time.
Sergeant Tucker, to what
do we owe this visit
from Internal Affairs?
FIN: Don't forget to salute
or you'II get a 30-day rip.
What are you doing?
Standing here
talking to a friend.
His name Derek Pfeiffer?
What's it to you?
Mr. Pfeiffer's
coming with me.
We got a dead kid
on our hands.
That baby is no Ionger
your concern.
Narcotics dime us?
AII you need to know
is your captain
signed off on it.
Mr. Pfeiffer, my name
is Sergeant Tucker.
You need to come
with me, sir.
Our captain told you
where we were?
What's the deal
with Tucker?
Sergeant Tucker
from IAB?
Yeah, did you send him?
Send him?
What's going on here?
Where's Pfeiffer?
Tucker took him
right out
of our hands.
Said he had your okay.
Let's take a ride.
Captain Cragen,
Detective Stabler.
How can I help you?
You Iying son of a bitch.
Now, it's not enough
you go behind my back
to steal our case.
Now you want my people
thinking I'm in your pocket.
Get off me now.
You don't need
what he can do to you.
Just relax.
I should Iock you up.
Do it. Then explain it
to your bosses.
You need anger
management, Captain.
And you need to kiss my ass.
Where's Derek Pfeiffer?
We questioned him
and Iet him go.
He's a suspect
in a murder investigation.
Any of your people
go near him,
and you'II go
before a trial board.
Good, and then
you can explain
why an infant died
on your watch.
I want to know
what the hell's
going on here.
I don't have to
tell you squat.
IAB investigating
means a dirty cop's
involved.
I want a name.
Go to hell.
So, now what's
our next move?
Pick up Derek Pfeiffer.
You really wanna
take on IAB?
Tucker doesn't tell us
how to do our jobs.
Look, EIIiot,
you're following an order
from your CO.
If it gets ugly,
that's what you tell them.
If we hurry,
we can catch Pfeiffer
just Ieaving work.
Hey, Special Victims,
what's up?
Came in as a 34.
Suit, not breathing,
in a bathroom
on the 20th floor.
That's where Pfeiffer works.
BENSON: Damn it.
It's Pfeiffer.
Somebody beat us to him.
MUNCH: Whoever killed Pfeiffer
must've followed him in
and got him
before he closed
the stall door.
Cable he was
strangled with
could've came
from any office
in this building.
Perp could've
brought it in to
make it Iook that way.
This is Keith Gerard.
He's Mr. Pfeiffer's
immediate boss.
Detectives Munch
and Tutuola.
Sorry for your Ioss.
I don't know
how this happens
in a business Iike this.
Building's been
Iocked down tight
since 9/11,
all visitors signed in
and escorted by security.
Probably 10 other ways
to get in,
nothing's foolproof.
Possible one
of Pfeiffer's clients
had it in for him?
If Iosing money
were enough
to set someone off,
we'd all be dead by now.
Derek's desk. Feel free.
Anything unusual about
his behavior Iately?
Derek was under
a Iot of stress.
You mean because of
the market going south?
No, I mean he got demoted.
What happened?
His biggest accounts
Iost millions.
The investors
called for his head
and they got it.
He used to run the floor.
And then
you stepped in.
Believe me, that's not
how I wanted it to happen.
You mind telling us
where you've been
for the Iast
couple of hours?
Sure. Meeting with
the managing partners.
Well, we're gonna
need their names
and a Iist
of Pfeiffer's accounts.
I'II have my assistant
get it for you.
This has gotta be a hit.
They knew Pfeiffer
was talking to us
and they shut him up.
That means his wife's
a target, too.
Derek never would have
been involved with drugs.
We think that
your husband smuggled in
the baby formula
from Mexico.
No, you're wrong.
Did you know your husband
was demoted at work?
No.
Did you know
he filed for bankruptcy?
I knew we were in debt,
but Derek said
he paid everything off.
Bonus for closing
a big deal, he told me.
Mrs. Pfeiffer,
did your husband
ever talk to you
about work?
No, he said he didn't want
to bring the job home
because he worked
so many hours.
Are all those hours
at the office?
He used to entertain clients,
three nights a week,
at the Bear and Bull.
Did you ever meet
any of his
business associates?
No, I told you,
Derek didn't want us
in that world.
Why are you asking me
all these questions?
Mrs. Pfeiffer, if your
husband was murdered
because of his
involvement with drugs,
the people who
killed him may think
you know something.
Oh, my God.
Are you telling me
Tommy and I are in danger?
Two detectives are
on their way over here.
They're gonna stay with you.
It's for your own safety.
No.
No, we'II go to
my sister's.
I'II feel more
comfortable there.
Has somebody
threatened you?
Mrs. Pfeiffer?
After you were here,
a man knocked on the door.
Said Derek sent him
to pick up the formula.
I told him
I gave it to you,
and he got really upset.
I asked him how he got
past the doorman,
and he showed me his badge.
It's an IAB operation,
and I warned you
to back off.
Your detectives...
Were following my orders.
Now who else at IAB
was in on this?
Don't even try
and pin this on me here.
Only five people
in this squad
knew about this case.
Three of us are here,
and the other two
are cleaning up your mess.
Now, I still got
a few friends on this job
who wear stars
on their shoulders.
You wanna tell them
how this went down,
or should I?
Twice, over the Iast year,
Narcotics tried to infiltrate
your baby formula
cocaine ring.
Undercovers got made
both times.
By your dirty cop.
Narcotics thought
it was one of theirs.
That's why they
turned it over to us.
BENSON: And you have
no idea who it is?
We're not sure.
You're not sure
about much, are you?
You know, our D.A.
could've made a deal
with Pfeiffer
to give up your dirty cop
if you hadn't crapped
all over our case.
It's our case, Detective.
Not anymore.
Your people can't handle
this kind of work.
My people do
this kind of work every day.
A baby died
of cocaine poisoning,
and we're damn well
gonna find out
who's responsible.
Now, you wanna help us, fine,
otherwise get the hell
out of our way.
AII right.
What do you need?
Fake IDs, vehicles,
drugs and buy money,
for starters.
You don't make a move
without telling me.
Checked everyone
on the security Iog
at Chandler Hinton.
AII visitors accounted for
and nothing useful
from the canvass.
Pfeiffer's phone records
any help?
Well, the only thing
that stands out
is that whenever Pfeiffer
was at the Bear and Bull,
he always called home
from a pay phone instead
of using his cell.
Sounds Iike
he doesn't want
anyone to know
who else he's calling.
CIassic paranoia.
Could be where he does
his other business.
Hey, there's plenty
of drug activity
down at some of those joints
in the financial district.
Coke to fuel
the high stress jobs.
You're the one with
undercover experience.
I go Iooking to score
in one of them
Wall Street bars,
I might as well
put a sign on my back
that says "cop."
But EIIiot here,
he Iooks Iike the clean-cut
corporate type.
Well, if that's
a compliment,
I'm game.
AII right.
OIivia and Fin
will ghost you.
Munch and I
are backups.
We need to get you
a cover story.
Baby formula scheme's
down the toilet,
so they're gonna be
Iooking for a new way
to bring in the product.
You wanna get
their attention real fast,
you gotta be the solution.
And I gotta be
vulnerable.
Never flash
your buy money.
If they offer to buy,
you know the test.
Snow seals.
There's a quarter gram
of coke in each one.
And take this.
What are you gonna do,
page me?
It's a wire.
If they frisk you,
they'II never suspect it.
Got it from a buddy
in TARU.
We got backup inside.
I'II be out here
recording. Cool?
Yeah.
(SOFT JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
How's it going?
What can I get you?
Give me a beer,
that Iast one on the end,
and give the Iady
whatever she's having.
BARTENDER:
Scotch on the rocks?
Yeah.
You got it.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
How you doing?
I'm not bad.
How are you?
Better now.
BARTENDER: Here we go.
That'II be 12 bucks.
(LAUGHS)
Sorry about that.
(CHUCKLING)
That any good?
I'II tell you what,
why don't you
just take a Iittle taste
and you tell me?
I can turn you on
to something
a Iittle fresher.
Have a taste.
What's your name?
Donna.
He's talking to somebody
at the end of the bar.
Probably the resident dealer.
And he's coming back.
I'm good. That's for you.
Gentleman down
the end of the bar
would Iike a word with you.
He interested?
Says he'II make it
worth your while.
He's following some guy
into the bathroom.
Whoa.
This your idea
of a conversation?
You trying to sell
this crap on my turf?
Who the hell are you?
Who am I?
Yeah.
I'm the guy whose spot
you're parked in.
And I gotta tell you, pal,
I don't Iike competition,
okay?
Wait a minute.
This guy said
you were interested.
This is a big
misunderstanding.
Hey, I don't want
a problem here,
man, really.
So, what's your name?
Here.
Greg EIIiot.
So, Greg, where are you
serving out of?
Building where my office is.
And how much?
How much...
How much quantity?
Three hundred grams
every two weeks, about.
That's... That's impressive.
Yeah.
What are you paying
your supplier?
Ninety.
I'II tell you, Greg,
my people could do better.
My customers Iike
what they're getting.
The stuff I got,
it's top quality.
Okay, I'm Iistening.
Good. Good.
Why don't you meet me
tonight at the entrance
to the seaport, say, 8:00?
And bring your money.
Who's he?
Shut up.
Nice to meet you, too.
He's clean.
Still didn't answer
my question.
You got the money?
Wow!
Wow, you wanna show me
the product?
It's a Iittle better
than mine.
Seventy a gram,
introductory offer.
Then we renegotiate.
No, you gotta do
better than that.
Why don't you taste it?
Taste it, because they do
random drug tests
where I work.
I don't do this stuff.
AII right.
AII right. AII right.
Seventy a gram.
Permanent price.
Permanent price. Done.
Hey. Hey.
Take the money.
What're you doing?
You guys, Iook. Hey.
He's got a gun,
Captain.
FIN: Wait a minute.
Everybody, hang tight.
Show me a badge.
Oh.
He's got a gold shield.
STABLER: Look, guys,
Iet's talk about this.
Now he's got
EIIiot's wallet.
What do you say?
You gonna read me
my rights?
You don't got
any rights.
Well, I guess we just
found our dirty cop.
This doesn't Iook
Iike any police station
I've ever seen.
You think
I'm gonna do business
with some dumbass punk?
Are we just gonna
sit here
while they beat
the crap out of him?
If they wanted to kill him,
he'd be dead by now.
What is this?
Some sort of initiation?
The guy with the shield
just wants to show
he's the alpha dog,
to mark his spot.
Your call, Captain.
You see a gun come out,
move. Don't wait.
I hope you didn't
bring me here
just to kick my ass.
Gregory EIIiot,
married, four kids,
house in Forest Hills.
You still got
that gambling problem,
Greg?
What's that?
Your homework assignment?
Director of Station Operations
for GIobal Package Express.
What's that mean?
I run our worldwide
shipping stations.
What are you doing?
Putting together my résumé?
Must be
a Iot of travel.
Yeah, I do my share.
I think you're just
the guy we're Iooking for.
Guys, I just sell the stuff,
small quantities.
I don't move it.
You do now.
I'm telling you,
I'm selling this
for an old friend of mine,
that's it.
You want Ioyalty,
get a puppy.
I got you with enough blow
for an A-1 felony.
That's Iife
without parole.
You don't think my company
doesn't have safeguards
to prevent people
from doing this sort of thing?
Then you're gonna have to
think outside the box,
Iike they teach you
in business school.
You got till
tomorrow to decide.
Phone number's
on there.
Who's answering?
Call me Kendall.
Oh, one more thing.
Yeah.
That's for the attitude.
Can I have
my wallet?
How's the patient?
Couple of scratches.
He'II Iive.
CRAGEN: What'd you find out?
Brad Kendall's
got 13 years on the job,
nine in Manhattan Narcotics.
He's got more decorations
than you can hang
on a Christmas tree.
Sounds Iike he was
a good cop once.
Nothing Iower
than a commendation,
even got a combat cross.
MUNCH: He walked in
on a gas station robbery,
perps shot at him
and missed.
He killed them both.
Decade of watching
drug dealers
make the big bucks,
guess he wanted
a piece of the action.
If I had went Kendall's route,
I could've been
a rich man by now.
He matches
Laura Pfeiffer's description
of a cop who came Iooking
for baby formula.
We know if Kendall
ever made an appearance
there before?
I spoke to all the doormen
in the building.
It was only that one time.
Which means Pfeiffer
normally delivered
the cocaine to him.
Probably at
the Bear and Bull.
Okay, what about
Kendall's butt boy?
Frank Barry.
Thirty. In and out of prison
on a string of drug collars,
mostly for possession.
Never carried enough weight
to be charged
with intent to sell.
Well, he and Kendall
are soldiers.
There's no way they got
the brains or the muscle
to run an operation Iike this.
We don't even know
how big this thing is.
But there's no way
that Pfeiffer's
their only mule.
Well, Kendall
gave you 24 hours.
That means he's hard up
for product.
If he doesn't
get some soon,
the people that buy
from him are gonna cop
from somebody else.
Get back to Kendall.
Turn up the heat this time,
but meet in a public place.
We don't want
a rerun of tonight.
Why here?
This is where
I do business.
You know, I don't remember
us talking money
while you were
kicking my ass.
I'm Ietting you
stay out of jail.
There's nothing
to talk about.
Oh, no?
Well, what's to stop me
from going to the cops
and telling them
you're shaking me down?
I'm a hero cop.
I mean, who do you think
they're gonna believe?
Then you must think
I am some dumbass punk, huh?
You know what I think?
You're trying
to stay in business.
What, you got
a crystal ball or something?
You need me so bad
you're blackmailing me
to work for you.
That smells
of desperation to me.
I'II tell you what,
hero cop, you're right.
Lock me up.
What do you want?
A third of the profits
of whatever I ship,
after you tell me
why I'm the answer
to your problems.
What's the difference?
It's business.
I don't do business
with Iiars or screw-ups.
(CHUCKLES)
I'II take it to my people.
I don't know
what that means.
What does that mean,
take it to your people?
What, you can't close
the deal?
I mean, doesn't sound
Iike you're very high up
in the food chain.
Maybe I should be talking
to someone who has
a Iittle more juice.
No, you're dealing with me.
Okay.
Have it your way.
You go "talk to your people."
See if they can afford me,
and I'II Iet you know
of my decision.
Try the veal,
it's great.
Okay, I'II call you back
with the details.
What do they want you
to do?
Bring in 10 boxes
of terracotta tiles
made of cocaine base.
Four kilos per box,
each worth $80,000.
My cover story,
I'm retiling my kitchen.
Where's it coming from?
Mexico City.
Gotta find a reason
to get me on down there.
Mexico's a Iittle
out of our jurisdiction.
Not to mention,
out of our Ieague.
Okay, you tell Kendall
you can't make the trip
on such short notice
without arousing suspicion.
Somebody in Mexico City
will make the pickup for you.
Where's the drop?
My alter ego's house
in Forest Hills.
Delivery company
drops off the tiles,
Kendall will come
and pick them up.
We'II have to involve DEA.
They can get us
a cover house
and handle
the pickup in Mexico.
Kendall could be working
with DEA people.
Well, that's a chance
we're gonna have to take.
That's the Iast one, sir.
Thanks a Iot.
This is the most
we've been able
to bring in at one time.
I guess you're saying
you're a satisfied
customer then.
That'II be $267,000.
You wanna count it?
I don't know. Do I need to?
Now Iet's move these.
Honey, are those the tiles?
No, it's a mistake.
They're the wrong ones.
This guy's gonna
exchange them.
He's got ours in his van.
Hey, this is my wife Dana.
Hi.
Hi. How are you?
Baby, you gotta get
in the shower.
We have to be
at Vanessa and GIen's
in Iess than two hours.
Oh, are these the tiles?
STABLER: I don't want to go...
Hey, hey, hey.
What's he doing back here?
Yo, I must've
not signed for it.
He must've made a mistake.
I'II deal with this.
KENDALL: Son of a bitch.
Back off!
Police, Kendall, freeze!
Freeze! Drop the gun!
Drop your gun.
Drop your gun!
Drop it!
Drop the...
You okay?
Call the bus.
FIN: 10-13, Manhattan SVU.
We got an officer shot.
We're at 6432 99th Street,
Forest Hills, send a bus.
What happened?
He turned around.
I had no choice.
The son of a bitch
just turned on me.
Okay.
He turned on me.
Okay. Take it easy.
I had no choice.
He wanted me to shoot him.
Son of a bitch
wanted me to shoot him.
Why'd he make me do that?
Why?
He didn't have the guts
to do it himself.
EIIiot, I need your gun.
I know the drill.
STABLER: Upon realizing
he was the target
of our sting operation,
Detective Kendall
pulled his weapon
on Detective Benson
and myself.
What happened next?
He ran. I followed.
AIone?
Detective Benson
wasn't armed.
Undercover operation,
it was her call.
But you were armed.
My call.
I didn't trust Kendall.
Are you sure you don't want
your union delegate here?
I've got nothing to hide.
Now how many more times
are we gonna go over this?
Detective Kendall
never fired his weapon,
but you did.
After I identified myself
as a police officer
and ordered Detective Kendall
to drop his weapon,
he turned
and pointed it at me.
Just Iike I told you before.
And how many times
did you fire your weapon?
Two.
Because you saw him
raise his weapon.
To shoot me.
There's nothing else
I could've done.
I'm officially notifying you
you're on modified assignment,
restricted to your office
until our investigation
is completed.
You're not to make
any arrests
or interrogate any suspects
until then.
Is that clear, Detective?
The bastard makes me
shoot him,
and I'm the one
under investigation.
EIIiot, maybe you ought to
take a few vacation days.
Not until I find out
who bankrolled Kendall.
I killed him,
I killed our only Iead.
EIIiot, the Iab found
dandruff flakes
on the computer cable
used to strangle
Derek Pfeiffer.
Matches Kendall's DNA.
So Kendall whacked Pfeiffer
to shut him up,
probably on orders
from the top.
With Kendall gone,
we may never find out
who that is.
Well, Kendall
arranged that shipment
of tiles somehow.
Anything on the phones?
Just a few Iocal calls
to family members.
Nothing suspicious.
We also took
a prepaid cell off him,
untraceable.
What about his gofer,
Frank Barry?
We haven't found him yet,
but he's too Iow
on the totem pole
to have access
to the top guy.
Maybe Laura Pfeiffer
can fill in the blanks.
BENSON: How?
We found the bad formula
in her kitchen,
we're thinking
Derek brought it in.
But when I called customs
to check on his trips
to Mexico,
we found out
she traveled there, too.
When?
In the Iast three weeks,
five round trips
with her baby,
all on different flights
than her husband.
Doesn't make sense
they would travel
separately every time.
It does if you're
smuggling cocaine
in baby formula cans
and you wanna stay
under the radar.
Mother traveling with a baby.
Customs wouldn't have given
a couple of extra cans
of formula a second thought.
No wonder she refused
our protection.
She's the mule,
not Derek.
But Derek's the one
that got whacked,
so he's gotta be in on it.
So question is,
did he or his company
arrange his business trips?
Let's go ask his boss,
Keith Gerard.
I'II go with you.
He was servicing
a Mexican client,
billionaire entrepreneur
who's afraid to fly.
So we go to him.
Fax this to Chicago.
Yes, sir.
Do you usually send a guy
to your billionaire clients
who spends his day
making cold calls?
Look, Derek was
the company's scapegoat
against the bear market.
He shouldn't have Iost
his position,
so I tried
to throw him a bone.
You wanna tell me
what this has to do
with his death?
Derek was smuggling cocaine
on your time and your dime.
Running drugs?
Are you kidding me?
AIong with his wife and son.
I knew it couldn't be true.
You're wrong.
BENSON: And why's that?
Derek and Laura
don't have any children.
If Tommy isn't
the Pfeiffers' child,
then who does he
belong to?
Somebody who needs
the cash so bad
that they're willing
to rent their kid out
as a drug mule.
And Tommy,
or whatever his name is,
he can't be the only one.
So you're thinking
whoever's running this
has a ring of mothers
with babies
bringing the coke in.
Well, it's gotta be.
Even if Laura Pfeiffer
brought in three cans
on each of her trips,
it's not enough of a profit
to warrant the risk.
We know where she is?
Yep.
She's staying
with her sister,
Denise Draper,
out on Staten Island.
(TOMMY CRYING)
(DOORBELL RINGING)
I can't believe
they Iet him cry
Iike that.
This must be the sister's.
The Pfeiffers don't have
one registered.
Let's check around back.
Captain.
CRAGEN: GIass is still
on the floor,
nobody cleaned it up.
Let's go.
(TOMMY WAILING)
You take him.
I'II check the rest.
Hey, hey, hey. Sweetheart.
It's okay, buddy. It's okay.
It's all right, sweetheart.
I know. I know.
Let's go find your mommy.
OIivia, in here.
It's okay, buddy.
It's okay, sweetheart.
It's okay.
Come here.
(BENSON GASPS)
Come here. It's okay.
Neighbors hear anything?
FIN: Nada.
CSU found the pillow
the shooter used
to muffle the gunshots.
Any chance
this is Kendall's work?
Unless it's his ghost.
M.E. places time of death
at four to eight hours ago.
Well, somebody's cleaning up
the Ioose ends
Kendall Ieft behind.
If that had been
the cartel,
they would've
killed everybody
just to make a point,
including the baby.
Guys, Tommy
was Laura's nephew.
I found his birth certificate
in the dining room credenza
next to this.
PIane ticket
to Mexico perhaps?
Rio, one-way.
Probably so Laura
couldn't be extradited.
This guy's one
cold-blooded customer.
He killed
this baby's mother,
he'II do the same
to the others.
So we're on borrowed time,
and the perp's already
two steps ahead of us.
Call EIIiot.
Have him start checking
every murder
in the Tri-State
since Kendall was killed.
We're Iooking
for any victims
with an infant.
Yeah. Got it.
Can you tell me
what time it happened?
Whacking mothers
with infants.
Right. Right.
Are you sure...
Yeah, that's what I said.
Any children?
BENSON: Two victims.
No, I'm not kidding.
We think there's
gonna be more.
I'm not trying
to be difficult.
Thanks a Iot.
Odafin Tutuola.
Tutuola. You need me
to spell it for you?
Come on.
Call me when you find out.
Thanks.
Got another one.
Where?
Mount Vernon.
Hooker.
Any kids?
They don't have that yet.
What do you mean,
they don't have it?
Munch, I need information.
I'm stuck here.
You guys are the ones
who are out there
trying to find this guy.
You think
I'm just gonna watch?
You need to take a break.
You should call
Mount Vernon back
and find out
if the victim had kids.
I brought you
some dinner.
Now is not a good time.
You've got to eat.
I gotta find this guy.
It's after midnight.
Come home, get some rest.
Kathy, I can't Ieave.
OIivia, state police
just found Kendall's
sidekick Frank Barry.
STABLER:
Munch, wait a minute.
Hug the kids. I Iove you.
Thanks for dinner.
Where?
Body washed up
on Jones Beach.
Same MO?
One to the back
of the head.
OIivia, grab your coat,
we got another one. Queens.
Hey, Donny,
called your people
as soon
as it came in.
They're in
the Iiving room.
OIivia Benson,
Lieutenant Philly Panzaretti,
Queens Homicide.
Hey, nice to meet you.
What've we got?
Two victims.
Francisco and BIanca FIores.
Lived here
with their Iittle girl,
eight months old.
How's the baby?
Screaming when
patrol showed up,
but otherwise, okay.
EMS took her to EImhurst
to make sure.
CRAGEN: Shooter used a pillow
to muffle the gunshots.
Looks Iike the same MO
as the Staten Island murders.
Except the perp
broke into that house.
There's no sign
anyone forced
their way in here.
So, whoever it was,
the victim knew them.
Looks Iike somebody
worked from home.
Mr. FIores was a gardener.
His truck's parked out back.
Wife did his billing.
Judging from this place,
Mr. FIores wasn't
making any extra money
running drugs.
Or he just hasn't
spent it yet.
What'd you find?
An invoice made out
to Keith Gerard.
Mr. FIores
Iandscapes his house.
That's no coincidence.
He's running
this drug operation
from that brokerage house,
he's the top dog.
Renting babies from people
Iike Mr. and Mrs. FIores
who work for him
and need the money.
And now
he's gotta kill them all
so they can't finger him.
Detective Benson,
Captain Cragen.
We need to speak
to Mr. Gerard now.
I'm afraid
he stepped out.
Do you know
where he went?
He said he was going
to the corporate
daycare center.
Where is that?
Right downstairs
on the second floor.
What's going on here?
You Iisten.
Listen very carefully.
If Gerard calls,
you do not tell him
we're here.
You got it?
There's Gerard.
With his next victim.
(SCREAMING)
Drop your weapon.
PIease don't hurt my baby.
Shut up.
Drop it.
Get back.
Get back now or she's dead.
It's over. It's over.
We can all walk away
from this.
I'm Ieaving the building
with her and the kid.
CRAGEN: You're gonna have to
show us some good faith,
all right?
Just Iet them go.
You're gonna watch her die.
CRAGEN: This is between us.
What, you think
I'm an idiot?
Just don't hurt them
and there's a way out.
A way out?
Okay, all right,
Iook, Iet them go.
You can walk
out of here alone.
No cops?
No cops.
Get off,
you're hurting me.
Yeah. That's tough.
I can make you
both rich.
Yeah? You better save it
for the fancy Iawyer
you'II need
to appeal
the death penalty.
D.A.'s office
isn't gonna drag you
before the grand jury,
and IAB cleared you.
In two days, how?
Incentive.
Spare themselves
the embarrassment
in the press.
What did it cost you?
Not nearly what it was worth.
I'II see you tomorrow.
BENSON: Good night, Captain.
How'd it go?
We got them all.
Ten other mothers.
Gerard paid
each mother 20 grand
to rent those babies.
Good job.
They making you
see the shrink?
Yeah.
You been there?
Not yet.
I thought I was okay, too,
when I shot that guy.
But even a Iowlife
Iike Kendall's
gonna stay with you.
I gotta get home.
Thanks.
How Iong has that sandwich
been sitting there?
I got busy. It's all yours.
You sleeping?
Yeah.
Seeing that shrink,
did that help?
Not much.