NARRATOR: In the criminal
justice system,
sexually based offenses
are considered
especially heinous.
In New York City,
the dedicated detectives
who investigate
these vicious felonies
are members
of an elite squad known
as the Special Victims Unit.
These are their stories.
What'd she say?
Moms won't budge.
Your arraignment's tomorrow,
so if you can post bond
you'II only be in
the Tombs for the night.
What do you think
they'II ask for?
Probably more than you got.
What if I can't
make bail?
Then you go to
Rikers till your trial.
Look, just Iet me talk
to Mrs. Parks. I'II try
to make her understand.
It's not gonna help.
She's on fire.
She wants you to pay
for what you did
to her daughter.
I Iove Sara.
Look, she's pregnant,
and I want to marry her.
She was 15 when
you took her to bed.
You're 21.
In case you haven't heard,
there's Iaws against that.
So there's nothing
I can do.
Serve your time.
If you're Iucky,
you'II be out in 18 months.
Gentlemen,
your stay here
is short,
but will feel
Iike a Iifetime
if you make trouble.
I will not Iisten to
pleas of innocence,
police brutality, entrapment
or evidence tampering.
Save it for Legal Aid.
You'II be fingerprinted,
photographed,
cavity searched
and assigned a cell.
Chow is at 7:00,
noon and 6:00.
Lights out at 9:30.
Have a nice day.
Spread them.
What's that God-awful smell?
(SNIFFING) Jailhouse perfume,
bitch. Get used to it.
He's in my bed.
There's a free bunk
right over there.
You have a problem?
On your feet, mark.
I said move it!
Brute.
Is that blood?
Guard!
Guard, help! Guard!
(INMATES CLAMORING)
INMATE: Hey! Hey, you got
a problem in there, baby?
It only hurts
the first time, baby.
Where's the crime scene?
BIock H.
The M.E. is with the body,
and one of your detectives
is interrogating
the cell mates.
How many prisoners
did you move?
Ten. We only cleared
the flanking cells.
Okay, I need their
names and their sheets.
Yes, ma'am.
(DOOR BUZZING)
(INMATES SHOUTING)
It's starting
to get to me.
The dead bodies?
The animals
rattling their cages.
Where's your partner?
He's at a VICAP seminar,
making nice
with the Feds.
What's his story?
Sodomized with
a foreign object.
BIed out internally.
Probably
perforated his colon.
Oh! Victim's name
is Carlos Torres.
Tomb intake record
shows he's only been
here eight hours.
One visit to the infirmary.
Liver temp is 96,
so that means he's
only been dead four,
maybe five hours, tops.
Just you and Torres
in the cell, and
you didn't speak to him?
I said, "Hi."
I won't repeat
what he said to me.
Did he hurt
your feelings?
(CHUCKLING)
He's Dominican.
They're animals.
You got a temper yourself,
Ortega.
Three domestic
disturbance calls
in the Iast two weeks,
and the Iast one,
you knifed your Iover.
He hit me first.
How's he Iook?
Ortega claims Torres
wanted nothing to do
with him 'cause he was gay.
Given the jailhouse routine,
not many people had access.
There are ways around
the system if you got
a fever to rack up
Dominican bodies.
You thinking this is
Mexicans against Dominicans?
It's easier to get
got on the inside.
Nowhere to run.
Mexicans transport the drugs,
Dominicans distribute.
Everybody just
wants a bigger piece.
Which is why we computerized
our tracking system
to keep them apart.
But it doesn't
always work.
No system is foolproof.
BENSON: Any Mexicans waiting
for court transfer?
Three, but they're all
in different cellblocks.
Any chance they had
access to our victim?
I don't see how,
since inmate movements
are restricted.
Torres didn't move
from his cell at all.
BENSON: He went to
the infirmary.
Right, after the processing.
Then he was assigned a cell
and Iocked down.
Hold on.
I spoke too soon.
Hector Ramirez
went to the infirmary
complaining about a bad tooth.
FIN: Was he escorted
to the nurse
while Torres was there?
Their visits overlapped.
I'm sorry.
Okay,
what's Ramirez in for?
Murder. What else?
I'II have a guard
bring him to a holding cell.
What's up, bacon?
BENSON: Carlos Torres.
Yeah, I heard he bought it.
Should be stiff
by now, right?
You think it's funny?
Yeah, puerca. Laugh a minute.
Well, how's this
for a punch Iine?
You don't cooperate
with us and I will make
it my business
to have the guards
house you in cellblock B.
One cage is as
good as the next.
B-block is Dominican deep.
I don't think they'd Iike
what you did to their brother.
Wasn't me.
Hector, I think
you forced your way
into the infirmary.
I don't think
there's anything wrong
with your tooth.
These your teeth or mine?
I was hurting.
FIN: We talk to the nurse,
what's she gonna say?
You give me too
much credit, man.
I didn't know the mark
was even gonna be
in the infirmary.
Opportunity knocked.
Torres is Dominican,
you're Mexican.
This is an easy close.
Yeah, if you make it up.
We didn't have to.
We checked your
prison records.
Seems you get off
forcing your fellow
inmates to bend over.
What'd you rape
him with, Hector?
Something real
handy in the infirmary,
Iike a mop or a broom?
I only went up there to
get next to the nurse.
Got a Iong bid this time.
I won't be seeing
Iadies for a while.
What makes you think
that the nurse
would even talk to you?
If she had been by herself,
I would have made her
do more than just talk.
I knew he was
Iying right away.
He had no abscesses,
no redness or swelling.
Was Hector Ramirez
ever Ieft alone
with the victim?
No. He spent
the entire time
harassing me.
What was wrong
with Torres?
I had no idea he
had a serious injury.
And when he came
in for vomiting,
I checked his vitals.
He had a slight fever.
I thought he had a flu,
so I gave him
some Pepto. He said
he felt better.
Who escorted him?
An intake guard,
Nathan Duarte.
And he seemed
pretty steamed, too.
Not that I blame him.
What was he mad about?
Uh, Torres was calling
him some ugly names. Uh...
Homo, faggot, pillow.
You get the gist.
Guards got to be
thick-skinned.
Except for Nathan.
Another guard
just outed him
not too Iong ago.
How Iong was Torres here?
Nathan took him to the shower
right after I gave
him the medicine,
and I could hear
Torres screaming
down the hallway.
He did not want
Nathan to touch him.
I'm already Iate to post,
so what gives?
I heard you had beef
with Carlos Torres.
He was hard to deal with.
No more than any other hump
coming through.
I heard it got
a Iittle personal
between you two.
Not at all, Detective.
I've been called a Iot worse
by some of my Iesser
evolved co-workers.
Still must have
bugged you.
This isn't exactly
a nurturing environment.
I Iearned a Iong time ago
not to take it personally.
You escorted Torres
to the showers
straight from the infirmary?
Yeah.
He puked all over himself
after he Ieft the nurse.
Was anyone else
in the shower
when you got there?
No. Why?
Anybody come in
while you were there?
I don't believe this.
I'm a suspect
because I'm gay.
No, it's because you
were the Iast person
who had access to the victim.
And since I'm
the sodomy expert,
I did this to teach
the homophobe a Iesson.
Is that your theory?
I didn't touch
the Iittle creep.
He took a shower, he got
dressed, I took him to his
assigned cell. That's it.
What time
did you sign out?
A Iittle
after midnight,
and I went
straight home.
Can anyone vouch
that you didn't
come back here?
His name is Chris Hartford.
He's a Legal Aid attorney.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
MRS. HARTFORD: Who is it?
BENSON: It's the police.
Let's see that again.
(BABY CRYING)
Which precinct?
Manhattan SVU.
Sex crimes.
What's this about?
We're Iooking
for Chris Hartford.
Why are you Iooking
for my husband,
Detective?
FIN: Is he here?
Chris? Police.
How can I help you?
Why don't we take this
out of the hallway?
Come inside.
It'd probably be best
if we could speak with you
privately, Mr. Hartford.
What about?
Nathan Duarte.
Chris?
I'II just be a minute.
It's client privilege.
It's all right.
What kind of
trouble is he in?
We just need
to verify his
whereabouts Iast night.
Uh, you have to understand,
this doesn't happen
all the time.
We get together when
my wife's out of town.
It's not what you think.
Okay, we're not Iooking
for an explanation,
just a time frame.
I was with him from
about 1:00 a.m. to 6:00.
Okay. You can go
back to your family.
Thank you.
BENSON: You almost done
with the autopsy?
Not yet. But I can
give you cause of death.
I recovered
wooden splinters
from his rectum.
The foreign object
was introduced
with such force
that it put
a hole in his colon.
How much time
would it have taken
to bleed out?
Hours.
BIood clot at the site
held for a while,
until it blew.
So you're saying the attack
didn't happen at the Tombs.
Doesn't seem Iikely.
The nurse and the guard
said he was sick
at the intake desk.
I found evidence
of peritonitis.
An infection Iike that
will cause nausea, vomiting
and a temperature spike.
Liver temp was 96,
TOD was four hours earlier,
so he had
a 101 degree fever.
So he arrived at the Tombs
before midnight
and was dead by 4:00 a.m.,
5:00 at the Iatest.
He was bleeding internally
before he got transferred.
A cop must've sodomized him
inside the precinct.
CRAGEN: Are we sure our
perp is a cop?
I mean, maybe
his injuries occurred
prior to his arrest.
Well, the 61 says
that Carlos Torres
was arrested at 8:00 p.m.
He didn't arrive
at the Tombs
until around midnight.
He was sick
when he got there.
He went to the nurse,
the showers,
then to bed and
never woke up.
Where was he processed?
29.
Who were
the arresting officers?
Les Cooper
and Randall Grant.
I'II have their
jackets pulled.
John Royce is
the commanding officer.
See him first.
I'II tell him
you're on your way.
Great.
Log book for the day shows
the collar was routine.
Torres was cuffed at 8:00
and transported around 1 1:30.
FIN: Three and a half hours
your average booking time?
It depends on the arrest.
This was pretty
straightforward, though,
even though he resisted
and assaulted
one of my men.
Who was that?
Luke Edmunds.
He was put out on medical
right after the brawl.
He'II be out
the rest of the week.
Was it serious?
Took a blow
to the head.
What can you tell us
about the arresting officers?
They're pretty
straight-up cops.
Grant's a rookie,
so the jury's still out.
Cooper gets the job done.
Not always
the way you Iike it.
Coop's a Iittle
free with his hands.
This precinct's
right in the center
of drug turf.
Sometimes you got to
flex on the players
to get their attention.
Not in my precinct.
BENSON: Where are Cooper
and Grant now?
Sector car Charlie.
I'd Iike to avoid
taking them out of rotation
while I'm shorthanded.
Officer Grant,
how you doing?
Detective Benson,
Tutuola.
Can we talk to you
guys for a minute?
Sure, what can we
do for you?
What can you tell us
about Carlos Torres?
(COOPER CHUCKLES)
Shocking when
a drug dealing gangbanger
shows up dead, huh?
You had run-ins
with him before?
Sure.
We arrested him
three, four times
in the Iast month.
Guy was made of Teflon.
Must be pretty frustrating.
One time a judge
threw out the crack
we pinched him with
because we found
it in his mouth.
Said it was
an illegal search.
So you tell me,
would you be frustrated?
Yeah, but not enough
to take him out.
And just so we're clear,
the arrest went by the book.
What happened that night?
There was a street brawl
outside the CIub Rendezvous.
It's a trouble spot.
Four sector cars showed up
to disperse the crowd.
Torres got caught
in the mix.
But once he took a swing
at Officer Edmunds
that was it.
Threw him in the back
of the blue and white,
put the bracelets on him,
headed to the house.
You guys make any stops?
Well, we didn't have time
to tune him up, if that's
what you're thinking.
No, our call came in at 7:00,
booking started at 8:00.
Took that Iong to
control the scene.
(TSKS)
It's a real problem,
that place.
Dominicans and Mexicans
ever mix it up in here?
Not inside.
AII players are welcome here.
The club's a safe haven.
As far as I heard,
there's no such thing
between Mexicans
and Dominicans.
That's where
you're wrong,
Detective.
Even a gangster
needs a safe place
to take his woman.
You know him?
Carlos Torres.
Yeah, he was here
that night
with his girl.
Inside the club?
Yeah, they was celebrating
'cause she was pregnant.
I remember,
'cause she asked for milk,
but I don't serve it.
Okay. You see him
go outside?
Not until the uniforms
came up in here
and got him.
When was that?
Right before
the street fight started.
BENSON: Cooper and Grant
had reason to hurt him.
They'd arrested
him four times,
and he kept skating
on the charges.
So why not
just whip his ass
instead of tapping it?
'Cause I think that
the tune-up went too far.
I think Cooper and
Grant took a nasty turn,
now they have to
cover for each other.
CRAGEN: What does
the evidence support?
Well, Cooper and Grant
didn't have time to do
the deed pre-arrest.
Edmunds came in
to back them up.
After Torres slugged him,
Cooper and Grant
cuffed him and put him
in the sector car.
Corroborated?
By the other cops
on the scene.
Central was notified
that Torres was in custody.
Ten-minute ride
back to the house,
and the Iog book confirms it.
That's why
it had to happen
inside the precinct.
And how did
they pull it off
without witnesses?
We've all done
our time in uniform.
Cop gets hurt by a perp,
you get a free shot.
Duty Iog has Officer
Luke Edmunds reported
to the hospital 8:00 p.m.,
blow to the head.
So the question is,
did Edmunds go home
or back to the precinct
to teach Torres a Iesson?
I'II sit him down.
Fin, I want you with
CSU to comb the 29.
Anything you find,
walk through the Iab.
That's a pretty big precinct.
You want to narrow it down?
Well, to do
that kind of damage
takes privacy.
Let's start with
the sector car,
interrogation rooms
and bathrooms.
You know,
Carlos Torres is dead.
If you're trying
to pinch me for it,
don't I need my PBA rep?
Actually,
I just need your account
of what happened that night.
It's in the 61,
Detective.
Is it?
Don't play games with me.
I do this for a Iiving,
the same as you.
Then why are you
giving me
a hard time?
Look, I'm still in pain.
I didn't mean to snap.
I know you got a job to do,
you got to clear your case,
even though the hump
had it coming.
And Torres deserved it
because his charges
always got dropped
or because
he hit you?
This kind of high-stakes game,
your number comes up
eventually.
Doesn't matter if
it's us or the streets.
Game over.
AII right. So what
do you think happened?
Some cellmate in
the Tombs cornholed him.
Well, how do you know
that's how he died? We haven't
released that information.
Cops talk.
Well, then
they didn't tell you
the whole story.
You see, the evidence shows
that he was attacked here,
not in the Tombs.
So how do you
explain that?
I can't. I got hurt
and went to the hospital.
But the hospital
released you at 8:45.
Where'd you go after that?
Home.
Home. Really?
'Cause the desk sergeant
said that you came back here
to get something
out of your Iocker.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Yeah, then I went home.
So,
can I go?
I think you're gonna
need that PBA rep now.
FIN: The trail of blood
Ieads out of the stall.
They sodomized Torres
with whatever was handy.
Over here.
(SIGHS)
Looks Iike we just found
our murder weapon.
Till we type it,
blood could've
come from anybody.
Came here
straight from One P.P.
I'm surprised
you can still sit.
Officer Edmunds
gave his confession,
wants to make a deal.
Public won't go for it.
They'II want that
cop's head on a stake.
That's why the brass
wants it kept quick
and quiet.
But what about
his accomplices?
Torres and Edmunds
weren't alone in
that bathroom. He had help.
That's not the way he
tells it, Detective.
He understands he cooperates,
he gets Ieniency.
He doesn't deserve it.
We make deals with
perps all the time.
Cops should be held
to a higher standard.
The Chief called the play.
The D.A.'s been notified.
It's done.
CABOT: Murder two, Counselor.
We've got your client cold
for depraved indifference.
That's 25-to-Iife.
And cops don't do
too well in prison.
Depraved indifference
for a dead gangbanger?
It's Iaughable.
The victim isn't Iaughing.
In fact, he's dead.
Oh, don't be naive.
His miserable Iife
would be fodder
for the jury.
But no one wants that, right?
So Iet's be reasonable.
Man two, eight-to-10.
Murder two, 1 2-to-25.
One-time offer.
I don't call that reasonable.
Your client sodomized
someone so violently
that he bled to death.
There is no way I'm going to
offer anything Iess
than double digits.
Okay.
(WHISPERING)
Man two, 10-to-20.
Fine.
I don't Iike it.
Do I Iook Iike
I'm having fun?
Your boss and my boss
just want to make this
go away.
'Cause they want it
business as usual.
But there is no way
that Edmunds acted alone.
No proof he didn't.
Our victim was a gangster
and a homophobe.
What Edmunds did
to him is tantamount
to his worst nightmare.
He would've
kicked Iike a mule
to make it stop.
You're thinking
Torres was held down.
He had to be.
And whoever
helped Edmunds do it
is gonna walk.
Not if you find me evidence.
Then the deal is void.
Let me know.
I got my orders.
Officially,
the case is closed.
Unofficially?
Work fast and
stay under the radar.
Good timing.
I just finished.
BENSON: PIease tell me
you have evidence supporting
more than one perp.
There had to be at Ieast two.
Victim's got deep tissue
bruising on both his hands
and knees consistent
with the mosaic tile
in the precinct bathroom.
So he was on all fours.
Figures he had to be
so Edmunds could have access.
WARNER: He's also got
a Iong cylindrical bruise
across the back
of his shoulders,
indicating he was
held down by force.
BENSON: Nightstick to
the neck?
That would get the job done.
But Edmunds still
could've worked alone.
Torres was cuffed.
Hey, he wasn't shackled.
So why didn't he fight back?
The bruise is deep.
So someone else
had to apply pressure
by using all their weight.
We dump his phones.
We'II find out who
he's covering for.
Look at this.
Here's another one.
That makes 55 calls
between Edmunds and Cooper
in the Iast three days.
They're trying to get
their stories straight.
Phone calls don't put Cooper
in that bathroom with Edmunds.
Forensics is not
gonna help us, either.
Any trace evidence
found on Torres
can be explained
by physical contact
during the arrest.
Well, if Cooper and
Edmunds were together,
other cops had to see them.
And if One P.P. finds
out we're still digging,
they'II shut us down.
So stay out of the 29.
Focus on Edmunds.
Dig in his Iife.
You'II find
a connecting thread
to Cooper.
Lots of calls went to
a residence, uh, registered
to Stephanie Grayson.
Girlfriend?
As much as he's paying in
cell phone bills,
she better be.
CRAGEN: Well, Iet's find out
how close they are.
There's no marital privilege,
so the pillow talk
is admissible.
I know Luke's been arrested,
but no one will
tell me what for.
How Iong have you known
Officer Edmunds?
I met him at the hospital
when his brother OD'd.
I'm a nurse.
He took it really hard.
Parents were dead,
he practically
raised the kid himself.
How often
did you see him?
Whenever he wasn't working
or on his breaks.
Did you meet any
of his buddies?
A few. Why?
Well, he might be taking
the heat for some of them.
Is that possible?
You know, maybe
we should take this
down to the precinct
and get a more
formal statement
from you.
This is about that
drug dealer, isn't it?
Edmund's came up
against quite a few,
so you're going to have to be
more specific with me
if you want to help him.
AII I know is his
name was Vasquez.
Luke was hot for the guy.
Said he was
moving too much weight
and was slipping
through the system.
And he hated drug dealers.
With a passion.
He said Vasquez
was too slick
to get pinched,
so he tailed him to
catch him in the act.
So what happened?
Luke busted him with a gram,
and then Vasquez
pulled out a knife.
The only thing Luke could do
was shoot him.
He was really messed up
about it for a while.
Till I gave him
a different perspective.
What was
your take on it?
He's a bad guy,
a drug dealer,
for God's sake.
Luke was saving
someone else's
kid brother.
Okay, got it. Thanks.
Turns out
the girlfriend
wasn't making it up.
A drug dealer
named Javier Vasquez
expired two months ago.
Only he wasn't shot,
his throat was slashed.
It hardly plays
Iike self-defense.
Where was
the body found?
Dead in the center
of the 29 territory.
Homicide detective
mentioned a cylindrical
bruise across his throat
but not across his back.
Sounds Iike
a chokehold to me.
Yeah,
but two dead drug dealers
still doesn't put anyone else
in that bathroom
with Edmunds.
I know, but pattern will.
Look, Iet's see
if we can connect
any other dealers to
Edmunds and Cooper.
A jury'II buy
they work together.
Okay, I'II check with Warner
and have her pull
any matching morgue files.
Okay, you know what?
I'II meet you
back at the squad.
What can I do for
you today, Detective?
I'd Iike to have another Iook
at that duty roster.
What for?
Investigation's closed.
Edmunds is in custody.
Actually,
I'm working on another case.
What's that?
I'm not at Iiberty
to discuss it.
I'd just Iike to
see the Iog book
from two months ago.
Get authorization,
come back.
I'II be here all day.
Get it straight, Sergeant.
I don't work for you.
I got a Iead on
an open homicide,
and I'd Iike to
check my facts
before I pass it along.
What are you Iooking for?
When a drug dealer
named Vasquez
was killed two months ago,
which sector car responded?
Two months ago?
Yeah, the 27th.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Edmunds and Cooper
were partnered that day.
How often did
they ride together?
AII the time, until Cooper
made field training officer
Iast month.
Thank you.
Officer Cooper!
Sweet ride.
What do you want, Detective?
Is that a 'vette
in your garage?
You must be working
a hell of a Iot of overtime.
Give it a rest, huh?
IAB wants to dig, fine.
I wanted to talk to you
about Luke Edmunds.
There's nothing to say.
He's guilty.
I heard he pled out.
I just want to
make sure it sticks.
Is there any reason
why it shouldn't?
A 20-year prison sentence
is a pretty tough sell
to a cop.
He could change his mind,
make trouble.
So I dug in his background.
I talked to his girlfriend.
Yeah?
She told a very
interesting story
about a drug dealer
named Vasquez.
What about him?
CIaims that Edmunds shot him
in self-defense.
You were partnered
with him then, right?
So?
His throat was slashed.
How do you explain that?
Some street punk
wanted revenge.
We get to the scene,
and Vasquez is
carved up Iike a turkey.
So this is just
your ex-partner playing Iike
a hero to get Iaid?
I met the woman.
She's a badge bunny.
Stories Iike this
get her juiced up,
you know what I'm saying?
I find out that
you're a murdering bastard,
I'm gonna nail your ass.
You know what I'm saying?
You went to the 29.
I can see the rumor
mill's working overtime.
Who says cops
don't communicate?
What the hell are
you trying to prove?
Look, I was trying
to cover your ass.
I didn't want you
to get a rip from the bosses
for insubordination.
You'II be Iucky if they
settle for just a rip.
I would've backed
your play.
That's why I went alone.
Well, there's a detective from
Fraud waiting. You want to
bring me up to speed?
Well, I requested a Iook
at our cops' financials,
because from what I've seen,
Cooper is Iiving
way above his means.
You think Edmunds
has something to do with it.
Well, if he is, protecting
a bankroll is a hell of
a good reason to confess
and stop any more digging.
Edmunds is clean.
Lives frugally,
Iittle savings, no assets.
You sure?
Positive.
Now, your guy
Cooper's a different story.
Reasonable mortgage,
well within his
paycheck Iimit.
Wife's a homemaker,
kid's in public school,
nothing to red flag.
BENSON:
But you're not buying it?
Nope.
AII of his assets
are in his wife's name,
car, condo in Boca,
some other
scattered real estate.
How'd this slip past IAB?
Checked his tax return.
Trick is,
claim Atlantic City winnings,
he pays the taxes on it,
no one's the wiser.
Well, can we prove
that the money's
not from gambling?
We can check
with the casinos.
Anything over $2,500
is reportable to the IRS.
How Iong will that take?
BENSON: More time
than we've got.
Edmunds' allocution
is scheduled
for day after tomorrow.
Cooper's on the take,
Edmunds isn't.
So why's he holding out?
Maybe Edmunds
didn't know what his
ex-partner's been up to.
It's a statistical
improbability that Mrs. Cooper
won so much so often.
You know where
the money's actually
coming from?
My guess,
payment for
some dead bodies.
What could not wait
until tomorrow morning?
I need a wiretap.
On who?
Luke Edmunds' former partner,
Les Cooper.
Is he involved in this?
We think that he got paid
to kill Carlos Torres and
another drug dealer.
He's got way too
much cash for a cop.
What about Edmunds?
Drug dealers
killed his brother.
See, Edmunds is doing it
for revenge, Cooper's doing it
for business.
Problem is, we don't know
who Cooper's working for.
That's why I need a wiretap.
If I am going to
wake up a judge,
I need something
more compelling
than a theory.
Cooper's finances
aren't enough?
Not without solid evidence
of where that money
came from.
Why are you still
working on this?
You're the one who
told me to come to you
if I had anything new.
Well, that was before
IAB got involved.
It doesn't matter how
you get your evidence,
as Iong as you
get it Iegally.
You are on a crusade
to get Cooper.
You're damned right I am.
He's a murderer.
How many bodies do
you think he racked up
to pay for that new Mercedes?
That's a good question.
Turns out you've got
five open homicides
with corresponding signatures
to your victim.
One knife wound,
one beaten and
kicked to death,
three were
gunshots to the chest.
Common denominator's
the deep bruising
at the throat.
And they shared
the same profession,
slinging drugs.
Were the bodies
found in the 29 precinct?
Where else?
Edmunds did it for revenge,
but Cooper was getting paid.
FIN: You get any inquiries
from anybody other than us?
Chief of Detectives called,
notifying me that
Homicide detectives
from Manhattan North
would be in to
collect the files.
I guess the rumors
of your visit to the precinct
made it to the bosses.
Well, Iet's see
what they have to say
about a cop
killing off drug dealers
for profit.
You've got to vacate
Edmunds' deal, AIex.
He's guilty of
multiple homicide,
but his ex-partner
has been committing
felony murder for pay.
Where's your evidence?
Cooper and Edmunds went
to CIub Rendezvous to
roust Carlos Torres.
But when they got there,
they didn't expect
a street brawl outside.
When the sector cars arrived,
they couldn't kill him,
so they had to take him in.
So they get him
to the precinct,
they take him
to the bathroom,
and they pull
his pants down.
Well, if this was
about business,
why sodomize him
with a plunger?
Well, we're thinking
that the cops were
trying to plant evidence.
Torres was headed
toward the Tombs.
The guards find drugs
during the strip search,
that's an added
possession charge.
That is another
10 years at Ieast.
FIN: But the plan backfired.
Edmunds took some
Iicks in the scuffle
with Torres, he went crazy,
and the plunger was
just a "screw you."
But you still didn't
answer my question.
Where is your evidence?
Five dead drug dealers.
AII unsolved homicides,
all with the same
deep bruising pattern,
and all on Edmunds
and Cooper's turf.
Same as Carlos Torres.
Let's see if Edmunds
is up for a renegotiation.
CABOT: Your present deal
is off the table.
You're digging
a political grave,
Counselor.
I'm willing to
make you an offer.
But if I Ieave here
before you give me an answer,
you're not going
to see me again.
What's this about?
BENSON: You recognize them?
Killing off drug dealers
wasn't gonna fill
that hole in you,
and it sure as
hell wasn't gonna get
your kid brother back.
Well, I didn't expect it to.
I just thought if I found
the one who strung Bobby out,
it'd be enough.
Gave a 13 year-old boy
his first hit of coke.
He thought it was funny,
supplying a cop's brother
day after day.
Okay, so you killed him,
you got what you wanted.
Why not stop there?
They use blood money
to hire the best Iawyers
to shaft us
with our own rules.
How is that justice?
Taking out
the competition for profit
isn't justice, either.
What the hell are
you talking about?
What profit?
Somebody paid your partner
to kill those drug dealers.
BENSON: See, you were
on a mission.
Cooper had a side business.
I don't believe you.
He wouldn't do that.
He hates them
as much as I do.
Six counts.
Murder for hire.
Wait, I didn't do that.
I was cleaning up
the streets,
not making money.
By committing murder.
It wasn't murder.
It was a reckoning.
And we didn't kill them all.
I just wanted to put
them out of business.
Well, then I suggest
you tell us exactly
what went down.
I can't.
Your ex-partner's
a dirty cop.
You're not.
We need
corroborating evidence
to put Cooper behind bars.
You'II take the needle
off the table?
CABOT: Yes.
What do you want?
Let's start
with a Iive victim,
someone to
support your statement.
A drug dealer
named Willie Angel's
doing 25 in Sing Sing.
Cooper shot him,
but the bastard wouldn't die,
so we had to plant
a drop gun.
We testified Angel
opened fire on us.
Jury didn't even blink.
If Willie Angel corroborates
Edmunds' statement,
call me right away.
What's the urgency?
How about
an innocent man in prison
on trumped-up charges?
There's nothing innocent
about a drug dealer.
He's probably got
dozens of bodies
to his credit.
Leave him where he is.
I can't do that.
If his statement
pans out,
I have to file for an
immediate writ
for his release.
I don't know one convict
who wouldn't say
the cops framed him.
Edmunds just admitted it.
We're supposed
to uphold the Iaw.
Your heart's bleeding
all over my shoes.
You condone his behavior?
I understand it.
It gets old
watching humps
walk away
from prison bids
on technicalities.
Dealers know how to
play the Ioopholes.
Yeah, but you wouldn't do
what they did.
You wouldn't take the Iaw
into your own hands.
It's not Iike
I haven't thought
about it, Counselor.
Same as every
other cop on the job.
There's a difference
between thinking
about it and doing it.
ANGEL: What do you
cops want with me?
We want to hear your version
of how you ended up here.
Police did this to me.
Cops Iike you
with that same Iook
in their eye.
Look, nobody
believed me before,
so what's changed?
BENSON:
We need to hear the details.
Maybe I need a Iawyer here.
I don't do well
with you people
one on one.
Look, Willie,
we're not Iooking
to jam you up.
Speak for yourself.
I do something to you?
You ain't nothing but
a drug dealer, so to me
everything you say is suspect.
I ain't in the game
no more.
Since when?
Since I Iost
the use of my Iegs
from a cop's bullet.
Since they jacked me
for my freedom. Or maybe
that's not enough for you.
Willie,
can you identify the cops
who did this to you?
Yeah. They wanted me
to step from my business.
And when I refused,
next thing I know I got
a bullet Iodged in my spine,
and I'm on trial
for attempted murder.
So what happens now?
We have
a corroborating witness
who supports your story.
And that means I'm
gonna get out of here?
Looks Iike it's
your Iucky day.
You don't know
the half of it.
I'm gonna file
a multi-million-dollar
Iawsuit against the city.
And the gravy's
your required testimony
on my behalf.
You're gonna Iet that Iowlife
piece of garbage
back on the street?
Yeah, in a wheelchair.
Willie Angel is scum.
He still doesn't deserve
what you and Cooper
did to him.
Way I see it, one Iess
dealer to worry about.
Whose idea was
it to shoot Willie
in the first place?
Cooper's.
But I went along with it.
And I suppose it
was Cooper's idea
to kill all those dealers.
You do the dirty work,
only you don't get paid.
He paid me.
How?
A couple of years ago,
we're answering a domestic.
Husband and wife
are going at it.
I walk in, never saw the gun.
Coop jumps in between me
and the other guy,
takes the.38
right out of his hand.
So you're paying him back
by killing people for him?
Well, Cooper did it
for a couple of
nice cars and a condo.
Testify against him.
No way.
He betrayed you.
You wouldn't testify
against your partner.
Don't throw that
blue wall crap at me.
If he did what Cooper did,
you bet your ass I would.
It's not so easy.
Partner's Iike blood.
You think that he feels
the same way about you?
He used you.
He used your dead brother.
He doesn't give
a damn about you.
When are you going
to have the balls
to face that?
You deliberately disobeyed
a direct order to stay
out of the 29. That's a rip.
Ten days of docked pay.
That's the only
thing you can do.
I understand.
I don't think you do.
Right now, the D.A.
is fielding writs
from every hump
ever busted by
those two cops.
Guilty or not,
they get a pass.
Edmunds and Cooper
are dirty cops.
Did you expect me
to ignore that?
And because you kept
me out of the Ioop,
we got blindsided.
We're Iooking at
press scrutiny,
millions in civil suits,
not to mention
criminals walking free.
I did the right thing.
Pick up Cooper.
Let's get that bastard
off the streets.
Lester Cooper.
You know,
I'm starting to think
you're stalking me.
You're under arrest
for first-degree murder.
Turn around.
Wait a minute.
What the hell
is going on here?
Step back, rookie.
You got nothing on me.
Just six counts of murder.
Hey, I didn't do
anything wrong.
I believe you.
Get a Iawyer, anyway.
What are you offering?
CABOT: Life, no parole,
in exchange for the man
you were working for.
I can't do it.
I name names,
I might as well kill myself,
save them the trouble.
Ex-cops don't get
housed with general pop.
That's very comforting.
Thank you.
Your cooperation is
the only thing that stands
between you and the needle.
So I'II take my
chance with a jury.
We've got
corroborating witnesses
and the bodies you
dropped for profit.
The jury's going to burn you.
You better have other
testimony besides
my client's ex-partner.
One of their
victims corroborates
his statement, Counselor.
Edmunds gets Iife,
you get Iife, no parole.
As far as I'm concerned,
you're getting off easy.
Edmunds. Gullible fool.
Yeah, well, at Ieast
he had his reasons,
unlike you,
who just exploited
his grief to get rich.
Oh, he thought he
was on a mission.
Like we were
gonna rid the streets
of drug dealers?
Only an idiot
would believe that.
What's it gonna be?
It's a real smart move,
Hector.
Get rid of the competition,
avoid a war by getting
a cop to do your dirty work.
This business is cutthroat.
You got to know
that going in.
This is one execution
I think I'II attend.
Look at you,
all yeasted up Iike
some kind of hero.
Death row is just geography
for me, mommy.
You're gonna be
crying Iike a baby
when you take that Iast walk.
You're gonna have
to wait 10, 15 years.
A Iot can happen
between now and then.
Witnesses get amnesia.
People up and die.
You never know.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Benson.
Suicide.
He Ieave a note?
Guards didn't find one.
Hasn't been dead Iong.
An hour, maybe two.
He just couldn't take it.
His sentence?
Facing what he did.