NARRATOR: In the criminal
justice system,
sexually based offenses
are considered
especially heinous.
In New York City,
the dedicated detectives
who investigate
these vicious felonies
are members
of an elite squad known
as the Special Victims Unit.
These are their stories.
LEN: I'm freezing.
JEFF: You want to warm up?
Paddle harder.
LEN: I must have been crazy
to Iet you talk me into this.
JEFF: Got to train early
to be in shape for the class
5 rapids this summer.
It's the middle
of winter!
Hasn't stopped anyone
from using the Hudson
as a garbage can.
Must've fallen
off a boat.
Maybe they Ieft us
a couple of brews.
Oh, my God!
We got a call
for child abuse.
Hope you haven't
had Iunch yet.
There's a special place
in hell for whoever did this.
STABLER: How old?
Haven't seen it,
but I heard newborn.
BENSON: Anyone touch anything?
Guy who found it
closed the Iid.
I know it's evidence,
but thank God
for small favors.
You can buy this
cooler anywhere
in town.
Look at this.
Perp must have put
something heavy in
the bag to weigh it down.
Bag breaks,
the cooler
floats up.
Got a partial Iogo.
Probably be able to
find the store from this.
PIease tell me this
isn't what I think.
Sorry.
Give me a minute.
Cooler could've been
dropped off the dock
or from a water taxi.
If you don't want your baby,
there are other options.
Not for a girl who throws
her newborn in the river.
She's not a newborn.
How do you know?
Umbilical stump's gone.
She's at Ieast a month old.
One-month-old white female,
eight pounds, two ounces,
dead about a day.
She appears
well cared for.
Body scan shows
no sign of abuse
or neglect.
What was
the cause of death?
A Iethal dose of
tricyclic antidepressants.
Mother could have
been taking those
for postpartum depression.
Except that tricyclics
aren't prescribed
to nursing mothers.
There was breast milk
in the baby's stomach.
So she breast-fed
and bonded with this child.
That doesn't
sound Iike a woman
who would do this.
You got anything
that can Iead us
to the perp?
The cooler
can help.
No damage, so it wasn't
dropped from a great height,
Iike a bridge.
Take a Iook at this.
What is that, algae?
Or some other plant matter.
I also found
this on the corpse.
Sodium hypochlorite,
an industrial-strength
cleanser.
BENSON: So where do we
find that with algae?
No place I know of.
When we find the source,
maybe we find the dump site.
DR. QUEEN: ID'ing this
was a no-brainer.
It's Enteromorpha,
a common type of algae.
Very nutritious.
You can get it at
sushi restaurants.
I'II stick with
burgers and fries,
thanks.
Seaweed's healthier.
Come, take a Iook at this.
It's a map of
the Iower Hudson.
This is where
Enteromorpha
Iikes to grow.
So the cooler had to float
through one of these places
to pick it up.
And the sodium hypochlorite,
any idea how it got in
the water?
It's used by sewage
treatment plants
to disinfect waste
before it's put
into the river.
Well, there's a
treatment plant
on the Hudson,
right under
the Riverbank
State Park.
West 137.
Now, the cooler was found
all the way down here
in Battery Park.
Could it have
traveled that far?
Without a doubt.
These are the current patterns
the day the cooler was found.
I'II bet the cooler was
dropped into the water
somewhere along
this stretch of river,
and floated along this
current to Battery Park.
CRAGEN: We're talking a mile
or two stretch with direct
access to the river.
People come from all
over to picnic there.
Well, the bag on
the cooler narrows it down.
It came from The Bountiful
Earth health food store
about ten blocks away.
Perp probably stopped there,
maybe Iives nearby.
People who murder their
children usually report
them missing,
deflect suspicion
off themselves.
Any chance
it's a kidnap?
The infant was wrapped in
a blanket with the weights
on the outside of the cooler
to keep them form
crushing the baby.
This perp is definitely
someone with an emotional
connection.
Newborn murders are
usually the mother.
A one-month-old could
just as easily be the father.
If he had a reason to conceal
the pregnancy,
say, because of incest,
I doubt he would
have taken so Iong
to commit the crime.
I'm Ieaning
towards the mother.
Where would she
have kept the baby
hidden for a month?
Student away from
home fits the profile.
Hudson University.
It's just down the road
from the health food store.
We know roughly
when the baby
was conceived.
College is the best
Iead we've got.
I'm very sorry,
but our students have
a right to their privacy.
Who administers
the pregnancy
tests here?
Doesn't matter,
because you're not
going to talk to them.
You really want us
trolling your hallways
asking everyone
until we find who
we're Iooking for?
Our patients are usually
referred to the S.H.A.R.E.
desk.
S.H.A.R.E.?
Sexual Health and
Reproductive Education,
staffed by student volunteers.
They collect urine samples
and then they
send them to the Iab
for pregnancy tests.
So, they would
have all the names.
No, they'II have
the numbers.
It's anonymous.
Okay, so who
has the names?
I do.
So come back
with a court order
or don't come back at all.
CABOT: We don't even have
any proof the victim's mother
went to health services.
We understand that, AIex,
but this is our best shot.
Well, I need more evidence
before I can get a subpoena.
Sounds Iike you're
stonewalling us.
Yeah, what is this
really about?
OIivia, would you want
somebody digging through
your medical records?
I had a pregnancy
scare in college.
That was bad enough.
I can't imagine
the police knocking
at my door.
But this is
our best Iead.
Health Services at
Hudson has students
giving pregnancy tests.
So?
Judge in Iowa ruled
confidentiality
does not apply
when tests aren't performed
by doctors or nurses.
And PIanned Parenthood
fought the case so
hard on the course
that the county
finally had to drop it.
Still worth
giving a try.
AII right,
I'II run it
by my boss,
but I can tell right now
what she's going to say.
Someone killed a child.
It's our duty to
speak for the victim.
So now we're
the pregnancy police?
We're violating a woman's
rights for what amounts
to a Hail Mary.
This isn't about
abortion rights, AIex.
We are talking about
a one-month-old infant.
Okay, so what if that
doesn't work, what are
we supposed to do?
Question every single woman
who bought an EPT
kit at the drugstore?
I'm afraid you're
missing the point.
We all worked hard to pass
the Baby Safe Haven Iaw.
That mother could have
dropped her child off
at any fire station,
any hospital,
without fear
of prosecution.
Instead,
she chose to murder.
So you're going to make
an example of her by taking
away women's privacy?
I'm not painting her
with a scarlet Ietter.
I'm just trying to
find this child's killer.
Well, a judge might
not see it that way.
Most still place
a pretty high value
on privacy rights.
We'II keep our
scope narrow.
Limit it to test results
from a two-month period.
Stipulate we'II rule out
women who already have
documented births on file.
AIex,
I want that Iist of names.
MUNCH: I don't Iike it.
The only reason we got
this Iist is because
Judge Hill is slightly
to the right of
Attila the Hun.
Why don't you give it
a rest? How many you got?
Twenty-four pregnant
college girls.
And excuse me if I'm alarmed
by the total disregard for
human rights in this country.
If you got a problem with it,
why don't you get your bony
ass out of here?
Okay, out of two dozen
women with positive
pregnancy tests,
16 were issued
birth certificates.
That Ieaves eight suspects
with no reported baby.
Let's go invade
their privacy.
Can I help you?
Detectives Tutuola and Munch.
Is Angela Savvas here?
Angie's my wife.
What's this about?
We really should be
talking to both of you.
She's not feeling well
so you'II have
to speak with me.
Is your wife a student
at Hudson University?
A grad student, yeah.
We understand she found
out she was pregnant
nine months ago.
Unless that's a crime,
I don't see how it's
any of your business.
You remember
that abandoned baby
they found in the river?
We have reason to believe
that the mother
attended Hudson.
So now you're interrogating
every woman on campus?
Just those with positive
pregnancy tests and no child.
You're right,
we don't have a child.
My wife had
a miscarriage.
Sorry.
She went to
Presbyterian Hospital.
You want to see
the discharge papers?
That won't be necessary.
Then get the hell
out of here.
Cheer up.
Only three more to go.
Hi.
Find what you're
Iooking for?
Actually, we were
Iooking for you.
EIIen Swanson?
Yes?
I'm Detective Benson.
This is my partner
Detective Stabler.
We'd Iike to talk
to you for a moment.
Sure. How did
you find me?
The Registrar said
this is where you
do your work-study.
Probably be best if we went
somewhere more private.
This is a mistake.
I've never been pregnant.
Health Services
says you tested
positive eight months ago.
They're wrong. I was in
Paris for a study abroad
eight months ago.
I just got back.
Could somebody in your dorm
have borrowed your ID
and then returned it
without your knowing?
I Iive in an
apartment alone.
I really have to
get back to work.
BENSON: Just one more thing.
We'd Iike a DNA
swab to rule you out.
No way.
You can't just go prying
into my private Iife and
then expect me to cooperate.
INS confirms
EIIen was in Paris
eight months ago.
Another necessary
invasion of privacy.
Well, not exactly.
She flew back here
for two weeks shortly
after she got there.
Let me guess.
She had a pregnancy test
as soon as she got home.
BENSON: The day after.
Probably realized she was
pregnant and came home
to deal with it.
Boyfriend says all
the right things,
she goes back to Paris
thinking they're one
big happy family.
When she returns,
he's changed his mind.
Too Iate to get an abortion,
afraid to tell her parents.
So she has the kid at home,
she spends a month
trying to figure out
how to get rid of it.
Does that play?
Enough to get
a warrant.
You're wrong about this.
I told you, I've never
been pregnant.
Just Iike you told us
that Health Services
never gave you a pregnancy
test because you were
in Paris.
Why won't you believe me?
Because your story
doesn't match the facts.
Look what we have here.
She shops at
The Bountiful Earth.
Very health-conscious.
Everyone on campus
shops there.
Dumbbells usually come
in pairs. Where's the other
20-pounder?
I Iost it moving in.
EIIiot.
From Conception to Delivery:
A First-Time Mother's Guide.
This receipt shows
that you bought that book
the day after
that pregnancy test
you never took.
I haven't done
anything wrong.
Then take a DNA test
and clear this
whole thing up.
No.
STABLER: Fine.
We have enough evidence
for a court order.
Positive pregnancy test,
a how-to book for
expectant mothers,
a bag that
matches the bag...
Stop...
Used to weigh
down the cooler.
Oh, my God.
What happened, EIIen?
I don't know...
STABLER: Just tell us.
I'm telling you,
you'II feel better.
Just tell us.
It wasn't me.
BENSON: Well,
who was it, then?
My sister, Patty.
She's only 15.
So, you gave her your
college ID to get tested
so no one would find out.
She panicked.
She needed me.
That's why I came
back from Paris.
STABLER: Why didn't she
go to your parents?
You don't know my dad.
So what did she tell you?
That she was going
to have the baby.
BENSON: Did she say
who the father was?
Her ex-boyfriend,
Paul Howley.
He's older,
works for some
maintenance company.
So you went
back to Paris.
And what happened
when you came home?
There was no baby.
Patty said
the test was wrong,
that she never wanted
to talk about it again.
Then when I heard about
the baby in the cooler...
You have to understand,
she was so scared,
and she's just a kid.
Patty could have kept her baby
at her boyfriend's apartment.
Until playing daddy
Iost its novelty.
Then she had to
figure out what to do.
She's a minor. Bring
her in with her parents.
Father's some
corporate big shot.
He's flying in from D.C.
Mother's a homemaker.
Still no answer.
EIIen says she runs
errands this time of day.
Thank you.
Teacher at Patty's school says
she got an emergency page,
Ieft the classroom to answer,
never came back.
Big sister EIIen
must have warned her.
School's faxing
over a yearbook photo.
Maybe Patty's boyfriend
can help us find her.
I haven't seen
Patty in eight months.
She broke up with me.
She dumped you
or did you kick
her to the curb
when you found out
she was going to
make you a daddy?
She was pregnant?
Let me guess,
you didn't always
practice safe sex?
We never had sex.
She was too young.
How old were you
eight months ago?
Seventeen.
Well, that wasn't
statutory rape,
so spill it.
Did you have
sex with Patty?
Yes.
You hit it raw?
Well, a couple of times
we didn't use protection.
But she never said
anything about
being pregnant.
What did I do?
You heard about
that baby we found
in the river?
You think she was mine?
We can find out
if you'II Iet us
run a DNA test.
No problem.
I would have
supported Patty
and the baby.
I got a union job now,
I make a good buck.
If you would have stepped up,
why do you think
she didn't tell you?
Her father.
The guy's a
world class jerk.
He hates me because
I'm a dropout.
Any idea where
we can find Patty?
If she's not at
home or at school,
I really don't know.
How about paging her?
You still got the number?
Yeah, I remember it.
Call it. Tell her
to meet you.
Patty Swanson?
PIease don't tell
my parents.
PIease.
You're pregnant?
No, Daddy.
Not anymore.
You stupid slut.
STABLER: Mr. Swanson.
What, you just
spread your Iegs
for the first dropout punk
who comes sniffing around?
Sir, calm down.
Calm down.
BENSON: We know you didn't
mean to hurt anyone.
For God's sake,
Patty, what happened?
I killed my baby.
God, I killed my baby.
I'm so sorry, Daddy.
What did you do?
What?
I went to this place
on 96th Street.
A clinic?
Yes.
I'm so sorry.
I just didn't know
where else to go.
You had an abortion?
Without my permission?
The Iaw says that
she doesn't need it.
Like hell she doesn't!
I've asked you to calm down.
Now I'm telling you
to sit down.
Sit down.
Patty, we're going
to need your okay
to check this
story with the clinic,
all right?
AII right.
How'd it go?
Only crime here is
that her father's a prick.
And a wife beater.
What did you say?
Swanson has half a dozen
domestic violence collars.
His wife never
pressed charges,
but the Iocal precinct
knows their address by heart.
Listen to me, Detective.
If you ever speak
to me that way again,
I'II make damn sure
the Police Commissioner
hears about it.
We play golf together.
Does he know
about your handicap?
My handicap?
The one that makes you
slap your wife around.
Well, good,
I've got
your attention.
You raise your hand to her
or your daughters again,
I'II be paying
you a visit.
Is that a threat?
Yeah.
Roger?
CIinic confirmed
Patty's abortion.
So we turned her
world upside down
for nothing.
Another good
day's work.
I heard what you
said to the father.
I meant every
word of that.
Wow, you Iook Iike
you Ieft somebody alone
at a very nice place.
My husband will wait.
This couldn't.
It's about the baby.
What's wrong?
During the autopsy,
I noticed her retinas had
a reddish discoloration,
so I ordered several
genetic tests.
One came back positive.
What for?
Tay-Sachs.
No treatment or cure.
She'd have died
a horrible death
by the age of five.
This was a mercy killing.
So, this changes the profile.
Instead of Iooking
for one parent,
we're probably
Iooking for a couple,
reasonably well-off,
responsible enough
to get medical care
for their baby.
Explains why
she's a month old.
Mother probably never thought
of doing this until she found
out the baby was sick.
People Iike this,
they wouldn't have
kept their kid a secret.
No, but they're
probably covering up
her disappearance.
They might have relocated
at the time of her death,
or reported her
missing in another state.
I'II check with the Center
for Missing and
Exploited Children.
In the meantime,
any idea how we can
pick up their trail?
Yeah. Tay-Sachs is most common
among certain ethnic groups,
particularly
the Jewish community.
Same old story.
When all else fails,
round up the Jews.
It's also common among
French-Canadians and Cajuns.
Genetic screening has
drastically reduced the number
of Tay-Sachs babies.
Both parents need to carry
the gene and they were
probably never tested.
If I had a kid with
some rare disease,
first thing I'd do
is find a doctor who
specializes in it.
DR. KLEIN: It's a horrible
disease, worse than most
parents can possibly bear.
And how close
are you to a cure?
Years away.
Tay-Sachs patients
are missing a key enzyme.
Without it,
a fatty substance
builds up in the brain,
causing progressive Ioss
of function and eventually
death.
Would our victim have
shown any symptoms?
Nothing the parents
would have noticed
until about six months.
Then why did they
have their baby tested?
The cherry-red spots
in the eyes your M.E. found
can appear as early as
two days after birth.
Any pediatrician
could have spotted them
during a well-baby checkup.
Do you have any patients
who died suddenly
or missed appointments,
haven't come back?
My work is in research.
I don't treat
these children myself.
But even if I did,
you know I couldn't
tell you about them.
Okay. Are there any places
the parents can go for help?
Fortunately,
this disease is rare.
There's only one
support group in the area.
Not everybody
comes to every meeting.
We get people from
as far away as Maine.
But these parents
would probably be Iocal,
child born about a month ago.
There was a woman
from Manhattan.
Came to a meeting
a few weeks ago,
but never came back.
Any idea why?
She seemed disturbed when
she saw the child of one
of our parents.
Can't say I blame her.
STABLER: Do you
remember her name?
Sorry.
Well, what about
a Iist of members or
a sign-in sheet?
Can't give that out.
Rabbi, we're pretty
sure that the parents
that we're Iooking
for murdered their baby
because she had Tay-Sachs.
Oh, God.
And with all due respect,
there is no Iaw protecting
the confidentiality
of support groups.
I'm only trying to protect
what Iittle solace the members
of this group have Ieft.
I'm sorry,
we'II have to
get a subpoena.
Okay.
Here's the Iist.
I'II fax you
the sign-in sheets.
But there's no guarantee
the woman you're Iooking for
is going to be on any of them.
We don't require
parents to sign in,
or even tell us who they are.
Do you remember anything
else about this woman?
Where she Iived,
who referred her?
Now that you
mention it, yes.
Her pediatrician,
Judah PIatner, sent her.
He belongs to
our congregation.
We're not asking for records.
We're asking for the name
of the woman
you referred to
the Tay-Sachs support group.
That's the same thing,
isn't it?
Besides, I haven't
had a Tay-Sachs patient
in a couple of years.
Rabbi Birnbaum
mentioned you by name.
Yes, I know.
He visits patients
here all the time.
It's easy enough to mix me up
with another pediatrician.
Dr. PIatner, a child has
been murdered. If you know
anything at all...
I would tell you.
The Iaw requires me
to report any abuse
of a child.
Have you had any
patients die recently?
Yes. A five-year old boy.
Neuroblastoma.
Just Iast month.
It doesn't happen often
but it never gets any easier.
Any you've sent
for genetic testing?
Detective, stop wasting
your time and mine.
Believe me,
I'd help you if I could.
National Center for Missing
and Exploited Children came
up with squat.
Same with Missing Persons
in all five boroughs and
the rest of the Tri-State.
Mother goes to
a support group.
She gets the kid tested.
You've got all of
this media coverage...
Someone who knows them is not
suspicious that this baby
is gone missing?
I mean, why hasn't
anyone reported them?
Because everybody
knows the baby died.
They just don't know how.
Yeah, and somehow
they covered it up.
Maybe with help from
your Dr. PIatner.
What'd you find?
Vital Stats had
the death certificate
on a cancer patient,
but he signed
one just Iast week
on a month-old girl.
Funny how he forgot
to tell us that.
Cause of death?
Asphyxiation Pneumonia.
Little girl's
name was Sarah Brown.
Parents, Andrea and Daniel.
The funeral was Wednesday.
We're still sitting shiva.
We're very sorry
for your Ioss.
We'II take as Iittle of
your time as possible.
Dr. PIatner was
Sarah's pediatrician,
wasn't he?
Yes, but how would
you know that?
BENSON: We have a Iist
of all his patients.
What exactly
is this about?
We're investigating
a complaint against
Dr. PIatner
and we're following up
with all of his
patients' parents.
I'm sorry,
may I use
the bathroom?
Sure, it's through
the bedroom.
Pardon the mess.
Anything?
Not in the medicine cabinet,
but there was an empty vial
in the garbage can.
Something called
Imipramine.
I've never heard of it.
When was it filled?
Last week,
two days before
the baby turned up.
For Andrea Richman.
Must be her maiden name.
Prescribed by Dr. PIatner.
Well, how often does
a pediatrician write a
prescription for the parents?
The M.E. confirmed
Imipramine is the
tricyclic antidepressant
that caused
Sarah Brown's death.
Parents probably
used what they needed
to put the baby to sleep
and flushed the rest
down the toilet.
If the doctor gave
them the pills to do this,
he's just as guilty
as the Browns are.
I'II get a warrant to
pick up that pill vial.
Our baby was
found in a cooler.
Are we saying these parents
buried an empty casket?
I checked out
the funeral home
that the Browns used.
There are
multiple Health
Department violations.
The Browns could
have paid them off.
Why dump the body
in the river?
Why not just bury it?
We're not going to know
until the parents give it up.
We can't prove the Browns
are the parents without
their DNA.
Which we can't get
without more evidence.
We got the pill bottle.
Is that enough to
dig up the kid's grave?
I'II run tests
on the Iining,
but I'm pretty sure
there's never been
a body in this coffin.
I see a selfless act
of mercy, not a murder.
STABLER: The Iaw doesn't
make that distinction,
Counselor.
The jury will.
They'II never convict.
Juries don't Iike defendants
who kill their own children.
If this was Dr. PIatner's
idea and you agree to
testify against him...
It was my idea.
But I couldn't
bear to hurt Sarah.
So you had your
husband do it?
He had nothing
to do with this.
Andrea, please,
don't say anything else.
No, I need to tell them.
I didn't know what to do,
so I asked
Dr. PIatner for help.
And you wrote
Andrea the prescription.
Nothing could
have saved Sarah.
I've seen many
children die.
Children born without brains,
riddled with cancer.
This time,
at Ieast I was
able to do something
before that
Iittle girl suffered.
What about your oath?
To do no harm?
I couldn't even
make Sarah comfortable.
Her mother wanted to spare
her years of torture.
Now, would it have been
Iess harmful to make her
go through that?
The jury will see him
as an angel of mercy.
Or an angel of death.
Our version goes
down a Iot smoother.
We'II consider a plea
if there's no time involved.
Your client provided
the murder weapon.
We're not going
to send the message
that you can kill
a terminally ill child
and get off with
a slap on the wrist.
STABLER: You're Iooking
at 25-years-to-Iife.
EMMETT: Not after
the jury hears her story.
You fed Sarah the drugs.
DNA proves that
Iittle girl in the river
is your daughter.
She was my baby.
You could never
know how hard this was.
Instead of suffering,
she just went
peacefully to sleep.
It's still murder.
You're not testifying?
I have a personal interest.
Sitting on
the defense's side?
Oh, ye of Iittle faith.
I assumed that you
were pro-euthanasia.
Yeah, for adults who are
competent to ask for it.
But not for children?
First kids with incurable
diseases, then the disabled.
Where does it stop?
Defense is going to argue that
Andrea did this out of Iove.
It doesn't matter
what intentions this
road is paved with, AIex,
it only Ieads
to one place.
I was Andrea's pediatrician
since the day she was born.
But you were more
than just her doctor,
weren't you?
Well, Andrea's father, Joel,
died when she was about 1 2.
I was sort of her
surrogate father
while she was growing up.
We Iost touch from the time
she went to college until
Sarah was born.
AHRENS: How did you Iearn
that Sarah was sick?
At her two-week checkup,
I saw the red spots
in her eyes.
I told Andrea she had
to get the girl tested.
And when the results
of those tests came back?
I told Andrea and Daniel
their child had Tay-Sachs.
They felt terrible guilt
because they had not been
tested themselves.
AHRENS: Did you tell
them what Sarah faced?
Yes, I did.
Would you tell us?
At about six months,
Sarah would start
having seizures.
Her vision would
progressively deteriorate
until she went blind.
Her brain function
would slowly disappear.
She would Iose
the ability to sit up
and swallow.
She would need
a feeding tube
to stay alive.
I told Andrea and
Daniel that their
beautiful Iittle child
would die a terrible death
before she was five.
How did they
take the news?
As bad as
you would expect.
They couldn't stand
the thought of Sarah
suffering and then Iosing her.
Doctor, at any time
did you advise Andrea
or Daniel Brown to
euthanize their daughter?
Absolutely not.
Then why did you
prescribe the tricyclics
that Andrea used to
put Sarah to sleep?
Andrea said that she was going
to euthanize Sarah with me
or without me.
You see, I knew what Sarah
was going to go through.
I just wanted it to be as
painless as possible for
both of them.
Thank you, Doctor.
No questions
for this witness.
Dr. PIatner, when you agreed
to help Andrea Brown
kill her daughter...
No, no, no.
That's not what I said.
PIease Iet me finish, Doctor.
Did you ever talk to
her husband, Daniel?
No, I didn't.
But he was Sarah's father.
Andrea would have never
done this if it wasn't
what they both wanted.
You also falsified
the death certificate,
didn't you?
Yes, I did.
Did you also advise Andrea
to dump Sarah's body
in the Hudson River?
No, no, of course not.
Then why did you arrange
for the funeral home
to bury an empty casket?
Andrea was supposed to call me
when Sarah had gone to sleep.
But she panicked.
She didn't come to me
until after she had already
put Sarah in the river.
CABOT: And you helped
her cover it up?
Yes, I did.
Dr. PIatner, do you
think that children
who have no
chance of survival
should be euthanized?
Objection.
Overruled.
Have you ever seen
a child with Tay-Sachs?
Or any fatal disease?
And how would we
determine the criteria
for killing a child?
Those born with half a brain?
Deaf children?
BIind children, maybe?
Is this necessary,
Your Honor?
You've made your point,
Miss Cabot. Move on.
Dr. PIatner,
for how many other patients
have you ended the suffering?
None.
Then why did you
do it in this case?
Sarah was hopeless.
I was Iike
a father to Andrea.
I couldn't Iet this
destroy her, too.
Nothing further.
Daniel had to
work Iate that night.
I crushed the pills,
I put them in some formula.
I nursed her one Iast time,
and then I gave
Sarah the bottle.
And I...
I held her and I watched her
as she peacefully drifted
off to sleep.
Tell the jury
what happened next.
I Iost it.
I was supposed
to call Judah...
Dr. PIatner, but...
I put Sarah in the car
and I just drove.
I went to the river
and stopped at a place
where Daniel and I
used to picnic.
Did you call your husband?
No.
I didn't want him
to see our baby Iike that.
EMMETT: What did you do?
I put the
tire iron into the grocery
sack, I tied it around the
handle.
I wrapped Sarah
in a blanket and I...
And I put her inside and
I placed it on the water
and I just... I
watched while
it disappeared.
Andrea,
you had other alternatives,
didn't you?
There was a support group
that Judah recommended.
And I went and I
Iistened to the parents
discuss their kids.
They can't move.
They can't see.
It made me even
more determined
to do what I did.
Why?
Because I Ioved
Sarah so much.
I could not stand
to see her suffer.
Nothing further.
Sarah wasn't
showing any symptoms
of Tay-Sachs.
Why didn't you
wait until she did?
I didn't want her
to be in any pain.
Wasn't this as
much about your pain
as it was Sarah's?
I did it to
spare Sarah,
not me.
I will be in agony
for the rest of my Iife.
You testified that you
went to the support
group by yourself.
Where was your husband?
I didn't think he
could handle it.
Dr. PIatner said
that you both wanted
to end Sarah's Iife
and yet you told detectives
that your husband
wasn't involved.
Why did you make
this decision
on your own?
I didn't want Daniel
to be the one who did it.
I know what I did
was against the Iaw.
But I believe
in a Ioving God.
And I cannot believe
that a Ioving God
would want an innocent child
to suffer so horribly.
(CHATTERING)
Miss Cabot.
Your client seems upset.
What's going on?
Dr. PIatner asked
me to talk to you.
Why?
He wants to make a deal.
In return for what?
I've already testified,
Ms. Cabot.
Believe me,
I'm not hiding anything.
I did what I had to do
for Andrea and Sarah.
What happened to
your noble intentions,
alleviating the suffering
of dying children?
I've been taking
care of children
for almost 40 years.
If I'm convicted,
I'II die in prison.
What are you Iooking for?
Man two, five-to-15.
And this doesn't have anything
to do with the fireworks
I witnessed after court today?
There isn't anything
that my client knows
that he hasn't
told you or the jury.
And he may very
well be acquitted.
You didn't Iet PIatner
cop a plea, did you?
We told him
we'd sleep on it.
AII that posturing about
euthanasia and now he
just wants to give up?
What's he
really afraid of?
I'm not sure,
but PIatner Iooked
pretty surprised
when Andrea testified
she never told her husband
what she was going to do.
This was the most
important decision
of their Iives.
How could she
not include him?
She said she didn't
want Daniel to be
the one who did it.
Maybe she was
protecting him.
Not from us.
Even if he was involved,
the only proof of that
would be Andrea's testimony
and spousal privilege
puts that off Iimits.
Well, maybe Andrea
was protecting him
from the truth.
About what?
Every Jewish couple I know
got tested for Tay-Sachs
before they walked
down the aisle.
Why would an educated
couple Iike the Browns
roll the dice and
take those chances?
Because they thought there
was no chance they could
have a Tay-Sachs baby.
If Danny wasn't born Jewish,
he'd got better odds
at hitting the Iottery
than carrying
the Tay-Sachs gene.
What kind of offer
requires the presence
of the defendant's
husband but not her?
No offer.
We have a court order
for a DNA test
for Mr. Brown.
What the hell for?
We checked your
birth certificate.
You were born Catholic.
Yes, but I converted to
Judaism before Andrea and I
got married. So what?
So there's very Iittle
chance that you carry
the Tay-Sachs gene.
(SIGHS)
You can't do this.
I know my rights.
Spousal privilege.
Husbands and wives
can't incriminate
each other.
Well, that's not
entirely true.
Communication between
spouses is protected.
But the privilege
doesn't cover DNA.
We can take you to
the M.E.'s office
right now for the DNA test.
Don't waste your time.
I'm
not Sarah's
biological father.
Andrea told you,
didn't she?
About the affair.
After she was arrested.
But I suspected something
when Sarah was diagnosed.
It was with some
guy in her office.
How do you know
she wasn't just trying
to cover up the affair
when she killed Sarah?
Because she Ioved
that child more than
anything in the world.
CABOT: PIease state your
name for the record.
Steven Kellerman.
Mr. Kellerman,
how do you know
the defendant?
I worked with her.
What was the extent
of your relationship?
I'm not sure
what that means.
Did you have sex
with Andrea Brown?
It only happened once
after we'd worked Iate.
Her husband was away.
After that, you transferred
to a different office,
didn't you?
To Boston, yes.
When did you become
aware that Andrea Brown
was pregnant with your child?
When I read about
the case in the newspaper.
So you're saying
you never even knew
about your own daughter?
Yes.
Nothing further.
Who ended the affair?
Andrea did,
immediately after it began.
I Ioved her,
but she Ioved
her husband
and she had
a moment of weakness...
Objection!
Mr. Kellerman is not here
as a character witness.
Sustained.
Jury will disregard.
When you read about
Andrea in the newspaper,
why didn't you come forward?
Because I had a brother
that died of Tay-Sachs and
I've seen what that does.
And if I'd been in Andrea's
position, I would have done
the same thing.
I'm very sorry.
Andrea Brown's actions
had one purpose.
One.
To spare the child she Ioved
years of horrible agony,
Ieading to
an inevitable death.
When you go into
the jury room,
Iadies and gentlemen,
you must decide if this woman
deserves to go to prison
for at Ieast 25 years.
But before you
answer that question,
ask one of yourselves,
"If this were my child,
"what would I do?"
And if that question
gives you pause,
I pray you decide
that Andrea Brown
has already suffered enough.
Andrea Brown ground up a
Iethal dose of antidepressants
and fed it to her baby.
The defense doesn't
dispute these facts,
but they argue
Mrs. Brown acted out of
the noblest of motives.
Let's examine these motives.
Andrea Brown had
an extramarital affair
and got pregnant.
When she found out the baby
wasn't her husband's,
did she tell him?
No.
Did she tell Steve Kellerman
that he was the father?
No.
Did she tell Dr. PIatner,
when pressuring him
for a prescription,
an act she knew
could Iand him in prison?
No.
From the start,
Andrea Brown's
primary concern
was preserving her
marriage, her image,
and her Iifestyle
by hiding at all
costs her affair.
She knew that
the Ionger Sarah
was alive,
the greater the chances
someone would find out
that Daniel Brown
was not the father.
So she killed her daughter,
a helpless child who had
not yet begun to suffer
the effects of Tay-Sachs,
all of this to conceal
the fact that she'd slept
with another man.
The defense would
have you believe
this was an act of mercy.
It wasn't.
This was a clear-cut
case of murder.
On the sole count of murder
in the second degree,
how does the jury find?
We find the defendant guilty.
(SOBBING)
Good work, Counselor.
She didn't
deserve 25-to-Iife.
Jury thought so.
Because I turned
her into a whore.
It doesn't matter.
She killed her child.
What if it was
your daughter?
What would you
have done?
Whatever I could.