NARRATOR: In the criminal
justice system,
sexually based offenses
are considered
especially heinous.
In New York City,
the dedicated detectives
who investigate
these vicious felonies
are members
of an elite squad known
as the Special Victims Unit.
These are their stories.
I just don't understand
why you never
bring your cell phone.
A cell phone
won't change the fact
that you ran out of gas.
No, I didn't!
The gauge is broken.
Where are you going?
Maybe they have
a cell phone.
Wait, you don't
know who they are.
Nobody.
Now what?
Start walking.
(THUDDING)
What was that?
Somebody's in there.
Get it open.
FIag down a car.
Hurry!
(WHIMPERING)
Multiple stab wounds.
Looks Iike the guy clocked
her a couple of times
with a tire iron
before raping her
with it.
She's conscious,
though.
She tell you anything?
Can't. He superglued
her Iips shut.
She stopped
breathing, so
we had to crike her.
You got anything to
dissolve that with?
E.R.'s got a solvent
if she gets there.
No promises.
I'II go. Call you
if she says anything.
You got an ID?
(SIGHS) No purse, no keys.
Car's registered
to Meredith McGrath.
Seems Iike there's some
recent damage
to the bumper.
So he bumps into her,
she pulls over,
he attacks her.
Found these
in the trash.
Eighty bucks cash
in her wallet.
No driver's Iicense.
AII the credit cards
say Meredith McGrath.
Did you find
keys in there?
No.
So he took the keys.
He Ieaves the money,
he takes her Iicense.
With her home
address on it.
What's the address
on that registration?
What the hell happened?
Someone heard
a commotion.
By the time we get here,
he's already dead.
(CHATTER ON POLICE RADIO)
Homicide here?
Bishop.
Stabler,
Special Victims Unit.
Sam Bishop.
This is Roger McGrath.
Looks Iike he
surprised a burglar.
But I'm pretty sure
the guy wasn't raped.
His wife was.
Tonight?
Couple hours ago.
We think the perp
stole her house keys,
came here Iooking
for something.
Hard drive of the computer.
Ripped it right out.
Was that the only
thing he touched?
Looks Iike.
But he missed this.
Found this in the desk,
with a couple of burned CDs.
I don't know,
might tell me
something.
So, how do you
want to work this?
I'II give you a call
if I need your help.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Stabler.
When?
Okay. Thanks.
What?
My victim, she's dead.
Does that help?
STABLER: OIivia back
from the hospital?
Still there.
Caught a child
abuse case in the E.R.
But what's the story
on the husband's murder?
Witnesses only
heard a fight.
We found prints
at the apartment.
They matched prints
on the wife's car.
I ran them through
the system. Zip.
AII this to
steal the hard drive
off the home computer.
Explains why
the husband was killed,
but why attack the wife
and superglue her mouth shut?
Sending a message.
Talked when she
shouldn't have.
Anything pop up
on the Iaptop?
Homicide detective
sent it over to TARU.
Said he'd give a buzz
if anything Iooked useful.
Yeah, meaning after his
case clears, we'II never
hear from him again.
So Iet's concentrate
on our own victim.
She was driving
home from work
when this happened.
Let's start there.
SCHWARTZ:
Everybody here
Ioved Meredith.
Anybody Iove her
in private?
What, Iike an affair? No.
At Ieast,
not with
anybody here.
How do you know?
Well, 80 percent
of the department
is female
and I don't think
her door
swung both ways.
The guys, not to be a jerk,
but I doubt she'd risk
her marriage on any of them.
Did she get
a promotion Iately,
a new office,
anything to make
one of her
co-workers jealous?
Not at all. In fact,
I almost had to fire her
a few months ago.
Why?
Well, some
performance issues.
Distracted, took a Iot
of sick days, vacation.
Then she was
back to normal.
What was going on
with her?
I'm not really sure.
She changed her e-mail
address seven or eight
times Iast year.
I think she had
some kind of stalker.
Do you mind
if we take a Iook
at her computer?
Oh, she didn't
have one here.
She always
brought her Iaptop.
Need the TARU report
on that Iaptop.
I don't have it yet.
Why?
Well, it belonged
to my victim.
You get anything
off those CD-ROMs?
Yeah, I got something.
STABLER: Kiddie porn.
BISHOP: Yeah.
Hundreds of pictures.
Probably what the perp
was Iooking for on
the hard drive.
And when were you going to get
around to sharing that piece
of information with me?
I've got to report to you
if my victim's a pervert?
No, you've got to tell me when
you find something pertaining
to my victim.
That CD belongs to her.
How do you know?
There's no
usable prints on it.
Listen to me.
Meredith McGrath changed
her e-mail address
seven times Iast year.
I am betting she did it
because she didn't want
to get caught with that.
She was raped,
tortured and murdered.
This guy was after her,
not her husband.
Well, you SVU guys
want the perv crap,
you can have it.
MORALES: Real pleasant work,
detectives.
Thanks for sharing.
Find more kiddie porn?
More than 50 images.
From what I can tell,
they're of two
different girls.
One Iooks
eight or nine.
One 14 or 15.
Really twisted stuff.
This computer is jacked.
Some kind of virus.
I haven't been able
to view everything.
Any way to ID
these girls?
We send all child
pornography to the FBI.
MORALES: They use facial
recognition software.
Compare the porn
to the database at
the National Center
for Missing &
Exploited Children.
Any idea where Meredith
got these pictures?
Sent to her from
Nick2Shy@wiremail.bz.
She saves his e-mails
along with the photos.
And where can we
find this Nick?
Used a Wiremail account.
Anonymous server.
Yeah. Truth is,
nothing is really
anonymous.
Every e-mail you send,
every website you visit,
you transmit
an internet protocol address.
Most e-mails
have the IP number
in the header information.
Who is it?
AII I can tell you
is the server he used.
The IP is assigned
to the computer Iab
at Stuyvesant College.
Get a subpoena,
they can tell you
who the user is.
One more thing.
Mrs. McGrath also Iiked
to save her Internet chats.
Oh, yeah?
What did she
chat about?
Trolling for more porn.
I tried reading a couple
but then I stopped
when I felt Iike puking.
Wow. This your partner?
Yeah.
Does she date?
A Iot of guys.
So, there's just no way
to retrieve it, right?
Okay. Thank you.
College computer Iab?
There's no record of anyone
accessing the IP address.
Someone from a remote site
bypassed the Iog-in code.
They were hacked.
It's an old system.
There's no way
to trace this guy.
This Nick2Shy
is going through
an awful Iot of trouble
to keep his
identity a secret.
Well, come on,
if he killed her,
I mean, I think
he did us a favor.
I mean, Iisten to this one.
Here's a guy offering
Meredith 300 photos
of boys under seven.
In return,
he wants to take her son
to a motel for an hour.
Isn't that sweet?
She doesn't
have any kids.
She told this
guy she did.
(SIGHS)
That is something
I am not understanding.
She seems to be doing
an awful Iot of Iying.
She goes into an adult
chat room, pretends she's
a 13-year-old girl.
She changes her screen name
to "Iuv2cheer13."
AImost immediately,
six guys are hitting on her.
So she's getting
off with a fantasy?
I don't know, but then
she starts setting up
meetings in hotels
with these guys.
Now, what the hell
is the point of that?
It's not Iike she
can all of a sudden
turn into this 13-year-old
girl once she gets there.
Okay. Why does she
flirt with them online?
Think about it.
She saves every one
of the communications
she has with these guys.
She doesn't offer
them anything illegal
until they ask for it.
Now, what does that
sound Iike to you?
A sicko.
It's also how the Feds
sting pedophiles online.
She's an informant.
Yeah, that makes sense.
How?
Well, that virus
I thought I found?
Actually a Trojan horse.
What's that?
It's a program hiding within
a seemingly innocuous file.
In this case,
it was designed to record
every single keystroke
Meredith McGrath made.
Each time she signed online,
it would transmit
the information in an e-mail.
To Nick2Shy.
Attached the Trojan to
a picture he sent her.
After that, he could read
every word she typed.
So he found out
she was an informant
and killed her,
stole the evidence
that she'd been
collecting against him.
So she's on
FBI payroll?
Possibly.
She sent huge
bundles of information
to a dot-gov address.
Federal domain.
Someone named
CIaudia Williams.
It's not FBI.
She's an assistant
U.S. attorney.
When were you going
to Iet us know that
she was working for you?
When I had something
to give you.
Well, when were you going
to tell me that you were using
a civilian to do your job?
Meredith McGrath was
going after pedophiles
on the Internet
Iong before
our involvement.
She considered herself
a cyber vigilante.
AII on her own? Why?
Maybe because she was
raped as a young girl
and decided to
get back at people
who exploit children.
She came to us, Detective.
What were we
supposed to do, ignore her?
So she did
your dirty work.
When she got killed for it,
"Oh well, it was her
decision." Is that it?
Meredith helped us
put away five pedophiles
in the Iast year.
Believe me when I tell you,
I want to find out
who killed her
just as badly as you do.
Okay. I want to see
the files on every perp
she went after,
and I don't want
to hear about it
compromising your cases.
Recognize her?
14-year-old
Mia Van Wagner
from Queens.
She's one of the girls
in the pictures on
Meredith's Iaptop.
How did you ID her?
FBI computer got the match.
She's been missing
for two weeks.
Mia's photographs didn't start
showing up on the Internet
until after her disappearance.
You're thinking she was
kidnapped and Meredith
found out about it?
It's possible.
Sounds Iike a motive
for murder to me.
What did the 117
have to say about
this missing girl?
They wrote it up
as a runaway.
She packed her bags,
stole a couple hundred
bucks from her mother.
There's no mention
of the porno pics.
Morning, Captain.
Bishop, you're getting
to be a regular
fixture around here.
Thinking about
a department transfer?
No, thanks.
I Iike my
victims dead.
Found the address
of the mother's work.
Restaurant
in Queens.
Thanks.
I had told the police
that I don't
think she ran away.
I know it Iooks
Iike that, but...
I think she must
have been forced
or something.
Mrs. Van Wagner,
does Mia spend
a Iot of time online?
No. My daughter
can't have the Internet.
I don't allow it. Why?
Pictures of her
showed up
in some e-mails.
We're just not quite
sure who sent them.
What kind of pictures?
Mrs. Van Wagner...
You have to show me.
Let me see them.
You don't need to
see the pictures.
If it were my daughter,
I wouldn't want
those images in my head.
Oh, my God.
Well, what's
happening to her?
That's what we're
trying to find out.
Is it possible
she uses
a friend's e-mail account?
I suppose.
She spends a Iot of time
at Samantha Gilligan's
house, but...
You know, the police
already talked to her.
Mia just took off.
She didn't tell me
where she was going,
and she hasn't
called me, okay?
Okay.
You know, you don't
seem too worried
about your friend.
Mia can take
care of herself.
She's way more
mature than people
think.
She ever come over here
and use your computer?
Probably.
I don't know.
BISHOP: You don't know?
Come on.
You guys went
online together,
right?
Hit the chat rooms,
maybe try to pick up guys.
Okay, whatever.
Did any guy ever
try to pick up Mia?
Am I psychic?
Wonder what your
friend's doing now?
Here, take a Iook at that.
Look Iike she's
having a Iot of fun?
Put it away.
Oh, my God.
That's Mia?
Put it away.
Somebody's doing
that to your friend.
So if you know where she is,
you've got to
tell us right now.
She had this
boyfriend, online.
Where are they?
I don't know, I swear.
She called me
a couple of days
after she Ieft,
but she didn't
tell me where she was.
There's no way
he would do
that stuff to her.
He Ioves her.
How do you
know that?
She showed me
his e-mails.
They were
really romantic.
Did you save
the e-mails he sent?
Go to the computer
and get them for me.
Why the hell did
you show her that?
She was Iying
her ass off.
So your solution is
terrorizing her into
giving you information?
Hey, we got what we
came for. I don't have
time to hold her hand.
Listen to me.
I don't want you
jumping in my
game Iike that again.
Are we clear?
Look, it's only going
to get uglier from
here on out,
so if you
can't handle it,
you've just got to
Iet me know right now.
Look, Iet's break
up the work.
I'II run down the phone
dump on this girl,
you run down the e-mails.
I don't recognize
the server name.
Let's see if the IP
tells us anything.
Whoa.
I think this is going
to be a Iittle out of
NYPD's jurisdiction.
Another state?
Another country.
Server's in Prague.
As in the Czech Republic.
U.S. Embassy in Prague
has confirmed the sender
is Erich Tassig,
a German national,
Iiving in the Czech Republic
for the Iast two years.
They pick him up?
The Czechs won't
arrest him based
on e-mails.
Which shows he was pursuing
a sexual relationship
with a minor.
He invited her
to Iive with him.
What else do they need?
Proof that he's
got the girl.
Erich Tassig has not
Ieft the Czech Republic
in eight months.
Yeah, well,
he must have convinced
her to go on her own.
U.S. Immigration says
Mia Van Wagner has never
been issued a passport.
AII right,
I don't know how
this dirtbag did it,
but he smuggled her
out of this country
and he's now
circulating pornographic
pictures of her.
Prove it.
The Czechs will
play ball with us.
We'II make sure of it.
Mia Van Wagner
had an e-mail
relationship with Tassig
for over one year.
Now, photos of Mia
and this unknown girl
were found on
Meredith McGrath's Iaptop.
AII of those photos
were sent to her
by Nick2Shy.
I'm thinking that this
is the guy who murdered
Meredith and her husband.
Could Tassig and Nick2Shy
be the same person?
I was thinking that,
but the e-mails
coming from Tassig
were clearly written by
somebody who doesn't speak
English as a first Ianguage.
Nick2Shy does.
So, Nick helps Tassig
get Mia out of the country.
Meredith finds out about it.
Nick kills her.
The question is,
how do these guys
know each other?
Okay. More importantly...
This girl is being
raped and tortured.
Where the hell is she?
Phone dump on
Samantha Gilligan.
Mia Van Wagner called
from a prepaid cell phone.
LUDs on that show she
used it the first two
days she was missing.
Nothing since.
Who else she call?
Three calls to
the same number.
Photocopy shop, Midtown.
You get passport photos
from those places.
WOMAN: Hi, can I help you?
We're Iooking for a girl
who came in for
a passport picture.
Oh, sure. That's Kerry.
What, is she in trouble?
How do you know Kerry?
I met her a couple weeks ago.
Ron brought her in.
She's his daughter.
Ron who?
Ron Crowley.
He's my boss.
He's right in the back
if you want to talk to him.
Ronnie?
I'm sorry,
this area's restricted
to employees only.
No, it's not.
We heard you brought
your daughter to
work a couple weeks ago.
So?
BISHOP: Is that her?
No.
Strong resemblance,
but no, that's not Kerry.
Take a better Iook.
CIerk out front said
that is definitely
your daughter.
Well, I guess I'd know
my own kid better
than she would.
BISHOP: How many
daughters you got,
Ronnie?
One. Is that all?
Got any pictures of her?
I got tons of pictures
of my kids with me.
Come on.
I'II show you mine
if you show me yours.
What are you doing?
Let me see
your wallet, Ron.
You can't do that.
Is this your daughter?
She Iooks nothing Iike
the girl you brought in,
Ron.
Let's go.
I never saw
that girl
in my Iife.
So your employee
was Iying.
She made a mistake.
How come Mia Van Wagner
called your store
three times?
How do I know?
Maybe she
needed copies.
Wrong answer.
What the hell
is your problem?
Detective Bishop
here is very impatient.
Now, you're going
to do yourself
a big favor
if you just answer
our questions
honestly.
I am.
Good. Tell me about
Meredith McGrath.
Never heard of her.
The woman you
raped and murdered.
Wait a minute.
You got the wrong guy!
She found out
about you, Ronnie,
what a sick Iittle
worm you are.
So you killed her!
I did not!
Take a walk, Detective.
It's all right.
CRAGEN: Let's go, Bishop.
I'm CIaudia Williams,
Assistant U.S. Attorney.
Are you all right,
Mr. Crowley?
I'II be better when I smack
a Iawsuit on that guy's ass.
Did you see that?
Well, you won't be
dealing with Detective
Bishop anymore.
Mr. Crowley,
do you still have custody
of your daughter, Kerry?
No, my ex-wife's got her.
Did you recently obtain
a U.S. passport for her?
No.
I have an application
you made to Immigration
with your signature
and I have an official copy
of your daughter's
birth certificate
that you gave them
along with this photograph.
This is not your daughter.
This is Mia Van Wagner.
Fraudulently obtaining
a U.S. passport is a serious
offense, Mr. Crowley.
And if you think
the NYPD was tough on you,
just wait until you start
dealing with the Federal
government.
I didn't kidnap her.
AII I did was get
her the passport
and help her
Ieave the country,
which she wanted to do.
Who's in Prague?
I don't know his name.
You trade
kiddie porn with him.
Don't bother to deny it.
Customs is already
searching your house.
He gave me five
grand to help her.
He bought her
the plane ticket,
but I'm telling you,
that girl went willingly.
Who's this girl?
I've never seen her.
Her picture is on
Meredith McGrath's computer.
I never heard of that woman.
Look, I didn't kill anybody,
and I didn't force
anybody to do anything.
I was helping.
Is that a crime?
Crowley's wrong
for the murder.
His prints don't
match either scene.
I'm more worried
about finding
Mia Van Wagner.
Detective Stabler,
how is it that you've
never been issued
a passport?
Never needed one. Why?
Well, you do now.
Customs wants an SVU
detective in Prague
when they find the girl.
You can pick up your
passport and plane ticket
at Kennedy in two hours,
assuming Captain Cragen
is amenable to
Ioaning you out.
Sounds Iike you
better pack, Detective.
(BELLS TOLLING)
Detective Stabler?
Yeah.
Kate Logan.
I'm the Europol officer
assigned to this
investigation.
Nice to meet you.
U.S. Customs will furnish
you with a sidearm for
the duration of your stay.
Do you speak
Czech or German?
A Iittle Spanish. Sorry.
Then you'II
stick with me.
NYPD doesn't often
dispatch their detectives
to foreign countries
to arrest a suspect.
Well, they do
when the guy is
a particular dirtbag.
Well, you'II find
there's no shortage
of those here.
Welcome to
the Czech Republic.
Why is Europol so
interested in Tassig?
Czech Republic is not even
an E.U. member yet.
Both Europol and Interpol
have independently
suspected Erich Tassig
of trafficking young girls
from Eastern Europe
to Germany and Austria.
Two years ago,
he fled to
the Czech Republic
and he's been off
our radar ever since,
reinventing himself
as this
Internet entrepreneur.
Producing and distributing
child pornography.
Likely,
but we can't prove it.
AII his work
appears to be
Iegitimate.
My specific interest?
We almost had the bastard
and he slipped
through our fingers.
It won't
happen again.
Detective,
glad to have you aboard.
Mike Pearson, U.S.
Customs attaché.
I'd Iike to give
you a chance to sleep
but we've had
some developments
since you Ieft New York.
That's okay.
I came here to work.
LOGAN: What developments?
Last night, the Czech police
jumped the gun
and raided Tassig's flat.
He and the girl
are in the wind.
How did he know
that we were
onto them?
Customs in D.C.
traced an e-mail
from Tassig's ISP
to a Samantha Gilligan
in New York.
Samantha replied
the next day.
That's Mia Van Wagner's
friend. She must
have warned her.
Well, we've released this
picture of Miss Van Wagner
to the media.
Tip Iine goes to the Czech
police, they'II contact us
with anything Iegit.
How hard would it be
for them to Ieave
the country?
Tassig won't try it.
He's got too
much reason to stay.
Why? He's already
got the girl.
I think you need a Iesson
on the child sex trade in
the Czech Republic, Detective.
LOGAN: In some of these
Czech border towns,
the brothels outnumber
the churches.
So every week,
about 10,000
Germans come here
because the prostitutes
are half-price,
because anything
you want, you can get.
See those pink
curtains there?
Mmm-hmm.
They indicate that if
you were so inclined
and had 500 crowns,
they'd give you a child
under the age of
10 for 30 minutes.
That's $17 U.S.
BIue curtains
mean you'd get a boy.
Where do they get
these children?
Some are orphans,
smuggled in from
Romania and Bulgaria.
Eric Tassig isn't
the only man profiting
off the sale of children.
You don't do
anything about it,
huh?
Europol has no authority
over the Czech citizens.
As far as the Czech police,
they have no
incentive to stop it.
There's too much
money to be made
handing out
parking tickets
to the German tourists.
Look, this is the world
that we Iive in,
Detective Stabler.
I should think in
your Iine of work,
you'd understand that.
In my Iine of work,
we wouldn't just
sit back and take it.
That's very noble.
But as Iong as
the demand for child
exploitation exists,
there's Iittle
we can do.
So what the hell
are you doing here?
It's my job.
What are you
doing here?
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Excuse me.
Hello.
Yes. AII right,
thanks.
We're on our way.
Detective,
a credible tip
just came in.
It's not far.
STABLER:
You've seen this girl?
Yes, I've seen her.
Comes by every day.
Buys chocolate
from me.
She with anyone?
AIone mostly.
There was a man
with her once or twice.
Not her father.
And how do you
know that?
The way he kisses her.
LOGAN: Have you
seen her today?
Not yet.
Then we wait.
(MAN CHATTERING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Erich, I think
somebody's following me.
Come on.
Where?
Mia! Mia!
Let's go.
Come on, run!
(BELL TOLLING)
Over here.
Come on.
Okay.
STABLER: Mia!
Mia, wait!
Mia.
Erich!
No! Let me go!
I got you.
Erich, help me!
I'm here to help you.
PIease!
I'm a police officer.
PIease! PIease! PIease!
Where's Tassig?
He's gone.
Stand up.
Stand up. Okay.
You Iet him run.
I had two choices,
get him or save the girl.
I thought Mia
was more important.
You just took away
Tassig's one reason
to stay in this country.
He could be
anywhere now.
So your solution is
I should have just
Iet her run away again?
We would have had him
in custody and we'd have
eventually found Mia.
Eventually?
And what? In the meantime,
you just Iet a child
wander around
in a foreign city
for a few days?
What about the other child
you're Iooking for,
Detective Stabler?
We forget about her now?
Like I said,
I made a choice.
We'II talk to Mia,
she'II Iead us to Tassig.
Mia has been terribly abused
and won't admit it.
She thinks we are
the enemy. You expect her
to help us?
You know, I just figured out
why you're so pissed off
and you're right,
it is easier to arrest
the bad guy than it is
to deal with the victim.
Why aren't you
Ietting me Ieave?
Because you're 14 years old
and we have to protect you.
I don't need you
to protect me.
That's Erich Tassig's
job, right?
Yes.
STABLER: So, why'd he
Ieave you behind?
You think he
Ioves you?
I know he Ioves me.
And I Iove him and I don't
care if you guys don't
understand because it's true.
Mia, he's told that
to so many other girls.
He's very charming.
You're a Iiar.
I'm not going to
talk about it anymore.
He sells girls for sex.
Did you know that?
Very young girls.
No, he doesn't.
Mia, we've seen
the pictures.
What pictures?
He made you do things.
He put drugs in your arm.
No, he didn't!
So you wanted to
do those things.
You wanted those
pictures taken...
Stop it! Shut up.
You wanted them
put on the Internet?
What?
Did you want them
put on the Internet?
That's how
we found them.
That's not true, right?
Mia, Iook, I'm sorry,
but it's true
and this guy
is not who
you think he is.
Erich Tassig is a criminal,
he's a Iiar,
he's a manipulator.
He won't protect you.
So don't sit here
and protect him.
Oh, my God.
But you could get
them back, right?
I mean,
nobody has
to see them?
We'II try.
PIease.
PIease?
You can't
Iet anybody...
You can't Iet my mom...
If we find Erich,
then we'II know every place
he's sent your pictures to.
We can destroy them
and I promise you,
we will.
Look, he's got
this place
where he works.
(SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
We'II talk to him
at your precinct.
Americans?
You are arresting
people all across
the globe these days?
A pleasant benefit
from terrorism?
I'II never understand
the pedophile's instinct
to incriminate himself.
We found Tassig's
Internet business
with customers in
New York,
Virginia,
Washington.
Business is booming.
(SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
The authorities in this
country have a history
of violating human rights.
That shouldn't
be your concern,
Mr. Tassig.
You're not in
Czech custody.
Because I have
done nothing wrong.
You recorded yourself
numerous times having
sex with Mia Van Wagner.
(TASSIG CHUCKLES)
This is a crime?
The age of consent
in this country is 15.
STABLER: She's 14.
She told a Iie.
STABLER: That sucks for you.
Why? Was I forcing
her on those tapes?
No. She Ioves me.
She wanted me.
Did she want
these two guys also?
that other girl?
Mia has appetites
Iike any of us.
She is an adventurous woman.
She's a 14-year-old girl
that you drugged
and photographed
being raped.
That is a Iie.
I am not a pornographer.
We have your
computer equipment,
Mr. Tassig.
You run a child
pornography website.
You're in possession
of over a hundred
thousand illegal images...
(EXCLAIMING) Why are you
so obsessed
with children?
That is disgusting.
Your business is
selling child rape videos
and we're disgusting?
I am trapping
these people.
They buy from me
and then I know
who they are.
I'm doing your work.
Don't arrest me,
arrest them.
LOGAN: If you're
so innocent,
Mr. Tassig,
why did you arrange
to kidnap a child
from America?
Mia came to me
by her own choice.
But I don't expect
you to understand.
I understand.
Who is she?
Who's that girl?
She is Iovely.
I don't know her.
You have 50 pictures
of her on your computer.
Did you photograph her?
No! I am not a deviant.
I'm supposed to be afraid
that the American
detective will hurt me?
You can't.
It is against
your Iaws.
(SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
What did you
just say to him?
I merely reminded
Mr. Tassig that
we were not in America.
So perhaps he'II be more
inclined to cooperate and stop
this ridiculous performance.
You need permission
from this bitch?
(GRUNTS)
Come here...
What did you
say to me? Huh?
What do I need?
AII right.
This Iittle girl.
Who is she?
I don't know her. I swear.
But I have seen her website.
What website?
It has pictures and
video of this girl.
It says her name
is Amy. That is all I know.
I swear.
We found the site
in Tassig's computer.
It's called
Amy's Little Secret.
You need
a password
to get on.
And for $29.99 a month,
you can buy one
from another website,
allowing you to access
multiple pornography sites,
adults and children.
They charge it to
your credit card,
it shows up as
a subscription to
a fly-fishing magazine.
How can we see
what's on that?
We use the ambassador's
Amex and get
our own password.
I already did it.
Pretty sick stuff.
Hundreds of images,
all of the same girl.
LOGAN: Amy at age nine.
Amy, age five.
Age three.
Live webcast,
twice a week.
Shut it off.
Can we trace the person
uploading these images?
AII we can do is
find the same e-mail
that Detective Stabler had,
this Nick2Shy guy.
We sent Tassig's computers on
to this Customs CyberSmuggling
unit in D.C.
They may be able
to tell us more.
The password company
is taking money for
the website. They've got
to know who's operating it.
According to the credit card
charge, they're from your neck
of the woods.
Outfit operating
out of New York State.
Looks Iike you're
going home, Detective.
Hey, welcome back.
Things turn out okay?
Mia Van Wagner's
back at home.
She's not too happy
about it but she's
got a Iong way to go.
I didn't expect
to see you back
at this department.
I'm supposed to
take you down
to the Federal Building.
Why?
You won't believe
what you started.
BISHOP: Customs put this
together while you were
on the plane.
GIad everyone's
been keeping busy.
Congratulations,
Detective.
AII this from
Tassig's computers, huh?
Customs found
financial records
showing payments
from a company
called Private-Code,
the same password company
that they used on
the Amy website.
We traced it
to a residence
in Westchester.
What are
the payments for?
Private-Code
sells the passwords.
Tassig gets a cut
of the profits.
Up to 25 grand a month.
And how many people
are we talking about?
Preliminary search
found 15 child porn sites
all on Private-Code's payroll
in three different countries,
over 400,000
individual images.
Who knows how
many subscribers.
Private-Code's
only a middleman.
Who will Iead us
to the producers
and the distributors
and the consumers.
We're busting 17 producers
in the Tri-State Area alone.
You've opened
Pandora's box,
detectives.
This is huge.
So I see.
With the FBI,
Customs, the Iocal PDs.
Looks Iike you
got it covered.
We do.
I just thought you'd want
to be there when we take
the bastards out.
OFFICER: Let's move.
United States Customs service,
we have a warrant to search
the premises.
Police! Drop everything!
Let me see your hands!
This is private property.
No, this is destroying
the evidence that you pay
people to molest children.
We only sell passwords.
We don't know what people
put on their website.
What are you
telling me, Iady?
That you don't know
what the website
child-dot-rape's all about?
Shut up.
STABLER: What's the story?
Unbelievable.
This is even bigger
than the Feds thought.
Company grossed 15 mil
in the past
fiscal year alone.
For selling a $30 password?
How many subscribers they got?
Last count, 300,000 accessing
more than a hundred child porn
sites in 20 countries.
What else
have you got
on the subscribers?
Everything. They keep
immaculate records.
Bank accounts,
checking accounts,
credit cards,
e-mail address,
home address.
AIready found 60
in Manhattan,
Detective.
You guys
are going
to be busy.
How hard would it be to
Iook up one of these guy's
e-mail addresses?
Just a simple word search.
Nick2Shy, Wiremail account.
Name's Nicholas Taylor.
No address Iisted.
However, I've got
a MasterCard
and Visa account.
Bills got to go somewhere.
Print that out.
Are you Amy?
Hi, I'm EIIiot.
I'm a policeman.
Is your dad home?
He's upstairs, sleeping.
Where's your
policeman clothes?
Well, I'II tell you what,
will my policeman's badge do?
Why don't you take it
while I talk to your dad?
PIease, sweetheart.
You can hang out here
with my good friend, Sam.
He's a cop, too.
What do you say?
Will you do
that for me?
Can I get a
glass of water?
Which way's
the kitchen?
Go ahead.
(GUN FIRING)
You're under arrest.
Get dressed.
Where's my daughter?
Where's Amy?
Where's your daughter?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Like you give a damn.
Now, get dressed.
Your prints were
at the scene of
Meredith McGrath's murder.
And your prints were
at the scene of
Roger McGrath's murder.
Okay. Let's get
Cabot down here.
We're ready to deal.
You think you can get a deal
out of her on two murders
and prolonged child abuse?
Good Iuck.
It's not going to make
a difference once
the Feds get you, anyway.
I don't abuse my daughter.
STABLER: Yeah, you do.
Since before she
was able to walk.
TAYLOR: So you say.
So your website
says, genius.
That's why you killed
the McGraths, isn't it?
She knew what you
were doing. You had
to protect your secret.
She misrepresented herself.
Yeah. Pretending to be
as disgusting as you.
She betrayed me.
You betrayed
your daughter.
I did not.
I Iove Amy more than
you'II ever realize.
And I'm not going to feel
bad just because you're
telling me I should.
That's enough.
This interview is over.
Detectives...
TAYLOR: Society
says I'm wrong.
But not Iong ago,
society said interracial
marriage was wrong, too.
Not Iong ago,
society executed
homosexuals.
Did you hear that?
Now, that is a classic.
It's the pedophile's
justification for why he's
not the pervert we know he is.
I used to think
I was alone. I'm not.
There are hundreds
of thousands of people
just Iike me.
Maybe millions.
You mean your
buddies on
the Internet?
You're right.
And you freaks
will never be alone
in prison.
Ever think that maybe
you're the minority?
Ever think that
maybe you're the freaks?
Go ahead,
arrest us,
persecute us.
We're not going away.
We're not going to
play by your rules
and nothing you can do
will ever change that.
Another round.
I'm buying.
No, I've got
to get home.
I've got to make
sure my kids remember
what I Iook Iike.
Yeah? How many you got?
Four.
(WHISTLES)
They why you do
this job?
They're part of it.
I guess I can see
what you get out of it.
AII those guys you put away,
who knows how many more kids
they would've hurt.
Tough gig, though, huh?
Really got to Iove it.
No. You've got
to hate it.
It's the only way
you'II be any
good at it.