NARRATOR: In the criminal
justice system,
sexually based offenses
are considered
especially heinous.
In New York City,
the dedicated detectives
who investigate
these vicious felonies
are members of
an elite squad known
as the Special Victims Unit.
These are their stories.
Love is all
very nice, darling,
but what does he really want?
Your pecan pies
or your nice,
fat bank balance?
What on earth?
Not you, dear.
I think there's a dead
animal in my wisteria.
Now, if AIbert
is only after sex,
you have my blessing.
I mean, you're pushing 70.
How many more rides are Ieft
on the merry-go-round?
(SCREAMING)
Home owner's name
is Katerina BIundell.
Victim dropped in
on her unexpectedly.
She's in her 20s.
Wearing a maid's uniform.
No ID.
Miss BIundell
have a housekeeper?
No. Lives alone.
She recognize the victim
from the neighborhood?
I doubt it.
The victim has no face.
From the Iividity,
she's been dead a while.
Why'd you call us?
WARNER: Looks Iike a suicide,
but somebody worked
her over pretty good.
There's bruising
on her breasts,
buttocks, thighs.
Maybe a rape
and toss?
Some of these
are old.
This stuff didn't
just happen once.
BENSON: Looks Iike
she fell from there.
STABLER: Trellacker Tower.
Millionaire heaven.
So she Iands head first,
breaks the glass,
falls onto the plants
which hold her for a while
until Katerina
goes poking around.
She's a maid.
Probably doesn't
speak much English.
AIone in a foreign country.
If she was raped,
it's not surprising
she didn't call the cops.
So she takes the high dive.
Or she was pushed.
STABLER: Mr. Paysen?
Yeah.
SVU. Detective Stabler.
My partner, Detective Benson.
Now, the doorman says
that you run security
for the Lamerly family.
Yeah. SVU?
What's this about?
We've got a jumper.
Looks Iike she fell
from the penthouse.
Did you check all
the other apartments?
Well, the doorman says that
the windows don't open wide
enough to Iet a child out.
Well, why is sex crimes
interested in a suicide?
We believe that
she was assaulted
before she fell.
You did some
time on the job?
Put in my 20 at the 29.
When'd this happen?
Sometime over
the weekend.
No one's been in
the penthouse from
Friday morning
till Sunday night when
Mrs. Lamerly came home.
From where?
Connecticut.
The rest of the family's
still up there.
I drove Mrs. L. back early
to take in a concert.
There's no sign
of a break-in.
Even so, we'd Iike
to take a Iook around.
Like I said, nobody's been
here since Friday morning.
Well, we could come back
with a warrant and a couple
of TV crews if you'd Iike.
Just Iet me
warn the old Iady.
Thank you.
You think she fell
from our balcony?
BENSON: It seems Iikely.
Oh, the poor soul.
Do you know who she is?
We're working on that.
She was wearing
a housekeeper's uniform.
Gray dress,
white apron.
But all our help
had the weekend off.
STABLER: We'II need
names and addresses.
Of course.
Tom will get
them for you.
BENSON: There's our
crime scene.
There's no sign of
a struggle here or inside.
I still don't
understand how she
could've got out here.
We're going to need to take
a Iook at the building
security camera tapes.
Ma'am, please don't
touch the railing.
I'm sorry. Is this
where she fell?
Looks Iike it.
We're going to have to have
a Crime Scene Unit come up
here and check things out.
Of course.
Lamerly money comes
from Iate Grandpa's
real estate business.
He had the cash,
Grandma had the class.
Son Douglas runs
everything now.
Wife Iives in Bermuda
and rarely comes ashore.
Kids?
Yeah, one son, Drew,
just back from Europe.
And what about Granny?
She hosts tea parties
and presides over
a dozen charitable events.
Their story hold up?
Doorman said that
the penthouse had
no visitors over the weekend,
but he can't see who comes
in through the garage.
FIN: This is off
the penthouse Iobby camera.
4:45 p.m. Saturday.
She's got her own key.
Any pictures of her face?
Now, that would be too easy.
And that's it.
She's the only one who
went into the penthouse
till Gran and the chauffeur
come home Sunday evening.
Any reports of
missing servants?
AII present and
accounted for.
So who is this woman?
I'm running prints,
dental, DNA.
There's too much bone damage
to try facial reconstruction.
Tested her for
drugs and alcohol.
She's clean.
Did you get anything
from the rape kit?
No fluids.
But traces of
Iubricant and spermicide.
Her attacker used a condom.
Can you connect the assault
to the time of death?
Most of the bruises
and strap marks are old,
but there are petechiae here.
Broken capillaries
that didn't have
time to form bruises.
So she was raped, beaten,
and went up to
the penthouse to die?
Or she Iikes rough sex.
None of this proves
she was raped.
Hands around
the throat could be
erotic asphyxiation.
The strap marks could be
the badge of an S&M junkie.
Possible. The degree
of violence is pretty
controlled.
Another thing,
CSU only found one shoe.
They're still Iooking
for the second one.
Pretty high-end for a maid.
Nice stockings, too.
Okay, she's wearing
high heels, fancy underwear,
dresses Iike a maid,
and Iets herself into
a rich man's apartment?
Sounds Iike an out-call
fantasy to me.
My God.
I think it's Anna.
I can't believe
she'd do this.
Who's Anna,
Mr. Lamerly?
Anna Rivera.
She worked
a month for us,
and then we Iearned
that she Iied about
her Iegal status.
Last week we
had to Iet her go.
Do you always check
the immigration
status of your staff?
We Iead public Iives,
Detective.
We have to be able
to withstand scrutiny.
Do you have any idea
why Anna would kill herself?
She was very upset
about Iosing the job.
She begged us
not to fire her.
But I honestly never
thought she'd do this.
The severance
was very generous.
Three months' salary.
That'II put a dent
in the bank account.
Did Anna usually wear
shoes Iike this to work?
I have no idea.
I don't inspect
the staff's shoes.
She was wearing
stiletto heels
and expensive underwear.
I don't think she came up
to polish the credenza.
What are you trying
to say, Detective?
Whoever abused Anna
made a habit of it.
Her body showed signs
of repeated, violent sex.
Well, what has that
got to do with me?
Anna came to this
apartment to die,
Mr. Lamerly.
Why do you think
she did that?
You can't honestly
think I have anything
to do with this.
How well did
your son know her?
Where was he
Saturday night?
In Connecticut.
We all were.
You barge in here,
no warrant, no nothing,
making wild accusations...
Douglas, please.
Don't shout.
Police have to
do their job.
BENSON: Do you know
where Anna used to Iive?
My son will get
you the address.
LAYTON: Detectives?
Something you should see.
BENSON: Prints.
Took the same prints
on the balcony door.
Was she alone?
Far as I can tell.
There's only the one set.
What about inside?
Nothing. PIace is immaculate.
But, hey, Granny Iooks
Iike a clean freak.
So our victim gets attacked
someplace else but comes here
to kill herself?
She came straight out here,
she climbs over the edge,
she holds onto the railing.
Smearing suggests
she didn't Iet go
right away.
She changed her mind.
She tried to pull herself up.
STABLER: Wasn't strong enough.
Anna's address.
BENSON: Mr. Karenn,
when was the Iast
time you saw Anna?
When she paid her rent.
Tuesday.
Did she pay you
for the whole month?
Wouldn't be
Iiving here
otherwise.
She ever bring
boyfriends here?
No. Is she in trouble?
That's what we're
trying to find out.
This her?
Yeah.
You got any
numbers or addresses
for her family?
Said she was from
Guatemala. Try there.
Can't find a note.
What was Anna Iike,
Mr. Karenn?
Quiet, clean.
She paid her rent.
Perfect.
Then I guess
you'd be real upset
to find out she's dead.
Oh, jeez.
What am I going to
do with her stuff?
Why don't you
send it to Guatemala?
We'II take these for the M.E.
so she can make a positive ID.
Can't get anything
off of these for DNA.
They're brand new.
Oh, well, that figures.
AII right, I'II have CSU
comb the place.
Take a Iook
at this first.
Lots of fine cuts,
some healed, some new.
BENSON: From cleaning
a penthouse?
I swabbed her hands.
Didn't find any
household cleaners
that a maid would use.
Only an acetone
called Rexton,
exclusively used
in cleaning
motion picture film.
Early 20s,
handles Iots of film.
Could be a
film student.
The Lamerlys were
definitely in Connecticut.
Had some Iocal muckety-mucks
over for dinner.
Son Drew even got his picture
taken up there running a red
Iight in his Iittle Audi.
6:10 p.m.
Anything on
the film schools?
Thanks.
Any idea how many
film schools there
are in New York?
PIus a student failing
to show up for class
on Monday morning
is not exactly going
to set off alarms.
Any chance Anna
was taking classes?
Well, not unless she
went by the name of
Carmen Trancoso.
Carmen was supposed
to screen her first-year
film at the New School.
She didn't show. The girl she
made it with said she hasn't
seen her since Saturday.
Suzie, you knew her
well. Has Carmen been
upset Iately?
Why? Tell me
what's going on.
We're worried
about her.
Does she Ieave her
personal stuff here?
This is hers.
And this stuff.
Yeah? Where's Carmen from?
Sao Paulo, Brazil.
Well, she have a hard
time adjusting here?
She does okay
considering her
English isn't too good.
Is this Carmen?
She's a beautiful girl.
Does she have
a boyfriend?
Used to. They broke up.
Carmen was pretty upset.
BENSON: She talk
to you about it?
Not really.
Well, what'd
she say about it?
That she was going
to make him pay.
Well, do you think Carmen
was upset enough to try
to hurt herself?
What do you mean?
Is that what's happened?
We don't know,
but we have to Iook at
all the possibilities.
What's her
boyfriend's name?
Drew. Drew Lamerly.
M.E. confirms.
The DNA off
the Iipstick proves
that the dead girl
is Drew Lamerly's ex,
Carmen Trancoso.
So he dumps her, she goes
to his apartment for an
attention-seeking suicide?
Dresses as the maid
to get by the doorman.
She uses a key that
either Drew gave her
or she stole it.
What about Anna Rivera?
Vanished.
Customs has no record
of her on any flights
out of New York.
And if she's going to go home,
why not take all of her stuff
with her?
Look who's here.
Poster boy.
Hi. Can we help you?
My name is Drew Lamerly.
Suzie called me.
I think I should
make a statement.
About what?
Carmen Trancoso.
It's my fault
she's dead.
Carmen and I went
out for about a month.
It was intense.
So intense it scared me.
I broke up with her.
When'd you break up?
About ten days ago.
She took it bad.
She kept coming
to the apartment,
following me around.
When was the Iast time
you talked to her, Drew?
Saturday. She called me,
begged me to see her.
I said I was with
my family in the country.
She became hysterical.
Said she'd make me sorry
if I didn't come over.
So I told her to get
a Iife and I hung up.
If I'd just gone there,
been kind to her,
she might still be alive.
What time did
she call you?
Around 5:30, I think.
So Anna Rivera
isn't dead then.
No, she's not.
One of the other
maids just heard from her.
Turns out she's in Miami.
Why'd she run and Ieave
everything behind?
Well, she didn't.
Her aunt was really sick
and she had to go see her.
Aunt is sick.
I'm missing something here.
Drew, why did your dad say
the dead girl was Anna?
He got all teary-eyed
and everything.
Well, the girl in the tape
Iooks just Iike Anna.
She's wearing
a maid's uniform.
Well, so was Carmen.
Why is that?
She knew she couldn't
get into the building
any other way.
I'd told the doorman
not to Iet her in.
Carmen got by him dressed
as a maid. She get a copy
of your key?
Yes, which she must have
taken from me while I was
sleeping and duped it.
You guys spent
the night together
a Iot, right?
Well, I told you,
it was a very
intense relationship.
You call beating
the crap out of
her intense, huh?
You Iittle prick,
you did this to her.
Yes, I did do this,
but she wanted me to.
No. No woman wants this.
Carmen did!
This was her thing.
So you beat and rape her
because it was her thing?
I never raped her.
She Iiked it.
It was never enough, though.
She wanted more.
She wanted more of what?
She... She wanted me to...
She wanted me to choke her
until she blacked out.
But I couldn't do that.
I couldn't.
That's when I knew
it was too much.
I couldn't do it.
I'm sorry, okay?
(SIGHS)
I'm sorry.
Drew's story checked out.
We got a 10-minute call
from the penthouse
to Connecticut.
5:32 p.m. Saturday.
What about the bruising?
M.E. said the violence
was controlled. So it
could have been consensual.
What's your take
on this kid?
He's got answers
for everything.
Fin, you and Munch see
if Drew's got history.
But do it quietly.
I don't want the Lamerlys
complaining to the brass
that we're harassing them.
You know,
this is Carmen's
date book.
She met with
this Roger Burnbaum
three times Iast week.
There's a number here.
Another boyfriend?
Maybe it was Drew
who didn't end it.
Maybe Carmen dumped him
for this Roger Burnbaum.
Guess who I'm holding for.
Roger Burnbaum and DeLisle,
personal injury Iawyers.
She was suing someone.
We represent Carmen Trancoso,
but I can't say why
without her permission.
She can't give it.
She's dead.
What happened?
She committed suicide.
So I hope
you're paid up.
We take cases on
a contingency basis.
No win, no fee.
That's noble of you.
What was Carmen
hoping to win?
A substantial settlement
from her ex-boyfriend
for rape.
Her ex-boyfriend
being Drew Lamerly.
How do you know?
She said she
hadn't told anybody.
Carmen died by
throwing herself 20 floors
from the Lamerly penthouse.
STABLER: She have
a good case against him?
To be honest, no.
She told me her sex Iife
with Mr. Lamerly had gotten
increasingly violent.
She tried to break up,
he pursued her.
When she resisted,
he raped and beat her.
And how is that
not a good case?
She refused to report
the rape to the police.
Afraid it might
affect her student visa.
BENSON: Did you believe her?
I believe
he hurt her very badly,
but I wasn't
sure he raped her.
But you took the case anyway.
Yes. I thought they'd settle.
If you were the Lamerlys,
would you want this
sort of publicity?
LAMERLY: Detectives,
our attorney, Lorna Scarry.
Funny, we just came from
Carmen Trancoso's attorney.
How is Mr. DeLisle?
Hit by any ambulances Iately?
He's sad that he won't
be trying his case.
Oh, pity.
Just when he thought
the gravy train had
stopped at his station.
You see a raped woman
as a gravy train?
I swear to you
I never raped her.
Drew.
Believe me, officers,
I am sorry for the girl's
death,
but she was unbalanced.
She tried emotional blackmail,
she tried the Iaw,
and when she realized that
we weren't going to cave in to
her outrageous claims,
she killed herself.
Well, the marks on
Carmen's body support
those outrageous claims.
I told you,
that's what she wanted.
Well, that's easy to say,
given she's not here
to defend herself.
Can you prove it?
It's not our job to prove.
But we can.
Affidavits from
three of Carmen's
former boyfriends,
two of whom
she picked up in bars.
They testified that
she was an animal.
The rougher the sex,
the better.
So our victim is now a
gold-digging whore and we are
totally being jerked around.
Every time we come
up with something,
the Lamerlys are ready
and waiting with some
plausible explanation.
What've you got?
Facts and figures
on Drew Lamerly.
Your typical red-blooded,
all-American boy with an
eight-figure trust fund.
Wrapped a few sports cars
around Iampposts,
a few parking tickets,
but no record,
no ex-girlfriends
crying rape.
He's popular.
PIayed hockey and tennis.
Good enough for any
college varsity team.
Except he didn't graduate
high school. He spent three
years at college in Paris.
Well, you know what I think?
I think we've got nothing
we can prove
and too many cases with real,
Iive victims to waste time
chasing shadows.
Now, see if there's a reason
Drew didn't graduate.
If there isn't, case closed.
(SCHOOL BELL RINGING)
I'm afraid the Radleigh School
didn't quite meet
Drew Lamerly's needs.
Can you translate
that for me?
We expelled him. Pity.
He was a good student.
What did he do?
Disrupted our senior prom.
He brought a very attractive
older woman as his date.
I suspect it was to show off,
but she seemed out of her
element.
Kind of girl you
don't bring home
to Mom and Dad.
Precisely.
Well, it still doesn't
explain why you kicked
him out.
To cut a sordid story short,
they both got drunk,
there was an altercation.
The woman called the police
and accused Drew
of assaulting her.
Did he?
The police didn't
seem to think so.
And neither,
in the cold Iight of day,
did the young woman.
She dropped the charges.
However, school policy
is very clear on
these matters.
No alcohol.
He had to go.
Do you remember
the young woman's name?
It was five years ago.
Radleigh High prom
gives us a date,
May 16th, '97.
We're at the 29 now. Yeah.
AII right,
we'II be in touch,
Captain.
Anything?
There's no 61.
You mean no one
filed a complaint?
Oh, they filed a complaint,
but the 61's disappeared.
Looks Iike the Lamerlys
are sweeping up after
Drew again.
This time they
missed some dirt.
One of the cops
filled out an "Aided" card.
They're not kept
in the same place
as the 61s.
Nope. Card gives the
assault victim's name
as a Miss Jenny White, 24.
She refused medical
assistance, but she
did give us an address.
I'm Camilla Hartnell.
Can I help you?
Yeah. Detective Benson,
this is Detective Stabler,
SVU.
We'd Iike to speak
to a Miss Jenny White.
Jenny gave this address
in a complaint that
she made to the police.
When?
About five years ago.
She was assaulted
at a high school prom.
It's taken you
this Iong to respond?
Well, we have some
new information.
I'm sorry, I... I've Iived
here for 20 years and I don't
know a Jenny White.
You know him?
No.
Oh, Frank, hi!
See you tonight
at around 6:00. Bye.
Is there anything
else I can do for you?
No. Thank you so much.
BENSON: It's a dead end.
Maybe.
I think we need
to talk to the cops
who took the statement.
STABLER: Wait, check this out.
Want to go get
a cup of coffee?
Come on, come on.
Yeah, okay.
I think one of
Mrs. Hartnell's girls just
decided not to come home.
PIace is a brothel.
(KNOCKING)
Oh, you're still here.
Yeah, and we're going to stay
here until you start telling
us the truth.
I have told
you the truth.
Then your memory's
not serving you correctly.
Jenny White works for you,
and if you don't
tell us where she is,
we're going to have
Vice tear this place apart.
Do you really think
I'm afraid of Vice?
AII I need to do is
make one phone call...
Great. Why don't you go
ahead and do that then?
Excuse me,
but where do you
think you're going?
AII right, Iisten up.
NYPD. This is a raid.
Everyone up
against this wall.
BENSON: Let's go.
You, all of you out of here.
Stand right there.
Come on.
PIease, don't do this. Don't.
I'II tell you, I'II tell you.
Jenny White stopped working
here three years ago.
BENSON: Where is she?
Married to Angus Rochester,
one of the richest men
in Manhattan.
And I think you'II find
she's similarly disinclined
to remember the past.
Excuse me,
Jennifer White?
I'm sorry,
my name's Rochester.
Prom night,
Radleigh High School.
Remember?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Sure you do. We spoke
to your former employer,
Mrs. Hartnell.
Drew Lamerly ring a bell?
We believe he raped
another young woman
who recently killed herself.
ANGUS: Jen!
Lady, we don't care
who you were or who you are.
Just yes or no,
did Drew Lamerly
rape you?
Yes, he raped me.
But if you ask me anything
in front of my husband,
I will deny it.
Oh, who's that?
ANGUS: Hi, hon.
Hi, sweetie.
Stabler. Yeah.
So now Drew gets
away with it again.
Maybe Drew's
Iuck just ran out.
Something was bugging me
about Carmen's suicide,
the arc of the fall.
So I had the boys
set up a simulation.
Digital model of
Trellacker Tower.
The M.E. gave us
Carmen's weight,
factored in building height,
wind speed,
body's acceleration.
If Carmen just Iet go of
the railing or simply stepped
off it, this is what happens.
BENSON: She falls into
the yard next door.
Five yards short
of where she actually
Ianded.
But if she's given some
Iateral propulsion from
the railing, we get this.
Lateral propulsion.
She was pushed.
That's right.
Wait, but the prints show
that she was over the railing
clinging onto the edge.
Yeah, but if she's pushed
back against the railing,
she'd be gripping it
in exactly the same way.
So he pushes her
further and further,
she fights, she kicks him,
the shoe comes off,
but his body weight is
against her, she can't
hold anymore, she goes over.
Not suicide, murder.
So somebody pushed
Carmen off the roof.
For all the evidence
you've got, it might
as well be a ghost.
That ghost is
Drew Lamerly.
Wouldn't be the first rich kid
who thinks he's entitled
to treat women how he wants.
You only have
the two rape cases,
Jenny White and Carmen?
Well, one can't talk
and the other one won't.
We've been Iooking.
Can't find anyone else.
But who knows how many others
were bought off or intimidated
into silence?
Okay, what's your
next move?
Well, Fin's checking
on why the cops buried
Jenny White's 61
from five years ago.
CSU just found the other shoe
stuck in a tree
nearly half a block away.
They're running tests.
It's Drew, Captain,
and I'm going to put
him on that balcony.
Well, your first
problem is
to explain how he is running
a red Iight in Connecticut
at the time of Carmen's death.
What if he's not Drew?
Baseball cap is
covering half his face.
Well, it doesn't help us
if it's not a positive ID.
Isn't there some work
you could be doing, John?
I am working.
The techs checked the security
tape after Carmen entered
the penthouse.
Came up with zip.
I've been Iooking at
it before she arrived.
I think I got something.
Look at the second
hand on the clock.
It stops and then
it jumps forward.
BENSON: Ten seconds
are missing.
Somebody cut it
out of that tape.
The doorman said
that a repairman
from tower security
came by Sunday morning
to do a maintenance check.
So at 4:15,
half an hour
before Carmen arrived,
we've got someone
entering that penthouse.
He was waiting for her.
That call from the penthouse
to Connecticut at 5:30 wasn't
from Carmen,
it was from Drew,
calling home
to say what happened.
Dad jumps into Drew's car,
runs a red Iight,
it's an instant alibi.
So Drew kills Carmen
but Ieaves no trace of
himself on her or the balcony
and he's clever enough to make
sure that Carmen's prints
are Ieft on the railing?
This kid had to have help.
He did.
Guess which cop interviewed
Jenny White five years ago?
Tom Paysen,
the Lamerlys' Mr. Fix-it.
PIot's starting to unravel,
Tom. We know about Jenny,
the camera...
I don't follow you.
Drew calls Carmen,
tells her to come
over to his penthouse.
"Let's try to
work things out."
Then he tells her to dress
as a maid so the doorman
doesn't recognize her.
Yeah, and Carmen comes over,
she still Ioves Drew,
but they fight.
So he rapes her
and pushes her
off the balcony.
That's when
the cover-ups begin.
Word from the Iocal precinct
is the jumper has no face.
Cover up number one,
girl's in a maid's uniform,
why not call her Anna Rivera?
FIN: Anna gets moved out,
place gets cleaned so the DNA
doesn't mess up the story.
But the dumb old cops
figure out
it's Carmen anyway.
Cover up number two,
Carmen's a nut and a whore
who offs herself because
she Ioses her rich boyfriend.
But who could have
fixed all this?
Somebody who knows
how the police think,
how they work.
You.
I got to hand it
to you guys. SVU.
I thought you were
just the panty police,
but you're right up there.
Up where?
Dreamland.
Carmen was a mixed-up kid
who committed suicide.
Look at the evidence,
you dumb bastards.
Evidence you manufactured.
You cut 10 seconds
off that security tape.
How many more cover-ups
you think this clown's got?
I don't have to
Iisten to this.
You've been off
the job so Iong
you forgot the Iaw.
Yeah, what Iaw?
The ones you broke, hindering
a police investigation,
tampering with evidence.
Make yourself at home.
I'm sorry
to have kept you
waiting, Detectives.
I was getting changed.
My son isn't back from
the city yet and I'm afraid
I have to go out.
Yet another
charity dinner.
Mrs. Lamerly, we need
to speak with your grandson.
But that's not possible,
Drew's my escort tonight.
Detectives, what is it?
We know that you were
in the penthouse with Carmen.
So what'd you do
to her up there?
What are you
talking about?
He was with us that night.
Tell them, Drew.
Look, can we do
this somewhere else?
My grandmother's not well.
Drew, we know
about the cover-up.
Are you saying
Drew hurt that girl?
That's not possible.
He couldn't do
such a thing.
Oh, yeah?
Jenny White.
That name mean
anything to you?
(SIGHS)
I knew this would
come out eventually.
I told you,
I told your father.
He wouldn't Iisten.
You told him what?
That Drew should
take his punishment
for hurting Jenny.
So you admit
that he did it?
Well, why didn't you speak up
then instead of shipping him
off to Paris?
One's instinct is to protect
one's children, Detective.
But I insisted
Drew get help.
Six months in
a psychiatric hospital.
He was a child then.
He's grown up now.
And become a murderer.
Drew didn't do
anything to Carmen.
Test him.
You have Iie detectors,
don't you? Test him.
If he didn't kill Carmen,
who did?
Tom Paysen,
our security man.
He was obsessed with Carmen.
He wasn't here on Saturday
night.
How can I make
you believe me?
Take the polygraph test.
HUANG: How would you
describe your childhood?
Was it happy or unhappy?
Pretty happy.
Did you get along
with your parents?
It's...
Am I being tested yet?
This is
the pre-test interview.
I asked you about
your relationship
with your parents.
Well, I mean,
it's okay, I guess.
My mom is not well.
Hasn't been for a while.
Dad's working
all the time.
So I guess you could say
we're mutually indifferent.
MAN: We're set.
I'm going to
show you some cards
and I'm going
to try to guess
what each one of them is.
You must answer no
even if I guess correctly.
Is it the four of hearts?
No.
Is it the king of spades?
Is it the eight of diamonds?
No.
It is the eight, isn't it?
HUANG: The graph clearly
registers the Iie.
No way out then, huh?
Are you ready?
Is your name Drew Lamerly?
Yes.
Have you ever
stolen from a friend?
No.
Have you ever forced a woman
to have sex with you?
Yes.
Was that woman
Jenny White?
Yes.
Did you force Carmen Trancoso
to have sex with you?
No.
Did you murder
Carmen Trancoso?
No.
The polygraph says
he's being truthful.
But I think he's Iying.
What, he's using
countermeasures?
Yeah, Iike a pebble
in the shoe,
breathing control.
Anything to manipulate
his body's
physiological response.
Well, how do you know
that from the test?
I ran a Control
Questions Test
which means that I included
non-relevant questions
which could still
provoke a guilty response.
Like, "Have you ever
stolen from a friend?"
HUANG: Right.
Drew was taught
how to spot
the control questions
and how to adjust
his body's response
accordingly.
The polygraph shows a guilty
response for, "Have you ever
stolen from a friend?"
But almost no response
for the relevant question,
"Did you murder
Carmen Trancoso?"
Well, couldn't that
mean he is innocent?
It could, but I think
he fooled the machine.
He ramped up
his body's response
to the control questions
to cover up his Iies
about killing Carmen.
He wanted to take the test.
He knew he'd pass.
HUANG: Exactly.
Captain.
You get anything
out of Tom Paysen?
He denies murdering
the girl and won't
roll over on the kid.
Even though
the Lamerlys
gave him up.
He's a cop.
He knows we have
no case against him.
Even if you get him for
tampering, the most he'II
get is a couple of years.
And one hell of
a Christmas bonus.
If we can't put Drew on that
balcony with Carmen,
we got no case against him.
Thanks.
Maybe we do.
CSU found something.
There are traces of suede
in the abrasions on
the heel of Carmen's shoe.
BIue-dyed calfskin,
pretty nice material.
So it Iooks Iike something
caught in the heel,
Iike a blue suede jacket.
Is that enough
for a warrant?
How many suede jackets are
running around Manhattan?
This suede was produced
by a toxic tanning process.
For starters,
they used a hexavalent
instead of a polyvalent
chrome to clean the Ieather.
Okay, which means?
Not made in the U.S.
Probably comes from
one of your Baltic states.
If your perp has the jacket,
I can match it.
What's going on?
We have a warrant to
search Drew's room.
What on earth for?
Kid's got taste.
Detectives,
can I help you?
We're helping ourselves,
thanks.
EIIiot.
Heel made
an impression.
Drew Lamerly,
turn around. Turn around.
You're under arrest
for the murder of
Carmen Trancoso.
You have the right
to remain silent.
If you give up that right,
anything you say can and will
be used against you in a court
of Iaw.
You have the right
to an attorney...
Okay, want to deal?
Getting cold feet,
Lorna?
Hardly.
Man two. He does five years
in a psychiatric institution.
Your client inflicts
a terrifying death
on a young woman
and you want him
to get counseling?
No. Murder two.
He does 25 years.
No, thanks.
The results of
Drew's psych eval.
Here's your notice.
Not guilty by reason
of mental disease or defect.
Diminished capacity
caused by brutalization
at the hands of his father?
You've got to be joking.
See if the jury Iaughs.
Well, it's an
impressive tactic.
Brutalization is part of
criminologist Lonnie Athens'
violentization theory.
Another Iame excuse
for criminal behavior?
Not necessarily.
Athens believes that
violent environment
and example
are the cause of all
violent criminal acts.
What, no interest in genetics
or brain chemistry?
No.
Athens interviewed a hundred
convicted violent criminals
and found that they were
all abused as children.
AII saw family
members brutalized
and were all taught
to use extreme violence
in response to stressful
and threatening situations.
We found nothing
that even hints
Drew was abused.
How am I going
to fight this?
By using Drew's
own words.
Defense claims
that Drew's
father abused him.
But in his polygraph
interview with me,
Drew said that his
relationship with his father
was one of mutual
indifference.
SCARRY: Was Drew's
childhood happy?
It was comfortable,
not happy.
Why not?
He always had to succeed.
At school,
at sports,
at everything.
And if he didn't?
He was punished.
By whom?
By whom,
Mrs. Lamerly?
His father.
My son, Douglas.
Did his mother
not protect him?
Grace tried,
but she was
terrified of Douglas.
That's why
she turned to alcohol.
Several years ago
she checked herself
into a clinic in Bermuda
and Drew hasn't
seen her since.
Did Douglas
ever beat Drew?
Yes.
After a flunked
test or a Iost game.
Douglas said failure reflected
badly on the family,
made Drew Iess of a man.
Your Honor,
I am showing the witness
Defense Exhibit Three.
Mrs. Lamerly,
do you recognize
this x-ray?
Drew's broken arm.
He got in a fight
at a hockey game,
and when he came home,
Douglas threw him
down the stairs.
Because he had
been in a fight?
Because he didn't
win the fight.
What happened
the next fight
that Drew was in?
He had to be pulled
off the other boy.
He nearly killed him.
So he had Iearned
the violent Iesson
his father had taught him?
Yes.
Thank you.
Mrs. Lamerly, you don't seem
to have a problem exposing
your own son in court.
I am mortified.
Douglas is my only son.
I failed him.
Don't mock me for
trying to redeem
myself with my grandson.
You say that your son
often abused Drew,
but in his interviews
with the police,
Drew never mentioned that.
In fact, Drew said...
Your Honor, the interview
to which the A.D.A. refers
was with a psychiatrist.
It's privileged.
Mr. Lamerly volunteered to do
the interview, Your Honor.
He was talking to
an FBI psychiatrist
in a police precinct.
A psychiatrist
is a psychiatrist.
My client had
the expectation
of privacy.
I'm sorry, Miss Cabot,
the interview is out.
You say that Douglas
taught Drew violence.
Did he also
teach him to rape?
He showed him
how to abuse women.
Drew's mother
will testify to that.
Unfortunately,
she's in Bermuda.
So do you have
some other examples?
He taught him to think
that women can be bought.
So does the advertising
industry.
The fact is that
Douglas didn't teach
Drew to rape, did he?
Drew Iearned
that all on his own.
No.
From the age of 13,
Douglas took my grandson
to have sexual encounters
with prostitutes.
Buy a woman,
you can do anything
you want with her.
Mrs. Lamerly assassinates
her son and turns her
grandson into the victim.
I couldn't put
a dent in her.
Jury's buying this
brutalization crap, huh?
Well, so far
the evidence
supports it.
Drew got into fights,
he beat up Jenny White.
Maybe his dad
did brutalize him.
BENSON: You don't
believe that.
If Drew was a gang kid
with no dad and a mother
who was on crack,
we wouldn't blame them
for using an environment
defense.
I do blame
his environment.
He's a spoiled rich kid
whose family helps him get
away with rape and murder.
What can we do, AIex?
Well, the defense is going
to use violentization to say
that Drew was not
responsible for
his actions.
Carmen threatens him
and Drew's Iearned
response is violence.
So in a rush of rage,
he pushes her off the roof.
If we could prove
that there were
other cases
where Drew acted
violently without
provocation,
then we might
have a chance.
But who'II testify
against him?
Jennifer, we really
need you to testify.
No. I can't.
You're going to Iet
Drew Lamerly get away
with rape and murder.
Very much,
will you
please just go?
I understand what
you have to Iose.
We've got to stop this guy,
and we can't do it
without you.
What's going on, Jen?
I can't. It's nothing.
Misunderstanding.
Who are you?
What do you want?
Police, Special Victims.
We were hoping we could speak
to your wife about something
that happened to her.
What?
It was before
you knew her.
It's not important,
Angus.
I know about
Jenny's past.
Well, maybe you don't
know the whole story.
She's my wife. Try me.
Drew said he
needed a date.
He bought me a dress,
picked me up in his car.
For a while it was
as if I really was...
His prom date.
Yeah.
But Drew had been drinking.
He pulled me into a room,
started to have sex.
I went along with it.
After all,
that's how
I made my Iiving.
But suddenly he
slaps me and says,
"I'm not paying you
to enjoy it, bitch."
He ripped my dress.
He hit me
again and again.
And he raped me.
He treat any of the other
girls the same way?
A couple said
he'd hit them.
But he was easier
to handle then.
He was 13, 14.
When his father
first brought him?
No, that was the sickest
thing about Drew.
He came with
his grandmother.
She'd pick
his girls for him.
I told Carmen
that it was over.
She got really upset,
ran out on the balcony.
And I tried to calm her,
but she screamed at me,
hit me.
And then something
inside just snapped.
You... You saw red?
Yes.
She kept on screaming
and kicking at me
and I pushed her
against the railing
and I just pushed
her and pushed her
until she fell.
SCARRY: Drew, did you
mean to kill her?
No, God, no.
Thank you.
Remind us again, Mr. Lamerly,
how did you break your arm?
I told you, my dad did it.
CABOT: Really?
Because I have affidavits
from your former headmaster
and the teacher
who took you to the ER,
and they could swear
that you did break
your arm playing hockey.
They remember because
they were afraid your parents
were going to sue.
Your Honor, we haven't
seen any of these.
It's the People's 23,
People's 24.
Go on, Miss Cabot.
So tell us again, Mr. Lamerly,
how did you break your arm?
Your father didn't do it.
He didn't touch you, did he?
Yes. Yes, he did.
Mr. Lamerly,
do you recognize
this woman?
No, I don't.
Her name is Jennifer White
and I have a sworn
affidavit from her
as well, the People's 25,
that states that you
attacked and raped her
without provocation...
Your Honor...
...which
expressly contradicts
your violentization defense.
Your Honor!
The jury will disregard
the Iast statement.
Miss Cabot,
watch your step.
Your Honor, I'm trying
to establish that
Mr. Lamerly's entire
defense is a Iie.
Then stick to
the facts in evidence.
Do not try to
introduce new material.
You testified that
your father took you
to a brothel. Is that true?
Yes.
May I remind you
that you are under oath.
I told you, it was him.
Who took you, Mr. Lamerly?
Stop it! Enough!
That's enough!
(GROANING)
SCARRY: Your Honor,
we need a doctor!
Order! Order in the court!
How could you do
such a thing, you bitch?
It's all your fault!
You're going to pay for this!
You can trust me on that!
Get off of me! Get off of me!
Get him out of here.
Settle down!
Grandma!
Mother, it's the police.
How are you feeling,
Mrs. Lamerly?
I'II survive.
I hope so.
Long enough for you
to stand trial, anyway.
What are you
talking about?
Conspiracy, perjury, hindering
a prosecution. Do you want me
to go on?
You can't prove
a damn thing.
We can. Douglas told
us everything
and now you'II be
joining Drew in prison.
What have you done?
I Iet you turn my son
into a monster.
You are nothing.
I built this family,
I kept it strong.
You never Ioved
Drew Iike I did.
I made him a man.
You are nothing!
You never were anything!
You're nothing!