NARRATOR: In the criminal
justice system,
sexually based offenses
are considered
especially heinous.
In New York City,
the dedicated detectives
who investigate
these vicious felonies
are members
of an elite squad known
as the Special Victims Unit.
These are their stories.
(PARTY MUSIC PLAYING)
(PHONE RINGING)
What in the hell
were you thinking?
You said to invite people.
I said, "Bring a friend,"
not 25 slobs.
You're out of cold beer.
Guess you should
go home, then.
You've got a phone call.
Whoever it is, I'm busy.
It's your neighbor.
It's something about
music and the cops.
Mrs. Grenis.
I'm turning it down.
Believe me, I'd Iove
for these parasites to Ieave.
(GLASS SHATTERING)
Okay. Oh, my God.
What are you doing
to my house?
Open the door.
Open the damn door!
What the hell happened?
He tried to rape me.
Rape victim's
a Cheryl Avery, 19.
Medic's checking her
out on the bus.
She hurt bad?
Got a bloody hand
from crowning her
alleged attacker
on the head with a vase.
Where is the
alleged attacker?
Oh, he's on way to Cabrini.
His name's a Joe Cappilla.
Miss Avery claims
he tried to rape her.
Well, it sounds Iike
you think she made it up.
Well, her blouse is torn
and her face was bruised,
but she refuses to go to
the ER to get checked out.
She was violated.
Doesn't want to be poked at.
Detective Benson, SVU.
Where's your patient?
In back.
No, she's not.
She was here a minute ago.
Must've bailed.
Son of a bitch.
Looks Iike they struggled.
See these black scuff marks?
Perp was wearing sneakers,
so these probably came
from Cheryl Avery's heels.
He shoved her backwards
into the window,
the glass broke,
she grabbed the vase
and whacked him with it.
Went down and banged
his head on the tub.
FIN: Find Cheryl yet?
Nope.
And neither did the sector car
I sent to her house.
The address she gave
the uniform is phony.
I wouldn't be surprised
if her name is, too.
Well, this was a party.
Somebody had to invite her.
I invited five friends over
for pizza and beer.
That Joe and Cheryl, they
weren't even on the Iist.
BENSON: Do you know them?
No. I don't hang out
with rapists.
And the first time
I saw Cheryl was in
my bathroom bleeding.
So who invited them?
(SIGHS) Name's Ricky.
Freaking social director.
Ricky, what can you
tell us about Joe?
Met him at a club.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Thought he was cute
till he showed up high
and started hitting on
every girl in the room.
Joe hit on Cheryl?
Didn't see it,
but maybe that's why
he was fighting
with his brother.
Joe's brother was here?
Yeah.
Name's Eddie.
Cheryl's his girlfriend.
You have any idea
where Eddie Iives?
With Joe and their mom,
23rd and 9th.
Hospital.
Joe going to be okay?
No, Joe's dead.
My mom called
from the hospital
and told me everything, so...
We're so sorry
for your Ioss.
Eddie, we need to find out
what happened at that party.
My brother tried
to rape my girlfriend.
That's what the hospital
told my mom.
What did you see?
I Ieft early.
How come?
I started having
palpitations.
From fighting
with your brother?
Yeah. I got
a heart condition,
so I came home
to take my medicine.
BENSON: You didn't take
Cheryl with you?
I told her to stay.
She was dancing,
having a good time...
Bum Ieg keep you
from dancing with her?
Yeah, I sprained my ankle
playing hoops.
I know, with a heart
condition, it's stupid.
Eddie,
why were you and
your brother fighting?
He's a punk.
He treated women Iike dirt.
He ever get rough?
Yeah, when he got high,
which was all the time.
That's what we were
fighting about.
Cheryl is the nicest girl
I ever met.
She wouldn't hit Joe
unless he provoked her.
I mean, if she says it was
self-defense, then it was.
She ran away.
That Iooks real bad.
You want to help her?
Tell us where she is.
I wanted to tell Eddie
what happened,
but I didn't think
he'd understand.
BENSON: We're having
a hard time ourselves, Cheryl.
Why did you Ieave
the ambulance?
I thought you
wouldn't believe me.
It would be Joe's word
against mine.
AII we've got is your word.
Joe's dead.
Oh, my God.
I didn't...
I didn't mean to kill him.
Cheryl, tell us
what happened.
Will I go to jail?
Not if he attacked you,
it's self-defense.
Oh, God.
I...
I went to the bathroom
and Joe followed me in.
I tried to be nice to him
for Eddie's sake, but,
God, he's so disgusting.
He's constantly
putting Eddie down.
And I told him to get out,
but he wouldn't Ieave.
Did he touch you?
He put his hands on my...
On my breasts.
I tried to yell for help
but the music was too Ioud.
Then he ripped my shirt
and he punched me in the face.
And I grabbed something
and I hit him,
but he fought back.
So I pushed him off me,
and that's when he fell
and hit the tub.
So are you going to indict
Cheryl or give her a pass?
No, I'm in no hurry
to convene a grand jury.
The crime Iab confirmed
Cheryl's account,
it's justifiable homicide.
What else have we got?
Tox-screen on Joe.
Positive for crystal meth.
That explains his
pugnacious personality.
Yeah, still here.
Those bruises are real, AIex.
He definitely hit her.
Does Cheryl have any priors?
She's clean. But Joe isn't.
26 has a sexual
assault complaint
filed by a Paige Salinsky.
Was Joe arrested?
MUNCH: Miss Salinsky
dropped the charges.
So Joe has a habit
of getting high,
abusing women,
and his own brother
thinks he's a hump.
Well, don't forget
his brother just happens
to be the victim's boyfriend.
Joe's the only one
who can't speak.
Maybe his wounds still can.
If Joe did attack Cheryl,
he may have injuries
to show for it.
Check with EMS
and the medical examiner.
Yeah, I remember.
Got him stabilized
halfway to the hospital
when he seized,
went into cardiac arrest.
DOA.
Doc told us Iater that
the blows to the head caused
a subarachnoid hemorrhage.
Well, did you notice
any other injuries?
Scratches, swelling?
Three knuckles
on his right hand
were cut up.
Bruise on Cheryl's face
was on the Ieft side.
So he punches her
with his right,
he cuts his hand
on her teeth.
Hey, you remember
anything else?
Before the seizure,
the guy was rambling.
Any of it make sense?
You tell me.
"Get Eddie, get Eddie.
He did it, he did it."
Are you sure that
he said Eddie?
Anything the patient says,
I write down.
Sounds Iike Cheryl
didn't tell us everything.
VERONICA: May I help you?
BENSON: Yeah,
we're Iooking for Cheryl.
In back. She's got company.
BENSON: Looks Iike
we're interrupting.
STABLER: Guess they had to
get their stories straight.
What do you mean?
Stop screwing us around,
the both of you.
Look, I told you
what happened.
BENSON: Yeah, you Ieft out
a few details.
Like what?
That bathroom window
was broken out.
It's a fifteen foot
drop to the ground.
How'd you really
sprain your ankle?
Wait, Eddie had
nothing to do with this.
STABLER: That's not
what Joe said.
What are you talking about?
In the ambulance,
before he died.
He said, "He did it.
Get Eddie."
Joe tried to rape me.
I hit him, he fell and
he banged his head.
Cheryl, you're hindering
a murder investigation.
Now, Joe said
that Eddie did it.
And I understand
that you're trying to
protect him.
Eddie went home.
We know that.
But we have witnesses that
saw Eddie and Joe fighting,
and then Eddie Ieft.
But he came back,
didn't he?
No. No.
If Joe was attacking you
and Eddie
walked in and came
to your defense,
then Joe's death
is an accident.
You tried to stop him,
it got out of hand.
You didn't mean
to kill anybody.
That's not what happened.
Eddie, no one's
gonna put you away
for protecting
your girlfriend.
I swear I never
touched Joe.
Oh, Eddie.
Okay, Eddie. Okay,
so I've got this all wrong.
Maybe Joe didn't try
to rape Cheryl, huh?
Of course he did.
No, you know
what I'm thinking?
You caught Joe and
Cheryl getting it on
behind your back
in that bathroom.
No.
No, no.
The betrayal,
the blind rage...
Cheryl Ioves me.
BENSON: Were you
making out with Joe?
Oh, my God, I would...
No, I would never
do that to Eddie.
Of course you didn't mean to,
but Eddie Ieft you alone
at a party with Joe,
so he starts making
the moves on you,
you got caught up
in the moment.
Wait, wait. No, no, no.
So you didn't want
Eddie to know...
You're wrong...
So when he walked in,
you said that Joe
was raping you.
And he responded Iike
any good boyfriend would.
STABLER: You hit Joe.
No, I didn't.
You went back to the party
to bring Cheryl home.
Don't do this.
You find her
in the bathroom...
What?
...with your brother's
hands all over her.
Come on, Eddie, be a man.
Don't Iet your girlfriend
go down
for something
you did.
Okay!
I was in the room.
I was there.
Just tell me what happened.
He was being a prick
to some of the girls
at the party.
And I told him, "Stop."
He got pissed,
gave me a shove,
then I Ieft.
We know,
to go home and get your pills.
We've been through that!
Why are you telling me that?
I want to know,
why did you come back?
I felt bad 'cause
I Ieft Cheryl there.
Joe was already
on the floor
when I walked
into that bathroom.
Cheryl Iocked the door,
said Joe tried to rape her,
just Iike she told you.
So you didn't see anything.
That's awful convenient.
Why would you jump
out the window?
She said people
would think I did it
'cause they saw Joe
and me fighting earlier.
(GROANING)
Cheryl was only trying
to protect me.
Eddie says he was
in the bathroom,
Cheryl says he wasn't.
I can't tell who's
covering for whom.
Eddie fought with his brother
in front of a dozen witnesses.
His brother winds up dead.
What if the rape itself
is the Iie?
Do you think Cheryl made
the whole thing up?
To cover for Eddie.
He kills Joe in the bathroom,
Cheryl walks in,
tells Eddie to go
out the window,
she'II say Joe was
trying to rape her.
Well, then they're
co-conspirators. And
I can't use anything
either one of them
says against the other
without independent
corroboration.
We canvassed
everyone at the party.
Nobody saw anything.
Let's see whose story the
physical evidence supports.
We're not done with
the reconstruction yet,
but I can tell you
that everyone's prints
are in that bathroom.
Eddie admits
he was there.
There's no surprise.
This will be.
This is Joe's shirt.
The blood on it
only belongs to him.
This is Cheryl's.
Two different blood types,
both male.
One matches Joe,
the other's unknown.
So it's gotta be Eddie's.
It's not.
Y-chromosomes from the DNA
say the samples come
from two unrelated males.
So now we got another guy
in that bathroom with Joe,
Eddie and Cheryl?
That's what I thought
until I tested this.
STABLER: You get that
out of the bathroom?
No. From EMS.
Medics used it to wrap
Cheryl's bloody hand,
then we collected it
for evidence.
It's called a control sample
because the only blood on it
is Cheryl's.
Well, what's that
gonna tell us?
I compared the blood
on the bandage
to our unknown male.
It was a match.
Cheryl's a man?
What in the hell
are we dealing with?
Probably a pre-op
transsexual.
STABLER: If she's still
got her package,
it explains why she didn't
go to the hospital
to be examined.
I've seen
plenty of trannies,
but she is amazing.
She's gotta be
taking hormones.
Boys with breasts get
more money on the street.
I don't make her for a pro.
She's got a straight job.
Probably saving up enough
money for the surgery.
Well, none of this
changes the fact
that Joe still
tried to rape her.
She's got the bruises
to show for it.
Maybe he got violent
when he discovered
her secret.
Or Joe threatened
to tell Eddie,
giving Cheryl motive
to kill him.
STABLER: Eddie's gotta know.
He and Cheryl have
been going out for
a couple of months now.
They were all over each other
when we picked them up.
So they're both covering up
Cheryl's secret.
Who do you think
we should try to break first?
Cheryl's pulling
all the strings,
telling Eddie what to say.
My guess is he's
the weaker Iink.
Eddie, I know you've
been through a Iot.
I don't want to
make things worse.
What do you mean?
I'm not here to judge you.
You know that, right?
I just want to find out what
happened in that bathroom.
I already told you.
I walked into the bathroom.
Joe was on the floor.
Cheryl was beat up.
You didn't tell us
about Cheryl, though.
What about her?
What you do
in your private Iife
is your business.
You gotta start
being honest with me.
I am being honest. What?
I don't understand
what you're talking about.
I'm talking about
Cheryl being a man.
(SCOFFS)
What kind of
sick joke is this?
I'm sorry you had to
find out this way.
You're crazy.
(CHUCKLES)
I have... I've seen her...
I've seen her breasts.
Female hormones.
They can do that.
Look, Eddie,
she had us all fooled.
We did a blood test.
(YELLING)
(GRUNTS) What are you
saying to me?
I held her! I kissed her.
I wanted to spend my Iife
with her. What are you...
She wouldn't have sex.
She said she wanted to wait.
She would just
push my hands away.
Oh, God. I need to see her,
I need to see her.
I want to talk to her.
Eddie.
Eddie!
Don't.
What's wrong with you?
Why are you Iooking
at me Iike that?
Say something.
Oh, oh!
You are a freak!
No!
STABLER: Eddie, get off.
Eddie. Eddie.
Okay?
Look, I was gonna tell you.
When?
After I had the surgery.
Oh, you make me sick.
Oh, God.
Why did you do this? Why?
Cheryl, stand up, come on.
It's okay. Come on, come on.
We thought that Eddie knew.
We thought that
he was protecting you.
How Iong did you think
that you could keep
this a secret?
I just thought if I could
make him Iove me enough,
he'd understand.
Okay, well, Iet's sit down.
Come on. Come on, sit down.
But you were also afraid
that he wouldn't understand.
For the first time in my Iife,
I had someone who Ioves me.
And if Joe was to tell Eddie,
that would be over.
My Iife would be over.
So what happened?
Joe was walking
out of the bathroom,
so I picked up the vase
and I hit him.
And then Eddie walked in.
I never meant to kill Joe.
I just didn't
want him to talk.
You'II have to tell Eddie
that I didn't mean to do it.
I mean, please make him
understand that.
You okay?
Oh, I'II never be okay.
This wasn't your fault.
Yeah, it was.
My brother's dead because
my girlfriend's a guy.
I should've...
No one knew.
What if I did know,
deep down?
You were in Iove with a woman.
That's what you knew.
You sure you're
okay? Huh?
Yeah.
I need some air.
Whoa!
I need some help in here!
What happened?
He just collapsed.
He's got a heart condition.
Call an ambulance.
Hardly has any pulse.
STABLER: This is empty.
Digoxin.
It's stopping his heart.
We got a drug overdose.
I'm Iosing his pulse.
You better start CPR.
Eddie!
Come on, Eddie!
He was pulseless
for ten minutes.
I pronounced him
at 1815.
You got
the pill vial?
Yeah, it's right here.
I'II do the autopsy,
I'II get you the results
quick as I can,
but doesn't Iook to me
Iike anything
other than a suicide.
It's a death in custody,
suicide or not.
You guys from
Internal Affairs
are Iike sharks smelling
blood a mile away.
Save it, Captain.
I got an investigation
to conduct.
You think we forced the pills
down his throat?
TUCKER: No, but you
Ieft a Iethal dose
of pharmaceuticals
in possession of
a distraught suspect.
Talk to me
through my delegate.
That distraught suspect
needed those pills
for a heart condition.
That still doesn't mitigate
your failure to supervise
Detective Stabler
and Agent Huang.
IAB doesn't have
jurisdiction
over Doctor Huang.
We'II refer his conduct
to the FBI's Office of
Professional Responsibility.
I hope your
med-mal insurance
is paid up, Doc.
COURT OFFICER: AII rise.
The Honorable
Judge Seligman presiding.
CLERK: Now in session.
Docket ending 5971,
"People v. Cheryl Avery.
"One count, murder
in the second degree."
Morton Berger
for the defense, Your Honor.
We all know
who you are, Mr. Berger.
How does your client plead?
Not guilty.
SELIGMAN: Ms. Cabot?
Uh... Remand.
My client is not
a threat to the community.
She has no prior
criminal record, Your Honor.
And you can't hold
a press conference
in a Iock-up.
She's out of Iine,
Your Honor.
Oh, come on, Morty.
You wouldn't have
taken this case
if you didn't smell
the publicity.
Bail is set at $200,000.
Mr. Berger, are you going with
an insanity defense?
Absolutely not.
This case is entirely about
society's prejudice...
REPORTER 1:
Ms. Cabot, Ms. Cabot,
a few questions, please.
Ms. Cabot, hold on.
The D.A.'s office
will try this case
in the courtroom,
not the press. Thank you.
REPORTER 2: Come on,
Ms. Cabot, give us a break.
REPORTER 3: Come on,
just help us out here.
Just something, huh?
Come on.
Don't want your 15
minutes of fame, AIex?
I hear you paid
Cheryl's bail.
That's a nice touch.
Can't take the full credit.
That was the generosity
of my firm.
Well, Cheryl makes
a Iovely poster child,
so I'm guessing you're
doing this pro bono.
And you work
for a pittance,
so we're even.
You're wasting your time.
The judge is never
going to suppress
Cheryl's confession.
Good.
I need it to support
my argument that she
acted in self-defense.
Joe Cappilla was
Ieaving the bathroom.
The threat had abated.
Her Iife was
no Ionger in danger.
Yeah, until Joe told
the waiting Iynch mob
she was transsexual.
Predictions of violence
are notoriously unreliable.
Nobody can say what
Joe might have done.
Come on.
We both know what people do
when they find out the truth
about the trans-gendered.
They kill them.
Now, Cheryl's not responsible
for beating Joe to death
because she's trans-gendered.
Well, that's an excuse.
It is, and it works.
You think
she's gonna walk?
I doubt it. The irony is
Berger's argument may
actually work for our case.
People are generally hostile
towards the trans-gendered.
So a jury will be, too.
Berger's gonna put witnesses
up there for Cheryl,
or whatever his name is,
to tell us all about
how he grew up
tormented, brutalized,
and treated Iike a freak.
You know, it sounds Iike you
have a problem with Cheryl.
My problem is this he-she
and her Iies are the reason
we've got two dead bodies
on our hands,
and I'm the one
who's all jammed up?
Look, I need background
on Cheryl now.
AII we know so far is that
she changed her name when
she was 18 years old.
She used to be called
Charles Avery.
Her parents still Iive
in AIphabet City.
Then why don't you
go talk to them?
Maybe they can undercut
Cheryl's abuse story.
I don't know, AIex.
I talked to her.
And unless she's
a damned good actor,
she is completely
in Iove with Eddie
and was afraid
of Iosing him.
So she kills
Eddie's brother?
True Iove doesn't
mitigate murder.
I don't think
she's a violent person.
That's fine. Prove it.
Charlie was 16
when he started
growing breasts.
Stole the hormones his mother
was taking for menopause.
We couldn't take it anymore.
Is that when she Ieft?
JOHN: We threw him out.
You think we're cruel,
Detective,
but we'd already
Iost our son.
There was nothing else
we could do.
What about therapy?
Charlie refused to go.
He insisted that inside
he felt Iike a woman,
and nothing was
gonna change that.
God doesn't make mistakes.
We've got two younger sons
and a daughter.
Now, how could we explain
Charlie waxing his Iegs
and wearing makeup?
Mom?
Sarah, honey,
go to the kitchen.
We'II be done soon.
Okay.
How did Cheryl get along
with her siblings?
They stopped hanging
around with him
because they were getting
teased at school.
Well, how did Cheryl
do in school? Did she
ever have any fights...
Charlie!
His name is Charlie.
Was he ever violent,
Mr. Avery?
He beat a kid
with a baseball bat.
Put him in the hospital.
That violent enough?
Detective?
Sarah, right?
My parents are wrong.
You still talk to Cheryl?
Yes, but if my parents knew,
they'd kick me out, too.
Your parents said that
Cheryl once beat somebody
with a baseball bat.
She cut through the field
one day after school.
The baseball team
saw her and chased her.
She had to grab a bat
to defend herself.
This kind of thing
happen a Iot?
AII the time, I mean,
kids made fun of her
Iike she was a big joke.
Anybody ever hurt
her physically?
They beat
the hell out of her
whenever they could.
I mean, she had to
go to the hospital
three times for stitches.
I don't care
what anybody says,
she's the bravest
person I know.
I talked to her teachers.
A sympathetic one
suggested that she
transfer to Harvey Milk,
an alternative
public school
for gay and
trans-gendered kids.
So why didn't she go?
Because her parents
wouldn't Iet her.
Where are you
going with this?
AII I need to know
is whether or not
Cheryl's been violent.
Only in self-defense.
One time, two boys
held her up against
a wall and pulled
her pants down.
AIex, this girl has
been through hell.
I know she's been a victim
and I know she's suffered.
But that doesn't give Cheryl
the right to kill Joe Cappilla
for threatening
to expose her.
Then at Ieast
offer her a plea.
Not until I know her intent.
If Berger will agree
to a psych evaluation,
I'II have Huang
talk to Cheryl.
Yeah, when I was seven,
I knew I was different.
I mean,
every night I'd go to bed
dreaming about being a girl.
Well, how did
you handle that?
Forced myself to be a boy.
That must have been difficult.
Yeah, I played with GI Joes
when I wanted to
dress up Barbies.
When was the first time that
you tried to become a woman?
Can you remember?
Yeah, I was ten.
And my father caught me
putting on my mother's makeup.
And what did he do?
Well, he beat
the crap out of me and
he called me a pervert.
Did that change
your feelings any?
No.
It's not something
you can change.
I mean, it's... It's me.
It's how I feel.
And I can't be anything else,
but I wanted to be
a whole woman.
Sure.
And I needed the surgery.
Especially after I met Eddie.
Eddie.
Had you ever considered
telling him?
No, no.
I figured I'd Iose him.
I mean, Eddie was
the best thing that
ever happened to me.
I mean, he was the first man
that Ioved me as a woman.
And I figured
if I had the surgery,
I wouldn't have to tell him.
But Joe was gonna
tell him, right?
How did that make you feel?
I saw fists punching me
Iike all those times before.
Any time Cheryl's
been violent,
it's been in response
to a perceived threat.
Joe had stopped the attack
and was Ieaving the bathroom.
The threat was over.
Not in her mind.
She feared what those
drunken party-goers
would do to her when
she Ieft that bathroom.
Boy, you'd make a great
witness for the defense.
I'm just calling it
Iike I see it, AIex.
I don't think she
intended to kill Joe.
AII right.
If you're convinced,
I'II drop it to man one.
I told Cheryl
about your offer,
but she wants
to go to trial.
She does, or you do?
Do you know why
I became a Iawyer, AIex?
To see your face on TV?
To change society's
misconceptions
about what's normal.
I'm here for the underdog.
You're here for yourself.
No, I'm here for a cause.
Gender is not always binary.
People are afraid
of what they don't know.
Cheryl's case can change that.
Are you so sure of this
that you're willing to
serve up your client
as the sacrificial Iamb?
She could spend the rest
of her Iife in prison.
Not after this is tried in
the court of public opinion.
Joe Cappilla sexually
assaulted Cheryl Avery
and threatened to out her.
She fought back
to save her Iife.
She's not going to prison.
Hello.
Thanks for meeting me.
Well, I shouldn't be
speaking to you
without my attorney.
I shouldn't be
asking you to,
but I'm very concerned
about how Mr. Berger
is handling your case.
You're the one prosecuting me.
Why would you care?
Because I think you're
getting bad advice.
No, he's...
No, he's the only one
who's been on my side.
He knows what
I've been through.
Then he should be
the first one
to tell you that your chances
of acquittal are slim to none.
I was attacked
and almost raped, okay?
He says a jury
will take my side.
I think a jury is going
to have some trouble
separating the facts of
the case from who you are.
Well, if you're so sure
I'm going to Iose,
then why are you here?
Because I want to know
why you won't take the deal.
What deal?
I told Berger
I would plead down to
first-degree manslaughter.
He never told me.
You had no right to speak
to my client without me.
I'm taking this
to Judge Larsen
and the disciplinary
committee.
Go ahead.
They'II Iove the part
where you ignored
your obligation
to bring my deal
to your client
and then Iied to me
and told me you had.
I've done hundreds of trials
and made new case Iaw.
I think I know what's
best for my client.
Doesn't Cheryl have
a right to decide?
Fine.
Cheryl, I have your
best interests at heart.
Go ahead, take the deal
and you'II go to prison
for at Ieast five years.
And if you don't take the deal
and you get convicted,
you'II go for a minimum
of 15-to-Iife.
Well, do you think
we'II Iose?
You're not guilty, Cheryl.
Answer her question.
Look, she's trying
to scare you.
Yeah, there's a chance
you'II Iose,
but think of everything
you're going to gain.
He's trying to make you
a martyr for the cause.
I'II take the deal.
You're making
a big mistake.
STABLER: How'd it go in court?
Cheryl pled out.
You know that the only person
that came to support her
was her sister.
And you.
Yeah, but I'm not family.
Excuse me. Detective Benson.
Mr. Berger,
how can I help you?
Cheryl wants to talk
to you about her plea.
She needs to speak
to the A.D.A. about that.
My client's not a big fan
of Ms. Cabot.
Why not?
Well, Cheryl feels she was
tricked into pleading out.
Well, why does she
want to talk to me?
She thinks you'II
understand the situation.
What situation?
Her accommodations.
Look, you have to help me,
I cannot stay here.
Cheryl, you pled guilty.
You knew that you
were going to prison.
I'm a woman,
and they put me
in a cell with men.
You didn't tell her?
I told her to go to trial.
Bull!
You set her up
for your own career.
What, the murder case
wasn't enough for you?
The civil rights issue
is more pressing.
Oh, and you're
going to ride it
all the way to the
Supreme Court, aren't you?
Why not? This could be
a precedent-setting case.
Yeah, not to mention
a juicy story.
A woman in a man's prison?
You'II have the media
drooling!
I'm sorry.
Just help me.
My hands are tied.
I can't move Cheryl
to a women's prison.
She was going
to have surgery.
Unfortunately, she's still
anatomically male.
New York State
determines a person's
gender based
on their genitals,
not their feelings.
So you're not going
to do anything?
There's nothing I can do.
The Iaw says she's not
entitled to special treatment,
and I can't put a man
in a women's prison.
But Cheryl is not
a man anymore.
Legally, she still is.
Look, Berger has to
fight it out with the
Department of Corrections
and I have to
make an appearance.
I will see what I can do.
BERGER: Cheryl Avery
is a woman.
The State of New York
doesn't see it that way.
The medical community
would side with the defendant
in the matter of her gender.
This hearing is not about
the politics of gender.
It's about where to house him.
It's extremely derogatory
to refer to my client
using male pronouns.
You have my sincere apology,
but biologically,
your client is a man.
My client will be
singled out for abuse
in a male facility.
Not if she stops
taking hormones.
Federal prison guidelines
state the pre-established
hormone Ievels
of transsexuals
must be maintained.
When prescribed
by a physician.
Your client was
self-medicating
with a friend's
birth control pills.
Look, I'd rather die
than stop hormone therapy.
What about protective custody?
Twenty-three hours a day
without human contact.
That's cruel and unusual.
I'm generously giving
your client the choice.
Either stop the hormones
or go into protective custody.
There's nothing else
you can do?
The defendant has not yet
been sentenced, Your Honor.
AII right.
Then ask Judge Larsen
to vacate the guilty plea.
Take this to trial.
Hope for an acquittal.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
What's this I hear about you
wanting off the Avery case?
I just don't think
I'm the right person
to try it.
That's not what I heard.
You've made
several impassioned
arguments on her behalf.
Perhaps you'd Iike to
defend her instead.
Well, she could use
better representation
than that self-serving
snake Berger.
Reptile though he may be,
Morty Berger's
a damn good attorney.
He deserves
a worthy adversary.
I think I'm more
sympathetic to Cheryl
than a prosecutor should be.
A good A.D.A. has to think
on both sides of the fence.
Your empathy is a strength,
not a weakness.
You know, if Cheryl
had been born a woman,
a jury would have
no problem acquitting her.
She killed a man.
What do you care
what sex she is?
Because that,
and not the evidence,
is what's going
to convict her.
No, what's going
to convict her
is a jury of her peers,
not angels or
divine ethical beings.
I suppose it bothers me
more than it should.
Well, I'II reassign the case
if you Iike.
But you might
want to consider,
who's gonna give Cheryl Avery
the fairest treatment?
You or some other
prosecutor who'II put
her gender on trial?
PSYCHIATRIST:
Gender identity dysphoria
occurs when a woman feels
trapped in a man's body.
These feelings are centered
in the hypothalamus gland
in the brain.
Specifically,
the stria terminalis.
PIease describe
the exhibits, Doctor.
The first photo is
the stria terminalis
of a male brain.
The second is that
of a female.
The stria terminalis
of the male brain is much
Iarger than the female's.
BERGER: The third appears
to be the same size as
the female stria terminalis.
It is, but it's actually
the stria terminalis
of a biological male
who is transsexual.
Are you saying, Doctor,
that despite being
born with male genitals,
a portion of this man's brain
is identical to a woman's?
Yes.
And in your expert opinion,
explain what this means
in Cheryl's case.
Cheryl feels Iike a woman
because her brain is
physiologically female.
Thank you, Doctor.
Referring to the defense's
Exhibit Three,
the stria terminalis
of a male-to-female
transsexual.
Is that a picture of
the defendant's brain?
PSYCHIATRIST: No.
These are photographs
of cadaver brains.
Why didn't you photograph
Cheryl Avery's brain?
The stria terminalis is only
accessible post mortem.
So as far as you know
Cheryl's stria terminalis
is the size of a man's
and she's not a transsexual.
Object, Your Honor.
LARSEN: Overruled.
Answer the question, Doctor.
I can't respond with
certainty either way.
Nothing further.
Let's talk about
the first time
you were assaulted
for dressing as a woman.
How old were you?
Twelve.
And what happened?
I was in
my room wearing
my mom's bra and skirt
when my brother's
friend walked in.
What did he do?
He Iaughed.
And he said he would
tell everyone.
Did he?
Yeah.
In fact,
the next day at school
three boys came
in the bathroom
and they hit me
and they kicked me,
and spit on me.
How many times
have you been assaulted?
I've had my nose broken
and my shoulder dislocated
and once someone
set fire to my hair.
Cheryl, how have these
repeated attacks affected you?
I was scared to
Ieave the house.
But I had no choice when
my parents kicked me out.
And every time someone
Iooked at me, I wondered,
"Are they going to hurt me?
Are they going to...
"Is this going to be the time
that someone kills me?"
When Joe Cappilla
assaulted you,
this is what
you were feeling?
Yes.
Your witness, Ms. Cabot.
So you thought your Iife
was in danger that night?
Yes.
Did anybody at the party
threaten you?
No, no.
Did anyone make
derogatory remarks
about transsexuals?
No, but why would they?
Nobody knew.
Had anyone at the party
ever hurt you before?
No. The only people
I knew there
were Joe and Eddie.
How Iong had you
been dating Eddie?
Two months.
Were you intimate?
Yeah.
We kissed and fooled around,
but we never had sex.
Why not?
Because I didn't want
Eddie to know
I hadn't had my surgery yet.
So you deceived him.
I had to.
What do you think
Eddie would have done
if he'd found out the truth?
I don't know.
Don't you?
You told Detective Benson
that you were afraid Eddie
was going to Ieave you.
In fact,
Eddie committed suicide
when he found out.
And I blame myself for that.
Do you blame yourself
for Joe's death?
I was protecting myself.
AII I wanted to do was
hit him over the head.
If you hadn't killed him,
he would have told everyone
your secret when he came to.
Well, I wasn't thinking
that far ahead.
Weren't you?
Joe was going to tell Eddie,
and you couldn't
take that chance.
You were finally happy.
Eddie Ioved you.
Well, Joe was gonna ruin that.
He was gonna ruin it,
and I couldn't Iet him do it.
I could not Iet him do it.
I had to stop him.
You did.
Nothing further.
Has the jury
reached the verdict?
We have, Your Honor.
LARSEN: Will the defendant
please rise?
On the sole count of murder
in the second degree,
how does the jury find?
We find the defendant
guilty.
PIease, please,
don't do this!
PIease, you can't
put me in that place!
PIease, help me, please.
Somebody! You can't
put me in that place!
Hey.
I'm heading out.
You want to grab a drink?
Thank you. But, you know,
I am just not in the mood.
Well, neither am I,
but I don't feel much
Iike going home.
Do you think I pushed
Cheryl too hard?
You did your job.
Then why do I feel so Iousy?
Because you Iook at Cheryl,
and you can't imagine
what it's Iike to feel that
your own body is a mistake.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Benson.
We'II be right there.
What's up?
I gotta go to Bellevue.
You should come with me.
Special Victims Unit,
you called about
a rape victim.
They are taking him up
to surgery now.
CABOT: What happened?
Cheryl Avery was
gang-raped at Rikers.