NARRATOR: In the criminal
justice system,
sexually based offenses
are considered
especially heinous.
In New York City,
the dedicated detectives
who investigate
these vicious felonies
are members
of an elite squad known
as the Special Victims Unit.
These are their stories.
(DANCE MUSIC PLAYING)
Can you take our order?
We've been waiting forever.
MAN: Excuse me, miss,
can we get some drinks?
I'II send your
server right over.
You said that
15 minutes ago.
I'II be right back.
Danya.
Yeah.
Where's Vanessa?
She was at the bar
with some guy.
A real hottie.
She's got six tables
waiting and she's taking
a bootie break?
Jake. Where's Vanessa?
With her boyfriend.
I thought she
kicked him
to the curb.
He didn't get
the message.
They got so Ioud,
I told them
to take it outside.
Vanessa. I need you.
(GLASS RATTLING)
Girl, what are you
doing back there?
(CAT MEOWING)
Damn cat.
You scared me
half to death.
You have blood on you.
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God! Jake! Jake!
Victim is Vanessa Bevins, 19.
Waitress here at Dominique's.
AIso has an ID from
Hudson University.
Hudson? That's...
Maureen's school.
Cause of death?
Shot once, close range,
after being raped
and sodomized.
BENSON: How did you get that?
Panty's torn.
Lumalite showed
semen on her chin.
Do we have a weapon?
Yeah, right over here.
Smith & Wesson Model 36.
Snub-nose.38,
one round fired.
Anything else?
Gun shot residue
on her hands.
Looks Iike she struggled
for the weapon,
went out fighting.
Who found her?
Another waitress,
Kimmie Robinson.
Kimmie, I'm Detective Benson,
this is my partner,
Detective Stabler.
I already told
the officers
what happened.
Okay, we'd just Iike
to ask you a few more
questions.
How Iong has Vanessa
been working here?
About a month,
part-time.
What else do you
know about her?
Not much.
She's a college girl.
She was always out there,
feeding the cats and arguing
with her boyfriend.
Like tonight.
Well, does her boyfriend
have a name?
Vanessa calls him Dee.
I don't know what
his real name is.
STABLER: What do
you know about him?
Maybe he was
her connection.
Vanessa got high?
I don't know. I never saw her
using, but one night she was
in here and she'd be flying
Iike a kite and next night,
she'd be dragging her ass
Iike a zombie.
You can't cross
the Iine, buddy.
My daughter works there.
The nightclub called me.
Get me who's in charge here.
Sir. Sir.
Who are you?
What's your name?
Ray Bevins.
I'm Vanessa's father.
Now, they said
there was an accident.
Is she okay?
Mr. Bevins, I'm sorry
to have to tell you
but your daughter...
Oh, my God.
Not my baby.
Oh, my God!
(SIREN WAILING)
(MAN CHATTERING
ON POLICE RADIO)
Mr. Bevins, you've been
up all night.
We don't have to do this
now if you don't want.
No, I want to help.
We're Iooking for
Vanessa's boyfriend.
You know him?
I didn't know
she had one.
Would her mother know
who she was dating?
No, Vanessa's mother died
when she was three.
It's just been the two
of us all these years.
How was she
doing in school?
She always used
to get straight A's
and then her grades fell
to C and D's Iast semester.
BENSON: She talk
to anyone about it?
The dean called me,
said that she was trying
to take out
a personal Ioan for $5,000.
I confronted her
about it yesterday
and she wouldn't tell me
why she needed the money.
Did your daughter
ever have a problem
with drugs?
(SIGHS HEAVILY)
She's been having
violent outbursts,
she accused me of
treating her Iike a child
when I told her to
stop working at that club.
The Iast thing
I said to her,
"Don't come to me for help,
when you ruin your Iife."
I didn't mean it.
We know that.
Look, I have three
daughters myself.
When I'm angry,
I say things
I don't mean.
You can take it back.
I can't.
Erratic behavior,
keeping secrets,
grubbing for money.
AII classic signs
of a drug problem.
If she owed five grand to her
dealer, maybe he decided to
make an example of her.
The sexual assault was
just an extra humiliation.
We finished
canvassing Dominique's.
A Iot of people
saw her boyfriend
getting Ioud with her,
but nobody knows
his full name.
Young guy, 5'10".
The only thing everyone
agrees on is he's cute.
Did you get
a timeline
together?
Vanessa put her
Iast order in at 1:15.
Bartender said that's
about the time Dee
showed up.
About 2:00 a.m.,
Kimmie finds her body.
That doesn't allow a Iot
of time for another player
to walk onto the set.
So, the boyfriend's
Iooking good for this?
Well, then Iet's
find out who he is.
Munch, Fin,
see if Ballistics got
any prints off that gun.
EIIiot, you and OIivia
follow up with Vanessa's
roommate.
Maybe Dee is supplying
more than romance.
His real name
is Donovan AIvarez.
STABLER: He go to school here?
Yeah, he's Pre-Law Iike me,
but Vanessa dumped
him Iast semester.
Why?
I don't know.
Donovan's a great catch.
AII the girls were after him.
After him
or his drugs?
Drugs? Donovan's
a total straight-arrow,
Iike Vanessa used to be.
So what changed?
She started blowing
off class, acting wild,
short skirts,
tight tops.
She flirted
with everyone.
Must've pissed Donovan off.
He was cool about it.
Said he Iiked that
Vanessa was a free spirit.
Then one day,
she dumped him.
Is this Donovan?
Yeah.
Where can
we find him?
(SNIFFS)
When he's not in class,
he's in the park
playing speed chess.
You think you can
take me, you patzer?
Shut up and move.
Oh, aren't we
tense today?
Hey, we're in
the middle of a game.
Not anymore. Move.
You're here
about Vanessa?
Yeah, I can see
you're upset about it.
What, do you grieve
by hustling some fish
in five-dollar blitz.
Chess takes
my mind off her.
I Ioved Vanessa.
So why were you
arguing with her
Iast night?
If you're trying to say
that I killed her,
you're wrong.
AII right, when I Ieft
Dominique's Iast night,
Vanessa was fine.
What happened
to your neck?
I see where
this is going.
I'm not answering
any more questions
without a Iawyer.
So give us a DNA swab
and you won't need one.
I'm not gonna give you
a sample so you can frame
me with my own cells.
Why would we do that?
I don't know.
Why would you stick a plunger
up Abner Louima's ass?
If you want anything from me,
come back with a warrant.
I believe
that's check and mate.
Sure is, smartass.
STABLER: Couldn't get a DNA
sample from our suspect,
but I think we got prints.
Index finger
and thumb.
I'II see if I can Iift
a print off the body.
Meanwhile, I've got
Iots to work with.
There's evidence
of vaginal trauma,
I've got the perp's fluids,
and I got skin cells,
from underneath
her acrylic nails.
Great for trapping evidence.
Could explain
the Band-Aid
on Donovan's neck.
Vanessa clawed
the son of a bitch.
She wasn't
the only one.
The blood on the cat's fur
was Vanessa's,
but the blood on its claws,
was a match to the perp.
We gotta get
Donovan's DNA.
I'II get the prints off
the chess piece and send them
over to Ballistics
to compare with the gun.
I dusted the gun.
The wooden grip is too
textured to raise prints,
and only your victim's
are on the barrel.
Like Vanessa
tried to grab it.
AIso found a greasy
substance on the weapon.
Gun cleaning fluid?
No, I'd recognize
that in my sleep.
I'II run some
tests on it.
So that's it?
Would I waste your time?
I've got the gun owner.
You mean we have a Iegal,
registered piece?
Mmm-hmm. Carry permit comes
back to Marvin KIigman,
address on Park Avenue.
Sure, Marvin had a gun.
My Iate husband,
may he rest in peace,
was in the diamond trade.
Dangerous business.
MUNCH: Where's the gun now,
Mrs. KIigman?
In my Iock box.
May we see it?
Of course.
Does anyone else
have access to the gun?
Only my son.
He Iives in the dorms.
At Hudson University.
It's gone.
I didn't take
my father's gun.
How did it get used
to kill your classmate?
I don't know anything
about Vanessa's murder.
But you do know her.
Yeah.
Yeah? You sleeping with her?
Yeah, I wish.
BENSON: Where were you
Iast night?
At an all-night cram session
with my study group.
Go check.
Oh, we will, but right now
you're the one who's Iooking
good for this murder.
Okay.
I got a Iittle over-extended
on the Super Bowl.
I was gonna sell the gun,
but someone stole it.
You know Donovan AIvarez?
Yeah, sure,
he Iives down my hall.
Could he
have stolen it?
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
I don't know...
Stabler.
Did Donovan ever
see the gun?
Yeah, I was Iooking
for a buyer.
I showed it to a Iot
of people, including Donovan.
Did he see
where you kept it?
Yeah, yeah,
in my desk.
Warner. She wants
to talk to us.
You fumed her.
It's amazing
what you can do
with crazy glue.
Vaporize it,
and when it hardens,
you can dust a print on skin.
Where's the print?
On the inside of her
right wrist, where
there's deep bruising.
STABLER: Like someone
grabbed her hard.
With the glue,
it's as clear as day.
Donovan AIvarez?
Ten point match.
PROFESSOR:
In People v. Carmichael,
the M.E. ruled that the death
was due to undetermined
homicidal violence.
How did the District Attorney
get a conviction?
Donovan AIvarez, you're under
arrest for the murder
of Vanessa Bevins.
PROFESSOR: Hey, what do
you think you're doing?
You can't do this.
Sure we can.
What do you think
you're doing?
Your teacher
cover Miranda yet?
What's going on? Hey!
You have the right
to remain silent.
If you give up that right,
anything you say
can and will be used...
This is your Iast chance,
Donovan.
Just tell us the truth.
Once there's a DNA match,
no one will care
what you say.
I am telling the truth,
all right.
I didn't kill Vanessa.
I only went to the club
to talk to her.
Because you were pissed off
that she broke up with you?
No, I was pissed because
she stole my credit card
and spent thousands
of dollars on crazy stuff.
That sounds Iike a good
motive to drag her out
to the alley and kill her.
No.
We were arguing because
Vanessa said she had bigger
problems than paying me back.
So then you pulled
the gun to make her
take you seriously.
No, I didn't have a gun.
Come on, Donovan.
Vanessa was killed with a gun
stolen from your dorm.
I don't know
anything about that.
Why don't you believe me?
I could never hurt Vanessa.
You grabbed her so hard
your prints were
bruised into her flesh.
She was walking away.
I grabbed her arm
so I could stop her.
Is that when
she scratched your neck?
I cut myself shaving.
See for yourself.
Does this Iook
Iike a scratch?
BENSON: You believe his story?
I don't know.
Vanessa's on drugs,
desperate for money,
she steals from
her ex-boyfriend.
Sounds Iike motive to me.
Donovan can't explain how
Vanessa was shot with a gun
that he had access to?
Something wrong?
Yeah. Ray Bevins,
he called five times.
CRAGEN: DNA's back.
The semen, fingernail
scrapings, and the blood
on the cat's claw,
all come from
the same person.
And it's not
Donovan AIvarez.
So, Vanessa had
sex with someone else
earlier that night,
and then Donovan
shoots her in the alley.
Possible, but not enough to
hold a kid you arrested in
front of a criminal Iaw class.
BENSON: We can't
cut him Ioose.
And we can't
talk to him anymore.
BENSON: Why's that?
Professor called and
Iawyered up for him.
Ray.
Detective.
It's the middle of the night.
What are you doing here?
I called.
I know. I haven't had a chance
to get back to you. I'm sorry.
I just wanted to know
if you had any Ieads.
Yeah, we're making progress.
Can't you tell
me anything?
No. Ray, go home.
Get some sleep.
I can't.
I can't...
I mean,
I can't sleep.
I just keep seeing
Vanessa's face,
in the morgue.
Ray...
If I have any news,
I'II call you.
I promise. You have my word.
Now go home.
Go home.
Hey, how's he doing?
He's a mess.
The Iogs on Vanessa's phone.
Check out this number.
Dozens of calls to it.
It's the Rape
Crisis Center.
Why was Vanessa
calling them two weeks
before she was raped?
Vanessa must've called me
20 times, but she never
gave a Iast name.
I was afraid if I pushed
too hard, she'd stop calling.
I know what she said
is confidential...
And any father would
waive confidentiality
to catch his child's killer.
Let's cut
the red tape.
Good. Why was Vanessa
calling you?
She was in
a sexual relationship
she couldn't handle.
So, she was raped.
She wasn't sure.
She needed help understanding
what had happened to her,
but it was rape all right.
She had gotten involved
with this man that she met.
Donovan AIvarez?
She never gave his name.
He was a sadist.
He Iiked to degrade her.
Make her have sex
in public places.
Get rough.
When she refused,
he beat her up.
After that she was too
scared to say no again.
Why didn't she
call the police?
I gave her your number.
Vanessa just wasn't ready.
She was very depressed.
She kept blaming herself
instead of her boss.
Her boss?
Yeah, that's
who was raping her.
Look, I understand
the need for investigation.
I just don't see
how I can help you.
Well, you were at the club,
weren't you?
I was in the VIP room.
I told that to the officers
who interviewed me.
You didn't tell them
you were sleeping
with the victim.
(SIGHS)
Well, now I see.
Someone's been talking
about me behind my back.
Then Iet's talk openly,
in our squad room.
Baby, I'm going now.
You'II call me Iater?
Come here.
You know I will.
Give me a moment to call
my Iawyer. I'II have him
meet me there.
There's no need to.
You're not under arrest.
And I'd Iike to
keep it that way.
My client is more than
happy to assist in
the investigation.
He'II answer
your questions.
Why don't we Iet
his DNA sample
do the talking?
Oh, hey, take a swab.
It'II match.
I'm sure
you'II find my blood
in the alleyway, too.
Damn cat clawed
the hell out of my ass.
Listen, I had sex
with Vanessa that night.
That's not a crime.
Rape and sodomy are.
(SCOFFS)
Rape? Detective,
I don't need to force
women to have sex with me.
Oh, so you expect
us to believe
that Vanessa Iiked
being half-naked,
down on her knees
in a dirty alley?
Yeah, she grew to Iike it.
Once you stripped away
that schoolgirl exterior,
underneath Iay
a very adventurous woman.
Why'd you go out back?
I don't Iike to
share my girls.
I saw Vanessa go
outside with a friend.
I went to make sure
they weren't
having a quickie.
Were they?
No, no. Her tastes
had changed.
She told him to
get the hell out.
BENSON: So,
did you see him Ieave?
He got into a cab.
Vanessa and I had
a Iittle fun,
and then I went back inside.
So she fought
with her boyfriend,
had sex with you,
and then, a third guy
came along and he killed her.
Is that what
you're telling me?
Truth is stranger
than fiction.
But you're the only one
with a history
of abusing Vanessa.
Oh, more gossip?
BENSON: No, we have witnesses.
Vanessa told people
about your repeated
sexual assault.
I don't recall anyone
watching us having sex.
So unless you guys
communicate with ghosts,
you've got nothing.
AII right. My client
has answered all
of your questions.
So, unless
you're arresting him,
we're Ieaving.
(CLEARS THROAT)
You'II notify me
if you want to speak
to my client any further.
Oh, we'II be speaking
to him again, yeah.
Come on.
Detective Stabler,
any news about Vanessa?
Are you her father?
Yeah.
Hey, I'm really sorry.
Thanks. Who are you?
Oh, sorry,
Perry Williams.
How do you know
my daughter?
I was her boss.
Let's talk. Come on.
She was really sweet.
What?
Why are you here?
WILLIAMS: I'm just answering
a few questions.
About what?
My relationship
with your daughter.
You bastard! You raped
and murdered my daughter.
Hey, hey, I didn't
have to rape her.
And I sure
didn't kill her.
He's not worth it.
Let him go. AII right?
AII right, all right.
Come on.
Ray, you've gotta
stop coming here.
I got nothing
else to do.
What about your job?
I don't give a damn
about my work anymore.
You're never going
to make an arrest.
It's been three days, Ray.
You gotta give me time.
That filth killed my daughter
and you're just gonna Iet him
walk out the door.
We don't have enough evidence
to arrest him for murder yet.
You could at Ieast
arrest him for rape.
He's claiming their
relationship was consensual.
That's crazy.
We need the proof.
What do you think?
It doesn't matter
what I think, Ray.
In your heart,
what do you think?
We may never know.
PIease...
Just tell me...
Did he rape her?
We're Iooking
at him for it.
Did he do it?
(SIGHS)
We're gonna
get the guy.
Thanks.
Go home.
You sound Iike
me talking to Ray.
EIIiot, there's nothing
we can do tonight.
We'II start fresh
in the morning.
I need to get
that bastard.
PIenty of other bastards
out there, EIIiot,
why this one?
You know why.
I'm gonna go catch
a few hours of sleep.
See you at 7:00.
Hey, it's Stabler.
Sorry to bother you so Iate,
I need you to do
me a big favor.
You gotta run
the tests tonight.
I burned a sample
of the greasy residue
in the gas chromatograph.
Tell me it nails
Perry Williams.
Hear me out.
The grease on the gun
had three component
organic substances.
The first two are
Ianolin and talc.
Skin care products?
Exactly.
Chemical compositions
identical to the Iotion
and face powder
brands Vanessa used.
So the gun
touched her skin.
It doesn't explain the flakes
trapped in the Iotion.
Cured tobacco, same brand
as the cigarettes we found
in Vanessa's purse.
Vanessa was carrying
the gun.
She tried to defend herself.
Perp took it away
and shot her.
You'd think so,
but I decided to take
another Iook at the residue
pattern on Vanessa's hands.
Here it is.
But that residue
pattern is not consistent
with any defensive posture.
Not Iike this.
Not Iike this. And so on.
So you have no match.
I think there
might be.
Like this.
Fire in the hole.
It's a match.
Vanessa killed herself.
Perry Williams raped Vanessa
and it drove her to suicide.
She steals the gun,
brings it down to
the alley to kill him,
Ioses her nerve.
When Perry rapes her again,
it's the Iast straw,
so she kills herself.
This bastards gonna escape,
we got nothing on the rape.
You know, maybe Vanessa told
someone in person, other than
the rape crisis counselor.
We get an outcry witness,
we got ourselves a chance.
Ray didn't know,
none of her friends knew.
Hell, no one even
knew she was suicidal.
They all say
she was a party girl.
This may explain why.
Vanessa's toxicology report.
It says that her
blood was positive
for Iithium.
What's that used for?
For treating
bi-polar disorder.
No wonder she was
flying high one day,
and crashing the next.
Promiscuous, going on spending
sprees, explains why everyone
thought she was on drugs.
It also explains
her inability
to break off from
Perry Williams despite
his treatment of her.
So why didn't
the Iithium help?
Because the amount
found in her blood
wasn't a therapeutic dose.
My guess is she stopped
taking her meds a week ago.
So why didn't anybody
tell us about her diagnosis?
This is a woman
who suffered in silence.
Now, I gotta tell Ray
his only child killed herself.
First you tell me she's
on drugs. Now you tell me
that she's crazy,
and I'm telling you
I know my daughter,
and she was never suicidal.
If you'd Iike,
you can talk to
our medical examiner.
She can explain how
she came to the findings.
Thank you.
You know what,
I will.
Did you know that she
was taking medication
for bipolar disorder?
She was moody.
I mean, she felt
things very intensely.
She was a caring...
Look, my daughter
was not sick.
Then Vanessa never mentioned
that she was seeing
a psychiatrist?
(SIGHS)
No.
Ray, maybe she was ashamed.
No daughter wants to
disappoint her father.
Vanessa's "problem"
was that bastard
Perry Williams.
He murdered her,
even if he didn't
pull the trigger.
But Iegally, Ray,
Iegally he's not
responsible for her death.
Can you give us
the name of her doctor?
I don't know.
She was using the college
health care service.
Could you all
just please Ieave?
Vanessa wanted help
controlling her behavior.
The Iithium worked,
and in combination
with psychotherapy...
Well, she was making
excellent progress.
Did she ever mention
a Perry Williams in therapy?
Yes.
He was encouraging her
to drink and stop
taking her meds.
STABLER: Why?
To make her more vulnerable,
more manic.
He Iiked being with
a hyper-sexual party girl.
When she began to stabilize,
he Iost his control over her.
That's when she realized
he was abusing her.
Well, why'd she keep
going out with him?
Well, he's a handsome,
successful older man.
She was blinded by his charm.
Our tox screen shows
that Vanessa had stopped
taking the Iithium.
Now you know what can happen
to a manic depressive
when they go off their meds.
What did you
do about it?
What could I do?
She's an adult Iegally free
to make her own choices.
STABLER: She was suicidal.
Not Iast week
when I saw her.
You should have
told her father
what was going on.
The only way
I could've disclosed anything
is if she'd been
homicidal or suicidal
and as I said, she wasn't.
Did Vanessa ever mention
confiding in anybody else?
She was keeping
a therapy journal.
Vanessa's roommate had
the diary. I can see why
she kept it hidden from Ray.
It's graphic sexual stuff,
a catalog of
Perry's perversions.
He's a sexual sadist,
he doesn't want a partner,
he wants a victim.
I'm not sure
that's enough.
We talked to several
of Perry's ex-girlfriends.
He gets off on pain,
they'II all testify to that.
Were they raped?
No, but...
But then
it's not enough.
Vanessa's body showed signs
of sexual trauma.
Well, Perry will argue
that it was rough
but consensual sex.
And we've got her statements
to the psychiatrist
and the rape crisis counselor,
that she was forced.
AII right, those I can get
admitted under the outcry
exception to the hearsay rule,
but I would still Iike
a confession from Perry.
AIex, it's all in here.
Everything that
he did to her.
"I'm still bleeding
from Iast night.
"I should go to the hospital,
but I'm too embarrassed
to tell anyone.
"When I said I couldn't have
sex tonight, he punched me
so hard I couldn't breathe."
Let's go after him
for the rape.
But, just in case, tell
Ray to file a civil suit.
CIean Perry out.
At Ieast arresting Perry
might give Ray some closure.
Maybe you, too.
EIIiot, can I talk
to you for a minute?
I'II meet you
down in the car.
What you got?
Ray Bevins came by
to see me,
asked questions
about why we ruled
Vanessa's death a suicide.
He accept it?
I walked him through
the evidence as gently
as I could, but I screwed up.
I mentioned the oral sodomy.
I thought you told him.
No. I didn't want to put
that image in his head.
His daughter on her knees
in some filthy alley.
I'm sorry,
but it's in there now.
He really Iost it.
He Ieft mumbling
something about a club.
Detective Charlie
to Central K.
Sorry, Detectives.
It was over when we got here.
Where's Ray Bevins?
In the wind.
Dead guy was the only one
here when we arrived.
We had him.
We had Perry.
EIIiot, Ray's still
got the gun.
(SIREN BLARING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
We boomed the door
and swept the place.
No sign of your guy.
Where could he be?
This is all about Vanessa.
He'd want to be with her.
Detective Stabler,
Section Central Park has
a man with a gun to his head.
Description matches your guy.
Secure the perimeter.
Tell Ray we're on our way.
No one talks to him but me.
Ray.
Put the gun down.
Don't do this, Ray.
I have nothing Ieft.
Let's just talk.
Let's just sit here and talk.
Vanessa's gone, I mean...
There's no other way
to end the pain.
Vanessa Ioves you.
She wouldn't
want you to do this.
My daughter needed help,
and she couldn't come to me.
I can't Iive with that.
Why here?
This was Vanessa's
favorite place,
when she was a...
When she was
a Iittle girl.
Those memories are
alive in you, Ray.
You keep her alive.
Everything that you
and Vanessa had together,
that's what you want.
I want her to know
how much I Iove her.
(SOBBING)
I want her to know
how sorry I am.
I couldn't be there for her.
She's here, Ray,
in your heart.
She's alive, here.
She can only die
when you die, Ray.
(RAY WAILING)
EIIiot, I want to
hear it from you.
Did you actually
Iawyer up for Ray Bevins?
He needed an attorney.
So you called
one of the best
defense attorneys in town?
Usually you get a confession
instead of throwing up
road blocks to
protect the perps.
Ray Bevins is not a perp.
He killed a man
in cold blood.
He killed a sexual predator
that you said
we couldn't convict.
I will not
condone vigilantism.
I am not going to Iet
my compassion for Ray
prevent me from doing my job.
Well, I did my job.
I arrested him.
He's all yours.
I want manslaughter
and probation. Extreme
emotional disturbance.
Ray snapped when he found out
his daughter's rapist would go
unpunished for his crime.
For someone who snapped,
your client was
thinking clearly enough
to obtain a weapon,
Iocate the defendant,
and execute him.
That's not
temporary insanity.
You know the EED
statute was designed
to downgrade murder charges,
when they are
mitigated by the defendant's
severe psychological trauma.
Only when the defendant's
mental state creates a Ioss
of self-control.
Ray's actions appear
deliberate and rational.
Don't take our word for it,
have your shrink evaluate Ray.
Perry Williams
killed my daughter.
He took her to
such a dark place that
she couldn't find a way out.
So what did you do?
Guy I know at the work site
gave me the gun.
I went to the club,
said I had an appointment
with Perry
and waited in his office.
And what happened after that?
Perry walked in.
I confronted him
with Vanessa's rape.
He denied it, and then...
Then he said that she Iiked
what he did to her.
Ray, how did Perry
end up in the alley?
I took him there.
I forced him to his knees,
the way he forced
Vanessa to her knees.
He begged for his Iife,
he swore that he would
tell the truth to the cops.
I said enough,
you know, enough Iies.
So I put the gun in his mouth,
and I pulled the trigger.
Ray's emotional pain
is genuine
and the cause for his mental
trauma is Iegitimate,
but I don't buy
his affirmative defense.
Why the hell not?
This is a man who's
Iost his daughter.
Well, despite his
emotional distress,
he had the presence of mind
to carefully
plan this murder.
He knew right from wrong.
He knew nothing.
This is a guy
drowning in grief.
HUANG: Ray made clear,
Iogical, and deliberate
choices.
He forced Perry
out into that alley
and symbolically re-enacted
his daughter's rape
and murder.
He didn't shoot
Perry in the chest.
No, he put the gun
in Perry's mouth,
imitating the oral sodomy.
I'II notify Ray's attorney
that we're gonna fight it.
She'II probably try for
jury nullification, get them
to acquit out of sympathy.
They should.
Look. I'm not mourning
for Perry Williams,
but I'm not rolling
over for Ray, either.
I need that report as
soon as you can get it.
I could've stopped him.
I should've known
what Ray was gonna do.
How?
I'd have done
the same thing.
No, you wouldn't.
Wait till
you're a parent.
Don't throw that
crap at me, EIIiot.
You made a mistake.
What?
You Iet Ray in.
You're right, I did.
He got to me,
and now I'm responsible.
I don't remember
Ieaving the nightclub.
EMMETT: What's the next
thing you do remember?
Sitting in the park,
by the Iake.
Vanessa and I went there
since she was a Iittle girl.
She would feed the ducks her
sandwiches when she thought
I wasn't Iooking.
But you still had the gun?
Yes.
What were you
going to do next?
Shoot myself,
so that I could be
with my daughter.
Thank you.
No further questions.
You blame Perry Williams
for your daughter's death?
Yeah, he raped Vanessa
and that's why
she killed herself.
CABOT: You sound very
certain of that.
But Vanessa was
emotionally unstable,
wasn't she?
BEVINS: He made her that way.
Mr. Bevins, she was
under psychiatric care
and had been
prescribed Iithium
for a bipolar disorder.
Are you suggesting
that Perry Williams
was responsible for that?
He Iowered her self-esteem,
and told her not to
take her medication.
My daughter was
happy and healthy,
before she
worked at that club.
As far as you knew.
There was quite a bit
about her Iife that
Vanessa did not tell you.
Did she tell you
that she had been
sexually assaulted?
No.
CABOT: So her relationship
with Perry Williams
could have been
consensual as he claimed.
You call the deceased
a rapist, but you have
no evidence
other than your
personal beliefs.
That's not true.
Detective Stabler told me
that Perry Williams
raped my daughter.
Thank you.
Nothing further.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
You're calling
me to the stand?
No, the Defense is.
You've just become
their star witness.
Excuse me?
EIIiot, did you tell Ray
that you knew Perry Williams
had raped Vanessa?
No.
He says you did.
I told him
Perry was a suspect.
Now they're going to
use you to justify
Ray murdering Perry.
Yeah? Well, the hell with him.
He got what he deserved.
Well, now it's your turn.
You gave premature information
to an unstable man.
You sure as hell
better be ready
when I cross-examine you.
Detective Stabler,
did you have a conversation
with Ray Bevins
about Perry Williams?
Yes.
Do you remember the content
of that conversation?
Not word for word, no.
Do you remember
telling Ray Bevins
that you believed
Perry Williams
raped his daughter?
I said we were
Iooking at him.
Did you say, quote,
"We're gonna get the guy."
Yes, I said that.
Who did "the guy" refer to?
STABLER: The killer. It didn't
necessarily mean that I was
Iooking at Perry Williams.
But it's reasonable to assume
that Ray believed
you meant Mr. Williams.
Now, did you tell Ray
that you were powerless
to arrest Mr. Williams?
At the time,
we didn't have
enough evidence.
Yes or no, Detective.
At the time of the murder
did my client believe
you would ever be able
to arrest Mr. Williams?
No.
Thank you.
"We're gonna get the guy."
Detective Stabler,
when you made that
remark to the defendant,
was it based on
any official determination
from the NYPD?
"Official determination"? No.
Was it based on
any forensic evidence?
Yes, we had Perry Williams'
DNA on Vanessa's body.
DNA proves that sex
took place, not rape.
We had her diary.
A person, Detective,
not her writings.
We had the rape
crisis counselor.
An eyewitness, Detective.
No.
So your statement
to the defendant,
that Perry Williams raped
Vanessa was based purely
on your individual opinion?
Yes.
Then why did
you say that?
Because he needed
something to hold onto.
So your sympathy
for the defendant
Ied you to give Ray Bevins
unsubstantiated information?
Yes.
Detective Stabler,
do you condone Ray Bevins'
murder of Perry Williams?
Detective?
No.
It was wrong.
Nothing further.
The Iaw is supposed to provide
us with safety and justice
but the Iaw failed to get
justice for Vanessa Bevins.
And in his time of grief,
Ray Bevins Iearned that
the man who had abused,
humiliated,
and raped his daughter
was going to walk free.
Now, if it were your daughter,
your wife, your mother,
who had been raped
and the police were unable
to arrest their attacker,
how would you feel?
Ray Bevins suffered
every parent's nightmare.
He did what every parent
knows in their heart
they would do.
He acted from
a place of profound grief,
of overwhelming Ioss.
He did not have
control of his actions.
He tried to get
justice for his daughter
in the only way he knew how.
And now you must make
justice for Ray Bevins,
and return a verdict
of not guilty.
Some of you may believe that
Perry Williams raped
Vanessa Bevins in that alley,
but Perry Williams
is not on trial here.
In fact, he never got
his day in court at all.
So in the eyes of the Iaw,
he is innocent
until proven guilty.
Even if his guilt
had been established
beyond a reasonable doubt,
he could not
have been executed
for his crime.
Ray Bevins executed
Perry Williams.
He shot a man,
who was on his knees,
begging for his Iife.
Now some of you may think
that he deserved to die.
But you have to
ask yourselves
if you would execute
a man whose guilt had
not been proven.
We have all felt
the need for revenge
at some point in our Iives.
We have all Iashed
out in pain and anger,
and we have all thought
that justice means
an eye for an eye.
But is that justice?
Does Perry Williams' family
now have the right
to kill Ray Bevins?
Does Ray Bevins' family then
have the right to retaliate
against Perry Williams?
When would it stop?
An eye for an eye
Ieaves the whole world blind.
LARSEN: Has the jury
reached its verdict?
Yes, we have, Your Honor.
Will the defendant
please rise?
LARSEN: On the count of murder
in the Second Degree,
how does the jury find?
We find the defendant,
Raymond Bevins,
guilty.
LARSEN: Thank you for
your service. You're excused.
Ray.
I'm sorry.
I'm not.