NARRATOR: In the criminal
justice system,
sexually based offenses
are considered
especially heinous.
In New York City,
the dedicated detectives
who investigate
these vicious felonies
are members
of an elite squad known
as the Special Victims Unit.
These are their stories.
(RUSTLING)
Armando,
wake up.
What?
Shh. Someone's
in the house.
Call 91 1.
I can't
find the phone.
Just get in
the closet.
(BOTTLES RATTLING)
Is that you, Itsy?
(PANTING)
Who the hell
is Itsy?
is she?
No ID.
Can't tell me
her name.
Can't
or won't?
I think Granny's only
knitting with one needle,
if you catch my drift.
Well, she came in
through a window, so she was
pretty desperate to get in.
Well, she thinks
she Iives here, apparently
with someone named Itsy.
And you canvassed
the building?
Yeah.
No one knows her.
Yeah, Granny Doe
made herself
right at home.
That's her coat
on the rack.
Okay. Thanks.
Why are all
these men here?
I'm not decent.
It's okay, ma'am.
It's okay.
PIease.
Make them Ieave.
AII right.
I'm Detective Benson.
Can you tell me
what happened?
I have to talk to Itsy.
Okay. Is Itsy the one
that hurt you?
You don't know anything,
do you?
Just what
Itsy told me.
She promised not to tell.
Well, that's because
she wants you to tell me.
What happened?
He had his way with me.
Who did?
Ma'am, may I?
Did you see that?
Yeah. Someone used her
for an ashtray.
Was she raped?
No abrasions or fluids,
you'II have to wait
for the kit.
But she had 12 raw burns
to her breasts and genitals.
She was in shock
when we talked to her.
You think
she'II remember
more details?
I doubt it.
Her head CT
and MRI are clear,
no sign of infection.
She probably
has AIzheimer's.
So, no short-term memory.
Any way to
kick-start it?
Damage done
is irreversible.
She's in here.
She hasn't been
admitted yet?
No need to.
She has mild
high blood pressure.
Nothing more serious.
I gave her Silvadene Iotion
for her burns.
This woman needs
supervised care.
Long-term. We don't provide
that here. I just need
someone to release her to.
Do you feel up to
talking now?
Oh, where's my purse?
Look, what happened
to my purse?
You didn't have one
with you.
Did you take it
when you went out?
Well, I had my purse here
10 minutes ago.
Of course I had my purse.
We'II help you
Iook for it.
Did it have
your name in it?
Of course it had
my name in it.
Okay.
What was the name?
I don't know.
Whatever.
What could have happened
to my purse?
Well, what's it to you?
You took my purse.
You make her
give me back
my purse.
I promise you,
she didn't take
your purse.
Yes, she did. She did take
my purse. Nobody else
could have taken my purse.
You give me back
my purse.
Maybe the person
who hurt you
took your purse?
Were you attacked in
your home? Or someplace else?
Can you remember?
I was in my bedroom.
I was... I was asleep,
and I...
I was asleep in my bedroom
I woke up and...
He pushed up my nightgown.
He was in there.
Oh, it hurt so bad.
I tried to hit him.
I tried to push him off,
but I couldn't move.
BENSON: Did you know
your attacker?
Who was it?
It was...
STABLER: How did he get
in the house?
Well, he stays there.
He stays there?
Why?
Well, he stays there
because he Iost all his money
investing it.
He drinks every night.
Whiskey.
Oh, he smells so awful
when he...
Okay.
We can help you.
I don't Iike it
when he comes
upstairs to me.
We can help you,
but you've got to
tell us his name, okay?
(MUTTERING)
Who?
It's sad.
Frightening. When this
steel trap starts to rust,
call Kevorkian.
Consider that done.
Have Adult Protective Services
pick her up.
Where are we on her ID?
We re-canvassed
the building and did
a sweep of the neighborhood.
No one's
claiming her.
Well, she said
her abuser
Iives with her.
MUNCH: Yeah, so
he won't be calling
Missing Persons.
Well, how far could
this Iady have gone
in her nightie?
She broke into that apartment
for a reason. She must have
Iived there at some point.
Manager's been there
20 years.
He's never seen her.
That building's been there
at Ieast a hundred.
Go back further.
The 1930 census
was just unsealed this year.
I can give you the name, age,
sex and race of any person
at any address.
Assuming they weren't paranoid
conspiracy freaks with
a wicked big-brother complex.
Well, that's why it's sealed
for 72 years, to cover
the average Iife span.
Actually, 72 is the
average man's Iife span.
A woman's is 79.
Oh, a man
who knows his stats.
Did you know the 1930 census
takes 2,667 rolls of...
Yo, stop, stop, stop.
Okay. There's Seventh.
Back up.
There's Sixth
and there's
the building, 213.
Yeah. Apartment 1-A.
The Staytons.
EIIsworth, Hilda
and three daughters,
Lilith, 11, Isabel, 10,
and Millie, eight.
Today they'd be 83,
82 and 80.
She's gotta be
one of these three girls.
STABLER: This isn't Lilith
or Isabel?
MILLIE: No, both my sisters
passed on.
Lily in '92
and cancer took Izzy
back in '78.
You called Isabel
"Izzy"?
Everyone did.
No one ever
called her "Itsy"?
Dear Lord,
Itsy and Bitsy.
I haven't thought
about her in years.
Who was Bitsy?
A neighbor girl
down the street.
Isabel's best friend.
It was Bitsy for Bess.
Bess Maclntyre.
Did Bess ever
Iive with you?
No, no. But sometimes
she'd sneak over
in the middle of the night.
Poor thing,
cry herself to sleep.
She would wake up
your whole family
in the middle of the night?
Oh, no, no,
she'd sneak in
through a window.
Why was she crying?
I was too young
to understand at the time,
but Bess had what we used
to call a "funny uncle."
Mother never Iet us play
at her house the whole time
he Iived there.
(WHISPERING) I got it, thanks.
I'm sorry,
did I wake you?
Who are you?
I'm OIivia. Remember?
And I'm sorry,
do you go by Bitsy
or Bess now?
Bess.
We've never met.
We had a Iong talk
this morning.
After the hospital?
I never go to a hospital.
I'm a very healthy person.
I am healthy as a...
As a horseshoe.
What is this place?
Why am I here?
You're in a police station.
I was arrested?
No, no, no.
You were attacked.
You said that it was
the man staying with you.
The man
who Iost all his money
in the stock market.
Were you talking
about your uncle?
What year
did he Iose
all his money?
What year did he Iose
all his money? He Iost his
money in 1929. Everybody did.
Bess, that was over
70 years ago.
Your uncle hurt you
when you were Iittle. Tell me,
who is hurting you now?
Well, in the small favors
category, her rape kit
came back negative.
You Iook at those burns
and tell me this skeev
did her any favors.
Looks Iike
the doc's done with her.
What'd you get?
The attack definitely
triggered memories
of her childhood molestation.
So she fled to the only
safe harbor she could think
of, her friend Isabel's home.
She'd sneak through
the window Iike
she did Iast night.
Who is she running from?
I doubt she's ever gonna
be able to tell you.
So we just solved
a 70-year-old rape case.
Uncle Ted was arrested in '53
on five counts of rape,
but not for Bess.
He was killed in prison
in '57.
Well, somebody tortured her
again Iast night
and I'm pretty sure
it wasn't the dead uncle.
So, who are we Iooking for?
A sadist.
He enjoyed the torture,
though I'm not sure
if it was sexual
or anger-based.
He's young
or socially stunted.
He chose an enfeebled woman
because of feelings
of inadequacy.
I tracked Bess
through Social Security.
Her checks are sent care of
Jubilee Towers on Madison.
Nice place
for a nursing home.
We're not a nursing home.
We're an assisted
Iiving facility.
Hello. Hope Garrett.
Hi.
Assistant Administrator.
How may I help you?
I'm Detective Benson.
This is my partner,
Detective Stabler.
Are you aware
that one of your residents
went missing Iast night?
Well, it couldn't have been
anyone from the nursing wing
because they're checked
on a regular basis.
Let's see. Uh...
Yes, all our Level One-ers
are accounted for.
You do bed checks?
The residents are required
to flip a switch
every morning,
just to Iet us know
that they're still with us.
Well, I can guarantee you
Bess Sherman did not flip
her own switch today.
How could she have?
Mrs. Sherman was released
about two weeks ago.
To whom?
Her son.
Joe Sherman.
Mr. Sherman?
These folks have a warrant.
I'm Ietting them in.
He's usually home from work
about now.
Nice place.
No, it's his mother's.
Rent-controlled.
$350 a month,
you believe that?
Mr. Sherman smoke?
Only in between
the times he quits.
How's Joe been getting along
with his mother
since she moved back in?
AII I know is
she sure brought him
some Iuck.
How so?
Well, ever since
she came back,
the repo men stopped coming,
deliveries started.
Deliveries.
What kind of deliveries?
Big-screen TV came in
over the weekend.
Couch, chairs, the media unit.
Got all the bells
and whistles, CD, DVD,
stereo, video, got a TiVo.
EIIiot.
Really fixed
this place up.
Except for this room.
Bess' room,
I'm assuming.
Looks more
Iike her cell.
Check this out.
Explains
the restraint marks.
Joe didn't want to Iose
his Iucky charm.
Who are you,
and what are you
doing here?
Police. Just checking out
your mother's accommodations.
Well, where is she?
Is she okay?
She's safer than she was
in this place. Let's go.
I wanna see my mother.
When we're done.
Have a cigarette.
I don't smoke.
Really?
We heard you did.
I quit.
Could I see her
right now?
As soon as
you explain these.
She never
bruised before.
It's some way
to treat your mother.
She wanders at night.
It's for her own protection.
Protection? But
you don't protect her
from this.
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God.
Well, you don't think
I burned her?
Actually, we do.
Well, then
you're more confused
than she is.
Obviously some pervert
attacked her on the street
when she got out.
BENSON: But you didn't notice
she was gone.
I had an early
breakfast meeting.
I didn't want to wake her.
But you don't mind
Ieaving her tied up
to a bed for 18 hours?
Now, how was she supposed
to use the bathroom?
Look, the housekeeper
takes care of that.
Maria comes in every morning.
She makes Mom breakfast.
She wakes her up.
But she didn't come
this morning.
No. I don't know why
Maria didn't call me.
And believe me, she's fired.
Well, we'II take care of
that for you.
What's her Iast name?
Her name is Sanchez.
You know, your mother
would've been just fine
if you hadn't pulled her
from that nice
retirement community.
They were draining her.
She paid those crooks
seven grand a month.
Leaving
nothing for you.
AII right, you know what?
I'm done. So you either
charge me, or you Iet me go.
And I'm gonna
take my mother with me.
No way we're releasing Bess
into his custody.
He's her Iegal guardian.
He's her abuser.
According to whom?
You have no witnesses,
and the victim
can't make a complaint.
Look, we suspect
a parent of abuse,
Child Services doesn't
need the victim's complaint.
The Iaw assumes
a child can't speak up
for itself.
CRAGEN: Neither can Bess.
And her son
is strapping her to a bed.
A Iawyer could argue
he believed
it was a reasonable,
albeit very misguided,
attempt to keep Bess safe.
Look, AIex,
there's gotta be some way
to get this guy on neglect.
In an attempt to ensure
her safety, he endangered her.
It's a stretch.
Well, then stretch it
into an order of removal.
We'II stall Joe.
What's the problem now?
I have a protective order
to place your mother
back in Jubilee Towers
until this matter
is straightened out.
My mom
belongs with me.
The courts
disagree with you.
Mom. Mom,
would you tell them
that I did not hurt you?
Why is it so noisy
in here?
I'm gonna sue
every one of your asses.
Lawyers are
mighty expensive, Joe.
Here's a protective order
freezing your mother's
accounts and assets.
You can't do that.
Mom, don't you worry,
I am gonna bring you home!
Captain, got any tissues
for me? I'm about
to break out into tears.
Hey, escort Mr. Sherman
out the back.
We'II see if we can
dig up any dirt
from the neighbors,
see if Maria the housekeeper
even exists.
BENSON: Maria Sanchez?
Yes.
You work for Joe Sherman,
take care of his mother,
Bess?
Yes, what's wrong?
BENSON: Did you go to work
yesterday?
No one was there.
I thought maybe
he took her to the doctor.
She ran away sometime
the night before. Could you
come up here, please?
We'd Iike to ask you
a few questions.
Do you have any idea
what she was running from?
You ever see
any marks or bruises
on Mrs. Sherman?
No.
Did you ever see
Mr. Sherman hurt her?
No, but when things
are stressful, he speaks
very harsh with her.
Was he stressed out
Monday?
Very. Everything had to be
just perfect for his party.
JOE: I invited
a few investors over.
You failed to mention it.
It wasn't relevant.
I can assure you
that none of them
touched my mother.
Delway Furniture Rentals
says your Visa
was declined.
Send them a check.
But the bank called...
Just deal with it.
Business troubles?
Police harassment.
You shut us down
when you froze our accounts.
I think you mean
your mother's accounts.
This is a start-up business,
my mother's a key investor.
What about
those big investors
at your party?
Don't go near them.
Why, they see something
you don't want us
to hear about?
Maybe Mom wandered out,
caused a scene,
embarrassed you?
So you drove home
the burning importance
of being a silent partner.
Why are you
trying to destroy me
when the monster
who tortured my mother
is still out there?
Joe, just cough up
the party Iist.
No way in hell
you're ever gonna get
that Iist.
Damn it to hell,
you got crap
all over my shoes.
If you wanna bitch,
switch places.
(EXCLAIMING)
This one's full of rancid
salmon puffs.
FIN: Maybe they didn't go over
too big at Joe's party.
You sure it's Joe's?
Incoming.
Housekeeper said she threw out
three bags with yellow ties.
We gotta check all of them.
Well, here's a Lick magazine
with Joe's address on it.
Hair dye for men.
And something that's
best applied anally.
Stop jerking around
and find the guest book.
Hello!
Names?
Cigarette butts.
One of them's
gotta be our weapon.
You're keeping me busy,
Detectives. Forty-five
cigarette butts in all.
Five different brands.
Any way to match
the butts to the wounds?
If we were talking about
cigars or slims.
Unfortunately, most brands
are identical in size,
so there's no way
to narrow down
by wound diameter.
Just need to prove
that the attack took place
in that apartment.
Any way to find
flesh residue?
Well, at
the point of inhalation,
the burn zone temperature
is around 850 and 900 degrees.
Seared away
all the evidence.
DNA from
saliva on the filters
will take weeks to run.
We're screwed.
Not really.
Fingerprints.
Ninhydrin.
I'II spray them all
and then I'II run them
through the system.
We already
checked out Joe,
no priors.
Yeah, but maybe not all
his mystery smoking guests
are as clean.
Investing in one of these
is Iike buying a Monet.
It's easy on the eyes
as it gains in value.
Will you excuse me, please?
Hi, there!
Hugh Wilkins?
How can I help you?
By fessing up.
The Tychon Food Chopper,
it couldn't really
slice and dice a beer can,
now, could it?
Sure it could.
Of course, you have to follow
the instructional video,
sold separately.
How did you...
When you got bonded to sell
that crap door-to-door,
you gave up your prints.
We found one on
a cigarette butt you Ieft
at Joe Sherman's party.
Did you have any trouble
with his moms that night?
His mother?
I never even saw her.
What's this about?
Joe.
Yeah.
What's his racket?
Oh! The Trifecta Wizard.
It's an unbeatable
horseracing software program.
Unlike his other
get-rich-quick schemes,
this one was "a sure thing."
His other ventures
stumble out of the gate?
Habitually.
You should ask Joe about
his IIama ranch in Texas.
That one even
scared off his mother.
She was an investor?
Up until two years ago,
she was
his principal backer.
After that, she had to
guard what was Ieft
of the nest egg.
She cut
the purse strings.
That must have
pissed Joe off.
Well, he went broke.
But then the old Iady
moves back in, Io and behold,
he has start-up money again.
According to everyone
we spoke to, Joe has been
a Ieech his entire Iife.
Right behind you,
speak of the devil.
Look, I asked you to stay away
from my investors.
Three just pulled out.
And we're only through
half the Iist.
JOE: You're ruining me.
Like you were
ruining your mother?
We pulled
her financials, Joe.
The only money
I ever took from her
was rent.
Five times a month?
AII made to cash.
Let me see those.
(SIGHS)
Andy.
FIN: He your bookie?
My college dropout son.
He's talked her into
writing checks before.
And was Andy
at the party?
He stopped by, uninvited,
with one of his
deadbeat friends.
He needed a place
to sober up.
They spend the night?
No. I gave him just an hour.
Told him to stay in the den,
out of sight.
Where does
your son Iive?
Jersey.
With his mom.
Now will you Ieave
my investors alone?
What the hell?
ANDY: Who Iet you in?
Your mother.
We heard you were
on the party circuit.
What?
Dad's?
Monday night?
I don't call
being exiled to
the broom closet a party.
We also heard that
your dad wasn't too proud
of his dropout son.
Dropout?
Is that what he said?
STABLER: What do you say?
My gran set me up with
a college trust fund. I had to
drop out when Dad drained it.
AII he Ieft me with
is a ratty old
IIama-hair coat.
Yeah? And now Gran
won't write out
any more checks.
That must've
pissed you off.
I'm not pissed at Gran.
It's my dad who's a jerk.
I'm the only one
who ever visited her
at the home.
You see her
at the party?
Of course I did.
She write you out
any more checks?
Sometimes
she gives me presents.
She doesn't even know
her own name. Must take
some prodding on your part.
She's the only person
in my Iife who ever gave
a crap about me.
I would never,
ever hurt her.
What about that guy
that you hang out with?
Hal?
Yeah. Does he smoke?
Yeah.
Was he ever alone
with your gran
at the party?
I don't know.
You don't know.
I might have
nodded off a bit.
Mmm-hmm.
Where can we find
this Hal?
At work.
Jubilee Towers,
where my gran was.
That's where we met.
He took care of her.
Leave me alone!
Stop it!
You can't make me!
Let go,
Mr. Leonard!
(CRASHING)
Idiot!
Look what you did!
Hey, Hal,
calm down.
Who are you?
We're the police.
Sir, are you okay?
He's trying to kill me.
What do you want?
Are you always this good
with the patients?
Help me,
don't Iet him
take me away.
Don't you worry,
nobody's taking
anybody anywhere.
Oh, please,
don't encourage him.
This happens every day.
Mr. Leonard hates needles.
But he is going to chemo.
We need to talk.
In private.
Look, I've got three patients
Iate for appointments
and I've had nothing
but troublemakers all day.
Troublemakers?
How about Bess Sherman?
She one of your troublemakers?
HAL: No, she's a dream.
We heard
you ran into her
on the outside.
With the end
of a cigarette butt.
Maybe that rings a bell.
I don't know
what you guys
have been smoking,
but I've got
Iives to save.
Jubilee Towers adheres
to the highest standards
of safety.
Even we
non-medical employees
are trained in CPR.
Well, have the safety
standards been slipping since
Hal started working here?
Are all of those
complaints?
You have to understand
that many patients
will complain if you just
Iook at them wrong.
Hal's worked here
a year.
He's only had
one serious complaint
against him.
Which was what?
Well, Mr. Jackson
accused Hal of trying
to suffocate him.
Well, did you
call the police?
Uh...
Mr. Jackson is senile.
Well, did you
at Ieast check on it?
Of course I did,
but we found nothing.
You have to realize
that fiction and reality
blend in the mind
of some of our patients.
You know, we get rape reports
after the enema cart
makes its rounds.
Hal didn't strike me
as a real people person. Now,
why hire someone Iike that?
It's a very Iow-paying job.
Not a Iot of people find
changing adult diapers
rewarding.
What else
is in the file?
Just incident reports,
on-duty injuries...
Whoa, whoa.
Hal injured
patients?
No, patients
injured him.
Mr. Jackson?
Yeah?
You the nude models
I ordered?
No. Actually we're...
That was a joke.
What can I do you for?
Heard you had
problems with Hal,
the nurse's aide.
That man's
a serial killer.
Tell us about it.
He pinches me all the time.
One day I bit him, real hard.
Son of a bitch
cut off my oxygen,
whispered,
"You're gonna die soon,
old man."
And nobody
did anything
about it?
MR. JACKSON: Hell, no.
Took his word over mine.
Well, we believe you.
He done anything
since then?
Sheet people scared him off.
Who?
You know who I mean.
KIan comes at night,
roams the halls.
Better watch your back.
Okay. We had Mr. Jackson
till he took a Ieft
at Mississippi.
Yeah, but even paranoids
are right sometimes.
Oh, we know Hal.
A Iittle short
on the bedside manner.
STABLER: Okay. Well, we heard
you scratched his face.
Why?
I can't say for sure.
Oh, you know,
just tell them.
It was after
I broke my hip
Iast fall.
Yeah, taking
dancing Iessons
for that cruise.
Anyway,
when I came back
after surgery,
I woke up one night,
convinced that someone
was suffocating me.
Was it Hal?
Well, it sure
wasn't the morphine.
AII I know is that I thought
I was dying. I started
clawing at something.
Then, suddenly,
I could breathe again.
When I opened my eyes,
Hal was standing over me,
his face scratched
and bleeding.
What'd he say?
That I was hallucinating.
He pinches the patients,
hides their dentures,
and when he wants a real rush,
he plays keep-away
with their oxygen.
But here's the rub.
Every victim was either
doped up or senile.
Making them
the perfect victims.
Even if they remember
what happened, they're still
unreliable witnesses.
That's probably why
he took the job
in the first place.
He gets his rocks off
watching them suffer.
What do you got?
A notice of claim
filed six months ago
against Jubilee Towers.
A $10 million
negligence suit
brought about by the estate
of a deceased former resident.
What happened?
Doesn't say.
A settlement was reached
with a nondisclosure clause.
Who was named in the suit?
Everyone the dead woman
came into contact with,
from the director
down to the Iowliest
of nurse's aides.
Including our pal Hal?
This dead woman
have a name?
Dahlia Brown.
I'm already working
on an exhumation order.
Not bad for nine months
in the ground.
Skin's perfectly intact.
She's Iost some muscle tone,
but haven't we all?
You know the day's coming
when embalming fluid
is put in a Iotion.
WARNER: Until then that time,
it will remain the medical
examiner's worst nightmare.
When the undertaker
flushed out her blood, he
also flushed away any toxins.
The embalming fluid then
dissolved any protein-based
poison in her organs.
Anything you
could test for?
Tissue toxicology,
heavy metals,
which came back negative
for arsenic, Iead and cyanide.
The death certificate
said cardiac arrest.
Which means
we don't know
what really happened,
but we don't think
it was foul play.
The M.E.'s gotta put
something down
for cause of death.
What would you have put?
I don't know,
but I certainly
would have mentioned this.
A tiny pinprick hole
unaccounted for
in the medical records.
She was in the hospital wing.
Maybe they gave her an IV.
She was in to have
her knee drained.
The hole's in the wrong place.
You settled with
the deceased's daughter.
Realize you made
a mistake?
No, it was cheaper
than going to court.
Well, then
what happened with Dahlia?
Well, grieving people
sometimes have trouble
accepting the death
of Ioved ones.
The pain makes them Iook
for someone to blame.
Well, speaking of which,
I noticed in Dahlia's records
that her Iast supper
was delivered by somebody
with the initials H.S.
STABLER: Any other nurses'
aides with those initials
besides Hal Shipley?
We're gonna need to speak
with anybody
who might have seen him
with Dahlia that night.
Okay.
Man, I don't want
to grow old.
In our Iine of work,
be careful what you
wish for. How'd you do?
No one remembers
any fireworks
between them,
but I did find out
a Iittle about Dahlia.
Great Iady,
Iousy patient?
When she was in pain,
she was a pain.
Needy and demanding,
Hal's favorite.
Yeah, he had means,
he had opportunity
with Bess, Dahlia,
Mr. Jackson, a dozen others.
That we know of.
He's Iike a psycho kid
in a candy store.
Time to take away
his candy.
Excuse me, where...
Room 410's coding.
Quick,
get the crash cart.
410 is Bess' room.
ANNOUNCER: Code blue
to room 410.
Code blue to room 410.
WOMAN: Hurry! In here!
Hope.
You were right.
I saw it was him.
He was...
Let's calm down.
Just take a breath
and tell us what happened.
After we talked,
I called Hal in
and, you know,
I told him to finish
his shift and Ieave.
He wanted to know why,
and I told him.
I said, "It's because
of the way
you treat the patients."
And he was furious
and he just stormed out.
You can't help in there.
Now, did he make
any threats?
No, but after
what we talked about,
you know...
I was worried, so I came down
to check on Bess,
and that's when I saw him.
What was he doing?
He was just...
He was Ieaving the room,
but I didn't even think.
I just went in there
and her pulse was weak
and thready
and I just pushed
the code button
and started CPR.
Hold on, hold on.
Bess?
NURSE: Move her
to the full-care wing.
I'm gonna go with her.
NURSE: Put her on a monitor
and start an IV.
She had a fresh
needle mark.
What are you still
doing here?
We heard you were fired.
The pencil-pushing
bootlicker told me
to finish off my shift.
Account for
your whereabouts
for the Iast 15 minutes.
Stockroom.
Taking inventory.
Let's go for a ride, Hal.
Am I under arrest?
No.
Then screw off.
Excuse me?
Whatever. Let's party.
I hope I'm not
interrupting anything.
Yeah, a big
tearful goodbye.
Oh, you really don't
wanna miss this.
STABLER: You got
a Iatent print report?
Hal's known,
identified print.
From that Iast cig break
at the Towers.
You really shouldn't Iitter.
You can't do that.
Yeah, well, you
voluntarily discarded it.
Meaning Iegally,
your butt is ours.
As is this one,
retrieved from Joe Sherman's
party trash.
Well, that Iooks
Iike a match.
Seven-point.
We've got a bifurcation,
three ending ridges
and an island.
Lots of guys
were smoking
at the party.
Yeah? Well, how many
had seared flesh at the end
of their cancer sticks?
That we can match
to Bess Sherman.
Uh... Where's the Iab
on the DNA?
I'm on my way there
right now.
Call us when you know.
When we have the results,
we won't need a confession
from pantywaist here.
No confession,
no plea bargain.
Which means
you do the max.
CSU said they couldn't
get flesh off
of the cigarette.
Oops.
Okay, I burned her.
What?
I burned her.
Why?
It's not Iike
I planned it.
Andy owed me a Iot of money,
which he said he could get
from Grandma Bess.
Owed you money
for what?
Nothing to do
with this.
He pulls a check
from her purse, says,
"You need to sign this, Gran."
Bam, she does.
So it's so easy,
you think you're gonna
try it yourself.
So you go back in,
get another check.
And she yells, "Rape."
Just Iike she used to
at the home when
I'd help dress her. As if.
Your job sucked, we know.
No, you don't know!
I had to clean them
and feed them
and wipe up their crap.
STABLER: They owed you.
So all she had to do
was sign the other check.
But what does she do?
She screams? She tried
to get you in trouble.
So I go over
to quiet her down,
and my cigarette
accidentally burns her chest.
And she starts screaming rape
at the top of her Iungs,
and I just...
I just snap.
I say,
"I'II show you rape."
And I pull up her nightgown
and I jab that cigarette
at her again and again
and again.
What happened
when you saw her today?
I didn't see her today.
Sweetie, we've got a witness
who saw you Ieaving her room.
Then they were hallucinating.
When she coded,
I was in the stockroom.
I can prove it.
Hal's been hacking into
the drug computer. Son of
a bitch was stealing drugs.
Maybe he fudged
the times.
According to the tech, this
machine is Iike the Fort Knox
of drug dispensers.
Then he's covered.
His Iist of stolen
nurses' codes
matches perfectly
to what we found
in his Iocker.
Well, Hope swore
she saw him Ieaving
Bess' room.
So, if the computer's
not Iying...
Bess isn't the first patient
Hope has saved, you know.
Really?
She found Mrs. Mercer
in cardiac arrest
Iast Christmas Eve.
Same situation?
She started CPR?
Can you imagine
a more depressing day
to die?
Sounds Iike
a Christmas miracle.
I think there was
one other time.
Zona?
ZONA: Yeah?
Didn't Hope Garrett
save another patient before?
Oh. She tried.
The guy didn't make it.
No, this was a woman.
Remember, uh, senior prom?
Oh, yeah.
Senior prom
with the emphasis
on "senior"?
It's a dance
the Level One-ers throw
every spring.
Their anti-youth
counterstatement.
You know, the punch always
gets spiked, somebody tries
to Iimbo and breaks a hip.
So this woman that Hope saved
was otherwise
a healthy dance casualty.
Well, she wasn't dancing.
She collapsed
at the buffet table.
It's a good thing
Hope knows her CPR.
I'm not gonna Iet
anybody else hurt you, Ma.
You're coming home with me.
You sure that's
in her best interest?
Oh, I don't know,
maybe I'II throw her
back in
with that Iunatic
who burned her,
Iike you did.
Dad, you're upsetting Gran.
JOE: No Iip from you.
You're the one that started
this whole thing by Ietting
that drug supplier
into my house.
I'II come by Iater, Gran.
I'II bring those brochures
of the other homes.
Sweet boy.
Just so you know,
Hal's in custody. He won't be
hurting anybody else.
Oh, you're so quick.
It only took two attempts
on my mother's Iife
for you to figure it out.
You're my friend,
aren't you?
Yes, I am, Bess.
Make this man be quiet.
Don't you worry about it.
He's just Ieaving.
JOE: Guess again.
I was wrongly accused.
The protective order
was dropped.
Well, I hear that
the misappropriation
of funds investigation
is just beginning.
Uh, I'm sorry,
is this a bad time?
No, you're welcome
anytime.
And thanks for
saving my mother's Iife.
Oh, well, Bess
is one of
our favorites.
No way
she's going anywhere
while I'm around.
So, you have saved,
what, three now?
Including Bess,
yeah, I guess so.
And just that
one Ioss.
Mr. Tazelo.
Yeah, what happened?
I was passing by X-ray and
there he was, just slumped
over in his wheelchair.
So, he'd been Ieft
unattended?
I'm sure an aide
was on the way.
But he was alone
Iong enough
to die unnoticed.
Or was he still breathing
when you found him?
He was. I mean,
you know, he was dead.
But you still tried
to resuscitate him.
Well, I didn't know
how Iong
he'd been there.
We bring people back
all the time. So, I just, um,
you know, pulled him
to the floor and started CPR.
I didn't want to give up.
They had to pull me off.
This woman
is a complete wacko.
It could be
malignant hero syndrome.
A person
sets up a risky situation
to create an emergency
and then comes out a hero.
Like a fireman
starting a fire.
It's all about personal gain.
In this case, attention,
prestige.
Like Munchausen by proxy.
She kills people
just to bring them back
to feel better about herself.
What was she
shooting them up with?
I picked up
Bess' tox screen report
from the hospital wing.
There's no poisons,
no anomalous drugs.
She had epinephrine
in her system.
That's what they give
when your heart stops,
right?
Exactly.
I guess that's why it's under
the "no big surprise" column.
Well, Hope revived Bess
with CPR.
Once her heart was started
again, she shouldn't have been
given epinephrine.
And according to
this chart, she wasn't.
What would happen
if that was given to somebody
who had a healthy heart?
It would speed up
heart rate,
increasing cardiac output
and blood pressure
to a dangerous Ievel.
Mimicking a heart attack.
Perfect crime.
Son of a bitch.
Hope was a nurse.
She worked at
Oak GIade Nursing Home.
Her Iicense
was revoked
15 years ago.
FIN: On what grounds?
Gross negligence.
"Failed to dilute
potassium chloride doses."
It's cozy, isn't it?
An elevator adjacent. Do you
Iike to swim, Mr. Hamrick?
Because you're gonna Iove
the water aerobics class.
I hear that really gets
your heart rate up.
It's a hell of a Iot safer
than being injected
with epinephrine.
Is everything
all right?
Absolutely.
Excuse me one minute.
EIIiot, OIivia. Um...
This probably isn't
a good time to talk
about the unpleasantness.
Oh, we don't plan
to discuss it here.
Good.
A squad room would be
much more appropriate.
Did something new
happen with Hal?
Well, our techs
pulled the used syringes
on the Sharps boxes here.
Hal's prints
weren't on
any of them.
Well, he had access to,
you know,
over a dozen boxes
of surgical gloves,
so maybe
he thought
to use a pair.
STABLER: You didn't.
They found your prints
on a syringe of epi in the box
at the nurses' station.
Well, you know Hal did it.
He confessed.
BENSON: To burning her.
But you didn't give a damn
about that as Iong as
you could grab the spotlight.
Why are you trying
to embarrass me?
People can hear you.
Drama queen, you enjoy
being the center of attention.
Hope Garrett, you're
under arrest for the attempted
murder of Bess Sherman...
What are you talking about?
...and suspicion of murders
committed at
Oak GIade Nursing Home.
This is ridiculous, okay?
You have the right
to remain silent.
This is absolutely ridiculous.
It's a mistake.
If you give up that right,
anything you say...
This is a mistake!
I examined the records
of 22 deaths at Oak GIade
between May of 1982
and March of 1987.
And what did you find?
Evidence of
potassium poisoning
in seven of them.
Why wasn't this discovered
in any of their autopsies?
WARNER: People expect
the elderly to die.
An autopsy is performed
maybe one out of 25 cases.
CABOT: Well, surely
some of them were examined?
Yes, but when cells die,
they release potassium.
It would have been
impossible to detect.
So, how did you?
By examining
their EKGs.
Could you please
show us on the board?
AII showed tachycardia
and a widened QRS,
indicative of hyperkalemia.
CABOT: Uh...
In Iayman's terms?
WARNER: Their hearts
were beating too fast.
Dr. Warner, what causes there
to be too much potassium
in the blood?
Kidney failure can,
or it was introduced
by an outside source.
Did any of them
have kidney disease?
No. Someone administered
Iethal doses.
Do you have any idea
how many mistakes
doctors make,
how many times
I've covered their asses?
Counselor,
you control your client,
or I'II have her removed
from this courtroom.
Yes, Your Honor.
JUDGE: The jury will disregard
the defendant's outburst.
The People may proceed.
One Iast question, Dr. Warner.
In all these cases, how many
different administering nurses
were there?
Just one.
Hope Garrett.
Yes, but you
have to understand
every Iast one of them
was at death's door.
JUDGE: Counselor.
Your Honor, I'm sorry.
This won't happen again.
You know, I don't think
you realize how Iittle time
that they had Ieft.
I don't care if they were
on their very Iast breath.
You had no right
to take it from them.
You don't understand.
I help people.
What do you do?
You stupid bitch!
Hope!
This is not helping.
Court is recessed.
Bailiff, take the jury out.
How can you just sit there
and Iet them crucify me?
I don't need this, you know.
I'm Ieaving.
JUDGE: Court officers,
remove the defendant.
This is not fair. AII you
tell them about is
Oak GIade and Jubilee Towers.
But I've worked in homes
for 15 years in between.
And how many of them
did you kill?
I didn't kill anybody.
Maybe a few of them
wouldn't pull through for me,
but I have saved hundreds.
Hundreds.
And you don't even care
about them, do you?
Take your hands off of me!
Let go of me!