NARRATOR: In the criminal
justice system,
sexually based offenses
are considered
especially heinous.
In New York City,
the dedicated detectives
who investigate
these vicious felonies
are members
of an elite squad known
as the Special Victims Unit.
These are their stories.
She's the COO now.
You need to
watch your ass.
If Amanda wants to fire me,
not much I can do about it.
Fight back, Mark.
She humiliates you
in front of everybody,
treats you Iike her
personal assistant.
File a complaint
with Human Resources.
And I'II still be
out of a job.
I'm serious.
Hey, what the hell
happened here?
You smell that?
Yeah.
It's Iike a urinal.
Is that
what I think it is?
(MOANING)
Oh, my God! It's Amanda.
Who did this to you?
Perineal bruising
and tearing
from rape and sodomy.
Friction burns
around the neck,
wrist and ankles,
and a scalp Iaceration
from being struck
with a sharp object.
The wound's deep
but not serious.
Any fluids present?
No, he wore condoms.
Your Iab should find
Iubricant in the specimen.
She say anything?
Not to me.
But maybe the other officers
will have her statement now.
It's Exam Room 3.
WOMAN: You have
the right to an attorney.
If you cannot afford
an attorney...
Detective Stabler, SVU.
What's going on?
FBI.
This is a rape victim
in our jurisdiction.
Not our concern.
At the moment,
she's under arrest.
Ms. Curry,
do you understand
your rights
as I've read them
to you?
Why are you guys
doing this to me?
I was attacked
and raped.
Do you understand
your rights?
Yes.
Look, we have to get
Ms. Curry's statement.
There's a rapist out there.
We'd Iike to get
a description.
You can do that
in federal Iockup,
but it's gonna take
a while to process her.
What are the charges?
Securities fraud,
violating interstate
and international
banking Iaws,
money Iaundering
for a criminal enterprise
and tax evasion.
Where the hell's our witness?
You know how
the Feds are.
They just Iove to flex
their muscles.
They usually work with us,
so why the stall?
CLAUDIA: Where are they?
MAN: Lockup Two.
I think we're about
to find out.
Assistant US Attorney
CIaudia Williams.
My apologies for the delay.
Where's Ms. Curry?
Outside.
I wanted to
talk to you first.
You cannot interrogate
the prisoner
about the federal case
against her
or anything
relating to it.
Well, what if her
criminal affiliations
directly relate
to the attack?
Well, if Ms. Curry's
business associates
were involved,
she'd be in the morgue.
Money Iaundering's
a RICO charge.
So she's in bed
with organized crime.
We talking LCN
or the Russians?
Stop fishing,
Detective Stabler.
Well, if you'd just
share a Iittle bit,
I wouldn't have to.
There's too much at stake.
We're not interested
in your case.
We're trying to find
a rapist,
but we can't do that
if you obstruct justice.
Well, until you file a 61,
I'm not obstructing anything.
And unless I allow you access,
you won't be able to do that.
So, what's it gonna be?
Oh, I guess
we'II just bend over.
I'II be right outside.
I wouldn't have it
any other way.
Thanks a Iot. Ms. Curry,
have a seat please.
Where should I start?
BENSON:
Well, why don't you start
by taking us
through your day?
Gym, work, Iunch,
work, meeting, work.
Where do you
work out?
It's called Workout Studio.
Couple of blocks
from the office.
Did you go out
for Iunch?
No, I ate at my desk.
Delivered?
My assistant
went out and got it.
When were you attacked?
Around 11:00.
I was in my office
crunching the next
quarter projections
for an emergency meeting.
Anybody else around?
Everyone Ieft
hours before.
That's why when I
heard the noise,
I went Iooking.
But as soon as I
opened up my door,
this man rushed me,
and after that,
it was Iights out.
Can you describe him?
Not really.
I just got a glimpse.
White, average height.
Any distinguishing marks?
Anything you can remember?
No.
Did he say anything?
Yeah.
That it was payback.
I thought he was
going to kill me.
Okay, is it possible that
the people you're accused
of working for
might have been trying
to send you a message?
Could be.
They're brutal, vicious men.
But they don't make a move
without Sergei's say so.
He would've cut my throat...
That's enough.
Get her out of there.
Good news is
we got enough urine
to test.
If we're Iucky,
there'II be some
DNA in it.
Perp gave her
a golden shower?
Rape took place on the table.
Found footprints
where he stood
over her.
Making the
humiliation complete.
Yeah.
The bad news is
there's too many prints
and fibers.
This kind
of building security,
maybe our perp
actually works here.
Or pretended to.
We found a
cleaning crew jumpsuit
stuffed under
the reception desk.
What company?
Atlas.
The great thing about
criminals, no matter how
smart they think they are,
they're not
smarter than me.
You found traces
of seminal fluid.
Not a drop.
But we did find
a few short and curlies
that didn't belong
to the victim.
Okay, so we got DNA.
Matching two
other rape cases,
both in Brooklyn.
AIso, your perp suffers
from diabetes.
How do you know that?
We found glucose
but no ketones in the urine.
I'd say he's
a middle-aged onset diabetic
who's not taking his meds
or doesn't know
that he's sick.
Based on what?
The Ievel of sugar's
pretty high,
and juvenile diabetics
Iearn early on
that if they forget
an insulin injection,
it can prove fatal.
Our serial rapist
started with two
Brooklyn targets.
The first victim,
Petra Ivankov,
was raped six months ago.
Worked as a stripper
at the Volga CIub,
a known front
for the Russian mob.
Mob boss
Sergei Perlman's girlfriend.
She got smoked
after talking to Brooklyn SVU
about her rape.
They were probably
scared she was gonna
slip pillow talk.
Number two is Perlman's
baby sister, Tatiana.
She died of uterine cancer
three months ago.
BIitz attacked
after a chemo treatment.
Took a pretty bad beating.
Our guy is definitely
Iosing control
and escalating.
Our victim, Amanda Curry,
raped, beaten and sodomized.
What did Brooklyn say
about the Russian connection
between their two victims?
I mean,
why choose these women
if not trying to get
at Perlman somehow?
Did they even
talk to this guy?
Organized Crime Bureau
shut them down.
Wouldn't Iet them near him.
Completely stalled
their investigation.
Sergei's a major player.
If we're Iooking
for someone with a grudge,
it's gonna be a Iong Iist.
What about physical evidence
other than the DNA?
The Iab's still working
on print elimination.
But they found a discarded
cleaning crew jumpsuit
from Atlas Janitorial.
The supervisor mentioned
a car blocking
the service entrance,
so we checked
the outside cameras.
The way
they were positioned,
you can't see much.
AII we saw was
a Iate model Ford Focus,
Jersey tags.
We can only make out "JLQ."
What about
cameras inside?
Well, they're in
the stairwells
and they're outside,
so female employees
feel safe working Iate.
I say we check out
the Russian angle.
Knock on a few doors
in Brighton Beach,
see what shakes Ioose.
Well, the Feds
will be all over us
before we ask
the first question.
Well, we do have a job to do.
Before we declare war,
there is another connection.
Both our victim
and the stripper
belonged to the same gym.
Workout Studio
was Iisted in her file.
What about Perlman's sister?
Well, nothing was
in her file.
Brooklyn probably
didn't ask
because she
was dying of cancer.
Okay, here it is.
AII three women
had recent memberships.
We had sent out
a promotional mailer
to businesses
and Iocal residents.
What's all this about?
An assault.
You're kidding.
When did they start
their memberships?
(SIGHING)
Within the Iast
year-and-a-half.
BENSON: They know each other?
They work out together?
I never saw them
with each other.
We're gonna need a Iist
of all your members
and all your male employees.
We have about
500 members
and just 10
on full-time staff.
Who owns the club?
My father.
You have any employees
40 years or older?
Just my dad.
Everyone else is under 30.
STABLER: What capacity
does he work in?
I run the place.
Dad just Iooks
over the books.
Makes sure we have
what we need.
How often does he
come in here?
Wait a second.
Dad doesn't interact
with our clients.
He wouldn't even know them.
What kind of car
does he drive?
A Focus.
PIate's a match.
Still not enough
for a warrant.
I'm Peter Sipes.
My son called.
He tells me
you have questions.
Mr. Sipes, if it's
all right with you,
we'd Iike to do this
down at our precinct.
Am I under arrest?
Not yet.
I can assure you
I didn't assault anyone.
Then you got
nothing to worry about.
(PETER SIGHING)
I don't see why you had to
drag me down here for this.
I've done nothing wrong.
Gregory.
It's Mike from LA.
I thought you were dead.
You're drunk.
I don't know you.
I swear, you got
a twin out there,
you know that?
Take it easy.
Can I get you
something to drink?
Soda, if you have it.
I thought you diabetics
had to control
your sugar intake.
Maybe you'd Iike some water?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Where were you
the night before Iast?
At my job.
I'm the shift supervisor
at a packaging plant
in East Orange.
So you own a gym
and you work?
Well, it's not a chain
Iike Bally's, Detective.
What shift do you work?
I work from 10:00 p.m.
to 6:00 a.m.
You drive to work?
What's this
really about?
Rape, Mr. Sipes.
I did not rape anybody.
Then you'II be willing
to Iet us take a mouth swab.
Make this
whole thing go away.
You want my DNA,
you're gonna have
to get a warrant.
We don't have
enough for a judge,
but I don't want to cut
this guy Ioose.
Let's do a voice Iineup.
I'II keep the suspect
on ice until then.
Well, we know how well
those hold up in court.
Well, it doesn't matter.
Amanda Curry
picks this guy's voice
out of the six,
we got enough for a warrant.
The AUSA
is not gonna Iet us
just take her prisoner
for a ride.
I'II have Cabot
pave the way.
Sorry. Amanda Curry's
not here.
She get transferred
to another facility?
Nope.
Does it say where she is?
I don't even know
who she is.
There is no record
of an Amanda Curry
in the system.
But that's impossible.
We interviewed her
in that cell yesterday.
I don't know who
the hell you talked to,
but no one was processed
through here by that name.
She's gone.
Metropolitan Correctional
claims they never
even heard of her.
I got a call from
the US Attorney's office
with assurances.
As soon as we
make an arrest,
they will produce
Amanda Curry for trial.
How are we supposed to do that
without the cooperation
of our complaining witness?
We ran the rape suspect's
prints off the coffee mug.
We got zip.
No arrests, no record.
So we checked
the property rolls,
the tax rolls, city permits.
Seems that Peter and his son
have consecutive
Social Security numbers.
How's that possible?
A few years back,
a couple got
pinched in Delaware
for running a stock scam.
The entire family
had consecutive numbers.
They'd been relocated
in the Witness
Protection Program.
It's gotta be WITSEC.
That's run by US Marshals,
which would explain
the US Attorney's
interest in this case.
There was a drunk
cuffed out in the corridor.
He recognized our suspect.
He called him Gregory.
And then he just waves it off
Iike it was an honest mistake.
We should talk to him.
Find out who Peter really is.
We do that, we'II blow
a protected witness's cover.
AII right, you and Munch
sit this drunk down,
and after that,
put him in our holding pen
for the duration.
Who we Iooking for?
I'II go ask
the desk sergeant.
You know, if our rapist
is a protected witness
how are we gonna
get around the Feds?
We won't have to.
You commit a crime
in the program,
you go to prison.
Sammy the Bull
is serving 15
for dealing drugs.
We'II check Peter's alibi,
see if he
was working his shift,
but he's still testifying,
they're not gonna
hand him over.
FIN: Michael Kerring, get up.
You got company.
Whatever it is,
I didn't do it.
You have an interesting
résumé, Michael.
Shoplifting,
a few B and E's
and purse snatching.
I'm not very good at it
or I wouldn't keep
getting pinched.
So I know I can't help you.
What do you guys
do here, anyway?
We catch rapists,
pedophiles
and murderers.
Damn.
Well, in that case,
I can honestly say
that whatever it is,
I didn't do it.
I am no short eyes.
I have never touched a woman
that I didn't have to pay for.
SIow your roll, moron.
We're just Iooking
for some background.
We brought a guy
in on a rape beef,
and we're told
you were friends.
Turns out he's got
a couple of aliases
we want to check.
I don't know
anybody Iike that.
You saw him right
out there in the hallway.
You called him Gregory.
I was drunk.
It couldn't have been him.
He's been dead for years.
MUNCH: Who's dead?
Gregory.
Rossovitch.
He used to run
with some serious hitters,
in way over his head.
Who did he run with?
Russians in West Hollywood.
Pulling gas tax,
Medicaid fraud,
shipping bootleg vodka,
kidnapping, the whole nine.
If he was that big time,
how'd you know him?
I used to be a gas jockey.
They put me in charge
of pumping hijacked diesel.
How'd he die?
Car bomb.
Was that really him?
Don't tell me.
I don't want to know.
FIN: What's the problem?
They put a heavy contract
out on Gregory.
You open this up,
you're asking for trouble.
Why'd they want him dead?
I heard
he was spilling his guts
to the Feds.
Bodies were dropping
all over the place.
Friends, business associates.
They even killed his parents.
That's when I moved East.
Guess I didn't go far enough.
BENSON: Looks Iike
we're too Iate.
Hi. Lynn Moody.
You folks interested
in seeing the house?
Actually we're interested
in the whereabouts
of the owner.
Oh. That I can't tell you.
I only got the Iisting
Iast night.
Who hired you?
CIaudia Williams.
When I got here,
there was a moving crew
in overdrive.
CIeaned the entire house out
in under four hours.
I've never seen
anything Iike it.
I don't suppose
I can convince you
to Iet me do the talking?
What's there
to talk about?
Either the AUSA
hands over our suspect
or she goes to jail
for obstruction.
We want her cooperation.
Peter wasn't at work
the night of the rape.
We've got a warrant
for his blood.
What else do we need?
You can go in now.
Thank you for taking
the time to see us,
Ms. Williams.
CIaudia. How can I help you?
Tell us the whereabouts
of Peter Sipes,
we'II get out of your hair.
No.
What do you mean, no?
You're harboring
a rapist, Counselor,
and using federal tax dollars
to do it.
Was there a trial
that I don't know about,
Detective Stabler?
We have a warrant
for Peter Sipes' blood,
duly signed by
a superior court judge.
I'II have it drawn
and delivered to your Iab.
Is that amenable?
The evidentiary chain
has to be followed.
We draw the blood, not you.
Now we're splitting hairs.
Is Gregory Rossovitch,
aka Peter Sipes, that
important to your case
that you're willing
to Iet him skate
on three class B felonies?
CLAUDIA: The DOJ
does not condone
criminal behavior.
Okay. Then why'd you move him?
Because he told us
he was recognized
by someone in your precinct.
Most of what
we now know about the mob
comes from Peter's testimony,
and he is an invaluable asset,
and we will protect him
at all costs.
At the expense of three women
who were raped and brutalized
by the man
that you are now shielding
from justice.
If he did do that,
he will go to prison,
but I think you have
the wrong man.
Where's Amanda Curry?
Unavailable to you.
How is she connected
to Peter Sipes?
AII of the victims
Iead back to the Russian mob.
Do you really think
that's a coincidence?
What is Peter's motive?
Why would he rape
these women?
You can tell by
the extent of the damage
that he's escalating.
Does somebody have to die
for you to care?
I know what you're up against.
But if, for one second,
I thought that my witness
was responsible,
I'd turn him over.
Why are you
protecting this guy?
Two hundred
and fifty-seven murders,
all ordered
by Sergei Perlman.
Policemen, businessmen,
because they wouldn't
pay extortion.
Even children,
butchered for fear
they might grow up
and seek revenge.
We've solved almost half,
and we've connected
California to New York
through Peter Sipes.
Does that answer
your question?
Can she really stop us?
No, but she can slow us down.
Hinder our investigation.
You know, I don't care
who that woman works for.
We can't Iet her do that.
CIaudia Williams
is doing her job.
She has an obligation
to protect her witnesses.
We have an obligation
to protect innocent women.
So whose side of the fence
you gonna sit on?
You seem awfully sure
Peter Sipes is guilty.
What are we
supposed to think?
It can't be easy
Iosing your identity,
starting over.
These people
cost him his past,
they're threatening
his survival.
I'm just not so sure
he would jeopardize
his Iast Iine of defense
against the very people
who want him dead.
What you're saying is
then that organized crime
takes precedence
over rape.
Arguments can be made
for both.
AIex, we don't have
that Iuxury.
We're working with
a serial rapist here.
And the next woman,
I'm telling you,
he's gonna kill her.
I will file a habeas
in the morning.
If CIaudia Williams
cannot produce the body,
the judge is going to
find her in contempt.
CABOT: The People request
habeas corpus, Your Honor.
A warrant was issued
for a blood sample
for a rape suspect
who is a federally
protected witness.
He has been made unavailable
by the United States
Attorney's office.
I made an offer
to have the blood drawn
by the FBI Iab
and delivered to the police.
The case isn't federal.
It falls under
the jurisdiction
of the city and county
of New York.
Special circumstances.
Our witness was recognized.
Objection.
Peter Sipes is a suspect
in three brutal rapes.
He is not a witness.
Nevertheless, he was spotted
at a Iocal precinct
by a former acquaintance
and had to be
moved immediately.
How can we settle
this amicably?
The AUSA is in contempt
of state Iaw, Your Honor.
Either she produces
the suspect
or she should sit in a cell
until she does.
She's made an excellent point.
Why shouldn't I give her
what she wants, CIaudia?
You know what I'm up against.
Perlman has eyes everywhere.
I have made every
effort to cooperate.
I mean, what difference
does it make
who takes the blood?
Chain of evidence.
How can we be sure
it's the suspect's
unless we actually draw it?
Objection.
I'm offended
by the implication.
Who else
would the blood come from?
Mistakes are made
all the time.
If that's true,
then I'm more inclined
to trust a federal
Iab facility
with greater resources
than your own.
Four vials of O negative
belonging to Peter Sipes,
as promised.
Yeah, and how can we be sure
this isn't your blood?
Signed affidavits
by the FBI Iab technicians
stating Iocation,
time and subject.
Or will you argue
conspiracy now?
No, I'm hoping
you just bend the Iaw
and don't actually break it.
I had the blood tested.
I wanted to make sure
that my trust
was not misplaced.
And what did you find?
I included the Iab report
with the affidavits.
I figured you'd want
to test it yourself.
Don't try to tell us
the DNA doesn't match.
Fine, but Peter Sipes
is cleared,
and you still have
a rapist out there.
Does our Iab report
match the FBI results?
Yes, it does.
Peter Sipes is innocent.
But his Y-chromosome
matches the DNA
in the rape kit.
Which means one thing.
His son, Gavin Sipes,
is our rapist.
Well, this time the AUSA
should turn him over
without a fight.
I don't think
she'd do anything
without one.
Gavin Sipes
is a protected witness
by default
because of his
father's testimony.
Just go reason
with Ms. Williams
and close this file.
And if that doesn't work?
Arrest her.
What do you want now?
Your office said
you'd be here.
What happened?
Well, as far
as I can tell,
a recent immigrant
refused to pay
her protection fee.
There are two bodies.
Innocent bystander.
You can see now
what I'm up against.
So what do you need?
Gavin Sipes.
You sure?
DNA doesn't Iie.
Gavin a diabetic?
Yes.
Hand him over.
Gavin Ieft our program
and our protection.
I don't have him.
Since when?
Since we moved his father
and he refused to go.
Said he had enough running
to Iast him for a Iifetime.
Didn't you find
that strange?
No.
Protectees exit
the program all the time.
You know,
we can't force them to join,
we can't stop them
if they want to Ieave.
PIus, he's an adult now.
Children Ieave
when they grow up.
So at Ieast
Iet us talk to Peter.
He'II know
where his son is.
It wouldn't do
any good.
They've severed
all contact.
From now on,
all phone calls and visits
are coordinated and monitored
by the Marshal's Service.
CIaudia, Gavin's not
going to stop,
and I hope
you're not hiding him
for Daddy's sake.
Now, why
would I do that?
To keep your witness
happy and talking.
Look for bad habits.
Gavin has a gambling problem.
But you didn't hear
that from me.
Gavin has racked up
a Iot of debt.
$10,000, $20,000
at a time.
So far, Peter has paid
about $100,000
in debts to Atlantic City.
How can he afford that?
Well, he can't.
They're behind
in the gym Iease
and the rentals
of the equipment.
Check this out.
New Jersey house
has three mortgages on it.
Yeah. $600 and $700 charges
on credit cards.
AII at the same restaurant?
You're sure about that?
Okay, thanks.
Vice says the place
is a known front
for an underground
gambling club downtown.
People can pay off their debts
by charging it to credit cards
for wine and filet
mignon dinners.
Russian restaurant?
No, it's Italian.
Now, the LUDs
from Jersey,
Iook at that,
a Iot of calls from downtown.
The Iast payment
was made a while ago.
Maybe they're not
too happy about that.
NYPD, Benson, Stabler.
Move aside.
Detectives, I'm Joe Tucci.
Tell me how I can help you.
CIose down.
This is an illegal club.
You're not from Vice.
Vice? I don't need to be
from Vice to ruin your day.
Causing you trouble sounds
Iike fun to me.
STABLER:
I'm gonna make the call,
get the ball rolling.
Now, what can I do
to make this right?
PIease.
Gavin Sipes.
He Iikes poker.
He Iikes it a Iot.
But he's not very good at it.
You found a Iot of money
coming your way.
Must've made you mad
when it stopped.
Sometimes people
need convincing.
Yeah?
So what'd you do?
You called Peter up?
Threatened his son's Iife?
You watch too many movies.
Dead men don't pay up.
AII right, come on,
stop screwing around.
Come on,
tell me what you need.
When's the next payment,
who's making it?
Peter called.
He's worried about his kid.
He's due here Iater
to talk over terms.
Well, what's he
so worried about
if you're such
a nice guy?
I'm a businessman.
Peter understands that.
His kid seems Iike
the type to try to skip.
I had to make it clear
to the old man,
his boy walks
into any gambling joint
anywhere in
this country, I'II know.
It won't be pleasant.
How much
does he owe?
400 grand
and still counting.
We're just
gonna stick around
and wait till Dad shows up,
if you don't mind.
My son didn't do this.
You knew he was guilty
after we talked to you.
He's the diabetic.
We need to know
where he is right now.
This is all my fault.
He stays out there,
the next woman could die.
I wish I knew
where he was.
Attacking these women,
gambling debts.
He's in so deep,
I don't know how to fix it.
STABLER: How old was he
when you went
into the program?
EIeven.
We were moved
five times in 10 years.
Every time,
he had to Iearn a new name.
New Iies for his past,
fit into a new school.
He missed so much
that finally
he just quit trying.
How can a Iittle boy
grow up to be a man
when he has no idea
who he really is?
What happened
to his mother?
Anna? Died.
That was before
we came into the program.
In fact, she was the reason
why I approached the Feds.
The Russians murdered her?
Punishment for skimming.
I used to be a chemist.
I was approached
by the Mikaelian Organizatsya
for a smuggling scam.
They moved millions of gallons
of grain alcohol to Europe
disguised as mouthwash.
I taught them
how to extract the blue dye.
It was very successful.
And then it was gas tax,
Medicaid fraud and extortion.
But you're the one
who got greedy,
so why kill your wife
instead of you?
Anna handled the money.
When she was caught
stealing from the family,
they killed her for it.
They were willing to do that
to their own flesh and blood,
what were they going to do
to me and my son?
So that's how
you got involved.
You married into it.
We met during the vodka scam.
After we married, I...
I rose very quickly
to vory v zakonye.
What does that mean?
I'm what's known
as a thief-in-Iaw.
Then there's about 500 eagles.
The rest are
Iieutenants, counselors.
AII in all, there's about
5,000 members in the US,
mostly assimilated
and accent free.
Not as organized
as the Italians,
but getting there.
So why did Gavin
target those women?
How did he even know
who they were?
I told him everything
about the Russians here,
in FIorida and in California.
I kept a record of everybody
I ever did business with.
Names, people I met.
He deserved to know the truth
about what his mother
and I did,
what he'd sacrificed
his Iife for.
Peter, the mob's
gonna wise up pretty soon,
if they haven't already.
He's targeting their women.
Now, what do you think
they're gonna do to him?
They're not gonna do
anything. He's gonna hide.
I cut him off.
I'm broke. I can't pay
his bills anymore.
Which means
he's a dead man.
He's got an addiction.
He can't Iay Iow for Iong.
If you Iove him, turn him in.
The Marshals are bringing
him to me today.
Supervised visit,
before they move me
one more time.
AII I ask is that
you don't hurt my son.
Here's the warrant.
I've notified the Iocals
in Connecticut, you'II be
in their jurisdiction.
Get any calls
from the US
Attorney's office?
No, nothing.
So much for cooperation.
We'II be able
to take custody
as soon as the US Marshals
pull up with our rapist.
AII right, just keep it clean.
I don't want some fight
with the Feds over injuries.
We're gonna Ieave.
We'II get a two-hour jump.
I'm here till it's done.
Car.
STABLER: That's him. Let's go.
Dad!
Oh, my God.
No!
Dad!
Drop it! Do it now!
NYPD.
Drop the gun!
Drop it!
I said drop it.
Hold up. We're cops.
I don't give a damn.
Drop it or I'II drop you.
Both of you,
on the ground.
Move!
You, too.
On the ground.
Get their guns
and cuff them.
GAVIN: Oh, God.
I already told you
what happened.
Tell it to me again.
How'd you get the address?
Peter Sipes
gave it to me.
Then it's convenient
for you he's dead
since we can't
corroborate your story.
Yeah, that's one way
of Iooking at it.
No, that's how it is.
Well, this is crazy,
and I'm due a phone call.
Who else did you talk to?
No one.
Who else besides
the gambling club owner,
Joe Tucci?
I already answered
the question.
Did you interrogate
a Michael Kerring?
We did.
Were you aware that he
was a criminal associate
from California
who knew Sipes' identity?
Yes.
And yet you still
pursued him,
even though
you knew the deceased
to be a federally
protected witness
and that you were
endangering his Iife.
Is that correct, Detective?
We were pursuing
a rape suspect,
Gavin Sipes.
His father
gave us the address.
We were there to do our job.
And yet two men are dead.
One a Deputy US Marshal
with a wife
and three children.
How much do you
make a year?
It depends on overtime,
but why don't we say $68,940.
Must be hard to make ends meet
with a family of six.
I'm a cop.
And the NYPD has a history
of being squeaky clean.
I want my phone call.
We can hold you
for up to 72 hours
without giving you one.
Fallout from 9/11.
Who else
did you talk to?
I'm done talking.
Charge me or Iet me go.
Have a seat.
You know we had nothing
to do with the hit.
I'm not confessing,
so why don't you
just let me go?
You think I don't use
these tactics myself?
I can make you
sit down,
Detective Stabler.
Up to you.
You are officially
under investigation
by the FBI.
Your police jackets
and your financial records
have been subpoenaed.
New York Police Department
has been duly notified.
Internal Affairs is running
a concurrent investigation
into the matter.
This is a witch hunt
and you know it.
You Iost a witness
so you need someone to blame.
Two men are dead.
I told you to back off.
You didn't. You pay.
You can't connect us
to these murders.
We had nothing
to do with it.
You could've sold
the information,
or your bush Ieague tactics
could have Ied
the killers there.
Either way, you're culpable.
STABLER: Yeah? How?
Michael Kerring.
He ID'd Peter Sipes.
He's in Iockup
in our squad room.
Not anymore. They took
him away yesterday
for his arraignment.
He is now serving
30 days in Rikers
for shoplifting,
where he has access
to phone privileges
and the general population.
If Michael Kerring
ratted out Sipes,
we're not responsible.
I disagree.
Now if you don't mind,
I'm busy.
Yeah, we're not done yet.
You arrest Gavin Sipes?
You read him his rights?
No.
Then bring him
on in here. Now.
I can't. I sent him
to your precinct hours ago.
Gavin Sipes, he processed?
Three counts rape
in the first degree.
Just waiting on transport
to the Tombs.
How you holding up?
Denied my civil Iiberties,
treated Iike some skell,
suspected of conspiracy
to commit murder.
But, you know,
I think I've hit bottom.
IAB was here
digging for dirt.
I think I spoke too soon.
How bad is it?
US Attorneys
get a Iot of Ieeway
to make their cases.
The burden of proof
rests mostly
on the defendants.
But we did nothing wrong.
As Iaw enforcement officials,
you were well aware
of the risks
and you disregarded them
for your own benefit.
CIaudia could argue
that sensitive information
was passed on
to the criminal element.
Why would we do that?
What's our motive?
They don't need
to prove motive.
In your zeal to show up
federal officers,
a witness
and a US Marshal are dead.
That's all a jury
needs to hear.
If the Feds can't make
a criminal case,
you're still gonna have
to face the brass.
And they could boot you.
I'm not just handing over
my tin without a fight.
I don't expect you to.
(SIGHING)
We gotta find out
who killed Peter Sipes
to clear our name.
Munch, what do we have
on your witness,
Michael Kerring?
Did he talk to anybody
at Rikers?
He made some calls.
STABLER: To who?
One to Brighton Beach.
Go sit him down.
Shake him up
if you have to.
Don't sweat it.
We got your back.
Who else do we think
could have pulled this off?
That guy at the club
had a Iot of muscle.
And access
to professional hitters.
I didn't do
anything wrong.
Phone call went to a woman
named Beana Wolfman
in Brighton Beach.
Yeah. She's my girlfriend.
I begged her to get me
out of here. She refused.
She said she was tired
of wasting her money on me.
Smart girl.
So what's the problem?
You talk to her
and she'II tell you.
We already did.
Then why the third degree?
Ms. Wolfman
works in a restaurant
that's owned by the mob.
Turns out she has to
because she's here illegally.
What better way
to get her out from under
than to pass on
some valuable information?
You don't know
what you're talking about.
The Organizatsya
does not work that way.
Then explain it to us.
They don't Ieave Ioose ends.
If I had talked,
someone in here
would've killed me already.
Hey, step back.
You wanted me
to set you up with some chips,
you just had to ask.
STABLER: You're
a generous guy there, Joe.
What gives?
Send some of your boys
to do a Iittle house cleaning?
Like what?
Like murder.
Peter Sipes
was killed yesterday.
It wasn't me.
I think it was.
You had about 400,000
reasons to kill him.
You don't know
what you're talking about.
The account's been closed.
Oh, just Iike that,
it's closed?
Yeah, the debt was paid
in full not an hour
after you Ieft.
By who?
Gavin Sipes.
In cash.
You wanna get off me now?
How's your glucose Ievel?
You need some insulin?
I got time.
What's your real name?
Nikolai.
It fits you.
Names are important.
I've had several.
I was Joshua for a while.
David, Daniel.
I was even a Thomas
for a whole nine days.
Why such a short time
with Thomas?
I screwed up.
I forgot our cover story.
So for once,
I just told the truth.
How old were you
when that happened?
Thirteen.
Everyone was upset.
My dad, the Marshals,
the attorneys.
They told me
it cost a fortune to move us.
If I kept running my mouth,
it would get us killed.
That's a hell
of a Iot of guilt for a kid.
Childhood's the time
to make mistakes.
Not in the program.
When we first went in,
Dad would sit
against the window
with a gun.
He never slept.
He'd have panic attacks,
so we didn't go out.
I used to ask him why,
why we Iived Iike that,
and all he'd say
was "someday."
When did he
finally come clean?
When I got my GED.
We moved around so much,
I couldn't even get a Iousy
high school diploma.
I had to take a test
with a bunch of Iosers,
pretending that it was
gonna change our Iives.
Well, maybe he wanted you
to be proud of him
for doing the right thing,
to Iet you know
that your sacrifice
meant something.
What he wanted was for me
to make him feel better
about screwing me
out of a future.
Is that when you
decided to get even?
Get even for what?
For getting screwed
by your parents.
Especially your mother.
You can't hold a grudge
against the dead.
Oh, sure you can.
She died on you
before you could vent
your anger.
Your mother betrayed you.
Both your parents
betrayed you.
No.
No? So why are you
raping innocent women
in some Iocal
mob boss's Iife?
Innocent?
Yeah.
Petra was a stripper,
Iiving off the proceeds
of Sergei's victims.
His sister, Tatiana, decided
where the illegals
would work off their debts.
And Amanda
was washing off the blood
from their money.
Those bitches
Iost their innocence
way before I was even born.
Just too easy,
though, huh?
Raping those women
couldn't even the score.
Nothing could make up
for those Iost years,
could it?
Is that why
your father had to die?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Sure, you do.
What better way to get back
at your old man
than to turn him over
to the very people
that he's testifying against?
That's not how it happened.
No?
Then why call
a butcher shop
in Brighton Beach?
Why call the house
in Connecticut
where your father
is staying,
if not to make sure
that he was home?
I didn't have the money,
and he wouldn't
give me any more.
What was I supposed to do?
They were gonna kill me.
(STABLER SIGHING)
Yeah, and now we will.
Murder of a Iaw
enforcement officer
is an automatic needle.
I didn't think
that they were
gonna kill him.
Sergei said
he just wanted
to talk to Dad.
You talked
to Sergei Perlman
yourself?
I met with his Iieutenant.
I was there
when he called him,
and I spoke to Sergei
on the phone.
That's them.
CIaudia's not here.
Where the hell are they?
We gotta take them.
BENSON: Sergei Perlman.
Are you
Sergei Perlman?
Yes.
You're under arrest.
Step back, please.
You're under arrest
for the murders
of Peter Sipes
and Deputy US Marshal
Raymond Lee.
You have the right
to remain silent.
Anything you say
can and will be used
against you in a court of Iaw.
You have the right
to an attorney.
If you cannot afford one,
one will be appointed to you.
Do you understand
these rights?
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Stabler.
PARAMEDIC: Heads up.
Watch your back,
watch your back.
You arrest Sergei Perlman?
He's in Central Booking now.
We're gonna have to
vacate the charges.
Iet him walk.
Yeah.
What happened?
Shooter entered the courtyard
masking as a guard.
Opened fire
with an automatic weapon.
Russian?
No ID, but I'd bet
my Iife on it.
Sergei had to buy
the information
on Gavin's transfer
in order to pull this off.
He had to get it
from someone inside.
Probably.
What's your next move?
That's just it, Detective.
I don't have one.
CIaudia.
If you need anything...