NARRATOR: In the criminal
justice system,
sexually based offenses
are considered
especially heinous.
In New York City,
the dedicated detectives
who investigate
these vicious felonies
are members
of an elite squad known
as the Special Victims Unit.
These are their stories.
(HORN HONKING)
STARTER: What'd you do?
Take a detour
through Staten Island?
Freaking construction
on the Van Wyck.
20 minutes at a dead stop.
Sorry for the delay, folks.
Customers ain't interested
in your problems.
Relax, everyone.
We'II be on our way quick
if you Ioad up your Iuggage
in an orderly fashion
and have your tickets ready.
(PEOPLE EXCLAIMING)
What the hell?
Call 911.
JFK Terminal 5.
We got a body on the bus.
I'm a nurse.
Ma'am, please stand back.
Barely breathing,
no pulse.
Can anybody help
with CPR?
Detective Katie Moore.
Hello, EIIiot.
My boss caught me
on my way into work,
told me to meet
Queens Special Victims
out here.
Now, we got a kid
in a Iuggage compartment?
Dead kid now.
Hispanic male
about nine or ten.
Asphyxiated.
Any ID?
Nothing in his pockets.
How we doing?
Cherry red Iips
and discoloration
under his fingernails.
Probably carbon
monoxide poisoning.
Where's the sex crime?
I found blood and
fluids in his underwear.
He also has
a two inch Iaceration
on his Ieft arm
and fresh bruising on
his chest and back.
Somebody kicked
the crap out of this kid.
And you invited me
out here to Queens because...
I've been waiting
for you to ask me
that for eight months.
Since we stuck you
with that dead hooker.
Is this payback, Katie?
Bus came straight from
the yard in Manhattan.
No stops, no pickups.
This poor kid was
assaulted on your turf,
so he's all yours.
Log says bus 202
was out of service
from 11 Iast night
till 7 this morning.
Any chance the kid
could have sneaked on
before it came back here?
No, we would have
found him.
Driver stays behind
to check every compartment,
all the seats, you know,
see if anything was Ieft.
They got security
at the front gate.
Any other way in here?
That's what I
wanted to show you.
You got yourself
a rat problem.
Tell me about it.
Every time we fix one
of these, another one pops up.
We're constantly kicking out
street kids and hookers.
Looks Iike you
caught a piece of one
right here.
The bus the kid was on,
where was it parked
Iast night?
Over here.
The bus Ieft for JFK
at seven this morning.
Liv, you got
a glove on you?
Here you go,
what did you find?
There's something
underneath the wheel.
Teddy bear.
It's not weathered.
That Iooks Iike
dried blood to me.
Maybe the cut
from the kids arm.
And there's
glass imbedded in it.
Hey, you have
any broken windows
on the Iot this morning?
Yeah, well, we
haven't had much of
a problem with vandalism
ever since the insurance
company made us put in
security cameras.
Okay, we'II need
to take a Iook
at Iast night's tapes.
Sure.
MUNCH: 11:47. There.
Walking along the fence.
The victim's holding hands
with this older kid.
CRAGEN: What's he
holding right there?
STABLER: Teddy bear.
We found one of those
at the bus depot.
FIN: There goes his shirt.
CRAGEN: You know, the victim
doesn't Iook Iike he's
being forced. Run it back.
Who is this
older kid, anyway?
Could be his brother.
Or the perp tricks the victim
into following him,
rapes him in the yard,
then Iocks him in
the Iuggage compartment.
Yeah, but the DOA
was clean. If he'd been
sodomized in that yard,
you'd expect to find
abrasions on his hands,
his knees, I mean, somewhere.
Could have happened
on another bus.
In which case
our already
contaminated crime scene
may be on its way to
one of the airports.
AIong with our perp.
I'II call the bus company
and the Port Authority cops,
have them put out alerts.
What about missing persons?
OIivia's there right now.
Have her meet you
at the morgue.
If our M.E. can find something
to help us ID the victim,
maybe we can
catch a break.
The blood on
the teddy bear is type AB,
same as the victim.
What about the glass?
Consistent with
what I found in the cut
on his arm.
Crime Iab says it's
tempered safety glass,
no coating or tinting.
So it's probably not
from a car window?
More Iike the kind
used for sound proofing.
Now, a teddy bear seems Iike
an awful strange thing
for a street kid to
be carrying around.
Your victim's no street kid.
He's recently bathed,
well-nourished
and disease-free.
And, somebody spent
a Iot of money
on his mouth.
Noah?
Detectives
Stabler and Benson,
this is our
forensic odontologist,
Doctor Noah Kamens.
So, how much we talking
for this dental work?
Smooth, invisible braces.
An implant where no
permanent tooth grew in,
I'd say we're Iooking
at ten grand, total.
Any idea how Iong
ago this was done?
Judging from the condition
of the materials,
within the Iast month.
There's got to be a couple
hundred orthodontists in
the Tri-State area.
True, but
the implant's
custom-made,
so the manufacturer's ID
will be on it.
We'II pull the fake tooth,
the Iab who made it can tell
us which dentist ordered it.
Detectives.
Benson.
Rape kit's back.
Positive for semen.
And I just
found something else
when I rolled him.
Suture scars.
Recently healed,
on his anus.
Someone's been
violently abusing this kid
for some time.
Thanks.
We got to go.
They may have
just found our perp.
BUS DRIVER: Pulled in
45 minutes ago.
One of the passengers
was this kid but I don't
remember him getting on.
Do you recognize this?
Yeah.
That Iooks Iike the shirt
he was wearing.
How many stops
did you make?
Only one,
Grand Central.
Anyway, I ask
to see his ticket stub,
and he bolts.
He must've been
hiding on the bus.
Did you see where he went?
Yeah, I chased him
down this way.
He ran right in there,
but I Iost him in the crowd.
Port Authority cops said
you waited 15 minutes
before you
called them, how come?
Are you kidding?
My dispatcher
would skin me alive
if he found out
I Ieft that bus
unattended two seconds.
Look, I'm running Iate.
I got to get out of here.
You stay here.
We're not done.
Driver made
a positive ID.
Thanks.
Any sign of the kid?
15 minutes ago, right here.
One of my guys spotted him.
Kid took off.
AII right.
I called in for help
as soon as I got
the heads-up
that you had
a piece of his clothes.
Maybe we can sniff him out.
BENSON: Here's the shirt.
(BARKING)
STABLER: What's back there?
It Ieads
straight to the tarmac.
We can get out
there this way.
STABLER: Stop!
Police. Stop!
Are you trying to
get yourself killed?
Leave me alone!
Calm down.
I want to go home.
We're trying
to help you.
Now, calm...
I want to go home.
We're trying
to help you.
I want to go home.
STABLER: What's your name?
Hey, you're in
a Iot of trouble.
Do you understand that?
Deport me.
We don't deport killers.
I didn't kill anyone.
Then what happened
to your Iittle friend
with the teddy bear?
José?
He's dead?
Okay,
Iet's try this again.
From the start.
What's your name?
Ernesto.
Ernesto Diaz.
Is José your brother?
He's my friend.
You said at the airport
that you wanted to go home.
Where's home?
Guatemala.
José, too.
Well, how did you
get here?
By boat.
Two years ago.
My parents sent me
here to go to school.
The charity promised
to protect me.
But instead they
gave me and José
to the man.
What charity?
ERNESTO: I don't know.
Did you come here with José?
ERNESTO: No.
He came in Iast month.
The man said I was getting
too old to please him.
What did he do to you?
Kept us Iocked up.
Made us have sex with him.
He would beat us
when we said no.
Did you ever try
to escape before?
ERNESTO: Once.
He said he would kill José
and my parents if
I ever did it again.
But I couldn't watch
José suffer no more.
Ernesto...
He's not going to hurt you.
He's not going to
hurt your parents
or anyone else ever again,
but we need your help.
Bret Jansen.
He made us call him "Dad".
The National
Center for Missing
and Exploited Children
and NCIC have
nothing on José
or Ernesto,
and INS has no
record of a visa.
Maybe the Guatemalan police
know if they were kidnapped.
What about Jansen?
There's a Bret Jansen
Iisted on Thomas Street.
That matches
Ernesto's description,
not far from Ground Zero.
Well, if that's him,
"Dad" has some bucks.
He's a partner at Stitt,
Beam and Cornell,
blue chip Wall
Street Iaw firm.
With his own
personal sex slaves.
You know,
if the INS never
processed these kids,
he had to have
smuggled them in here.
Well, Iet's go pick
him up at his office
and ask him about it.
Jansen's office
says he's MIA.
He's probably out somewhere
Iooking for his boys.
So we'II get a warrant for
his place. Ernesto's statement
has got to be enough.
AII these deadbolts
are unlocked.
This door weighs a ton.
Steel over wood,
foam and rubber
on the inside.
It's sound-proofed.
FIoors are, too.
They're elevated,
probably
insulation underneath.
Magnetic Iocks.
This guy's serious
about his security.
Windows are Iocked,
it Iooks Iike you need
a key to open all of them.
Guys, over here.
Broken window.
Went down the fire escape.
Dad didn't even bother
to clean up the glass.
Jansen must've panicked
when he came home,
found the boys missing,
rushed right
out to find them.
Poultry shears.
Probably used it
to cut through the wire mesh.
Explains the cut on José's arm
and the broken glass
on the teddy bear.
And why it's tempered. Even if
the boys screamed for help
nobody would hear them.
So far Ernesto's
story totally checks out.
This Iock has been jimmied.
Got the shears out
of this drawer, huh?
Both the boys' bedrooms
also have magnetic Iocks
on the doors.
Kept them Iocked in
to protect his investment.
And I haven't seen
a phone around here anywhere.
Probably got
them Iocked up, too.
I think we found the guy
who owns this place.
Where?
In bed.
SIeep tight, Mr. Jansen.
Somebody slit his throat.
And sliced off
the family jewels.
Doctor found bruises
all over his body.
Permanent damage
from being repeatedly
sodomized over two years.
That's a hell
of a good reason
to cut up Jansen.
Ernesto have anything to do
with this murder?
It's possible.
Jansen used his
genitals as a weapon
against him and José.
Cutting them off
might be
the ultimate protection.
That crime scene
was a bloodbath
and Ernesto didn't
have a drop on him.
PIus we didn't find
any spattered clothing.
And CSU found
fresh traces of blood
in the shower.
So whoever did kill Jansen
was savvy enough to
clean up after himself.
An adult might think of that,
but a 14-year-old boy?
I said it was possible.
I didn't say I
thought he did it.
Just seeing Jansen chopped up
would be horrific enough
to traumatize this kid.
If he saw the murder,
then he might be afraid
that the killer will harm him
if he tells.
Well,
what's the strategy, Doc?
Ernesto was abused by a man.
OIivia, give him
all the affection
and approval you can.
Ernesto.
Last night,
no matter what happened,
it's not your fault.
Do you understand that?
José's dead.
That's my fault.
No, sweetheart.
You tried
to save José.
Not many boys your age
would have done that.
Now, I can help you
but I need to know
what happened Iast night.
PIease, Ernesto,
Iet me help you.
He went into José's room.
I heard him crying,
begging him to stop.
I yelled,
called him a pig.
I told him to
Ieave José alone.
Then he came in,
pulled me out of bed,
and I hit him
over and over.
And what did he do?
He just smiled.
He said when he
was done with José
I'd find out
what real pain was.
Then what?
He was mad.
He told José,
if he didn't be quiet,
he'd send him
to the other men.
But José cried,
begged him to stop.
He got so mad he Ieft.
Ernesto, these other men...
Did he ever send you to them?
I'm afraid.
Honey, I promise you,
nobody can hurt you
as Iong as you're with us.
I promise you.
They'd take me for a while.
Then they would give me back.
I didn't want them
to do that to José.
Now it's a ring
of pedophiles.
How many of
these sick bastards
raped that kid?
Better find them fast.
God knows how many other
boys they're passing around.
The Ievel of rage
in Jansen's murder
could've been jealousy.
Especially if one of
his boy-sharing buddies
kept Ernesto
and didn't want
to give him back.
That makes sense.
Jansen had to know
whoever killed him.
That apartment
was Iocked up
Iike a fortress.
Captain, it gets worse.
You better see what
we found in his crib.
MUNCH: For your
viewing disgust.
Apparently Jansen wasn't
satisfied just victimizing
José and Ernesto.
Oh, that's great.
Two men and a kid
no older than
my 10-year-old son.
CRAGEN: Well,
I recognize Jansen,
but who's the other guy?
MUNCH: I forced myself to
scroll through this excrement.
You never see his face.
STABLER: Second guy's got
a couple tattoos.
Let's turn this off.
Turn it off, will you?
Odds are that video was made
in Central America,
since that's where Jansen
found José and Ernesto.
We also got adoption papers
on both the boys, all bogus.
But this will really
make your skin crawl.
Bulletins from the
North American
Man/Boy Love Association
and their constitution.
We got ourselves
a NAMBLA member.
This stuff is
Iike a how-to guide
for pedophiles.
"Keep your Iover's
identity a secret,
"never discuss
your relationship
with a shrink.
"Hide your photos
where the cops
can't find them."
"How to make that
special boy feel good."
Complete with instructions.
They're pedophiles
who claim they can help boys
as young as three
discover their sexuality
in a non-threatening,
nurturing way.
And they hide behind
the First Amendment
to spew that crap.
But they operate in cells
Iike al-Qaeda, so one group
can't finger another.
Look, Iet's be honest.
Killing Jansen was
a public service.
And if we find
who did kill him,
it might Iead us to
the rest of these pervs
and the boys they're keeping.
Now, first thing
in the morning, you and OIivia
go to Jansen's Iaw office,
and track down his friends.
Thanks.
That was the M.E.
I got the dentist
that worked on José's teeth.
As soon as
the Iab notified us,
my assistant called you guys.
How did José die?
We think it was an accident.
His father must
be devastated.
Well, he's dead, too,
and that wasn't an accident.
My God, what happened?
Murdered in his apartment.
And Ernesto?
He's fine.
You took care of him?
The occasional
cleaning and filling.
Nothing Iike
the work I did on José.
MUNCH: How well did you
know Bret Jansen?
Not well at all
but I admired him
for adopting two boys
from a foreign country.
He seemed Iike
a really caring father.
Jansen ever
make any referrals?
No, no, we're so busy
we're not accepting
any new patients.
Why do you ask?
Just routine questions.
Anything unusual about him
or the boys you remember?
Well,
just that he was impatient.
He wanted it all
done at once and fast.
Did he say why?
He'd just adopted José
and he was about to
enroll him in school.
Mr. Jansen told me he got
teased for having metal braces
when he was a kid
and didn't want his
son to get picked on.
Only the best for his boys.
He was a great boss.
I'm sick over this.
We all are.
Did you keep his calendar?
I put his daily schedule
on the computer.
But Mr. Jansen kept
his own Iawyer's diary.
It's that red book
on his desk.
Surprised there are
no family pictures around.
Mr. Jansen didn't
have any family.
Both parents passed away,
no siblings.
He ever mention his two sons?
You must have him confused
with someone else.
No way Mr. Jansen has kids
and I don't know about it.
What about friends?
You know how
many hours you have
to bill to make partner?
Mr. Jansen didn't
have time for friends.
But there was
a Iunch Iast Tuesday.
Stewart Lynch?
He's a client. They ate
at Mr. Jansen's club.
LYNCH: Bret was
a real Iadies' man.
Different beautiful girl
every week.
I was jealous.
He ever mention
having children?
No, the only kids
we ever talked
about were mine.
I could brag
about them all day.
I don't think
Bret would have made
a very good father.
And why's that?
He had a terrible temper.
Let Iittle things tick
him off that wouldn't
bother most guys.
Kids would have
driven him crazy.
Was he friends
with anyone else
here in the club?
Uh, Tony Damon's
the only person
I can think of.
They played squash together.
Okay.
Thanks for your time.
Oh, one more thing.
You ever been to
Jansen's apartment?
No.
Thanks, Mr. Lynch.
We'II be in touch.
No problem,
and it's Dr. Lynch.
I'm sorry, I didn't know.
What kind of doctor are you?
Reconstructive
plastic surgery.
My specialty is hand repair.
Well, Dr. Lynch,
would you mind telling us
where you were
the night that
Jansen was murdered?
Not at all. I was in the OR
from 10:00 at night
until dawn the next morning
re-attaching
a thumb and two fingers
severed in a car accident.
STABLER: Two nights ago?
I was home, just off
the plane from Chicago.
Still have the boarding pass
if you need it.
That won't be necessary,
Mr. Damon.
We just heard that you
and Mr. Jansen played squash
a couple of times a week.
Well, when I'm in town.
Bret usually kicked my ass
all over the court.
Did you ever socialize
outside the club?
I'm on the road a Iot
for work, Detective.
I spend my down
time at home relaxing.
Come on, you must know
something about him?
He had a strange
sense of humor.
How so?
Friday, we're in a match,
I serve and ace him.
He Iaughs, says
it was a Iucky shot,
because I usually
play Iike a woman,
and that he should have
cut off my balls years ago.
Jansen's genitals
weren't exactly cut off,
they were surgically excised.
Come again?
Removed with a scalpel
by someone who knows
anatomy. And pre-mortem.
So someone wanted
to really make him suffer.
How did the perp
incapacitate him?
Whacked him on the head
with a blunt object.
Probably took that with him.
Now, an amateur would have
slit his throat right across.
Jansen's killer
made precise incisions
at the carotid artery.
Here and here, after...
You don't need to
demonstrate that part.
PIastic surgeon
would know how to do
the job on Jansen.
And sew up José.
Like an expert.
Ernesto, we got
some good news for you.
Did you find my
mama and papa?
BENSON: Yep.
And they're coming here
to get you.
When?
Tomorrow.
But, Iisten, first
we need your help
one more time.
What is it?
Well, you said Bret
sent you to
some other men.
Do you know any names?
No.
What about a doctor?
Did he ever take you
or José to go see a doctor?
He would come over
to see us,
when we were sick.
Okay, do you know
his name?
No. But he was nice.
Ernesto, did he
ever touch you?
Never.
We're going to
show you some photos.
Do you recognize anybody?
Just tell us.
That's him.
That's our doctor.
You're sure?
Yes.
The good Dr. Lynch.
Lynch has three sons,
all adopted.
He's never been married.
He's head of
reconstructive surgery
at Chelsea Hospital.
He's known for
operating on disfigured kids
in third world countries.
And, in his spare time,
he sews up his
friends' slave boys.
Guy's a real humanitarian.
What about Damon?
Damon owns a travel agency
called GIobal Voyages.
He Iives in Scarsdale.
He's single, no children.
Now, there was a whole Iot
of phone activity between them
the night that
Jansen was murdered.
At 10:52 Jansen makes
a 30-second call to Lynch.
Presumably when he came home
to find the boys
had flown the coop.
Then Jansen called Damon,
they talked for two minutes.
Damon then gave Lynch
a 20-second call back.
Customs says
that Jansen traveled
to Guatemala two years ago,
around the time
Ernesto was brought here.
That's probably
when that videotape
was made.
Damon is
setting up his friends
on sex tours,
and they're bringing
back human souvenirs.
And passing them
around to their friends.
Which means we've got to
try to get Lynch's kids
out of that house tonight.
AII we have are
two phone calls?
That's not enough.
STABLER: We checked,
Lynch's three kids are boys.
God knows what he's doing
to them right now.
Are they Iegally adopted?
We won't know
that information
until tomorrow morning.
Does he keep them Iocked up
Iike Jansen's does?
No, all three of the boys
go to public schools.
Are there any
complaints of abuse?
None to ACS or
the Iocal precinct.
Look, we already have Lynch
on failing to report
José's abuse.
LANGAN: An A misdemeanor?
With no priors I'd argue
for a fine and no jail time.
I think AIex is
dining with the enemy.
Can you give us two minutes?
Yeah, the game's on
at the bar. Why don't I
check that out?
Look, we take
Lynch's kids away from him,
and we are wrong.
A heavy hitter Iike him
is gonna drag us into court
and make our Iives miserable.
Get me some hard evidence.
Computer crimes
found this buried
on Jansen's hard drive.
Your special tour
to Central America
is confirmed.
If your friends enjoy,
have them get in touch.
That is an e-mail
from Damon to Jansen
right before Jansen's trip
two years ago.
Now, that sounds Iike
a confirmation Ietter.
And that he's soliciting men
to travel overseas
to rape children.
That's a federal crime.
Let's catch him in the act.
Anthony Damon.
Mr. BIackmum, is it?
John BIackmum.
So, you got my e-mail?
About our special tour
to the Philippines.
Let me first ask you
where you got my
e-mail address.
From a friend of ours.
But I don't want to
mention any names.
Well, your personal and credit
information checked out okay.
You ran my credit?
To make sure you are
who you say you are,
for both of our protection.
Which is why I also
need to see some ID.
I understand completely.
Good.
It's a standard
two-week package.
You fly business class,
stay in a business hotel,
meals and entertainment
included for $5000.
And the entertainment?
Do you prefer girls or boys?
Or both?
Boys. 11 to 13.
We work with an orphanage,
five-year-olds on up.
PIus, you get a videotape
so you can
cherish the memory.
Great. It's all there.
I didn't want to
Ieave a paper trail.
When would you
Iike to travel,
Mr. BIackmum?
Or is there another
name you'd Iike to use?
As a matter of fact,
there is.
John Munch, but you
can call me Detective.
Get up. Put your hands
behind your back right now.
Now! Now!
This is entrapment.
And we call it conspiracy.
Police officers.
Step away from the table.
Don't touch anything.
Get the computers
and the files.
Tape good?
Did you get it all?
Every single word.
Great.
So, what's this conspiracy
that you're charging me with?
Facilitating
the rape of children
in foreign countries.
There's no state
Iaw against that.
STABLER: Federal Iaw.
We turn our tape
over to the US Attorney,
you're toast.
Federal statutes require
proof of a sex act.
That means they
need a victim.
Where are they
gonna find one?
No wonder this guy
doesn't need a Iawyer.
He's got the Iaw memorized
with all his other
NAMBLA buddies.
NAMBLA?
I'm not one of those freaks.
How many boys they
pass around to you?
I don't know what the hell
you're talking about.
Do you think I am
some dumb cop?
I had nothing...
EIIiot.
You think you're
smarter than me?
I need a doctor.
You're gonna need
a morgue, pal.
He's not worth it.
Get off me!
You're nothing
but a Iow-Iife pimp
who sells children.
You sent Bret Jansen
on a sex tour.
Him and a friend made a video
doing a 10-year-old boy.
Friend?
Yeah.
I don't know
about any friend.
Yeah, right just
Iike you didn't know
your customers have
been smuggling back
Iittle sex toys of their own.
Listen, Jansen and Lynch
did that on their own.
I had nothing to do with it.
You got nothing to do
with anything, do you?
How about sex tours?
Do you know anything
about them?
Do you book sex tours?
Yes. Yes.
How many do you book?
Couple dozen.
Yeah?
Over the years.
Yeah. Just a couple dozen?
I swear, I'm not one of them.
I was just in it
for the money.
Which the Feds
are gonna take away
from you, while you're
sitting on death row for
slicing up Bret Jansen.
What? I had nothing
to do with that.
That's funny, because somebody
did to him exactly what
he joked about doing to you.
That rat bastard.
You got to be more specific,
there's a Iot of them
running around in this case.
Lynch. I told him about
Jansen's joke that he was
gonna cut my balls off.
He's using it to set me up.
Why would he want
to kill Jansen?
Because Lynch
hand-picked José
for Jansen.
Then Jansen called Lynch,
said he wanted his money back
when José and
Ernesto escaped.
When's the Iast time
you spoke to Lynch?
Before Jansen was killed.
Lynch called, he said
he wanted to know
why the video of this trip
hadn't arrived yet.
I told him it was on its way.
Make me a deal.
Make me a deal,
and I will give you
Lynch on a silver platter.
What can we do here?
The sex tours are federal
and I am not giving him
immunity
until we're sure
he didn't kill Jansen.
Maybe we can get Lynch
without Damon's help.
The doctor's sex tour
video is in the mail.
Have the post office
set up a sneak preview.
Postal Inspectors found it
in a box marked Iike pottery
and knew it was
the real deal.
Mail carrier drops
it off 15 minutes ago.
He Ieaves, Lynch comes out,
scoops it right up.
Like a kid attacking the tree
on Christmas morning.
Police, open the door.
(BENSON SPEAKING SPANISH)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
He's in the study.
What's up, Doc?
You can't just barge in here
Iike this.
We just wanted to
watch a Iittle TV.
What's on?
Looks Iike the doc's star
of his own freak show.
Put your hands
behind your back.
Where'd you get
Ramon and his brothers?
They're my
Iegally adopted sons.
I have the papers to prove it.
Oh, and the boy on the tape,
he Iegally adopted?
I'm not saying anything
without an attorney.
Yeah, well, I'm sure
this will say it all.
If you're offering a deal,
we're willing to Iisten.
Listen to this.
We checked the adoption papers
on your so-called sons,
they're all forgeries.
We also found the INS agent
you paid to
phony up their visas
and Bret Jansen's
two boys' visas,
as well as...
Well, who knows
how many others.
That is 10 years'
federal prison for
every boy you smuggled in.
I smuggled in?
Are you people insane?
Not to mention kidnapping
and sexual abuse.
I didn't abuse my sons.
Stewart...
Look. No, I need to say this.
I would never force my boys
to do anything
they didn't want to do.
Your boys are
barely teenagers.
They can't consent
to statutory rape.
How'd they feel about you
passing them around
to your pedophile pals?
I did no such thing.
I Iove them.
I would never do
anything to hurt them.
You're not actually
considering bringing this
NAMBLA crap to court?
The boys will tell
you it's all true.
And when our shrink testifies
to how your client
brainwashed them,
the jury is going to
Iock him up
and throw away the key.
Sex abuse three for his sons
and immunity on
any federal charges.
I can't speak for
the US Attorney.
You're going to
have to give me
something I can bring her.
Damon is the one
smuggling in boys.
Is he a NAMBLA member, too?
No, they're just
merchandise to him.
He brought in six boys a year,
two at a time on
a chartered sailboat.
Who else is in the ring?
I'II give you the names
of everyone I know.
The night Jansen was murdered,
what did he say to
you on the phone?
What are you talking about?
I never spoke to him.
STABLER: Until you
sliced him up?
Not another word, Stewart.
I didn't kill anybody.
You surgically
removed his genitals
and cut his throat.
We have a statement from
our M.E., saying the killer
had medical knowledge.
I was in surgery
the night Bret was killed.
You're a Iiar. Your hospital
said you were on vacation.
Wrong hospital.
The case I did
was up in Rochester.
I am telling you,
I would never do
two men and a boy.
Prove it.
Take your shirt off.
I'm not doing
anything without an attorney.
Okay, here's how we're gonna
find out which one of you
is the movie star.
We're gonna get
a court order,
we're gonna strip you,
we're gonna take
some pretty pictures
and see if your tats match.
We rounded up
17 pervs so far.
Teacher, court clerk,
engineer,
couple of Wall Street
masters of the universe.
AII of them say that Damon
got them their
so-called son or daughter.
How many kids?
Fourteen.
ACS is placing them
with their
temporary foster homes.
Chief of detectives wants us
to beat the feds
to a news conference,
pat us on the back
for breaking
this pedophile ring.
You know what
the thing of it is?
Not one of these sickos
is gonna do nearly
as much time as
whoever killed Jansen.
And Lynch's
alibi checked out.
We got a whole operating room
full of people that swear
that he was 350 miles
from here the night
Jansen was murdered.
Here's the doctor's
report on Lynch's kids.
Confirms they
were sexually abused.
And that they're in otherwise
excellent health.
BIood work is normal.
Hearing and vision
all check out
and perfect teeth.
What's the name of
that dentist? Massey.
He wasn't a member of the
Metropolis CIub and he wasn't
on Damon's sex tour Iist.
It doesn't mean
he's not one of them.
These pedophiles operate
in their own
parallel netherworld.
Makes sense they'd
have a dentist, too.
Massey have any kids?
Two and a wife.
And he would have taken
anatomy and done oral
surgery in dental school.
Find out how
many of their boys
Dr. Massey worked on.
If there's a pattern,
it should be enough for us
to get a warrant.
Search our house?
What in God's name for?
Mrs. Massey, I'm so sorry,
we're just doing our job.
Why don't you start upstairs
in the master bedroom,
check everything
in the closets.
Homicide?
You think Walt
murdered someone?
You know where he
was two nights ago?
Um... He had
an emergency patient.
I... He Ieft about 9:30.
So Walt
couldn't have done it.
Handsome boys.
Thank you.
They Iook so much Iike you,
but I don't see any
resemblance to your husband.
They're from my
previous marriage.
Where's their father?
Attica,
doing eight-to-ten years
for trying to kill me.
He's Iost his
parental rights.
Walt adopted the boys.
Mrs. Massey,
how did you
meet your husband?
I put a personal ad
in the newspaper
and he answered it.
PIease forgive me
for asking this,
but how has your relationship
been with your husband Iately?
What's that got to do
with anything?
PIease. Mrs. Massey...
Walt is a good man,
our relationship
isn't about sex. It...
He's a saint.
He rescued me
and my boys.
Does he pay
attention to one boy
more than he does to another?
The elder one, Shawn.
They're together all the time
when Walt is home.
Oh, my God,
what's he done?
Do you miss your
real dad, Shawn?
WaIt's our dad now.
And how do you
feel about that?
My other dad
used to hit my mom.
He didn't want to be
with me and Darren,
my Iittle brother.
We had to Iive
in a shelter
till Mom met Walt.
And what do you and Walt do?
You know, we hang out,
go to ball games.
He coaches my soccer team.
STABLER: That's cool.
What do you do
when you're alone together?
He said I could
never tell anyone.
That they
wouldn't understand.
Shawn, Iook at me.
I do understand,
and there's no need
to be afraid.
Walt Iikes to stay with me.
STABLER: Okay. What do you
mean stay, like, stay where?
At night in my room.
When did this start?
One night he just came in.
He said he
wanted to be near me,
and he just climbed in.
Did he ever
touch you anywhere?
Not then.
How about now?
He says it's how fathers
are supposed to
Iove their sons.
Shawn, you need to know
that none of this
is your fault.
That what he is
doing is wrong.
I know, but Walt
takes care of my mom and
we don't have to live
in the shelter anymore.
And my mom doesn't
get beat up anymore.
Walt really Ioves us.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
I've been dealing
with another case.
Am I under arrest?
Your colleagues dragged me
out of my office
in front of my patients,
Iike I'm some criminal.
That was a huge mistake.
I'm really sorry about that.
They weren't
supposed to do that.
I saw you were
talking to Shawn.
He seems Iike
a really great kid.
What did he tell you?
Oh, you know,
how much you Iove him
and his mom.
Look, EIIiot,
we got to move on this.
Look, I told you I'm not
wasting my time with
that crap. You handle it.
You have it your way.
Have it my...
Have it my way.
I got this case,
got a 14-year-old girl,
who's dating this
22-year-old guy,
completely consensual sex,
and they wanna
Iock this poor guy up
for statutory rape.
He shouldn't be penalized
because of the girl's age.
She was expressing
natural sexual feelings.
Well, I wish the people
who made the Iaws
realized that.
It'd make my job
a hell of a Iot easier.
So, you agree?
Look, we're all
sexual beings.
Children, adults, you know.
That's why I'm thinking that
this is a misunderstanding.
What do you mean?
(SIGHS)
Okay, my colleagues
brought you in here
because they think that
you're sexually abusing
your boys.
Okay, now,
I've busted my share
of child abusers.
I'm not getting
that vibe from you.
I would never do anything
to hurt my boys Iike that.
I believe you.
I think we both understand
it's about Iove.
You Iove your boys.
You treat them with respect.
Not Iike Bret Jansen.
He beat his sons.
He Iocked them up.
You treated José,
you know what he did to him.
He had bruises
all over his body.
Jansen does not
Iove those boys.
Well, he forced
Ernesto and José
to have sex with him.
Forcing them, well...
Between you and me,
I think Jansen got
what he deserved.
His punishment, it was
especially appropriate,
don't you think?
Do you know how
Jansen was killed?
Oh, God.
I just know that he
hurt those Iittle angels.
I think you know
more than that.
What's with this
tattoo that I've seen
in the videotape?
And what about that glass
from Jansen's apartment
that we found
in your sneaker?
What am I, an idiot?
Come on.
You killed Jansen.
He ruined it for everybody.
I had to make sure
he'd never hurt
another Iittle boy again.
And I'm gonna make sure
that you never do, either.
You're under arrest
for the murder of Jansen
and for sexually
abusing your son.
No. No.
I didn't force Shawny.
He seduced me.
How could I deny him?
I never beat him Iike
Jansen beat his boys.
It's not the same thing!
No, it's worse.
You have sex
with your stepson
and you don't think
there's anything
wrong with that?
What kind of sick
bastard are you?