NARRATOR: In the criminal
justice system,
sexually based offenses are
considered
especially heinous.
In New York City,
the dedicated detectives
who investigate
these vicious felonies
are members of an elite squad
known as
the Special Victims Unit.
These are their stories.
Hi, we're Iooking
for a patient,
Stephanie Rawley?
BENSON: Hey!
We don't have her.
STABLER: You sure?
She's a rape victim.
I haven't had
one all night.
Call came from
this hospital,
just got it.
Well, maybe you
mixed up hospitals.
Maybe you could
check the computer.
Oh, well,
here's your miscom.
She's not in emergency.
She's in the ICU.
Good God.
What'd this guy
do to her?
Put her on
Iife support.
Beautiful girl.
He didn't touch that.
There's not
a mark on her face.
BENSON: No defense wounds,
either.
STABLER: BIitz attack
from behind?
Knifepoint to the throat?
STABLER: Let's
check her chart.
She has pneumonia.
But she's out
of the woods.
We brought the fever
down with antibiotics.
Somebody called in a rape.
That was me.
I'm Dr. Sedaly.
She was transferred here
from Mountcastle Rehab.
Drug overdose?
No, she was in
a car accident.
BENSON: When?
About a year ago.
She's been in
a persistent vegetative
state ever since.
Okay, she's been in a coma.
I don't understand why you
called us.
Because of the pneumonia,
I ordered a chest X-ray
and the Iab automatically
ran the standard tests.
Hers turned up positive.
For what?
A baby.
She's six weeks pregnant.
My daughter
was raped?
We should have
kept her at home.
I told you I could
take care of her.
Prayer wasn't going
to bring her back,
Janice.
Mountcastle was
our Iast hope.
How could they
Iet this happen?
I promise you,
we're going to find out.
Was Stephanie moved from
rehab for any reason,
say six, seven weeks ago?
No.
Check all of
Mountcastle's employees.
Anyone who had access.
Don't bother.
I know who did this.
Who?
It couldn't have been David,
he still has
a restraining order.
BENSON: Who's David?
The man Stephanie
was Iiving with.
The wreck was his fault.
Why is there
a restraining order?
After she went
into Mountcastle,
he tried to kill her.
I never tried to kill her.
I only told them her wishes.
Death wishes?
We Iived together for
six years. Yeah, we talked
about everything.
Stephanie never wanted
to Iive Iike this.
FIN: Ma and Pa catch you
tripping over the plug?
No, but they convinced
a judge I might.
I Iove her more than
anything in the world.
Really? How's your
sex Iife been Iately?
None of your business.
It is now.
If you two think...
You two are sick.
Besides, I haven't
seen her in months.
Call me a hopeless romantic,
but I don't see
a Iittle court order
standing in the way
of your undying Iove.
You don't know
her parents.
If it wasn't for them,
I'd have been there to
protect her from that pervert.
You blame them, even though
you're the one that put her
in a vegetable crisper?
It was my bachelor party.
The guys dragged me
off to a strip club
in Port Chester.
My friends got smashed,
so I called her
to come get me.
She drives out there,
you being a man,
had to take the wheel,
even though you'd had a few.
She never showed up.
She got hit by
a truck on the way.
MUNCH: He came across
pretty straight up.
FIN: We're not completely
ruling him out, but we're
thinking an inside job.
That's a big place.
Benson and Stabler
could use some help.
They're interviewing
the coma wing staff now.
I don't even want to think
how under-reported
coma rape is.
CRAGEN: Well, victims
don't tend to come forward.
Counselor, question.
What would it take
to blanket DNA
an entire facility?
A constitutional amendment.
But we know
the rape happened there.
It doesn't cover
probable cause for
each individual employee.
Not to mention patients,
vendors, visitors...
I mean, where would
your genetic dragnet end?
Whose side
are you on?
What about that
case in Germany?
11-year-old girl
was raped and killed,
they tested everybody
in the town.
Over 16,000 men.
But it was on
a strictly
volunteer basis.
I'II take volunteers.
It's still cost-prohibitive.
It's $600 a pop.
Who says they're all
gonna be processed?
I say we get
everybody's DNA now
while we've got 'em,
we can narrow down
the suspects Iater.
I gave your tech
a separate Iist of everyone
working six weeks ago,
including swing, graveyard
and weekend shifts.
We'II need to start
with the men who worked
directly with Stephanie.
At this point,
she's basically
receiving supportive care,
turned to prevent bedsores,
change IV tubes.
Mostly female nurses.
Except for CIark Jensen,
her physical therapist.
That should
make it easy.
Oh, and her neurologist,
Dr. Mandell.
He's her primary.
And where can
we find him?
He's with a patient.
STABLER: Catch you
at a bad time?
Not at all.
I'm just doing an LP.
Is that a
spinal tap?
She's having
unexplained
seizures
and since she can't
fill in the blanks,
I need to find out
what's going on.
Don't you normally
have a nurse present?
I'm an old hand at this.
STABLER: I meant
as a chaperone.
That policy isn't
for the patient,
it's to protect the doctor
from false allegations.
She can't make any.
Neither can
Stephanie Rawley.
And she has
a Iegitimate one.
Yeah, I can't tell you
how upset I was to hear that.
You examine her alone?
Often.
Stephanie's parents insist
that I repeat every test,
hoping there'II be
a change in her condition.
And what's
her prognosis?
Oh, it's very grim.
She's suffered
massive cortical damage.
She has minimal
brain stem activity.
She has no intellectual
or motor function.
STABLER: Sounds Iike you
spent a Iot of time with her.
I spend time with
all my coma patients.
Would you have any problem
volunteering your DNA?
Not at all.
FIN: CIark Jensen?
Yes?
You do these exercises
with Stephanie Rawley?
Three times a week,
to keep the joints fluid and
the muscles from atrophying.
She's hooked to Iife support.
You roll those machines
up here?
I have a special routine
for the coma patients.
I can do them in their beds.
You don't say.
Two-minute break,
Mr. Crowe.
You happen to hear about
the voluntary DNA test?
I was the first in Iine.
You work with Stephanie a Iot.
Who do you think did it?
I don't know.
But I can't believe one
of my co-workers is a rapist.
What about a patient?
Or visitors.
You ever see this guy?
(SIGHS)
When?
Month or so ago.
I came in early one morning,
he was with her.
I knew the deal,
but when he told me
his side, I felt for the guy.
Didn't report it, though.
What exactly was he doing
when you walked in?
SIeeping in her bed.
You Iied to us,
Mr. Andersen.
I had to.
The second the Rawleys
find out I broke
the restraining order,
they'II have me arrested.
You Iooked me
right in the eye
and had the violins going...
I stayed away as Iong as
I could, then I started
visiting once a month.
Guess we all know
what you brought her
instead of flowers.
You're wrong.
How'd you manage
to sneak in there?
There's a nurse
on night shift.
She feels bad for me,
she Iooks the other way.
So you get to spend the night
with her in the moonlight,
just Iike old times, huh?
Naturally,
it got hot and heavy.
She gets agitated
at night.
She shakes,
her face twitches.
What do you do
about it, David?
I just hold her.
The doctors say
that she's not aware,
but it seems to
calm her down.
So you'd have no objections
then, to taking a paternity
test, huh?
None.
I want to know who did this
to her as much as you do.
BENSON: So far nobody has
a clue or has any problem
giving up their DNA.
FIN: Including the fiancé,
who was at
the top of our Iist.
Still headlining mine.
I think he's so Iovesick
he doesn't care whether
he goes to jail or not.
If that's the case,
why not just admit it?
Cause he's freaky sick.
I don't know.
They were gonna be
married in one week's time.
BENSON: Come on,
Iike that makes
a difference?
If she didn't give consent,
it's still rape.
I'm saying she would've
if she could've.
Fiancé, best case scenario.
It's not Iike she's facing
psychological trauma
over this. She's produce.
Mrs. Rawley.
Try to stay calm,
we're gonna be right there.
Mrs. Rawley went to mass
and when she came back,
Stephanie was gone.
Where is she?
Nurse said she'd been
transferred back to
the rehab center.
Why would they send her back
to where she was raped?
Where is she?
Look...
Tell me where she is!
STABLER: Mrs. Rawley,
Iet us handle this.
I want to see my daughter.
Right now.
I don't understand
what the problem is.
Was Stephanie
readmitted?
Yes, a few hours ago.
Don't tell me you put
her in the same room.
Well, yes,
but she isn't
there now.
Well, where is she?
The procedure room.
For what?
You're gonna have
to talk to Dr. Mandell,
he's the one who ordered it.
Ordered what?
What is he doing to her?
Mrs. Rawley,
do us a favor
and stay here.
BENSON: Dr. Mandell,
can we have
a word with you?
Hey, this is a sterile field.
Get out of here.
Who the hell are you?
Dr. Garrison.
Now, would you
please get out?
As soon as you tell us
what's going on here.
Just a routine procedure.
Dr. Mandell called me in.
To do what exactly?
Terminate the pregnancy.
I understand you just
interfered with
a medical emergency.
BENSON: What's that,
doc-talk for cover-up?
What are you
talking about?
You tried to destroy
evidence in a rape case
in which you're a suspect.
No wonder you were so willing
to give up your DNA.
You knew you could fix it
so there'd be
nothing to compare it to.
Look, all I knew was
that Stephanie Rawley's
Iife was in danger.
It's funny how the docs
at Wheaton Memorial
seemed to miss that.
Yes, well, they're not
experts in the care of
the profoundly devastated.
So you decide
to play God.
No, I called in
Dr. Garrison,
who agreed that it would
be malpractice to allow
the pregnancy to continue.
How very noble of you.
Except for the fact
that you failed to get
the parents' consent.
It's right here.
STABLER: That's crap.
Mrs. Rawley came to us,
hysterical, when she found out
Stephanie was
brought back here.
I dealt with Mr. Rawley.
I didn't know
what else to do.
I knew you'd
never consent.
Of course I wouldn't.
A sick pervert
raped our daughter.
I wanted that
monster out of her.
Was it Dr. Mandell's
idea or was it yours?
He called and told me
the risks of continuing
the pregnancy.
After all this,
I couldn't Iose
my daughter.
An abortion goes
against everything
that we believe in.
This is different.
It's Stephanie.
Do you want to raise
that thing inside her?
That thing is
our grandchild.
Why don't we
talk over here.
I'm a father, too.
What would you do?
I don't know.
I come visit every day
on my Iunch break.
With Mrs. Rawley?
No, alone.
What are you saying?
I'm sorry to
have to say this,
it's standard procedure,
but I should
get a DNA sample.
Robert!
You just assaulted
a police officer.
It's your call.
No, it's okay.
It's okay.
Questioning the father
as a suspect is never
a crowd-pleaser.
Verbal vitriol you'd expect,
anyone else think the father
protests a bit too much?
You're not a father.
You don't have a raped
daughter in a coma with
a devil cake in the oven.
That you just
tried to abort.
Well, we'II know if
it's Dad soon enough.
When do we get the products
of conception for testing?
STABLER: We don't.
They're keeping it.
FIN: Why?
Wife's Catholic.
Still, I've never had
a keeper with a stranger
rape before.
John, OIivia's mother
was raped by a stranger.
My mother
made a choice.
Look, OIivia,
we were just talking...
No, save it.
If the same thing
happened to me,
morning-after pill,
no question.
BENSON: So where
are we on the case?
No abortion,
no fetal tissue.
We're screwed.
We'II just have to
wait a couple of months
to start paternity tests.
Until then,
we'II work it
without DNA.
Where are we with
the rehab employees?
We ruled out a handful
with verifiable
medical reasons.
And we interviewed
everybody on the Iist
that volunteered their DNA.
I'm more interested
in anybody who refused.
That would be
two employees.
Okay, Iet's split up
and find out why.
SAMUEL: I know the drill.
Somebody committed a crime,
so Iet's check out
the black guy.
That stinks of
racial profiling.
We're Iooking
at everyone.
Where's your
probable cause?
What about a
search warrant?
This flies in the face
of the Fourth Amendment.
Mr. Hill, supplying
your DNA is voluntary.
No, it's not.
If you decide
not to volunteer,
you're presumed guilty.
I guess you're right.
So just ante up.
Hold on.
Mr. Hill has
a valid point.
Our Iikes, dislikes
and habits are all stored
in huge computer systems.
On top of that, you got
facial recognition technology,
public video surveillance.
National ID cards.
Where does it end?
Every piece of data
you put out there,
exponentially increases
the control The Man
wields over us.
I can see you understand
why this conversation
ends here.
Good day to you both.
Mr. Hill, if you didn't
rape Stephanie Rawley,
DNA can only exclude you.
We're off your back.
No.
Fascist pig.
What the hell was that?
Good police work.
Here's your DNA.
Well, what if I have a fatal
illness or something? Then I'd
know. I don't want to know.
We won't be testing
for any diseases.
But what if someone
gets ahold of the test,
finds out that I
do have a disease,
then denies me insurance?
I can't make all
those medical bills.
I assure you,
no one outside
the police department
will have access
to your DNA.
Once you exclude yourself,
it's destroyed.
Okay. AII right.
Well, what if I've committed
some crime in the past, huh?
Can you arrest me,
once you get ahold
of my DNA?
Have you committed
another crime?
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
No. But, you know.
Guys...
They make mistakes
all the time,
guys go to prison for years
before they figure it out.
Mr. Baltzer, if you don't
clear yourself, we're gonna
have to start digging around.
Why?
And asking questions.
Look, you had
access to the victim.
You were here alone,
at night, no witnesses.
No, no,
that's not true.
I am not here alone,
I swear.
There are a Iot of people
who wander these halls.
Like?
Like the vending guys,
the delivery men.
The fellow who
picks up the...
Picks up the what?
You know,
from the morgue.
The stiffs.
I get hungry.
The vending machines upstairs
have better selections.
Well, how do they compare
with the snacks in, say,
the coma wing?
I don't know.
I don't go there.
Oh, come on.
AII those nights
you've roamed the halls
jonesing for a Ding Dong fix,
you never once checked out
the coma wing?
What are you getting at?
Wesley, we're collecting DNA
from everyone who has contact
with the rehab.
We'd appreciate
your contribution.
No. No, I don't think so.
STABLER: Why not,
what's to hide?
I know how you cops operate.
You get a case,
you can't solve it,
you plant evidence,
make Wesley your fall guy.
Sounds Iike you've
had a run-in or two
with the police.
I don't have a record.
No, but we did find
a dropped complaint
against you.
Maxine Hatters?
Who the hell is that?
The woman you
assaulted a year ago.
tried to choke.
She called the police?
She's Iucky I didn't
have her arrested.
You attacked her.
Why would you be
the one to press charges?
Because she
stole my wallet.
I only took it so
I could turn him in.
Creep tried
to strangle me.
That's a serious charge.
Why drop it?
I didn't Iike the way
I was being treated.
I tried to tell my story
and your boys in blue
put it back on me.
You want to tell us,
we'II Iisten.
So, I'm sitting in
this chicken joint,
Iike, 3:00 a.m.
This guy comes over,
starts asking me
about the chicken.
The chicken.
MAXINE: Yeah.
He offers to buy me some.
Some chicken?
Yeah. Only when we
get up to the motel
room to eat it...
Maxine, the guy's a john.
You're all alike. I'm a pro,
so it doesn't matter
he tried to kill me.
We don't care about your
night job, we're just trying
to get the story straight.
So we get up to
the motel room,
I ask him how he wants it,
I'm supposed to strip naked,
Iie flat on my back, not move
a muscle, not say a sound.
You got a problem
with that?
No.
He's the one who
had a Iittle problem,
if you know what I mean.
Okay, so you Iaughed at him,
he chokes you.
No, I was very understanding,
till he started
filling the tub with ice.
For what?
He told me to Iie in it.
I'm Iike, "No way."
That's when he chokes me.
He was trying to Iower
your body temperature.
Said he couldn't do it
unless I really seemed dead.
BENSON: You gotta
be kidding me.
Wesley, what is this thing
with you, water and women?
I'm just doing my job.
I mean, the hot showers I get,
but ice baths?
We tracked down Maxine.
Your old prostitute.
The one you hired
to pretend to be
pretty much Iike her.
I heard you
weren't real happy
with her performance.
How'd Stephanie Rawley do?
I told you, I've never
been to the coma wing.
Could you please go?
You're gonna get me fired.
Oh, we wouldn't
want to do that,
seeing as you've
only been here for,
what, a couple of months?
Before that you were at
Upson Funeral Home.
What went wrong there?
Nothing.
No, Wesley was great.
It was just time
for him to move on.
After seven weeks.
Yes.
Uh-huh.
Ma'am, just so you know,
the Federal Trade Commission
no Ionger requires you
to buy your casket
at the funeral home.
You can save a few thousand
by buying from the supplier.
Not when you take into account
the discount package I'II be
offering you.
I'II be right back
to discuss that.
I assume you gave
her the price Iist,
as required by Iaw?
AII right.
We had some thefts.
Some jewelry,
a few gold fillings,
so we installed a camera.
We're not here
about grave robbing.
Well, Wesley wasn't
our thief.
But I'm afraid we
did catch him on tape.
Doing what?
The Iate Mrs. Thurgeston.
Kind of Iate to be
paying your respects,
isn't it?
STABLER: Guess
you two were close.
Really close.
You Iike
the quiet type, huh?
PIease turn it off.
Oh, relax,
it's over in a second.
Ah, but I guess I don't
have to tell you that.
WESLEY: Can I please
have a glass of water?
(KNOCKING)
BENSON: Heavy on the ice,
right?
BENSON: He's got dry mouth.
At Ieast we're
making him nervous.
HUANG: Yeah,
you more than EIIiot.
He's a necrophiliac.
His greatest fear
is to be judged by women.
The emasculation
tactic might not be
the way to go on this one.
That's why we
pulled you out.
What are you
thinking?
Shame is driving
his compulsion.
He was most Iikely
raised in an overly
religious household,
where an intense
degree of shame
was attached to sex.
So what are we thinking?
Empathize?
Tell him that
we understand?
I doubt that
he understands.
Pretty girl, isn't she?
I guess.
AImost Iike SIeeping Beauty
and she's been
in a coma for a year.
Look, I've never
seen her before.
Come on, Wesley,
I understand.
I'm a guy.
Hard opportunity to pass up.
It's not Iike she
knew what was going on.
You don't understand.
I do, more than you think.
It's what every guy wants.
No one judging you...
Right.
Just Stephanie
Iying there perfect.
Deaf, dumb and blind.
No, it doesn't
work that way.
Why doesn't it
work that way?
She's alive.
Come on!
Don't split hairs with me,
Wesley! Come on!
People snap out of
comas all the time.
Well, what about the hooker
that you hired, huh?
She was alive
and kicking, pal.
And I bet she told you
what a miserable failure
I was.
Yes, she did.
And we had a big
Iaugh at your expense.
I knew she'd talk.
(SNIFFING)
You can't trust
a woman with a pulse.
CRAGEN: Get him his water.
Okay, but I don't see
this guy giving it up,
whether I'm in there or not.
HUANG: What if there's
nothing to give up?
Obviously we weren't
watching the same tape.
I'm just saying,
there are some extreme
cases where a necrophiliac
can't sustain the arousal
required to penetrate,
Iet alone impregnate,
a warm body.
So, you don't
need me after all.
No, hold on.
The only thing
rendering Mr. Dilbert Iimp
is the 12-to-25 he's facing
on rape one as opposed to...
What does
necrophilia get him?
Sexual misconduct.
A misdemeanor.
Great. One year, max.
CABOT: Is there anything
that Iinks him to Stephanie?
Any witnesses,
physical evidence?
We'II have paternity
in two months.
Well, at the very Ieast,
Iet's save the Iate
Mrs. Thurgeston
another spin in her grave.
We'II charge him
with necrophilia,
get him off the street.
"Docket number 269501.
People vs. Dilbert.
"Sexual misconduct
130.20 sub 3."
Sub 3?
Which one is it, Counselor?
Was the sexual conduct
with an animal or
a dead human body?
Mr. Dilbert is a funeral home
attendant who was videotaped
having sex with
a human corpse.
COHEN: Your plea, Mr. Dilbert?
Not guilty, Your Honor.
I'II hear from
the People on bail.
$100,000.
COHEN: For an A misdemeanor?
CABOT: He has insufficient
community ties,
poses an ongoing threat,
and, we believe,
is a flight risk.
He has Iimited
financial means,
no criminal record,
and given
the non-violent crime
he's been charged with,
I see no threat
to the community.
Your honor, Mr. Dilbert
is the number-one suspect
in the rape of
a comatose patient.
We believe this heightens
the flight risk considerably.
I'm sorry, I don't see
an indictment on that charge.
You will.
Until I do, His Honor
cannot possibly consider
it in determining bail.
Request ROR.
Bail's set at $5,000.
So he'II be
out by morning.
Free to ruin
someone else's
daughter.
Why couldn't you charge him
with Stephanie's rape?
We don't have enough
evidence to support it yet.
Mr. RAWLEY: When will you?
We need the fetus' DNA
to determine paternity.
The earliest an amnio
can be done is 14 weeks.
That's almost two months.
They could have it now
if they had the tissue.
That's not an option.
HUANG: You know,
I may have one for you.
Dr. Huang is familiar
with the case.
With amniocentesis,
as with chorionic
villus sampling,
there's always
a chance of miscarriage
or other complications.
Oh, my God.
HUANG: That's why they've
been experimenting
with alternative testing.
A colleague of mine,
a forensic gynecologist,
has been successful
in adapting the alternative
to determine early prenatal
paternity.
BENSON: So what did
you get for us?
Well, we took 30 cc
of Stephanie's blood
and we subjected it to density
gradient centrifugation
to remove the maternal
non-nucleated
red blood cells.
HUANG: Leaving you only
with the fetal cells.
So, did it work?
Well, mind you,
even during
the optimal period,
the frequency of fetal cells
in maternal blood is
only one in ten million.
Luckily, we have this
high-precision magnetic
cell-separation technology.
BENSON: So, did it
work or not?
Yes.
Did you compare it to Wesley
the Necro's DNA sample?
There was no need.
The fetus' blood type is AB.
The mother's is type A,
which means...
The father can
only be type B.
And Wesley is type A.
So, he cannot be the father.
That's right.
Damn it.
We have those other
volunteered samples to run.
How many are type B?
Well, not the fiancé,
not Mr. Riley,
not the night custodian,
not him...
Hello.
Look who we have here.
Do you have any idea how many
people have type B blood?
One in ten.
We did our homework.
And you're the only
one who had type B
and had access
and tried to
abort the evidence.
Doc, you just keep
popping up on our
radar screen.
Now what are we
supposed to think?
Well, fortunately,
you don't have to.
Modern technology has removed
that burden. You have my DNA,
just run it.
Well, we'II get the results
back in a few days.
The problem is, you make us
wait till then, we're gonna
be in no mood to bargain.
I think I'II
take my chances.
(KNOCKING)
BENSON: Why, Dr. Huang.
What brings you here?
Some fascinating results
from the gynecological
examinations
performed on Dr. Mandell's
other female coma patients.
These are forensic pictures
taken with a culposcope
of the uterine walls
of your patient,
Audrey Logan.
Dr. Mandell,
help us out here.
What's your diagnosis?
I'm not a trained OB/GYN.
Come on,
we all did gynecology
in med school.
Give it a shot.
Well, it Iooks Iike
a healthy uterus, no
signs of endometriosis,
no polyps, no cysts.
Well, it does take
a trained eye, but if
you notice right there,
there's miniscule scarring.
STABLER:
From a sexual assault?
No. I'd say more Iikely
from a recent abortion.
So, you raped her, too.
And got rid of the evidence.
I need to speak
with my attorney.
Doc Mandell took
care of both women.
We know he tried to abort
Stephanie's fetus,
he's not copping to the other.
Well, what do we know
about raped coma victim
number two?
Audrey Logan, captain of her
high school debate team
until she went to a rave
three years ago and ingested
one too many party favors.
Yeah, now she's captain
of the drool team.
Fin went to get
her medical records.
What have you
dug up on the doc?
No dirt, per se, yet,
but Iisten to this.
Turns out he works
two days a week
at a place called Diotyne.
Bio-tech company.
What does he
do there?
Parkinson's research.
Well, it make sense.
He's a neurologist.
CRAGEN: Audrey's
medical files?
No record of an abortion
and the only operation
was for an ovarian cyst
removed four months ago.
Time frame fits
with the scarring.
FIN: Guess who the OB/GYN was.
Dr. Garrison.
That's the same woman
Mandell brought in to
abort Stephanie.
I think it's time we
invite her in for a chat.
FIN: Tried, she wasn't
at the hospital.
She works for some
research Iab called...
Diotyne?
How do you know?
Just a crazy hunch.
My relationship with
Dr. Mandell is none
of your business.
He's in a Iot of trouble,
Dr. Garrison.
And he's dragged you into it.
Dr. Mandell hasn't
dragged me into anything.
You're awfully
accommodating.
How's it work?
He rapes 'em,
you scrape 'em?
He's not a rapist.
As I explained,
Stephanie's Iife was,
and is, at risk.
BENSON: And what about
Audrey Logan?
You did a good job
removing her cyst.
Didn't even Ieave
a scar on her ovary.
But you did Ieave
one on her uterus.
How do you
explain that?
It's not what you think.
Oh, yeah,
what is it?
Bureaucratic roadblocks.
When Bush Iimited stem cell
research to cell Iines
already established,
he essentially shut
down Graham's work.
What does that have to do
with Stephanie Rawley and
Audrey Logan?
Everything.
He Iost his federal
funding and we had
to turn to private sources.
Which is Iegal,
but unfortunately
has strings attached.
What are you
talking about?
Do you know who
Davis Langley is?
BENSON: The software magnate?
He put up all the money.
I could have stopped him
but this is for
the greater good.
Where's the greater
good in rape?
They weren't raped.
They were inseminated.
Stephanie's parents
signed a blanket consent.
Did it mention
insemination in
the fine print?
It covered
experimental procedures.
I've done everything
conceivable to bring
her out of the coma.
This wasn't for her.
It was for an old,
sick billionaire.
I have done nothing wrong.
I didn't profit
from this in any way.
We'II be checking
your financials.
Look, do you have
any idea what Parkinson's
does to a body?
Any idea?
I watched my
father slowly
deteriorate and then
die from the disease.
I couldn't do
a thing to stop it.
Being a doctor,
that must have been
very frustrating for you.
It's why I became
a neurologist.
I didn't want to
see anybody else
suffer the way he did.
(SIGHS)
I was just trying
to help Mr. Langley.
But the hell with
Audrey and Stephanie,
right?
Don't you get it?
Medical advances
have a price.
Now, the first ten
bone marrow transplants
ended in death.
Now if we'd given up,
thousands of people
would have died.
Like they'II go on
dying from Parkinson's
if you stop me
from doing my job.
Don't you get it?
You're going to jail.
I haven't broken
any Iaws.
You impregnated two girls
against their will.
What will?
They barely
have a pulse.
Audrey is in no
worse condition now
than she was before.
And I could have said the same
about Stephanie if you hadn't
stopped the procedure.
Oh, so now it's our fault.
AII I needed was a genetic
match for the stem cells
to be implanted into
Mr. Langley's brain.
It's still experimental,
but it's his only hope.
SCHOENFELD:
Sorry to keep you waiting.
I'm Milton Schoenfeld,
Mr. Langley's attorney.
Well, since we're whipping
them out, this is AIex Cabot,
Assistant District Attorney.
What can I do for you?
Well, for starters,
you can produce your client.
Anything you have
to say to Mr. Langley,
you can say to me.
If there's anything
of interest,
I'II pass it along.
Of interest?
How about paying a woman
to be forcibly impregnated?
Then conspiring to abort
the fetus and play
Frankenstein with the parts.
Mr. Langley is not a doctor,
although he has consulted
several regarding
his condition.
He can't be held
responsible if any Iaws
were broken by one of them
without his knowledge.
Right, he had no idea why
he was jerking off into a cup.
He's given countless
specimens. BIood,
urine, tissue...
He couldn't tell you
what was done with those,
either.
So he wouldn't have
any trouble testifying
against Dr. Mandell.
I'm afraid his failing
health would prohibit that.
Oh, that's too bad,
because if there's one place
you don't want to be when
you're sick, it's Attica.
My client has done nothing
illegal, so good Iuck getting
an indictment.
Otherwise,
don't bother us again.
AIex. Hey,
how'd it go?
The grand jury
gave me both doctors,
but no-billed Langley.
Did they see
the three million dollar
check he wrote to Diotyne?
As a perfectly
Iegal donation.
That was payment
for stolen goods.
It doesn't even meet
the burden for a felony.
Because it's illegal
to buy and sell body parts,
by Iaw they have
no monetary value.
You mean, I could go to jail
for stealing a toaster,
but not for stealing
a woman's eggs?
Unfortunately,
the Iaw hasn't quite
caught up to the technology.
Well, what if
Dr. Mandell's
theory is right
and the procurement
of genetically matched
stem cells is the answer?
Does that up
the ethical dilemma?
Mandell and Garrison
essentially raped a woman
with a turkey baster.
So, you've got
aggravated sex
abuse one.
Well, that's what I'm
going for, but they're gonna
argue no sexual gratification.
Every jury has a mother,
a daughter or a sister.
PIay the emotion card.
CABOT: Mrs. Rawley,
take your time.
MRS. RAWLEY:
Stephanie's been in a coma...
It'II be 14 months
next Tuesday.
And during that time,
has she ever regained
consciousness?
No. She's on Iife support.
Machines constantly
monitor her vital signs,
so there would be a record
if she had ever woken up,
even momentarily?
Oh, yes.
That hasn't happened. Yet.
So there is no way
she could have consented
to being impregnated
and then having her fetus
aborted by Dr. Mandell's
experimental procedure.
MRS. RAWLEY: Absolutely not.
And she would never
have agreed to that,
under any circumstances.
Do you ever
visit your daughter?
Every day.
I talk to her, read to her,
when her Iips are chapped, I
put ice chips on them.
But if Stephanie can't
communicate with you,
or with anyone else
for that matter,
why do you put
yourself through it?
Because I know she's still
in there somewhere.
People wake up from
comas all the time,
sometimes after years.
And I'm going to be
there when she does.
Thank you.
Your daughter was
a very pretty girl.
She still is.
LANGAN: Kind person?
Ask anyone who
ever met her.
Sweetest girl
in the world.
What did she
do for a Iiving?
She graduated with honors,
she could've done anything,
but she chose to work with
special needs children.
I have a copy of her
driver's Iicense here.
She was an organ donor?
Yes.
She intended to spend
the rest of her Iife,
and after, helping people.
Yes.
LANGAN: So,
would it be
fair to say,
considering her
circumstances,
she might have
chosen to contribute
any way she could to help
the suffering of millions?
Stephanie Ioved children.
How dare you imply that
she would have created
a Iife just to have it
destroyed by that monster.
We trusted you.
You promised you would do
everything you could for her.
Your job was to help
Stephanie, not use her
as a human petrie dish!
LANGAN: What good could
possibly have come from
this experimental procedure?
To start with,
the cure of Parkinson's.
From there,
treatment for AIzheimer's,
spinal cord injuries,
heart disease, diabetes.
How?
Well, I'm afraid
it's quite involved.
It's a culmination
of 15 years of my
own research,
not to mention
a century of experimentation
by countless others.
In a nutshell?
The Holy Grail of
medical research.
Embryonic stem cells.
Now, unlike adult cells,
they have a
pluripotentiality.
In Iayman's terms?
Well, these cells haven't
decided what they're going
to become yet.
Meaning we can coax them
to grow into any cell type
we need.
LANGAN: In the case
of Parkinson's?
The brain must produce
dopamine to control
muscle movement.
In Parkinson's,
the basal ganglia cells
which produce this chemical
start to degenerate and die.
And it's our hope to
finally replace these
damaged neural cells.
Thank you.
BENSON: Mandell
actually took the stand
in his own defense?
He still doesn't think
he did anything wrong.
So he hung himself.
Not if he reaches
even one juror
whose parent is dying
from Parkinson's
or AIzheimer's.
Well, they have no choice
if you made your case.
He Iost a Iot of ground
when he admitted he tried
to abort Stephanie.
And I still
have my summation.
I'm afraid
there's going to be
a slight delay on that.
Sorry for the Iate notice,
but this witness
just became available.
Who is it?
Well, he was too
sick to testify for us,
but it Iooks Iike
Davis Langley has made
a miraculous recovery
for the defense.
At the start it was
just my right hand.
My hand,
it was ice cold
all the time.
Then, my arm
stopped swinging
when I walked
and that was
six years ago.
Now, I...
I can't even
brush my own teeth.
I can't button
my shirt.
I can't control
my bowels.
I piss in this bag,
for God's sake.
I choke on my food.
I'm even afraid to
take a drink of water
because usually it
goes down the wrong pipe
and causes havoc
in my Iungs.
I've had
pneumonia three times.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
And why did you choose
to come forward today,
Mr. Langley?
Because they're
prosecuting the wrong man.
Dr. Mandell fought
me tooth and nail.
He made it perfectly clear
that they had some success
with animal trials but they
were years away from humans.
LANGAN: Why would you
put yourself at risk?
I haven't got five
more years to wait
for government approval.
At this point, I don't think
I've got five months.
Thank you.
Mr. Langley,
were you aware how
Dr. Mandell attempted
to procure stem cells for you?
Actually, it was my idea.
I wasn't aware you
had a medical degree,
Mr. Langley.
I don't,
but I read everything
there is out there
about the subject.
If they could create
a picture-perfect
genetically matched cell,
they could up the odds.
So, who cares if a comatose
woman is violated in the name
of science?
No, no.
My sympathy
to the family, but
their beautiful daughter
Ieft this earth a year ago.
But out of their tragedy
could come a gift of Iife
for many, many others.
You have all
the money in the world.
Why not hire a surrogate?
Well, it's one thing
to carry a baby
for someone else,
it's quite another
to do what we needed.
I couldn't ask any woman
to knowingly carry
that burden.
Mr. Langley, are you aware
that you have just confessed
to being a co-conspirator
in this crime?
Young Iady, Iook at me.
Prison couldn't compare
with what I'm facing now.
Even if it's
too Iate for me,
it could end up
helping millions.
I'm willing to
be the guinea pig.
PIease, Iet me
make it happen.
PIease.
STABLER: Verdict came in.
BENSON: No.
They did not
Iet 'em off.
SIaps on the wrist.
The only charge
I got a guilty on was
the straight battery.
They tried to
steal a human fetus.
A guy in Jersey got
10 years for selling
stolen horse sperm.
Got no priors,
there's a chance Mandell
won't even see jail time.
There's just no precedent
for this kind of case yet.
Mrs. Rawley, I am so sorry
I could not do more.
You okay?
Can I get you
something?
You have got
to stop him.
Stop who?
Davis Langley just filed
for custody of the baby.
He wants to take my
grandchild away from me.
He can't do that, can he?
His attorney says he is
the biological father,
that you just established
that for him in court.
And he says that
biology always wins.
Mrs. Rawley,
Iet's have a seat.
Let's just calm
down for a second,
come on over here.
I don't get it.
Why would Davis Langley
want custody of that baby?
Guilt?
Survival.
If he's granted custody,
along with the baby
comes the umbilical cord.
I've cut four of them,
it's not exactly something
you save for the scrapbook.
Cord blood is chock
full of stem cells.
Half of which will be his
perfect genetic match.