NARRATOR: In the criminal
justice system,
sexually based offenses
are considered
especially heinous.
In New York City,
the dedicated detectives
who investigate
these vicious felonies
are members
of an elite squad known as
the Special Victims Unit.
These are their stories.
Yeah. Okay, thanks.
Come on.
Go, go, go!
Police! NYPD!
We have a search warrant!
What the hell?
Somebody got here
before us.
Secure it.
I don't want
any surprises.
OFFICER 1: Too Iate.
I better call in SVU.
We are not handing
this bust over to them.
Don't worry.
I got a buddy.
FIN: Better be good.
Anonymous phone tip
said somebody was dealing.
We surveilled a week,
caught a Iot of traffic
in and out of this place.
Get our warrant, bust in,
find our alleged
dealer sliced and diced.
Signs of burglary, and by her
appearance I'm guessing she's
been raped, too.
But, you know, I wanted
a trained SVU detective
Iike yourself on the case.
Rape-homicide falls
on SVU no matter what.
You didn't have to
hand it to me personally.
There's a big haul here.
Looks good for my guys
to turn it in.
Yeah, right.
You get all the glory
and we get all the work.
So you trying to tell me
that Laura Ashley here
is some kind of big kingpin?
Where are the drugs?
You didn't get
the complete tour.
Over two hundred plants.
Pull in a couple
of hundred thou
on the street.
Perp missed the jackpot.
M.E. estimates TOD
yesterday between
9:00 a.m. and 2:00 p.m.
Looked Iike about
30 to 40 stab wounds.
Overkill.
He either knew her
well enough to hate her
or he's psychotic.
Point of entry Iooks Iike
the fire escape window.
Perp probably waltzed
out the front door.
Got minimal fluids
from the rape kit,
but enough to test.
You Iocate a
murder weapon?
Must've taken
it with him.
Three-inch, single-edged,
non-serrated blade.
About the size of the knife
missing from this?
Yeah. The other
weapon he Ieft behind.
Bashed in the back of her
head before he stabbed her.
Probably enough
to knock her out.
No defensive wounds.
It's not the most
obvious weapon.
So she surprises him.
Probably picked up
the first thing
he could grab.
Then he walks all the way
across the apartment
for a knife?
This guy's Iogic is
all over the place.
Maybe he's mentally ill.
Or high.
LAYTON: He covered
Mrs. Oestreicher with this.
By the amount of blood on
the blanket, I'd say right
after he stabbed her.
So afterwards
he gets remorseful,
embarrassed?
And then sick.
Our guy must
have thrown up.
It's too far away
to be the victim's.
Okay, Iet's send
a sample to the M.E.
We can compare it to
the stomach contents of our
victim, just to be sure.
LAYTON: I Iove my job.
What do we know about
this anonymous phone tip?
Narcotics traced
it to a neighbor.
Said she's nosy,
but not homicidal.
I thought anonymous
tip meant anonymous.
Like nobody would
bug you about doing
your civic duty.
We certainly don't mean
to inconvenience you.
But there was a woman
murdered in your building.
I know. I'm sorry
about that.
But you Iive
that kind of Iife,
you're asking for it.
And what kind
of Iife is that?
Criminal. You should've
been here when she was
sparking up.
Just walking down
the hall you'd get a buzz.
Marc, get in there
and brush those teeth now.
So you reported
Mrs. Oestreicher
as a drug dealer
because you smelled dope.
That was the only reason?
What about the daily
Easter parade?
In and out of there,
people banging on the door
all hours of the day.
Did you ever actually
see any of these deals,
any money changing hands?
No. No, but if she wasn't
selling, I don't know where
she got her money.
She hasn't worked
a day in over a year.
Autopsy's done.
So are the preliminary
Iabs on the fluids from
the rape kit.
Anything interesting?
Your perp had no sperm.
Interesting and pathetic.
I'm not talking
Iow sperm count.
This is azoospermia.
Zero sperm in the ejaculate.
It's pretty rare.
So our guy
got a vasectomy.
That's one
explanation for it.
It's also a sign of
Kartagener's Syndrome
and Cystic Fibrosis.
The Iab can still extract
DNA from the skin
cells in the sample.
And they're
analyzing the vomit.
We know who puked?
Victim hadn't eaten
in hours, so it had to
come from your perp.
As far as Miss Oestreicher
is concerned,
I suspect she would have died
within the year, had she not
been murdered.
What was
wrong with her?
Advanced
ovarian cancer.
She has small radiation burns
on the skin of her abdomen,
and blood tests reveal
Taxol and carboplatin.
She was undergoing
chemotherapy.
That explains why
she didn't have a job.
And why she was
growing pot.
Must have been using it
to counteract the side effects
of the cancer treatment.
Decent Ievels of
THC in her system.
But that woman was growing
a forest in there.
You think she was
toking on all that
by herself?
Maybe she wasn't.
You know, medicinal
marijuana clubs are
popping up everywhere.
People are pooling their
resources, growing their
own stuff.
Better product without
having to pay street prices.
Well, if she's running a club,
then there has to be
a membership Iist.
How many people
we Iooking at?
According to her
day planner,
nearly 100.
But there's no names.
She only writes initials.
We got C.K. down
the second Monday
of every month.
J.A.S. every
other Saturday.
Probably a schedule.
Members take turns
tending the crop.
Why the hell you
know so much about it?
Twenty-five years on the job
and he's still a damn hippie.
Okay, I got the phone dumps
from Susan Oestreicher
for the past six months.
We got to match the names
with the initials and weed
out the potheads.
Find one club member,
might Iead us to the rest.
Convincing somebody
to turn over that Iist
is not going to be easy.
People Iooking at
a narcotics rap tend
to be real cooperative.
Threatening cancer patients.
Now, that's why
I became a cop.
They're breaking the Iaw.
I don't care how sick
they are.
Do you have any idea
why cannabis is
illegal in this country?
Because William Randolph
Hearst's paper mills
were threatened by
the hemp industry.
And that's got nothing
to do with the fact that
it's a drug.
What do you call
alcohol and tobacco?
Legal.
Here we go.
For the initials C.K.,
we've got a Cindy Kerber.
C.K. C.K. Charles Kelsey,
Christian Kessler.
This is going to be fun.
We'II run them all down.
If they had access
to the victim,
they're all suspects.
STABLER: We know about
your club, Miss Kerber.
Then I assume you found
what we were growing.
Pretty tough to miss.
You guys have
very green thumbs.
We're not hurting
anyone and we're
not making a profit.
We are investigating
a murder.
Now, all we need
are the other names
of the members in the club.
The rest is between us.
I don't know most of
the people involved.
We don't socialize.
Give us the names
of the people
you do know.
I'm sorry. I can't.
This woman
was raped.
She was stabbed
38 times.
You don't want to help us
in our investigation?
That is very strange to me.
Because it wasn't
anyone in the club.
Some of these people were
debilitated from nausea,
from chemotherapy.
The only thing that controls
my tremors from M.S.
is smoking once in a while.
Why would we kill the woman
who was helping us?
Maybe she was
helping the wrong person.
Somebody's sick,
doesn't make
them an angel.
There was some trouble
with this one woman, Becky.
Not her, really. Her husband.
What kind of trouble?
He threatened Sue.
Said she hooked
his wife on drugs.
Becky was dying
from metastatic
breast cancer,
and he wouldn't allow her
the tiniest bit of relief.
Well, do you think
that he's capable
of murder?
I know his own wife
was afraid of him.
Especially after he broke
some guy's back in a bar
fight. Went to jail for it.
I wouldn't
touch that bitch.
Isn't it refreshing to hear
such militant adherence to
the "Just Say No" philosophy?
It's so rare
in convicts.
That incident
was an accident.
I did five years inside,
and now my wife's dead.
I paid the price.
Go bother somebody else.
No, we're bothering you,
Mr. Paglione.
You got an awful Iot of hate
for the woman who was trying
to comfort your wife.
Yeah, that's a real
beautiful story.
Until one of you comes to my
house and finds drugs and
busts me for parole violation.
I was working from
6:00 in the morning
to 4:00, and no Iunch break.
And that's all I'm saying.
BENSON: We'II see you
back at the house.
Munch says the husband's
alibi checks out.
This membership Iist
is getting smaller.
Half these people
are either dead or too
weak to get out of bed.
Maybe we're going
down the wrong path
with this pot club.
No, I just can't buy that
the murder and the drugs
are a coincidence.
Susan Oestreicher's neighbor
thought she was a drug dealer.
What if somebody
else thought so, too?
An M.E. out of the morgue?
Must be big.
Captain Cragen told me
you were here.
Lab finished analyzing
the vomit from
the crime scene.
Hey, am I gonna
want to stop eating
before I hear this?
Pieces of roast beef,
a Iittle mozzarella cheese,
kernels of corn and raisins.
Luckily, they hadn't been
in the stomach very Iong,
so everything was
only partially digested.
Yeah, I'm done.
And this is
good news because?
My daughter's in
the sixth grade.
She had that exact
meal for Iunch at school
on the day of the murder.
I've got the menu
on the fridge.
I called the Board of Ed.
Every middle school
in Manhattan serves
the same Iunch.
No sperm in the ejaculate.
We're Iooking for a kid.
Are we buying in to
this juvenile theory?
Well, it makes sense.
The disorganization of
the crime scene indicates
an immature thought process.
The number of stab wounds
could mean he has no real
understanding of physiology.
He just kills
the way he thinks that
you're supposed to kill.
The rape. Sexual curiosity.
Well, we know the kid went
to school that day Iong
enough to have Iunch,
so he must've
cut out afterwards.
Well, we're not canvassing
every junior high in the city,
and I'm not waiting for a DNA
analysis of the puke,
so Iet's hear suggestions.
Okay, we're Iooking for
a boy who has a history
of fights in school.
Minor vandalism with
risk-taking behavior.
Sounds Iike every
teenage boy on the planet.
I know.
It's not much
to go on.
But adolescent behavior
is inherently unpredictable.
That's why mental
health care professionals
won't Iabel a child
a sociopath even if
he fits the definition.
So the profile's wide open.
What else?
Juvies stay
with the familiar.
Maybe the victim
knew this kid.
And even if she didn't,
he's Iikely to commit
the crimes in his
own comfort zone.
The neighbor
who phoned in
the tip to Narcotics.
Her son Iooked
about 13, right?
That was Mrs. Lesinski
and her son Marc.
Maybe he Iistens to Mom
rail about the drug
dealer down the hall,
he figures he can get
himself some free dope.
And get some cash
for a new Xbox
while he's at it.
Check him out.
Look, I told you,
Marc didn't see who
killed her.
He was in school.
You're sure about that?
Of course I am.
And the school calls
if he skips class?
What exactly
are you asking?
Mrs. Lesinski,
we need to speak
with Marc right now.
You think he could
have done this?
He is a child.
Are you crazy?
Has Marc bought anything
that he doesn't have
the money for?
No.
Have you seen him with...
Seen him with anything
expensive that you
didn't give him?
He said it was
a present from
a friend.
STABLER: Come on over here.
Show it to us, will you?
An MP3 player.
Must be a very good friend
to be so generous.
No, the kid's a total geek.
He's always giving stuff
to people.
Oh. This total geek
have a name?
Jeremy Brice.
STABLER: Mmm-hmm. Where do
you think Jeremy got that?
Did you tell him that you
had a drug dealer Iiving
down the hall from you?
Yeah.
What'd you say?
I said that she's probably
got some pretty cool stuff,
you know, 'cause she deals.
BENSON: So don't you think
it's possible that he got it
from Mrs. Oestreicher's place?
I don't know, maybe.
But there's no way
Jeremy killed her.
Well, how do you
know that?
He's just not that cool.
(DOOR BELL RINGING)
It is almost 8:00.
Everybody's already Ieft.
Let's pull him
out of school.
Liv. Liv.
Kids waiting
for the bus.
Hi, guys.
Anyone know
Jeremy Brice?
Who?
Jeremy Brice.
There.
You Jeremy?
Relax, relax,
relax, Jeremy.
I didn't do anything!
We're the police.
We want to talk to you.
Just relax.
Jeremy, that Iooks
Iike blood.
No, it isn't.
We're going down to
the police station,
Jeremy, all right?
Where are
your parents?
I have to go to school.
I have to...
You made a mistake.
Jeremy was in school all day.
We checked, Mrs. Brice.
Jeremy's teachers told
us that he was absent
after Iunch.
You skipped school?
No.
Jeremy? Jeremy,
Iook at me a second.
You know you're
not supposed to Iie
to the police, right?
I'm not Iying.
STABLER: Where'd you get
the MP3 player you gave
to your buddy Marc?
I gave him that
for his birthday.
Do you know a Iady named
Susan Oestreicher?
No.
You sure? She's the woman that
Iives right next door to Marc.
Jeremy, you went
into that apartment,
and something bad
happened there,
didn't it?
I didn't go anywhere.
Jeremy, these are your
fingerprints that your mom
Iet us take when you got here.
Remember that?
These are the ones
that we found in
Miss Oestreicher's apartment.
They're exactly the same.
No, they're not.
STABLER: They are.
This tells me you
were in that apartment.
No, it doesn't.
Jeremy, what happened?
Nothing. Why is
everybody picking on me?
We'II take another crack
at him once he calms down.
Well, we know he
was in the apartment.
Once the Iabs come back on
the forensic evidence,
we won't need a confession.
A typical kid.
Thinks if he denies
everything,
it'II just go away.
He's 14. EIigible to
be tried as an adult.
Murder two.
Would've been
eligible if he was 13.
He Iook Iike
a grownup to you?
He brutally
raped and murdered
a 34-year-old woman.
That's a grownup crime.
He's not crying
for his victim,
he's crying for himself.
Guess you can't blame him.
His Iife is over.
Labs are back.
BIood on Jeremy's coat
matched the victim's type.
Sounds Iike your
job is done.
No. We're not that Iucky.
Lab's determined
that the rapist's
blood was a type B.
I got Jeremy's from
his school. He's type O.
He had a partner.
Yeah.
No sperm, so it's
got to be another kid.
Well, what about
that neighbor's boy?
Well, I checked him.
He didn't skip school
and went to basketball
practice afterwards.
Can we hold off on charging
Jeremy as an adult till we
get the story straight?
Well, he's 14,
so he's automatically
arraigned in Supreme Court.
But if you can prove to me
he wasn't the primary actor,
I will recommend he be
removed to Family Court.
Find out who
his friends are.
We're no strangers
to police inquiring
about some of our students,
but I am surprised to hear
you're investigating
Mr. Brice.
Jeremy's not a
troublemaker?
I don't know him,
so I guess not.
1,500 students, Detectives.
I only got time
for the bad eggs.
You're saying he's
a model student, then.
Academically, yes.
He does very well.
Especially in math and art.
But he was recently
diagnosed as dyslexic,
and according to his file,
his fifth grade teacher cited
social problems made him
repeat the year.
What kind of
social problems?
Well, I spoke with
Jeremy's teachers
this morning,
and he's a Iittle
behind maturity-wise.
He has some
trouble fitting in.
But again, nothing
to suggest any serious
discipline problems.
Teachers give you the names
of Jeremy's friends?
That's the thing,
no one knew.
Seems he really
doesn't have any.
We're going to need a Iist
of all the boys that were
absent the day of the murder,
and we're going to
need your permission
to search their Iockers.
I find any dead animals
in here, I'm going to
deputize you for this.
Got him.
What'd you find?
Susan Oestreicher.
(BELL RINGING)
And the weapon
that killed her.
PRINCIPAL CORRALES:
This is a surprise.
Locker 142 belongs
to Zachary Connor,
a sixth-grader.
I'II get his schedule
and we'II find him
in his next class.
I think he found
us already.
What happened
to my Iocker?
STABLER: Zachary Connor
is 12 years old.
I tell you, I've been on
this job a Iong time,
some things still surprise me.
You'II get over it.
His parents coming in?
They should
be here any minute.
We're going on 12 hours
holding Jeremy Brice.
He and his mother are
still in interrogation.
And they're staying until we
know his exact involvement
in this woman's death.
Munch is still
at the crime Iab.
CSU Iifted three
sets of prints off
of that knife.
One unknown,
one the victim's,
and one belonging to Jeremy.
Captain, these are
Zachary Connor's parents.
Mr. and Mrs. Connor,
thank you for making it down.
Nobody's told us anything.
Is Zach all right?
Well, he's fine. Fine.
We think he might know
something about a crime.
Now, Ted here
will get you settled,
and in a minute
a detective will
explain everything to you.
He's never been in
trouble before, Captain.
Not once.
Is that true?
No trouble with this boy?
Straight As.
Not a mark on
his school record.
Let's go easy on this.
Finesse them.
See if one turns
on the other.
Fin, you take
Zachary and his parents.
You guys take
another run at Jeremy.
Set up video cameras
and monitors in both rooms.
I'II call in Cabot
and Huang to observe.
FIN: Remember where
you were day before
yesterday, Zachary?
At school.
And then I went home.
You there all day?
Yeah.
Well, I talked
to your teachers,
and they said that you missed
all your classes after Iunch.
I was in the Iibrary.
I had to study
for a math test.
He does have
a big test coming up.
Okay. You know
Jeremy Brice?
He's a seventh-grader.
Friend of yours?
No. I don't
Iike him.
You didn't hang
out with him at all
day before yesterday?
No. He's dorky.
And he's a bully.
You got a knife, Zach?
A what?
You mean the one
in my Iocker.
FIN: Where'd you get it?
I found it in the dumpster
behind the school.
And the wallet, too.
What were you
Iooking for
in the garbage?
Well, sometimes they
throw out cool things.
Once I found
new markers.
Yeah, that is cool.
So why'd you take
the knife and wallet
and put them in your Iocker?
I was gonna
turn them in.
I thought someone Iost them.
But then I forgot.
Did you know there
was blood on that knife?
MRS. CONNOR: Oh, my God.
I thought it was fake.
But you should ask Jeremy.
He told me where to find it.
STABLER: So, Jeremy,
you want a drink?
No. I want to go home.
Well, I know you do.
But the reason that we have
to stay here is because you're
not telling us the truth.
Yes, I am.
Jeremy, we picked up
your friend Zachary
at school today.
Zach's here?
He's right in the next room,
speaking to one
of our detectives.
What do you think
he's going to say?
Nothing.
I think he might.
Look, I know you don't want
to get him in trouble,
but you've got to
tell us what happened.
Even if it's something that's
really, really bad,
you've got to tell us.
Zach's my best friend.
You can't make me say
he did something bad.
He didn't do anything.
Jeremy's in for
a rude awakening.
His best friend's
about to flip on him.
What I find hard to
believe is how a kid
as young as Zachary
is physically
capable of rape.
Biologically, all he needs
is enough testosterone
to achieve an erection.
These days,
boys reach puberty
as early as nine years old.
Add to that an ill woman,
weakened by chemotherapy.
She's the perfect victim
for a 90-pound rapist.
You think he did it?
I think he's Iying.
He keeps changing his story
so that it's just
plausible enough to be true.
He's involved.
What's all this?
Interrogation tactics,
Captain.
A few special mementos
from Zachary Connor's Iocker.
This is Detective Munch,
my partner.
MR. CONNOR: How much Ionger
do we need to be here?
Entirely up to your son,
Mr. Connor.
Is that your book?
I don't know.
AII our books
Iook alike.
Oh, yeah?
Is that your name?
Yeah.
Then that must
be yours, right?
What is this about?
It's his book.
Why does it matter?
We also have a CD
Iabeled with your initials,
a pen, a magazine subscription
sticker in your name.
You know where I got them?
In my Iocker at school?
Right. You know what else
they have in common? Hmm?
Detective Tutuola?
Covered with
his fingerprints.
MUNCH: Correct.
Just a minute.
Now, Zach,
you're a bright young man.
You understand that every
time you touch something,
you Ieave a
fingerprint behind.
So I want you to think
real hard before you
answer this question.
Were you ever in
an apartment on Avenue C
where a woman was killed?
Oh, what the hell?
I was in that Iady's
apartment with Jeremy.
He killed her.
Hey, Jeremy,
I think you might
want to see this.
FIN: Whose idea was it?
Jeremy's.
FIN: To rob her
or to kill her?
ZACHARY: Everything.
He said she had
lots of money.
But then she came home.
He made me do
bad things to her.
He made me touch her.
And then Jeremy got the knife
and he killed her.
FIN: What happened after that?
I ran away.
I was scared.
Jeremy. No.
Jeremy, is that
what happened?
He's Iying!
So you tell us the truth.
I didn't want
anyone to get hurt.
Was it your idea to break
into that woman's apartment?
Jeremy, why would
you do that?
Zach thought it was cool.
STABLER: Was it cool when
you took the telephone
and bashed her head in?
I didn't do that, Zach did.
Do I Iisten to
his story or yours?
She fell down.
She was bleeding.
Zach said to get
a knife from the kitchen.
I didn't want to,
but he was screaming at me.
I didn't know what
he was going to do
with it, I swear.
So you got the knife,
and then what happened?
When I walked back in,
Zach was on top of her.
He took the knife
and he stabbed
her over and over.
There was all this
blood and I threw up!
I'm sorry.
I'm really, really sorry!
(SOBBING)
I'm sorry.
Jeremy, who covered her up
with the blanket?
I did.
You shouldn't Ieave
someone Iike that.
Can I go home now?
I just want to go home.
I want to go home.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
CSU finished
with Zach's house?
Top to bottom. No blood.
Must have tossed the clothes
he was wearing.
So we've got two kids,
two different stories,
and either one of them
could have killed her.
Which means I have
an even bigger problem.
Whether or not to
try Jeremy Brice
as an adult.
Zachary Connor is 12.
So even if he acted alone,
he's out of my jurisdiction.
He is going
to Family Court.
And what kind of punishment
is kiddie court handing out
for rapists and murderers
these days?
Their mandate is
rehabilitation,
not punishment.
So the maximum
sentence is 18 months
in a Iimited secure facility.
And Jeremy's Iooking
at Iife in Attica.
If the D.A. thinks
he's a danger
to society, yes.
Okay, I got to tell you
that I believe Jeremy's
version of the events.
You know,
this kid is more of a danger
to himself than anybody else.
Doc, you saw both interviews.
What do you think?
I agree with you.
Jeremy is more
easily manipulated.
He's desperate to
fit in at any cost,
whereas Zachary is
far more calculating.
I think he wields
a great deal of control
over Jeremy,
and I think he
murdered and raped
Susan Oestreicher.
So the question is
do we go after Jeremy
because we can't get Zachary?
No.
I'II recommend
we remove Jeremy
to family court.
The D.A. is seeking
an indictment against
Jeremy Brice.
You've got one day
to prepare for
the grand jury.
On what charges?
Felony murder
and burglary one.
I recommended against it.
Well, the D.A. disagreed.
But the evidence clearly
indicates that Jeremy Brice's
involvement was Iimited.
The DNA proves
that Zachary Connor
committed the rape.
Jeremy already confessed
to participating
in the burglary.
That's the predicate felony.
He knew it was dangerous,
he knew someone
could be killed.
No, he didn't.
This boy is not mature
enough to understand that.
The Iaw says he is.
That Iegislation
was passed in 1978
as a knee-jerk reaction
to some perceived
youth crime wave.
It also says that
we prosecute
juveniles as adults
at the discretion of
the district attorney.
He made the call.
You do your job.
Which should be easy enough
with Jeremy's confession.
A win for the D.A.
So that's what this is about.
'Cause I'd Iike to know just
how much of a sycophant
I have to be in this
new administration.
Let's say you're right.
Let's say Zachary Connor
did everything.
That means every
step of the way,
Jeremy Brice had a choice.
Do the right thing
or do the wrong thing.
Watch your friend
rape a defenseless
woman or stop him,
run away or
give him the knife
so he can stab her to death.
Do we punish
him for this?
Or do we tell him that
there are no consequences
for his actions?
We remove him to Family Court
in hopes of rehabilitation.
That won't happen if he goes
J.O. and you know it.
You have more faith in
the Juvenile Justice
Department than I do.
You're adamantly opposed
to prosecuting this case?
Yes. I think it's wrong.
AII right.
Then I'II do it.
You're second chair.
EIizabeth Donnelly
is back trying cases?
Or did your new boss
demote you already?
Funny comments Iike that,
it's a wonder both
your Iegs aren't broken.
You get attacked
by one of your repeat
offenders again?
No, actually one of your
esteemed colleagues
knocked me off a curb.
There's a
Iaw suit pending.
AIexandra Cabot,
Gina Bernardo,
public defender.
Nice to meet you.
So the D.A. has assembled
a Iegal dream team
to crucify a child.
You know as well as I do
charging Jeremy Brice
as an adult is
a gross injustice.
Tell that to
Susan Oestreicher's family.
You honestly believe
he deserves to be
charged for murder two?
The grand jury did.
You can't possibly hold
my client responsible
for something
it's impossible for him
to be responsible for.
Notification of
affirmative defense.
Not guilty by reason
of mental disease or defect.
What defect?
His 14-year-old brain.
DONNELLY: Your Honor,
this is an obvious attempt
to backdoor
the defense of infancy.
Article 30 clearly states that
defense cannot be used for
juveniles charged with murder.
I'm not saying that my
client isn't responsible
because of his age.
I am saying he isn't
responsible because
of his diminished capacity.
Dictated by his age.
It's the same thing.
This is a Iegislative issue,
Your Honor, not a matter
for the court.
Then why did three
Supreme Court justices
draft a public statement
calling for the abolishment
of juvenile executions?
Because it is cruel and
unusual to impose adult
punishment on someone
who isn't capable
of adult thought.
Couldn't one argue then
that certain behavior,
such as the committing
of a violent crime,
proves adult thought?
No. If your 10-year-old
son takes your car
out for a joy ride,
do you automatically
hand him
a driver's Iicense?
This is all very interesting,
Ms. Bernardo,
but I fail to see
how any of this applies
to an insanity defense.
These are scientific studies
proving that an adolescent's
brain is significantly
different than an aduIt's.
That, in fact, our brains
aren't fully formed until
we're in our early 20s.
And I can present scientific
studies which prove
my cat is trying
to kill me in my sleep.
Daubert test, Your Honor.
Scientific evidence must meet
federal standards of relevance
and reliability.
Well, one of the studies was
done by the National Institute
of Mental Health.
Is the federal government
reliable enough for you?
The reliability
of the studies
isn't in question.
My job is to determine
whether or not they have
any material value.
I believe they do.
And I believe
the jury should hear them.
Dr. Hayman, can you
tell us about the study
you recently completed?
We used functional magnetic
resonance imaging
to map the brains of healthy
adolescents over several years
and compared them
to those of healthy adults.
And what did your study find?
For adolescents,
brain activity is much
higher in the amygdala,
which guides instincts
Iike fear or anger.
In adults, the activity
in the frontal
Iobe is higher,
and that's the seat
of reasoning and
good judgment.
BERNARDO: So what are
the conclusions of
your findings?
Adolescents are
physiologically prone
to impulsive and
irrational behavior.
So teenagers are moody
and unpredictable,
and even violent,
because they are
wired that way?
Objection. Leading.
Sustained.
That's all.
No further questions.
So, your study says
that teenagers are
impulsive and irrational.
Here's what
I don't understand.
If that's true,
how is it that
every single teenager
isn't a rapist or a murderer?
I believe I said
adolescents were prone
to certain behaviors.
Then some teenagers
are perfectly
reasonable and rational.
Yes.
How many?
How many what?
How many teenagers are
rational and how many are
rapists and murderers?
There's no answer
to that question.
I thought you
mapped their brains.
We haven't tested
every single teenager
in the world.
Oh. So if you had given MRIs
to every single teenager,
you would be able to predict
whether or not they would be
a criminal. Is that it?
No.
Well, what?
If the irrational
part of the brain
is overactive,
that proves that
they'II be violent,
doesn't it?
It doesn't
prove anything.
This research is
in its infancy.
Your study doesn't
prove anything?
Not what you're
asking for, but...
Then it's a theory,
an unproven theory.
This research is
a huge step forward
in understanding
how the brain works.
Which is just another way
of saying we really don't
understand the brain at all.
Nothing further.
BERNARDO: Jeremy, do you know
the difference between
what's right and what's wrong?
Yes.
Was it wrong to break
into Susan Oestreicher's
apartment?
Yes.
Then why did you do it?
Zach said he
wanted some money.
Do you always do
what Zach wants?
He's my best friend.
Jeremy, did you know
that Zach was planning
to kill that woman?
JEREMY: No.
And if you thought
even for one moment
that that's what
he wanted to do,
would you have gone
with him to the apartment,
even though he's
your best friend?
No.
I don't want
anyone to get killed.
BERNARDO: Jeremy,
what is more wrong?
Watching someone do something
terrible or telling on your
only friend?
I don't know.
So, maybe, you don't
know right from wrong
as much as you think.
Thank you, Jeremy.
Who hit Susan Oestreicher
over the head?
Zach.
Hard enough so she
was knocked out, right?
Yeah.
Then Zach told you
to get the knife.
He... He said to
Iook in the kitchen.
Did you think he
was going to stab her?
No.
What did you think
he was going to do?
Scare her.
He didn't want
her to yell.
But she wasn't awake.
How would she yell?
I don't know.
What do people do
with knives, Jeremy?
Cut things.
So you walked
into the kitchen
and you got the knife.
Yes.
You said you were
afraid of Zach. Why?
He was yelling at me.
Why didn't you
walk out the door?
I don't know.
So, you got the knife.
You walked back to Zach,
and you were holding
the knife in your hands.
Yes.
Why did you
give it to him?
Was it because you were
afraid or because you
wanted to be
cool for your friend?
I don't know!
You knew what he
was going to do,
and you helped him do it.
Isn't that why?
I'm sorry!
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry.
(JEREMY SOBBING)
Nothing further.
I'm so sorry.
AIex.
Well, guess you got
what you wanted.
Destroying a child on
the stand is not quite
the highlight of my career.
You did your job.
Careful, AIex.
You're beginning to sound
Iike me, disillusioned
before your time.
I need you to subpoena
a rebuttal witness.
Who?
Zachary Connor.
Why?
As of today,
he's been adjudicated
by Family Court.
Any testimony he gives
won't be tainted
by his co-conspirator status.
If you put Zachary Connor
on the stand,
he's going to say that
Jeremy did everything and
I believe that's a Iie.
I'm not putting him
on the stand. You are.
Jury already thinks
I make Iittle kids cry.
No. I won't
suborn perjury.
Then I guess you
better make sure
he tells the truth.
CABOT: Zachary,
who killed Susan Oestreicher?
Jeremy did.
So he stabbed
her with a knife?
Yes.
That must have been
very frightening for you.
Yes. I was scared.
What were you scared of?
Jeremy.
Why?
Because he's bigger.
Was Jeremy
afraid of anything?
Yes.
What?
He was just afraid.
He didn't want to get caught.
But you did get caught.
Miss Oestreicher came home.
That was Jeremy's fault.
He got it wrong.
You must have been really
scared when she walked in
that door?
No, I wasn't.
Okay.
Zachary, when did
you throw up?
That was Jeremy.
I thought you
were afraid, Zachary.
I thought you threw up
because you couldn't
Iook at the blood.
I could, too.
Jeremy couldn't.
He was being a baby
and crying.
When? Before or after
she was killed?
The whole time.
And you weren't crying?
Not even just a Iittle?
No.
But I thought you
were afraid, Zachary.
I thought you were
afraid of Jeremy.
No, I wasn't.
And you were also afraid
of that woman because she
was going to call the police.
She was afraid of me.
And you wanted to show
them both that you were a man,
and that's why you
had sex with her.
Well, that was her fault
because she wouldn't tell
me where the money was.
Jeremy was crying!
He wouldn't do anything
so I had to do it!
If she had just told me where
the money was, I wouldn't have
had to hurt her!
Nothing further.
Five to 10 years.
He wouldn't get out
until he was 24?
It's the minimum sentence.
With good behavior,
he's out in five.
But if they say not guilty,
he won't go to jail at all.
The jury will not say that.
The Iaw is very clear.
Jeremy already admitted
to being in the apartment
with the intent to burglarize
it and someone was killed.
He can still be found
guilty of felony murder.
You want me to tell you
to send my son to jail.
Why don't we take a day
to think about this?
No. I don't need
to think about it.
The answer is no.
He didn't hurt anyone.
Mrs. Brice, if Jeremy is
convicted, he is facing
a possible Iife sentence.
Miss Bernardo, please tell
your client's mother how
rare jury nullification is.
We should take the deal.
I don't Iike taking
chances with the jury.
They heard that other boy.
They know Jeremy is good,
and they won't
send him to jail.
No.
No deal.
Ladies and gentlemen
of the jury,
have you reached a verdict?
We have, Your Honor.
RIDENOUR: On the first count,
murder in the second degree,
how do you find?
We find the defendant guilty.
No!
RIDENOUR: On the second count,
burglary in the first degree,
how do you find?
We find
the defendant guilty.
Poll the jury, Your Honor.
Juror number one,
what is your verdict?
Guilty.
Juror number two?
Juror number three?
Guilty.
Juror number four?
Juror number five?
Guilty.
Juror number six?
Juror number seven?
Guilty.