NARRATOR: In the criminal
justice system,
sexually based offenses
are considered
especially heinous.
In New York City,
the dedicated detectives
who investigate
these vicious felonies
are members
of an elite squad known
as the Special Victims Unit.
These are their stories.
Cab driver went the way
I told him to,
we wouldn't have
got stuck in traffic.
We should've
taken the subway.
Body-slamming my way
onto the Number 9
with the great unwashed?
No thanks.
You're a snob.
(DOORBELL BUZZING)
We're so Iate,
I'm sure they started
dinner without us.
Come on, guys.
Take it easy, Josh,
I'm sure
they're in the back
by the dining room.
There. Open.
(SHIVERS)
Evan?
Sorry we're Iate.
Oh, my God.
(GROANS)
Yo, Lucates.
Take this couple
up to Homicide
and have Kroling
get their statements.
AII right?
Detective Dave
Duethorn,
I missed dinner
with my wife and kids,
this better be good.
Two naked women,
fluids everywhere,
both raped
and shot in the head.
That's our bread and butter.
So I guess the two
head-shot naked guys
with them
are nothing special, right?
DUETHORN: Well, what do
you think?
STABLER: Looks Iike
the party from hell.
DUETHORN: Dinner party,
to be exact.
With an orgy
for dessert.
Except they
never made it
to the appetizer.
Dining room
table's still set.
And check that out.
"Happy engagement.
Share wonderful
Iives together."
There's no signature.
Who's the unlucky
couple here?
Evan Briggs
and his fiancée,
Melissa Ziman.
Other two are
Dean McCarren
and Regina Valerio.
Couple who found them
made the IDs.
Evan and Melissa
invited some grad school
friends over to celebrate.
Not the type of evening
you'd expect to turn into
a sexual free-for-all.
I'm thinking
home invasion.
Doorbell rings,
victim opens door,
whacko busts in
and robs them.
You got four victims,
gotta be at Ieast two perps.
What'd they take?
AII the victims' jewelry.
Marks on the men's wrists
indicate they wore watches,
the women wore necklaces.
DUETHORN: Their wallets
and IDs are also gone,
along with Miss Ziman's
two-and-a-half karat
engagement ring.
Couple who found them
told me she got it Iast week.
Oh, and there's
something else, right, Doc?
Both men were beaten,
probably with the business end
of an automatic.
Something must have
set them off.
Pummel the men
and rape the women.
WARNER: Not just the women.
Excuse me?
The men were raped, too.
AII the violence
was pre-mortem,
the beatings and the rapes.
Anything
from the kits?
PIenty of fluids.
But when I
combed for hairs
things got strange.
Define strange.
Take a Iook.
Hairs Iook
the same to me.
WARNER: Both belong
to Evan Briggs.
I found the one
on the Ieft
on his fiancée.
Nothing unusual about that.
The other was in
the second male victim.
What the hell went on here?
Both men had blood
and fluids on them
that matched the blood types
of the other victims.
So the perps
forced the men
to rape the women
and then each other?
I'II need the DNA
to confirm it.
But that's how it Iooks.
The townhouse belongs
to Earl Briggs,
CEO of Happy Time Toys.
Evan is his son,
two of them Iived there alone.
Mom's deceased.
I checked Earl's
background and financials.
Tutuola.
Aside from being
worth 50 million,
nothing points to anyone
intentionally targeting
his home.
Well, what about
the victims?
Squeaky clean.
AII four come from
wealthy families,
had entry-Ievel
jobs in media.
FIN: Are you
ready for this?
We're Iooking
for one perp.
Lab found a bunch
of bloody footprints,
all made by the same
pair of shoes.
And I checked ViCAP.
Nobody's active
with a similar MO.
It's hard to believe
this sadistic son-of-a-bitch
just suddenly popped up
on the radar screen.
Guy Iike this was probably
in the system before.
Sexual assault, rape,
burglary, maybe a few
street holdups.
Pretty big step from there
to making four people
sodomize each other
and then whacking them.
What set him off, Doc?
Probably one of the victims
said or did something
to challenge his masculinity.
The sodomy
was to humiliate them.
Killing them was the
ultimate power trip.
Is this nut job
gonna hit again?
If he is a sadist,
he enjoyed it
and he'II want more.
Fin took your notification
and your boss agrees
we should be working
this case together.
So you're temporarily
reassigned here.
AII right.
That works for me.
But we got a Iittle
math problem.
MUNCH: Yeah?
Well, educate us.
Four deceased,
plus our two Iatecomers.
Look at the dining room table.
MUNCH: Seven place settings.
Well, maybe our
missing dinner guest
didn't Iike what
was on the menu.
We know who it is?
No, but Evan's father
probably does.
Everybody Ioved Evan.
I can't...
I can't think of a soul
who'd want to hurt him.
Anybody have a grudge
against you?
Oh, I doubt any
of my competitors
would resort to this
kind of mayhem.
As soon as you can,
we're gonna need a Iist
of everything
that was stolen.
There's some jewelry missing,
none of it's worth much.
The most valuable thing to me
was the picture.
What? A piece of art?
A framed photo
of Evan and me fishing.
It was hung in that
empty spot on the wall.
Why would he steal that?
Well, it's possible
it fell during the break-in,
and we have it in evidence.
We'II check.
Best we can tell,
Evan invited two couples
and another friend
for dinner.
But we can't account
for the single friend.
I think it was Buzzie.
FIN: You know Buzzie's
real name?
I'm sorry, Paul Dumont.
He just moved back
from Boston.
Evan and Buzzie
used to go to camp together.
You have any idea
how we can find him?
I just got him a job
over at NOHO Magazine.
He started two weeks ago.
Paul's not picking up.
You want to Ieave a message
on his voice mail?
No, we want to talk
to him in person.
You don't know
if he's in?
We have over 100 people
working here.
It's not my job
to keep track of them.
FIN: Is there anybody
that can help us?
The police are here
Iooking for Paul.
Sure, I'II tell them.
Editor is on his way out.
Appreciate it.
Are you the officers
Iooking for Paul Dumont?
FIN: Yes, we are.
I'm Ralph SIoan, the editor.
I just got a call
from Paul's parents.
Did something happen?
There was an
accident Iast night.
He's in the hospital.
FIN: They say which one?
Roosevelt. He's in bad shape.
EMS brought him in Iast night
with massive skull fractures.
DUETHORN: Was he awake
at any time?
Extent of his injuries,
I'm surprised he was alive.
We rushed him to the O.R.
to reduce the swelling
in his brain.
What are his chances?
Not good. A Iot of
damage and bleeding.
In my opinion,
too much for a fall.
Who said he fell?
EMS run report.
Said he was under
the influence,
found Iying on the street.
But it didn't scan for me.
FIN: I'm no doctor,
but that doesn't Iook good.
It's not.
Mr. Dumont
was hit in the head
in three places
with such force,
it caused
radiating fractures.
More consistent
with being whacked
on the head
with a blunt object
than with a fall.
You checked
his blood alcohol?
Yes, and it was zero.
He didn't have
a drop to drink.
MUNCH: Patrols from the 20
respond to a call for a drunk
in one of the stairwells
of the 79th Street
subway station.
They find Dumont,
all covered in blood,
smelling Iike he was
dragged through a wine vat.
Cops figure he tied one on,
fell down the stairs,
so they call the bus.
DNA put this guy
at the crime scene?
No. No, no.
Only blood found
belonged to the four
murder victims.
So he never went inside.
But his flowers did.
FIorist IDed Dumont
as the guy
who bought the flowers.
So we're thinking
the perp sees Dumont
going up the steps
of the Briggs place
with his flowers
and a bottle of wine.
Conks Dumont on the head,
throws him down the stairs.
Holds the flowers
Iike he's delivering them.
The door opens,
he goes and he does his thing.
Meanwhile, those whacks
on the head
Ieave Dumont disoriented
but not down
for the count.
So he somehow makes it
from the townhouse
all the way to
the subway station.
That's a Iong way to go
with a skull fracture.
Doctor said it's possible,
before he passed out.
And the wine?
Lab found stains on his coat.
Bottle must've broken
when he went down
and got all over him.
So Paul Dumont
is victim number five.
Crime of opportunity,
Captain.
Wrong place, wrong time.
Thanks. Just Iike
victims six and seven.
We got two more?
Riverside Park.
LAYTON: Parks Department guy
emptying the trash
found them.
Any ID?
In their wallets.
Russell and Darlene Weston,
both 51,
Iive a couple of blocks
up Riverside.
Both head-shot, naked.
Same as the townhouse.
Any signs of rape?
BIood on Mrs. Weston's
nether region.
Still waiting
for the M.E.
Your guys
find anything else?
Dug a spent slug
out of a tree.
Looks Iike a.380.
Rushed it to Ballistics,
waiting to see
if it matches
the other victims.
And check this out.
DUETHORN: Keys.
Belonging to one
of the victims,
I presume, right.
But found a couple
of yards away.
And Iook at the ring.
Oh, he Ieft
the keys to the house,
but he broke off
whatever was on the other end.
Maybe the keys
to the car, right.
Cash and credit cards
are gone.
LAYTON: So is their jewelry.
Got six murders in two days.
Dumont dies, that makes seven.
We got ourselves
a spree killer.
Add Paul Dumont
to the Ioss column.
Hospital called.
He died an hour ago.
Seven victims.
Except for Mr. Dumont,
they were all robbed,
sexually assaulted
and then shot.
Both scenes
are within 20 blocks.
This guy's killed
as many people in two days
as Son of Sam did
in four months.
Now you all have
your assignments,
Iet's get this guy.
Okay, how's it
going at the park?
CSU's still there,
Munch is supervising.
The slugs they found confirm
that the Westons were shot
with the same gun
used at the Briggs' townhouse.
Anything from the M.E.?
Rape kits on both victims
tested positive for fluids.
Doc Warner says pending DNA,
no stray hairs were found
other than the victims'.
So it's the same MO,
perp probably forced them
to have sex.
Well, Mrs. Weston
also had bruising
consistent with being
pistol-whipped.
Before she was shot.
Perp orders them to do it,
hubby says no.
Perp beats wifey,
threatens to kill her
unless he can get it up.
HUANG: That makes sense.
He probably beat the men
at the townhouse
for the same reason.
Okay, we got five kids
in their 20s
and a middle-aged couple.
This guy's making it up
as he goes along.
Or to him they all
have something in common.
Did we find out
what was hanging on
Mrs. Weston's key chain?
Family said it was
a picture of her grandson.
HUANG: And the photo missing
from the Briggs home?
Not in evidence,
so it was probably stolen.
Those are items that only
have value to their owners.
We thinking trophies?
Very specific trophies.
He's destroying
happy families,
maybe because
he's jealous.
I bet his own family
was miserable,
some kind of abuse.
And he's just gonna
keep taking it out
on these people
until we stop him.
EIIiot and OIivia
will run things from here.
Duethorn and Fin,
Iight a fire under CSU.
SIPER: We're combing the park
half a mile north and south,
from Riverside Drive
to the Hudson.
Any Iuck
besides the slug?
So far,
three distinct sets
of footwear impressions
at the murder site.
Two sets belonging
to the victims.
The third is a work boot,
presumably the perp's.
This is where
he Ieft the park.
Toes facing towards
the sidewalk.
Dental stone'II
pick up his tracks.
He ran from the bodies
to this point.
DUETHORN: You know he ran?
Yeah. Check out
the foot angle.
When you walk,
your feet point out slightly
at 10 o'clock and 2 o'clock.
But they're slightly
straighter when you run,
Iike these prints.
GEORGIE: Captain!
SIPER: What's up, Georgie?
More impressions.
FIat sole, athletic shoe
and work boot.
Get Ivan over here
with the camera.
Our victims
and the perp.
Toes pointing to
the murder site.
Here's your entry point.
I guess Mr. and Mrs. Weston
weren't out for a midnight
stroll in the park.
They're on the sidewalk,
they Iook Iike easy marks,
our guy forces them
to go with him.
Yeah. When he's done,
he Ieaves the park
a couple yards south
of where he came in.
He's got a thousand
places to run,
he goes back to the only place
where he could be seen. Why?
No parking,
8:00 a.m. to 7:00 p.m.
Our perp's traveling by car,
it's perfectly Iegal
to park here.
He comes back for his ride
after he's done the deed.
Well, maybe somebody
in one of these buildings
parked behind him,
remembers the car.
(DOG BARKING)
The reason most
spree killers get caught
is 'cause they can't
help baiting the cops.
This animal's
giving us nothing.
Yeah. Neither are any
of these people.
How'd you get past
the doorman?
With this.
Detective Tutuola,
Detective Duethorn
and you are?
Renny Nix,
and you can't
barge in here Iike
you're Hawaii Five-O.
Take it easy, Mr. Nix...
When there's some guy
running around killing people.
What are you doing about that?
Seeing if anyone
in the building
saw anything.
Do you own a car?
No. Now get Iost.
You'd think
they'd be more helpful
instead of slamming
their doors in our faces.
Some people
don't Iike talking
to the cops.
Yeah, until they
need us, right?
How old are you?
Thirty.
How Iong on the job?
What, eight, nine years?
Five.
Where'd you work
before Homicide?
Patrolling the 48,
before I got my gold shield.
Only way that happens
is you collared
Osama Bin Laden
and I didn't get it,
or you got a real good
rabbi on this job.
I grew up next door
to the First Deputy
Commissioner.
So you parachuted
into Homicide.
You know what,
start in on how
I didn't earn it
and I'II parachute right back.
I don't need a Iecture.
You do the job,
you got no problems with me.
BRENDA: Excuse me, Officers?
Can we help you?
I'm sorry, my husband,
Renny Nix, was horribly
rude to you inside.
He said we shouldn't
get involved.
Did you see
something, Mrs. Nix?
Yes.
Last night, around midnight
I was closing the curtains
on my Iiving room window.
I saw a man and a woman
standing here
next to a car that was
parked right there.
Then another man
got out of
the driver's seat,
and walked behind them
into the park.
Could you see
what he Iooked Iike?
His dark winter coat,
wool cap.
I didn't see his face,
he walked around
the front of the car.
FIN: How Iong before
he came back?
I don't know.
I went to sleep.
Do you remember
anything about the car?
It was gold,
Iast two numbers
of the Iicense plate
were 3-5,
my daughter's birthday,
March 5th.
But I wouldn't know
a Lexus from a Lincoln.
Detective Shubel
from our Accident
Investigation Unit's
gonna take you through
his computer program.
Now we already know
the car's gold.
Were there two doors or four?
Four.
Did it have a trunk,
a hatchback, or a flat bed?
A trunk, definitely.
So it's a sedan.
Can you describe
the rear Iights?
Kind of oval?
Okay. Like this?
No. The Iights wrapped
around the side.
And the Iicense plate
was on the trunk.
Okay. How's this?
That's it!
Ford Contour.
Here we go. '95 Ford Contour.
Address Central Park West.
Oh, wait. There's gotta be
hundreds of them.
How do you know
that's the one?
This one came up as stolen.
CHARLIE: This about the car?
DUETHORN: Yeah.
You AI Baker?
I'm Charlie Baker,
AI's my father.
Dad, the cops are here.
AL: Hey, how you doing?
Auto Squad,
Detective Tutuola,
Detective Duethorn.
You filed
a stolen car report
with the 20th Precinct
three days ago?
Charlie, you're
gonna be Iate.
Okay, okay.
AL: And don't forget
your brother, Billy.
So, you haven't found it,
have you?
Sorry, we're just
doing a follow-up.
Could you tell us
what happened?
Yeah. Sure.
About three days ago,
I go out to my plumbing
supply place in Jersey,
and I go to where
the car is parked,
it's not there anymore.
It's all in the report.
Are you sure you just didn't
Ieave it somewhere else?
I mean, me,
I'm always forgetting
what street I put the car on.
No. No. I searched
this neighborhood,
I'm telling you,
I even called both my boys.
I thought maybe
one of them took it
without telling me, you know?
You gonna get it back for me?
Well, it was a Ford,
so it probably wasn't
boosted for parts.
Most Iikely some kid
Iooking for a joyride.
We'II get back to you.
Thanks.
Okay.
How'd that happen?
AL: What?
Working on an owner's sink
and I forget to Iook out
for the cabinet, you know.
It's occupational hazard.
Occupational hazard,
my ass.
Guy smelled Iike
he bathed in Johnnie Walker.
Probably didn't even see
that cabinet door.
High-end building
Iike this,
surprised the owners
put up with a drunk
for a super.
DUETHORN: What's up, guys?
FIN: Drag you Iost your car.
Well, it sucks for Dad.
Don't know how
he's gonna pick up stuff
for the building now.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
This your brother?
Oh, yeah, sorry.
Billy.
Hey, how you doing?
So you guys use that car?
FIN: Tutuola.
No. It's an eight-year-old
piece of crap.
I mean, would you
wanna pick up girls
in that?
Yeah.
How do you
get to work?
Subway.
Charlie, we better move it,
we're gonna be Iate.
AII right.
Take it easy.
FIN: AII right. Thanks.
What now?
They found the Contour.
Two more bodies.
CRAGEN: Two cops in an RMP
spotted the car.
Lights on, driver's side
door wide open.
Steering column
hasn't been touched.
So whoever boosted this,
did it the easy way,
with a key.
Or the owner dumps it
with the key in it.
Somebody else steals it,
owner collects the insurance.
Where are the victims?
CRAGEN: Adam Darling
and Craig Fischetti,
both 22.
Found both guys' wallets,
no cash inside.
What about jewelry?
WARNER: They both
wore wristwatches,
they have corresponding
marks on their wrists.
CRAGEN: How Iong
they been dead?
Six to eight hours.
They were murdered Iast night.
They got their clothes on.
Any signs of sexual activity?
Haven't checked yet.
But Mr. Darling's fly is open.
Yeah. Could have stopped here
to take a Ieak, you know?
This place is a
Iover's Iane at night.
These two might have been
in the middle of something
when the perp found them.
Or maybe the perp
didn't have enough time
to make them do
what he wanted.
Well, assuming
these two walked in,
why'd the perp
dump his ride?
My guess, he got spooked.
He could've Ieft on foot.
Or in the victim's car.
Registration in
Adam Darling's wallet.
Silver Acura,
address Tenafly, New Jersey.
New York Police?
We're here about
the silver Acura SUV.
My son Adam
borrowed it Iast night
and we haven't
heard from him.
Are he and Craig
and the girls okay?
What girls?
DUETHORN: Names are
CIaudia Smullen
and Diane Combs,
both 21,
roommates at Barnard.
Double-dating with our
two male victims.
We grid-searched the park,
checked their apartment,
and called their parents.
These girls are in the wind.
Let's get alerts out
on all their credit cards
and bank accounts
in case somebody's using them.
How are we doing
on those phone tips, John?
Do you remember
that white van
everybody saw
during the DC
sniper shootings?
Well, our man is a plumber,
garbage man, doorman,
husband.
The city's out of control.
Ballistics says
it's the same gun.
Nine dead, two missing.
This guy's killed every one
of his victims so far,
why snatch these two women?
They're Iiving trophies
and I think he's stashing
them somewhere.
So what's changed?
HUANG: His confidence.
He used the victims
as surrogates
to rape each other.
Maybe he's ready to rape
the women himself now.
This guy's MO's
all over the map.
But we still do have
some constants.
The gun, for one thing.
His comfort zone,
the Upper West Side.
He Iikes
controlled environments,
the townhouses,
secluded areas of parks.
And he targets couples.
A woman or a man
walking alone
Iate at night,
they're vigilant.
But two people walking together,
they don't always
perceive the danger.
Guy's an animal hunting
the slowest prey in the herd.
Or a Ioner who has trouble
making social connections.
So people in
successful relationships
trigger his rage.
Because they have
what he never will.
And maybe kidnapping
these two women
is his way
to fulfill his fantasy.
BENSON: Assuming that
they're not already dead.
How much time do we have?
When he's done
or when one of these women
pisses him off,
he's gonna kill them.
STABLER: Maybe we
just caught a break.
Lab got something
out of the Contour.
No blood,
no prints matching anyone
in the system,
no fibers connecting
any of the victims
to the Contour.
But we did
find footprints
consistent with all
of the crime scenes.
So we can estimate his height.
EIeven-and-a-half
inch impressions
means the perp's shoe size
is between eight
and nine-and-a-half.
So our guy is
between 5'5" and 5'10".
And, he's wearing these.
OutdoorWear Explorers.
Very expensive.
But great treads
for trace evidence.
Which we found in the car
and in his boot impressions.
Wood?
Pine, oak and cherry.
The tube next to it
has fiberglass insulation.
Sounds Iike we're
after someone who works
in construction.
That's what I thought
until I found the rest.
DUETHORN: What is this?
Grass seed?
Two different blends.
Rye and Kentucky bluegrass.
Suburban boy?
Yonkers,
but even my old man
never made me seed
the Iawn in the
middle of winter.
Well, I doubt it came
from the park.
There were also
traces of diazinon,
a common pesticide,
ammonium nitrate and Iime,
both used for fertilizer,
and some metal shavings,
bronze and brass.
From what?
I'd say a
key-cutting machine.
So he had key shavings, wood,
insulation and bug killer.
AII the stuff
a building super uses.
Except for the grass seed
and the fertilizer.
We're Iooking for someone
who works around
these materials every day.
DUETHORN: The only place
you can find all that stuff
is in a home
improvement store.
AII right,
send a flatbed and a team
and make sure
nobody touches it
before it gets here.
What's up, Captain?
Your silver SUV
just turned up.
With somebody sleeping inside.
Anti-Crime found the SUV
parked on 49th
between 8th and 9th.
I managed to get
a description from a drunk
who was sitting in
the back seat of the car.
Young, average height,
dark hair, blue eyes.
Great. So he Iooks Iike
a million other people.
Yeah, but most of them
don't work in a home
improvement store.
And we're gonna have to
canvass every single one
of them that sell Iumber.
That's the only
solid Iead we have.
He's about 5'9",
dark hair, blue eyes.
We have several employees
who fit that description.
Hari Singh,
Andy Regal,
Butch Lanahan,
Billy Baker...
Billy Baker?
Yeah.
Works 4:00 to 11:00
in the Iumber department.
He Iives over
on Central Park West?
Yeah.
Seems funny someone
with that address
would work here.
I can't imagine him
being in any kind of trouble.
Yeah. Why's that?
He's a boss's dream.
Does whatever
you tell him to,
never complains.
Worked here three years,
only Iate once.
FIN: When?
Other day.
Said his car was stolen.
The Contour was never boosted.
Billy just took it.
Yeah, and Billy knows
we're asking
questions about it,
he figures it's too hot,
dumps it in Central Park.
CRAGEN: Explains why
the steering column
was clean.
That quiet Iittle guy
was a time bomb
waiting to explode?
Billy's the super's kid.
He grew up surrounded
by rich people
who probably treated
him Iike dirt.
And every one of our victims
is wealthy or appeared to be.
And now he's getting
back at them.
We picking him up,
Captain?
Doc?
It's an all-power game.
Arrest him now,
he may never tell us
where these missing women are.
CRAGEN: Then we sit on him
to make sure
he doesn't kill again
and hope he Ieads us
to the victims.
Three teams,
three shifts, 24/7.
CSU is done with the Contour,
Iet's get it back
to the Bakers.
Unless he stole another car,
Billy's gonna need
some transportation.
FIN: How you read that trash?
I got an inquiring mind.
You get off on that
psych stuff, don't you?
Average murder's
one drug dealer
shooting another,
a bar fight
or a domestic gone bad.
Once you figure out the who,
working Homicide's all about
where the perps are
and finding them.
So?
Sex crime is about the why.
This city's
a three-ring circus
and SVU's the freak show.
And you wanna be
the ringmaster.
I wanna know
what makes them freaks.
Here it comes.
FIN: It's the Contour.
Okay, kiddies,
car's on the move.
Billy's driving.
South on Columbus.
Our boy's behind the wheel.
Comes all the way
down here to get cash?
He could have done that
on Columbus Avenue.
DUETHORN: Look at that.
Do you know anyone
that needs a cheat sheet
to remember a PIN number?
Only when it
ain't their card.
SVU detail to base,
subject appears to be
using a stolen ATM card.
If he's got the PIN number,
they could still be alive.
CRAGEN: Take him.
FIN: 10-4.
We're taking him.
Nice and easy,
may have a gun.
Police officers, stop!
BILLY: No, no.
Get off of me, please.
PIease!
That what you did,
Billy? Huh?
FIN: Dave!
Huh? Is that what you did?
You made them
plead for their Iives?
Before you blew
their heads off?
Come on. Ease off.
Is that what you did? Huh?
Dave! Easy! Easy!
Crying Iike a Iittle girl.
Where are they?
Don't you move.
Where are the girls?
Dave!
(BILLY GRUNTS)
The ATM card will be enough
to get a warrant
to search his crib.
CRAGEN: Anything?
If it's here it's well-hidden.
You guys are making
a big mistake.
Billy wouldn't do
something Iike this.
Our evidence says he did.
Billy have access
to anywhere else
in the building?
Yes. Everywhere.
I keep all the master keys
in my office.
Billy's been hanging out
in the basement a Iot Iately.
What's down there?
Boiler room, Iaundry,
owner's storage Iockers.
You got keys
to those, too?
AL: Yes, sir. I do.
Don't you need, Iike,
a warrant or something?
Not if we have
the owner's consent.
Over here.
What have you got?
CRAGEN: Evan
and Earl Briggs.
MUNCH: Mrs. Weston's
grandson from
her key chain.
Melissa Ziman's
engagement ring.
And one pair of
OutdoorWear work boots.
DUETHORN: Game's up, Billy.
We got you cold.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Save it, Billy.
I don't wanna hear
how you didn't do it,
it wasn't you,
you were abused
as a child.
We have the boots.
Look at them.
They match prints
at all the crime scenes
and in your father's car.
What, you can't stand
the sight of them, Billy?
Look at them, Billy.
They're your boots.
Look at them.
(SOBBING)
Why are you picking on me?
I told you I didn't do it.
Then explain this stuff!
You know what this is?
This is your one-way ticket
to a Iethal injection.
But you got
a chance here, Billy.
What chance?
Tell us where these women are.
The DA'II spare you
the death penalty.
They die and it's all
over for you.
The story doesn't have to
end that way though.
Look at me.
Don't blow this,
it's your only shot.
I wanna talk to my brother.
DUETHORN: You gotta show us
some good faith here first.
Where are the women?
I'II tell you
whatever you want.
Just Iet me talk
to Charlie first.
Two hours,
it's the first time
he's cracked.
Brother goes in
and tells Billy to Iawyer up,
we're screwed.
Doesn't matter,
the case is already
bulletproof
without Billy's confession.
Our priority is
finding those women.
They've been missing
for 24 hours.
We gotta
take the risk.
Charlie goes for it,
I want both of you and Huang
Iistening to every word.
Maybe I should call a Iawyer?
No Iawyer in the world's
gonna be able
to help him out of this.
His only chance
to stay alive
is to tell us where
those women are.
He's right, Dad.
We have to save his Iife.
Look, you sure
you know what you're doing?
Yeah.
Let me talk to him.
Billy...
I'm so sorry, Charlie.
It's gonna be okay,
I promise.
I screwed up.
Are you mad at me?
No, you're my brother.
But you and me,
we gotta work this out.
How?
The cops want you to show them
where these women are.
No, I won't do it.
You have to do
the right thing here, Billy.
You have to be strong.
You have to be a man.
I am.
Can't you see that?
No matter what happens
I'm always here for you.
You understand?
I Iove you, Charlie.
I love you,
too, Billy.
He's not gonna
tell us a damn thing.
Lied so he could
see his brother.
Anything, Doc?
Nothing, except Billy never
asked for his father.
Well, Charlie's sober.
Dad isn't.
Sorry, Detectives.
Thanks for trying.
Your father's outside.
He didn't give up
anything, Captain.
We're heading back in.
Forget it.
We got two more bodies.
Greenwich Village.
That's way out
of his comfort zone.
What's going on?
Iris and Daniel Braverman.
Mid-20s. Found by their maid.
Iris was shot once,
execution-style.
Husband's another story.
(GROANS)
Man, this guy's face
is gone.
Found some stippling
on what skin was Ieft.
Shooter put the gun
right between his eyes.
As if he wanted him
to see it coming.
Was Mrs. Braverman raped?
Yes. But no fluids
on the husband.
Which means our guy
did the deed himself.
How Iong they dead?
They're not in rigor yet.
Less than six hours.
DUETHORN: Rules out Billy.
He's been in custody
all night.
Okay. The perp empties
a whole clip
into this guy's face
point-blank
then rapes
the wife, himself.
It's way off the MO.
It could be a copycat.
Or Billy had a partner.
Whoever it is,
this is personal.
We need to check
these victims'
backgrounds
as quickly as possible.
And get the ballistics.
The Bravermans
have been in the same
address for two years.
Before that, college.
Before that, Daniel
Iived with his parents,
same address as Billy Baker.
How Iong?
Their whole Iife.
Grew up there.
With Billy
and his brother.
I got it! I got it.
Guess what?
It's the same gun.
But guess what.
CRAGEN: What?
It's two perps.
How do we know that?
The footprints. AII right.
This one we found
in Riverside Park, right?
in Central Park
where the women
were snatched.
Two right foot prints,
same boot, same size.
This one,
this guy walks normally.
And then this one,
with the smudge,
we found four of them,
one right in front
of the next.
This is our second perp
and this guy,
he walks with a Iimp.
Just Iike Charlie.
HUANG: That song-and-dance
in interrogation
was all an act.
Charlie was telling Billy
to keep his mouth shut.
Charlie's the dominant one.
He's the one
calling the shots.
We gotta pick him up.
Go easy.
He knows we're onto him,
he's Iiable to kill the women
if he hasn't already.
Charlie's gone.
Where?
I don't know.
He at work?
No.
They called here
Iooking for him.
But they said
he never showed up.
When's the Iast time
you seen him?
Was when we Ieft
the police station.
Got any idea
where he may have gone?
Why, you think
he'd tell me?
Let me guess,
he's in trouble now,
too, huh?
DUETHORN: You don't even
sound surprised.
No. Because if Billy did
what you think Billy did,
Charlie must've had
something to do with it.
Why do you say that?
Because Billy
can't do anything
without somebody
telling him to.
This kid has never
made a decision
in his whole Iife
on his own, you know?
Lets the whole world
push him around.
Listen!
Hey, hey, hey.
We got two women missing
and I don't have
a Iot of time!
Okay. Okay. Just don't hit me.
Just... Just don't hit.
AII right. AII right.
We got it.
Does anyone
besides his brother
know where Charlie is?
Yeah. Yeah. His girlfriend.
He and that slut
work together.
MARIE: I have no idea
where Charlie is.
Why are you asking me?
Well, because
you're his girlfriend.
I was his girlfriend.
I dumped him six months ago.
He's crazy.
He and that brother of his.
You know Billy?
Yeah. Too well.
And that was kind of
the problem.
You had sex
with your boyfriend's brother?
Billy was a Iittle fast,
but cute.
I didn't really mind
when Charlie told me
to break him in.
And you did everything
Charlie told you to do?
I thought I Ioved him.
Until the Iast time.
What happened?
Charlie climbed into bed
with me and Billy.
You had a threesome?
Yeah.
Until it became a twosome.
And I wasn't one of the two.
Charlie and Billy?
Yeah.
Billy didn't really want to,
but Charlie made him.
Billy was crying so Ioud
that their daddy came back
and caught us.
Charlie threatened to kill me,
Billy and their father
if we ever told anybody.
What'd those officers
bring me here for, huh?
I told you
I don't know anything.
Mr. Baker, how did you
hurt yourself?
I'm a building super.
It happens.
FIN: You're pretty
accident-prone.
I had a bad week.
Yeah. Is that why
you been drinking?
So I take a pop
every now and then, so what?
FIN: You reek of booze.
You're drunk!
Hey, hey! Come on!
I said just,
just don't hit me, okay?
Just don't, don't hit me.
I'm not trying to hurt you.
Come on.
I'm trying to help you.
Get up.
HUANG: Who's been
beating you, AI?
Nobody.
Was it Charlie?
No.
But you caught Charlie
having sex with Billy,
didn't you?
AI?
Yeah. He was raping Billy.
And you tried
to stop him.
I told him to Ieave him alone.
He just Iaughed at me.
He said I was a drunken Ioser.
He said I couldn't
keep a woman.
He told me he was gonna do
whatever he wanted to do.
So I tried to
pull him off Billy,
he just pushed me away.
AII right and then
what happened?
Then I called him a faggot.
So he hit me. Boy.
My kid hit me,
again, and again, and again.
Now he hits me every day.
Did Billy beat you, too?
No.
Never. Billy would never
do that. He's a sweet kid.
Wouldn't hurt a fly
unless Charlie told him to.
Billy's a good, good kid.
Billy didn't put
that stuff in that Iocker
from those poor people.
Charlie did it.
Charlie got the key
and Charlie stole
every time he could
from all those residents.
Said I was gonna Iose my job
if I told anybody.
Did you help Charlie
hide those women?
No. I swear I didn't.
HUANG: AI?
We need to find them.
Yeah. I know.
FIN: Are you hiding Charlie?
Boy, you guys
don't understand.
He's gonna kill me.
He's not gonna ever be able
to hurt you again.
If you don't tell us
where he is
and those women die,
that's on you.
He's in an apartment
in my building.
One of the residents
is on vacation.
(SOBBING)
Police!
Don't move!
Get off of me!
Let me go!
You told them where I was!
You bastard! I'II kill you!
I should have killed you
for what you did to Billy.
CHARLIE: Billy hates you
more than I do!
Cuff his Iegs, too.
I got him.
(CHARLIE GRUNTING)
.380 Beretta.
Is this what you
were Iooking for, Charlie?
Two more seconds and you guys
would all be dead.
Then us, then your dad,
then you'd do yourself?
Not today, Charlie.
Come on.
You're never gonna
find those bitches.
They're gonna die
and you're never
gonna find them.
Where are they?
How many times
you gonna ask me
the same stupid question?
As many times as it takes!
Where are they?
You're wasting your breath
because I'm not gonna
tell you a damn thing.
Give it up, Charlie!
Your father
told us everything!
My father doesn't
know dick.
Yeah? He saw you
rape your brother.
He doesn't know what he saw.
He's a drunken Ioser.
That why you beat him?
Because he caught you
screwing your brother
and he called you a fag?
Your ex-girlfriend, Marie,
said that right foot of yours
ain't the only thing
that's Iimp.
But you can make it happen
with your own brother,
ain't that right, Charlie?
Yeah. That why
you raped him?
That's why
you got that gun
to show everybody
you're a man.
You think you guys
are better than me?
You think you're Iike
all those rich people?
You think you can push me
around Iike they did?
Is that what this
is all about?
You're damn right it is!
And I showed them!
Yeah.
You showed them.
Now tell us where they are!
If you're so smart,
go find them yourself.
Look at that...
Look at that door,
pretty boy.
Look at that door.
You think this
is gonna work, huh?
Billy, you have to
tell them.
No. Take me
back to jail.
I tried, Son.
I did. I tried to
protect you from him.
So I could grow up
to be Iike you?
Charlie is twice the man
you'II ever be.
FIN: Charlie set
you up, Billy.
What are you
talking about?
Know all that
stuff you stole
from the people
you murdered,
and the boots you wore,
you know where
we found them?
In a storage Iocker
in your building.
Don't tell them
anything, Billy.
That's not where
we hid those things, Charlie.
Why'd you put them there?
Because he was gonna make you
take the rap all by yourself.
No, I wasn't.
It's not true, Billy.
It is true.
He stole the keys.
He betrayed you, Billy.
He would never do that.
AL: He's no good.
I may not be much,
but I never Iied to you, Son.
I never sold you out.
He sold you out.
BILLY: No.
Only your boots
were there, Billy.
Not Charlie's.
Why did you do that?
Be a man, Billy.
Don't tell them
where those bitches are!
Why didn't you protect me?
Shut up!
You said it was us
against everyone else!
And you Iied to me.
You're a Iiar!
You Iittle wimp!
I'II rip you apart
if you tell them anything!
Charlie made me
kill those people!
Shut the hell up!
But he shot those
women's boyfriends!
Shut up!
Where are they, Billy?
Where are the women?
CHARLIE: No!
Don't tell them anything!
They're on the roof!
You stupid son of a bitch.
What roof? What roof?
Shut up!
Of our building.
In the old water tower.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING ON RADIO)
How are they?
PARAMEDIC:
They'II be all right.
They're frostbitten.
Got her.
They wouldn't have
Iasted another night.
Any signs
of sexual assault?
Not that
we can see.
Won't be sure
until we get them
to the hospital.
You're gonna be okay.
What now?
Go to the hospital,
take their statements,
get some sleep.