NARRATOR: In the criminal
justice system,
sexually based offenses
are considered
especially heinous.
In New York City,
the dedicated detectives
who investigate
these vicious felonies
are members
of an elite squad known
as the Special Victims Unit.
These are their stories.
(SIREN BLARING)
He robbed me.
Guy came in to rob me.
Take it easy, take it easy.
Did you see where he went?
Cops chased him
into the alley.
(GUN FIRING)
Get back inside!
Get down!
OFFICER TAYLOR: Police!
Drop it or you're dead. Now!
Bailey! Taylor!
Where are you guys?
OFFICER BAILEY:
Over here! We got him.
Two-two-Henry.
SIow everyone down.
We got one under.
Anyone hit?
Just this mutt.
Winged him in the arm.
Bus is on the way.
Here's his piece.
Hey, guys, you better
check this out.
What?
Oh, man.
She's dead.
Police, coming through.
Thank you.
Hey.
Kind of strange,
Cragen calling us in on
an officer-involved shooting.
Maybe not.
Look who's
over there.
STABLER: Swell.
Stabler, Benson,
thanks for coming.
Yeah. It's the middle
of the night. I hope you're
not jerking us around.
I'm not.
I've got a black
female teenager,
sleeping on the streets.
We think she's a runaway,
then somebody
worked her over.
Burn marks, both arms.
Braids, ribbon in her hair,
covered by
a pretty decent blanket.
Yeah, and a big hole
in her head.
Not your average
homeless kid.
Maybe not,
but she's an
abuse victim.
We think the perp
shot her.
No, you think the cops
accidentally shot her,
and you're trying to pull us
into your own mess by calling
it an SVU case.
This girl was tortured
and we have no idea
who she is.
You want her parents
to see her face
in the morning news?
That's your problem,
not ours.
Come on, SVU knows
how to protect victims
and deal with families.
You mean you want us
to keep this under wraps.
We want this to Iook clean
from the beginning.
So I'm asking
for a favor.
AII the times that
you people at IAB
jammed us up
and now you
want to play nice?
You've got a set of balls
on you asking us for anything.
If we find out that
a cop shot that girl,
you expect us
to keep it quiet?
I expect you
to do your job.
However this turns out,
it turns out.
You don't want to
do it for me, fine.
Do it for her.
Found seven slugs,
all of them too badly
damaged for any
microscopic work.
Shell casings?
Had better Iuck there.
Matched them to each weapon.
Well, they were all carrying
nines, so the casings would
have gone
about 10 feet to the right
and a Iittle to the rear.
So we know
approximately where
each person fired from.
Number one
is Officer Bailey,
two is the perp
and Officer Taylor
is number three.
The bullet passed
through this steel drum
before hitting the victim,
making a trajectory
through two fixed points.
The ballistic alignment Iaser
will tell us for sure
who shot her.
They all fired on the run,
so it could have been
any one of them.
And there's
our bullet path.
Hal, you be Officer Taylor.
Benson, you take Bailey.
Stabler, you're the perp.
We'II see where
the Iaser Iands.
EI, it's on you.
The perp fired the shot
that killed the girl.
Only problem is, your Jane Doe
was already dead when the perp
shot her.
That son-of-a-bitch
Iucked out.
The cops at the scene
said she was still warm.
So did my assistants.
But by the time
they got her back here,
her Iower extremities
were already stiff.
She was going into rigor.
Well, she had to be
dead four or five hours
before the shooting, then.
That's about right.
Do you know
what killed her?
Hopefully we'II find out
when I open her up.
But she was filthy,
Iike she hadn't
bathed in weeks.
I have her personal effects
to put into evidence.
STABLER: Anything good?
Just some cheap clothes
from one of your
better discount stores.
And this necklace.
That's an infinity
symbol on a chain.
What's up
with these burns?
That's what they Iook Iike,
but they're actually
cockroach bites.
Well, if she was homeless,
she could have gotten them
from Iiving on the street
or after she died.
Except the bites
wouldn't swell if
she was dead.
And the roaches wouldn't bite
unless she was immobile.
You're thinking
she was restrained?
Or so sick
she couldn't move.
It sounds Iike this
girl was held captive
in a very unpleasant place.
And then dumped at the scene.
Lab checked the ground
where the girl was found.
No evidence of
any bodily fluids.
So, if she was already dead,
the new blanket is
a care-giving gesture.
The same reason as the hair
ribbons. Whoever Ieft her
there Ioved her.
MUNCH: We've got an ID.
And you're not
gonna believe it.
Who is she?
Samantha Tassler.
The girl who
disappeared from Philly?
FIN: Montgomery County,
Pennsylvania, to be exact.
Less than
eight months ago.
Didn't we spend, Iike,
two weeks Iast year
searching for her?
Maybe three.
Are they sure
it's her?
Cops there say our
photo matches theirs.
The parents are
coming in tonight.
Her friend's older brother
was supposed to drive
her home.
We called when it got Iate
and Samantha hadn't
come back yet.
That's when we find
out she never got there.
We have some of Samantha's
personal effects
when she was found.
It would help us if you
could take a Iook at them.
Are you up for that?
I ain't never
seen this.
I don't recognize
this necklace, either.
Sharon, did you buy
this for Samantha?
SHARON: No.
Are you sure that she
didn't have this one
when she was home?
Positive.
You found her on the street.
I'm surprised
she still had this necklace.
It's solid platinum.
It's probably worth
close to a grand.
The girl's wearing
dime store clothes
and Iiving on the street.
It doesn't make sense
she wouldn't have
sold this for food money.
You have any idea
where this came from?
You're not going to find it
in a case at Tiffany's or
any other mainstream retailer.
Here, have a Iook.
I don't notice anything
unusual about it.
The X-ray
fluorescence test did.
It's coated in rhodium
to make it shine
instead of the regular
polishing and finishing.
That hasn't been popular
in this country in decades.
So?
So, it's definitely
handmade.
And there are
three tiny initials
engraved on the back.
I just put it
in our database.
What are you
checking?
Every jeweler in the Tri-State
who makes his own jewelry
with the three initials RSC.
Any hits?
Yeah, here we go.
Ross St. CIair.
Got a Iittle shop
down in the Village.
No, I don't
remember her.
I don't get a Iot of
teenagers in my store.
My jewelry's
too expensive.
What about this?
How much does something
Iike this run you?
Eight hundred bucks.
It's custom-made.
Something happen to her?
Actually,
she's dead.
Geez. And she was
wearing my Infinity?
That's why we're here.
Who'd you make it for?
Garret Lang.
Who's he?
Regular customer.
He sent his assistant
over with a drawing.
Come on.
You know, I usually
make my own stuff,
but this guy,
he orders
a hundred of them.
Gave me 80 grand
up front.
Where can we
find this Lang?
He Ieft me a stack of business
cards to hand out to my
better-paying customers.
LANG: It's the symbol
of eternal Iife.
I give the necklace
to all my patients.
STABLER: At $800 a piece,
that's an expensive gift.
What exactly do you
treat them for?
You're what,
early 40s, right,
Detective?
Late 30s, why?
Do you ever feel that
your stamina's declining?
That you don't have
the energy you used to
or that you've Iost your edge?
No, but Iet's say
that I was.
Well, then,
I would put you on a course
of human growth hormone
and testosterone therapy.
I guarantee you'd be
a new man in the squad room,
not to mention the bedroom.
But you didn't come here
to hear me pontificate.
How can I help you?
You ever seen her?
I don't think so.
Well, are you sure
that she's not one
of your patients?
Human growth hormone is used
to treat children of short
stature, Detectives,
but that's not what I do here
and I don't treat children.
Well, what about
Dr. Foy?
There is no Dr. Foy.
It stands for
Fountain of Youth.
Why would you think
that I would
know your victim?
Well, because when she was
found, your infinity symbol
was hanging around her neck.
My God.
What happened?
BENSON: That's what we're
trying to find out.
My patients who
wear the necklace
tell me that
people often ask them
where they can get one.
Any chance we can get
a Iist of those patients?
Detectives, you know
that it would be unethical
as well as illegal for me
to give you that information.
Lang's summa cum Iaude
from Stanford,
MD and PhD from Yale,
residency in OBG/GYN
with a fellowship
in infertility and
reproductive endocrinology.
That's big credentials to be
running some feel-good clinic.
He was one of the top
researchers in his field
until he Ieft academia
to open up shop.
Guy's had Iots of
magazine articles
written about him.
CIaims hormones can
reverse the aging process.
The guy's a chick magnet
for the society set.
Sounds Iike the Iunatic
fringe of medicine.
Well, it makes you feel good.
What's wrong with that?
That's the same excuse
people use to get high.
The doc's nothing more
than a dealer with a Iicense.
MUNCH: What he's doing
is perfectly Iegal.
Don't tell me you're thinking
about taking this stuff?
I've considered it.
And why shouldn't I add
some Iean muscle
to what you so
Iovingly call
"my bony ass"?
You can hit a gym
when we close this case.
Otherwise, everybody, focus.
I mean,
what's Lang Iooking for
in a 14-year-old girl?
If he's a pedophile,
maybe his own
fountain of youth.
Well, there's nothing other
than that infinity necklace
to tie him to Samantha.
And there's no way to prove
that she didn't get it from
one of his patients.
And we can't find
out who they are.
What about the autopsy?
It's backlogged.
Internal exam's
not done yet.
Well, then,
wait at the M.E.'s
office until it is.
I found traces of facial
tissue and dried saliva
on her right cheek,
which we're testing for DNA.
So it sounds Iike
somebody was with
her before she died.
Can we rule this
a homicide yet?
I need more
information.
But I can tell you that
Samantha died of a blood
clot to her Ieft Iung.
Caused by?
Severe dehydration.
I'd say she was deprived
of fluids for between
five and 10 days.
Turned her blood to sludge.
Well, it supports the theory
that somebody Iocked her away.
That's probably where
she got those
cockroach bites.
That makes sense.
What I found when
I examined her
reproductive organs doesn't.
BENSON: How so?
When a woman goes through
her menstrual cycle,
one, maybe two eggs
are released,
Ieaving the follicles
where the eggs
came from empty.
And something was wrong
with Samantha's ovaries?
She had 12 visibly
involuted follicles.
That means 12 eggs
all released at
the same time.
I've never seen that
in a 14-year-old.
But I thought
women were most fertile
in their teenage years.
Usually this only happens
when the ovaries are
hyperstimulated by hormones,
Iike, for in vitro
fertilization.
So, assuming that
she even wanted to,
why does a 14-year-old girl
need help getting pregnant?
I don't know. But whatever
the reason, it worked.
Samantha was carrying
an eight-week-old fetus.
CABOT: You can't prove
Samantha Tassler
even knew Garret Lang.
She was wearing
his necklace.
A trinket she could
have gotten anywhere
does not help me.
The guy's an infertility
specialist, he's a big wheel
in hormone research.
Now, can you think of a better
candidate to help Samantha
get pregnant?
I wouldn't want to
argue that in court.
AIex, we know that
it's circumstantial,
but this guy had to
have something to do
with Samantha's death.
I cannot get
an arrest warrant
based on supposition.
You have to find
me a direct Iink.
So give us something
that we can work with,
subpoenas for his financials,
phone records
and a patient Iist.
No judge is going to give
us a Iook at a doctor's
patient Iist.
But the rest is doable.
I can also get you
a Iook at his IRS records.
This guy doesn't have
one phone Iisted
in his own name.
AII under the corporation,
Infinity Partners.
This is gonna take a week
to trace who made all these
calls to and from his clinic.
That voodoo medicine
he practices pays big bucks.
Between his personal
and corporate accounts,
he's got almost five mil cash.
His real estate holdings
are worth at Ieast
five times that.
He owns his building
and three brownstones
and get this,
he's applying for tax-exempt
status on one of them.
Let me see that.
What's he claiming?
Charitable organization.
"Foundation for
Knowledge Expansion."
Application says
it's a non-profit
educational enrichment
program for young women
at risk.
Where?
Chelsea.
I wonder if he's
enriching these girls
Iike he did Samantha.
BENSON:
There's three more girls.
They don't Iook Iike
your typical street kids
at risk.
That makes four
going in so far.
And there's
another one.
STABLER: Just Iike
all the others.
I've seen
that girl before.
Her face Iook
familiar to you?
STABLER: Yeah. That girl
from the posters on
the Upper East Side.
You shorten her hair and you
change it back to dark brown,
that's Jessica Morse.
Disappeared about
the same time as Samantha,
presumed kidnapped.
What the hell
did we step into?
Can I help you?
Police department.
I... I didn't call
the police.
Where's Jessica Morse?
I don't know who
you're talking about.
She just walked in here.
Step aside.
Excuse me, please!
You can't do this.
You have no right to do this.
We have every right.
This is a girl who's been
missing since Iast year.
EIIiot.
What is this?
This is my school.
I am a Iicensed teacher.
These are my students.
How did they
get here?
I find them on the streets.
We run a foundation.
For knowledge expansion.
Yeah, we know all about that.
Who are you?
I'm Paula Haggerty.
We give them a safe place
to Iive, we give them food,
we give them education.
And these kids are going
back to their parents.
Mrs. Haggerty,
you're under arrest.
Is this really
necessary?
Oh, that's a nice tattoo you
have here on your Ieft wrist.
An infinity symbol.
For infinite potential.
I would Iike to call
a Iawyer, please.
You can do that
at our precinct.
Can I talk
to you a minute?
Why?
"Why"? Because you
Iook a Iot Iike a girl
who disappeared Iast year.
I'm not who you
think I am.
Jessica, your family
wants you back.
My name is Marjorie
and this is my family.
My client should be Iauded
for what she's done,
not arrested.
Your client kept
five 14-year-olds
whose parents reported them
as kidnapped or runaways.
I was just trying
to help them.
They Ieft home because
their parents
mistreated them.
And you know this how?
Mrs. Haggerty has a master's
in child psychology.
Well, then, she understands
that just because a teenager
disagrees with her parents
doesn't mean the parents
did something wrong.
Who pays your salary,
Mrs. Haggerty?
JOAN: The foundation's
board of directors.
The funds come from
charitable contributions.
Well, Dr. Garrett Lang
owns the building.
So he on the board, too?
No. He started the foundation
and provided the initial
endowment.
But he has no other dealings
with the foundation
or the employees or clients.
Was she one of your clients,
Mrs. Haggerty?
I never saw
this girl before.
I'd Iike to know
what charges, if any,
are forthcoming?
Let's start
with kidnapping.
Can I get you something
to eat or drink?
I'm not hungry.
When can I go?
Your parents are
coming here to get you.
Jessica, they've missed you
very much. They can't wait
to see you.
I've told you,
my name is not Jessica.
It's Marjorie Maddox.
Jessica, we both know
this is a picture of you.
When I talked to your mom,
she said you'd
missed your birthday.
Your family can't wait for you
to come home, they want
to celebrate it with you.
You cannot believe
how sad they were.
They thought you were
never gonna come home.
Okay. Hey, Jessica.
Come on,
it's gonna be okay.
No, it's not.
Mrs. Haggerty's going to be
so worried about me.
I have to go
back to her.
You're 14 years old.
You belong with your parents.
I belong with Mrs. Haggerty.
Can't you see that?
I know everybody thinks
that I was kidnapped.
But I ran away.
You did? Why?
Because my parents...
Oh, they didn't
understand me.
Mrs. Haggerty does?
Yes.
She saved my Iife.
She did?
How'd she do that?
She took me in
off the street.
She feeds us,
teaches us...
What does she teach you?
Stuff we should
Iearn in school.
And that all the girls
should respect themselves
and each other.
This is Samantha Tassler.
Is she one of the girls?
No.
The other four girls
are from Denver, Chicago,
Omaha and Detroit.
AII high-profile cases
because they all come
from wealthy or upper
middle class families.
How did they react
to being found?
Oh, the same
as Jessica.
They all denied
their real names,
they said they'd run
away and that
they weren't kidnapped
and they all want
to know when they can go
back to Mrs. Haggerty.
Is this
Stockholm Syndrome?
More than that.
These girls haven't
just formed a bond
with this Mrs. Haggerty.
Their total devotion
to her feels Iike
they've been brainwashed.
So this is some
kind of cult.
It explains why
they were all wearing
the infinity symbol.
And why they're all
sticking to the same story.
Well, unless one of them
starts talking, the best
we can get Haggerty on
is custodial interference
for not returning
the kids to their parents.
That's just a misdemeanor.
We can't even hold her.
What about Lang?
Right now,
he's untouchable.
If this is a cult, then maybe
Samantha was being punished
for misbehaving
or wanting to Ieave.
Cults often re-educate
their members by Iocking
them up without food or water.
Which is how the M.E.
said that she died.
That's depraved
indifference murder.
Including Samantha,
we've only found five girls.
Maybe they're holding
more somewhere else.
Like at the foundation's
brownstone.
What the hell?
This place was
completely furnished
when we found the girls.
I'II check upstairs.
They took every
damn thing.
We need every piece of dirt
off the floor in every room.
Any reasonable surface
gets dusted for prints.
Second floor is empty.
This place has
been sanitized.
Like no one
was ever here.
Neighbors say three trucks
pulled up, emptied the place
out in two hours.
Somebody had to tip them off.
CRAGEN: The call couldn't have
come from any of the girls.
We made sure none of them
got near a phone.
Well, it had to be
Haggerty or her Iawyer.
That's obstruction
of justice.
You think she'd
risk her Iaw Iicense?
We'II ask her as soon
as we're done
processing the girls.
AIready done. ACS picked up
the four from out of town,
took them to the shelter
waiting for their parents
to arrive.
What about Jessica?
Her folks
just got here.
BENSON: She Iooks
real happy to see them.
This is a cult
we're dealing with.
If we're gonna see Haggerty's
Iawyer, I want Huang along
for the ride.
You can't come barging in.
I'm with clients.
I'II handle this,
Joan.
Detectives Benson
and Stabler. And you are?
FBI. George Huang.
LANG: Can we help you?
Who cleaned out your
foundation's brownstone?
How would we know?
Oh, come on.
Somebody gave the order.
Now, it was either
you or your attorney.
Are you accusing me
of a crime?
Well, I'd Iike you to explain
why Dr. Lang and Mrs. Haggerty
both have the same Iawyer.
I had called Miss Quentin
after you arrested Paula.
You've made
a terrible mistake.
Do you know how much
she's helped runaways?
You mean after
she kidnaps them?
You're wrong, Detective.
And what about
Samantha Tassler undergoing
in vitro fertilization,
which you happen to perform?
Are we wrong about that, too?
Any OB/GYN who's
a fertility specialist
could have done that.
Yeah, but she and the other
girls weren't wearing
any other fertility
specialist's infinity
necklace.
And you've got Miss Haggerty
here who's got that symbol
tattooed on her wrist.
Any questions from the FBI,
Agent Huang?
You enjoy this,
don't you, Dr. Lang?
I enjoy helping those girls
thrive and realize their
full potential.
Because of you people,
we may have to close down
the foundation. Joan?
Unless you're going
to arrest me or either
of my clients, we're through.
Or my next call is to
the Internal Affairs
Bureau for harassment.
He's a narcissistic bastard
and he's calling all
the shots.
You saw the way his
Iawyer deferred to him.
I can understand a 14-year-old
being taken in by Lang,
but not a smart,
educated woman
Iike Quentin.
Jim Jones got hundreds of
his disciples to drink
poisoned Kool-Aid
because he had
a charismatic
personality.
Lang uses his to get people
Iike Quentin and Haggerty
to Iove and obey him.
Those teenage girls
couldn't be more
vulnerable.
They're not
that attractive.
Probably got bad
grades in school.
They're just social outcasts.
So this cult is
a place for them
to fit in.
And inundate them with
approval and affection.
It's called Iove bombing.
"You're perfect
the way you are."
Right, which is what
every teenage girl
wants to hear.
And Haggerty as a substitute
mother is a perfect person
to tell them that.
There's no way
these girls got to her
by accident.
No. They were targeted.
We've got to find out how.
MR. TASSLER: First you said
Samantha was homeless and now
you think she was murdered?
BENSON: We're not sure
exactly, Mr. Tassler.
That's what we're
investigating.
It's possible that Samantha
was starved to death
and Ieft in the alley.
Oh, my God.
We can still take her home
for the funeral, can't we?
Yes, you can.
But we need to know,
at the time of
Samantha's disappearance,
were there any changes
in her routine,
different people she was
hanging out with, friends?
She only had a few friends,
two or three girls.
They were a bad influence.
How so?
They drank and smoked
and got Samantha to
do it, too.
(SIGHS)
Her grades started to drop
but we couldn't get her
to care.
We even enrolled her
in one of those
remedial tutoring centers.
You know, the kind
with private instruction.
Help kids realize
their full potential.
What did you just say?
Help kids realize
their full potential.
It was in the brochure.
What's the name
of that center?
STABLER: You know this girl?
No. Never saw her before.
Now why are you here?
She attended this center
right before she
disappeared Iast year.
Just Iike this girl
who vanished right
outside of Philly.
I don't Iike your
insinuation, Detective.
I don't Iike Iiars,
Miss Kinderski.
Well, now,
if you're going to be rude,
this conversation is ended.
What are you doing?
Nice tattoo.
An infinity symbol.
Yes.
We believe in
the infinite potential
of our students to succeed.
Is that a crime?
It is if Garret Lang
paid for it.
Garret Lang?
Yeah. I bet if we pull your
certificate of incorporation,
his name's on it.
Doctor Lang is a
forward-thinking,
generous man
who wants to help
young people further
their knowledge.
He's just an investor.
Sure, he is.
And you're just a teacher,
right?
Kinderski Iawyered up.
Quentin's not
Ietting her talk.
Yeah, but we found
the connection.
AII six girls, Samantha
and Jessica included,
attended a Knowledge Builders
Center in their city.
Lang's at the top
of the pyramid.
Quentin keeps him
out of trouble,
Haggerty keeps
the girls in Iine
and Kinderski recruits them
from the Iearning centers.
I wouldn't be surprised
if the initial test they give
includes personality questions
to identify the most
susceptible girls.
We checked Kinderski's
credit card statements.
She was in Philadelphia,
Detroit, Omaha, Chicago
and Denver
three days before each
of the girls disappeared.
Which Ieaves us with
another coincidence
but no smoking gun.
Well, the other girls
have all gone home.
Means we're gonna
have to get Jessica to talk.
Pretty tough coming home,
isn't it?
I guess.
Mrs. Haggerty,
she was good to you,
wasn't she,
at the foundation?
Yeah. I really miss her.
I bet you do.
You want to
talk about it?
You think she
did something bad.
Hey, maybe I'm wrong.
If that's the case,
I'd Iike to know about it.
Mrs. Haggerty is the most
wonderful person I ever met.
She and the other girls
accepted me for who I am,
and not who they
thought I should be.
That's nice.
And how about Dr. Lang?
Am I wrong about him?
He is a great man.
He's going to
save the world.
Yeah? How's he
gonna do that?
Well, the ozone Iayer
is disappearing.
Yeah.
And the ultraviolet rays
will make everybody sterile.
So the only way our
species will survive
is by cloning Iiving cells.
Jessica,
are you pregnant?
Yes.
He chose me to be
one of the mothers
of the future.
So he told you
that you were
carrying a cloned baby?
To help a couple
whose baby died.
I'm going to bring
their child back to Iife.
Did Dr. Lang have
sex with you?
No. He'd never do
such a horrible thing.
He took the baby's cells
and put them in my eggs
and then put the eggs
back in me.
Where'd he do this?
BENSON: This is Lang's
Iittle shop of horrors.
I'm no expert,
but this equipment
Iooks Iike it cost millions.
FIN: Check this out.
Dr. Frankenstein's
doing his experiments.
Let's get a bus.
EIIiot, put this on.
If my patient
gets an infection
because you've contaminated
my sterile field,
she could die.
Okay. Is she cut open?
No. Of course not.
Then wake her up,
safely.
You don't understand,
do you?
I'm going to make
medical history here.
Not by using teenage
girls as guinea pigs,
you're not. Wake her up.
You're under arrest.
So how many more girls
do you have stashed away?
Dr. Lang has assured me...
Look, there are
no more.
You endangered my patient's
Iife when you entered my
operating room.
We stopped you from
experimenting on her.
AII of those
girls consented.
You have no idea
how you've harmed
our cause.
Oh, we've been through
your records, Doctor.
Your "cause" is preying
on the grief of parents
who have Iost a child
by promising them
a cloned baby in
return for a donation.
We've got one here for
half a million dollars.
Now I call that fraud.
I call it hope.
You can't prove Dr. Lang
intended to defraud anyone.
I believe that it is possible
to clone a human being.
Well, that's now
illegal in this country.
Well, it won't be
once we start dying off.
So, we as a species
are on our way out
and cloning is our only
chance at survival.
Is that it?
Not just survival,
Detective.
I'm talking about
immortality.
And you use this
idiotic crap to coerce girls
into being human incubators.
Stabler, that's
Irish Catholic, right?
Hey, pal, this ain't
about me, it's about you.
You believe
a virgin gave birth.
You think that was
a very popular theory
in Jesus' time?
What I believe has
got nothing to do
with your case.
Doesn't it? Heretics were
burned at the stake for saying
that the world is round.
Darwin was vilified for even
suggesting that humans evolved
from the primordial ooze.
Yet science and reason
proved him right.
So you're saying
that you're the new Darwin?
Or maybe even the Messiah?
I wouldn't
take it that far.
What exactly is my
client charged with?
Fraud and aggravated
sexual abuse.
You don't really think that
either of those will stand up
in court, do you?
He's right.
We can't charge him.
AIex, he deceived those
desperate parents and
inseminated minors.
It's not fraud because
there's no intent.
It's not rape because
there's no penetration.
And if we arrest him
for aggravated sex abuse,
he'II argue that
the contact was for
a valid medical reason.
My ass.
What Lang is doing
in the name of science
is no different from what
Mengele did for the Nazis.
Except these girls consented
to the procedures.
They're not old
enough to consent.
They are when it comes
to reproductive rights.
They don't need
permission to get pregnant,
no matter how they do it.
So that's it?
We can't touch him?
Not unless we can prove
he is in some way connected
to Samantha Tassler's death.
I'm ruling this a homicide.
The DNA results are back.
The saliva on Samantha's cheek
belongs to Paula Haggerty.
Saliva and facial tissue.
It's Iike a mother
wiping her child's face,
the brushing of the hair,
the wrapping in the blanket...
Now what about
Samantha's fetus?
I mean, you're not
going to tell us that
that's the clone
of some family's
dead child, are you?
Until someone
proves otherwise,
that's science fiction.
The cloned fetus would
only have DNA from that child.
Samantha's had DNA
from herself and a father.
So this whole
cloning thing
is a scam.
Samantha's eggs
were fertilized
by someone's sperm.
And I wonder who's
that could be?
We'II need DNA from Lang
to prove it's his child.
Well, Cabot got us
a blood order for Haggerty.
It shouldn't be a problem
getting one for Lang.
So, if Samantha's
baby was Lang's,
and she found out,
that sure would give Lang
a motive to kill her.
And if Lang fathered
Samantha's baby,
who do you think
fathered Jessica's?
My parents want me
to give the baby
up for adoption.
They took you
to test your baby's DNA.
Do you know why?
To make sure
that it's okay.
Mmm-hmm.
And to find out
who the father is.
Dr. Lang says my baby
doesn't have a father.
Has he ever
Iied to you?
No.
Why are you
asking me this?
Because the DNA
from your baby tells us
that it does have a father.
That's impossible.
Dr. Lang told me that
it was a cloned child.
We tested Dr. Lang.
He's the father
of your baby.
No!
Yeah.
That's the truth
and I'm sorry about it.
No, I believe in him.
I Iove him.
He fertilized your
egg with his own sperm.
He did the same
thing to Samantha.
I... I was helping
a couple whose baby died.
He Iied to them, too.
Jessica, they gave
him a Iot of money...
No, please don't!
He betrayed them.
He betrayed you,
he betrayed Samantha,
and then he killed her.
No.
It's my fault
she's dead.
What do you mean
it's your fault?
Samantha said that
Dr. Lang was a fake,
and that she was going
to report him to the police.
And I told
Mrs. Haggerty.
What did Mrs. Haggerty
say to you when you
told her that?
That Samantha had
to be reasoned with.
And then one day,
right in front of all of us,
she took Samantha away.
CABOT: Jessica, could you
please describe the room
where Mrs. Haggerty
took Samantha Tassler?
It was empty.
No chair, no bed, no toilet.
Just four walls,
a floor and a bucket.
When was the next time
you saw Samantha?
Never.
I didn't even know she was
dead until a week ago when
the police took us away.
Thank you, Jessica.
Nothing further.
Was there a Iock on
the door to the room?
I don't know.
JOAN: So for all we know,
Samantha could have been
free to Ieave at any time.
Objection.
Sustained.
Did you believe that
Dr. Lang could clone a baby?
Yes.
Did you believe that the human
race would become extinct
unless he cloned children?
Yes.
And you believed that
Samantha should be punished,
didn't you?
Yes, but not Iike that.
So you're just as responsible
for her death as anyone.
Objection.
Withdrawn.
Jessica, did you ever,
at any time,
see Dr. Lang around Samantha
or at the foundation home?
No. We always went
to see him alone.
Did Dr. Lang ever ask you
to do anything that
you didn't want to do?
No, but...
You Ioved him very much,
didn't you, Jessica?
Yes.
Nothing further.
I was on one of the first
teams to successfully
clone a cat.
I'm close to
cloning a human being.
Dolly the sheep
only Iived for six years.
And experts say that
cloned human babies
could be sick or deformed.
So, isn't it irresponsible
to even try?
Medical visionaries
throughout history
have been ridiculed.
Not only do you not know
how this is going to turn out,
you don't even know
how to do it, do you?
So why did you promise cloned
babies to parents who had Iost
their children?
Oh, I have every intention
of delivering on that promise.
But you testified on
direct examination
that you used your sperm
to fertilize the eggs
you had taken from
Samantha Tassler
and the other girls.
So you were going
to give your children
to those parents?
Until I'm able to clone
their babies, yes.
But you were
going to continue
taking their money.
The money was crucial
for me to continue.
I have no other way
to fund my research.
Research that is
now against the Iaw.
What were you going to tell
those mothers
and those fathers?
I would have told
those parents to be patient.
And they would have
had other children to Iove.
Children who belonged to girls
Iike Samantha whose eggs
you took.
Those girls,
Samantha included,
consented to the procedures.
Really? Did Samantha also
consent to being Iocked in
a room without food or water?
Objection.
Withdrawn.
Dr. Lang, isn't it true
you were afraid the money
would dry up
when the parents who paid you
to clone their children found
out that you had Iied to them?
You're treating me Iike
a criminal, when I'm trying
to give Iife, not destroy it.
You destroyed
Samantha Tassler's.
You knew if she exposed
what you were really doing,
your research would be
all washed up.
Objection.
Withdrawn.
No further questions.
Re-direct, Your Honor.
Dr. Lang, did you ever set
foot in the Foundation for
Knowledge Expansion?
Only in the beginning,
when we were setting it up
and never when
the girls were there.
Who took care of the girls?
Paula Haggerty.
Did you ever tell
Mrs. Haggerty
how to handle the girls?
No. She was more than
qualified to take care
of them on her own.
When did you Iast
see Samantha Tassler?
When I confirmed her
pregnancy a week before
she died.
So Mrs. Haggerty is the only
one who could have known
what happened to her?
LANG: Mrs. Haggerty sets
her own rules at
the foundation house.
I can't speak to
what took place there.
Thank you, Doctor.
No further questions.
The defense rests, Your Honor.
I don't need
another Iawyer.
Miss Quentin
is on her way.
I have asked Mr. Langan
to represent you
until she gets here.
I'd rather wait.
Why?
So your attorney can tell you
to keep your mouth shut?
Don't you understand?
They are sacrificing you.
I don't have to
answer that, do I?
No, but I'd advise you
to consider what
Ms. Cabot is saying.
(SCOFFS)
What's the difference?
I'm guilty.
You'd spend the rest
of your Iife in prison
so Garret Lang is free
to continue his work?
Yes, if that's
what it takes.
Why would you martyr
yourself for him?
He gave me back
something I had Iost.
You mean your daughter?
Who told you
about Carrie?
We found the missing persons
report from 1975.
When she ran away.
You never saw
her again, did you?
No.
That's why I wanted to work
with teenage girls.
I wanted to help them find
a place that they could
always call home.
And Dr. Lang
gave that to you?
Yes.
He told me that I could Iove
and help teenage girls
and that they would
bring back to Iife
these dead children
of these poor parents.
But those girls
have parents, too.
Those parents should
have treated them better!
Better than you treated
your own daughter?
Carrie was very Iittle
when my husband Ieft us.
And I didn't handle it well.
We fought constantly
and then one day I woke up
and she was gone.
In her note she said that
she had to Ieave me because
she had...
She had to find a mother.
Paula?
We brought you a visitor.
It's Jessica.
You're not mad at me?
No.
They told me all
about your Iittle girl.
I Iove my parents,
but I still Iove you, too.
AII Lang has done is
manipulated your pain.
He's used you to help him
experiment on
girls who Iove you.
They trust you.
You're the only one
who can stop him.
HAGGERTY: Marcie Kinderski
at Knowledge Builders
identified each girl
at her individual
Iearning center.
That's where
the indoctrination began.
Who brought
the girls to you?
They were told to Ieave
and come to New York
on their own.
Dr. Lang said it was
to avoid kidnapping charges.
But Marcie gave them money
for the trip and false IDs
if they were coming by plane.
And once the girls arrived,
what was your role?
I was...
I was their mother
and teacher
and nurse.
I gave them
hormone injections
to prepare them
for the procedures.
When Samantha Tassler
wanted to Ieave,
what did you do?
Reasoned with her.
I put her in a room
in the basement,
as is the doctrine.
Did you give her
any food or water?
No. I was ordered
not to.
By whom?
By Dr. Lang.
He said she had
to be re-programmed.
Who did
the re-programming?
He did.
He came over at night
after they had gone to sleep.
What happened on
the sixth night
of Samantha's re-programming?
I went to check on her.
She... She...
(STAMMERING)
She could barely move.
And just as I was about
to give her some water,
Dr. Lang
walked in
and took it
away from me.
(GASPS)
Samantha died
in my arms.
What happened next?
She was so dirty.
I tried to wipe
her face with tissue,
I fixed her hair
and I put a blanket
around her.
And then we carried
her out to my car.
Dr. Lang said that
I should Ieave her.
As if...
As if she were homeless.
(SOBBING)
But I tried to make her
as comfortable as possible.
Paula, why are you
doing this?
Why would you
betray me Iike this?
Dr. Lang, you are
out of order!
This entire trial
is out of order.
Don't you understand?
I'm trying to save you.
I'm trying to save
the human race.
Sit down, Dr. Lang,
or I will have you removed!
The cat's out of the bag,
folks!
Remove the defendant!
Science and the future
wait for no one.
If not for me,
someone will clone
a human being.
You wait and see!