NARRATOR: In the criminal
justice system,
sexually based offenses
are considered
especially heinous.
In New York City,
the dedicated detectives
who investigate
these vicious felonies
are members
of an elite squad known
as the Special Victims Unit.
These are their stories.
Did she come in
with anyone?
Just the paramedic
who dropped her off.
How bad?
Passed out drunk.
We hooked her up
to the banana bag,
Ieft her to sleep it off
and she starts to choke
on her own vomit.
Is she okay?
Now.
But she started to freak
when we cut her clothes off
with the trauma shears.
Thought she was
still being raped.
How Iong has she been waiting?
Came in at midnight,
we finished the kit
around 1:30.
I'm sorry.
It's been a crazed night.
Well, she's in here.
You dumped a rape victim
in Isolation?
We're having
a crazy night, too.
Hi. Chloe, right?
Is it okay
if I call you Chloe?
I'm OIivia from
Special Victims Unit.
I'm so sorry to have
kept you waiting.
Stupid nurse made me
sit here for these.
Nice Iook, huh?
So, Chloe, I know
how difficult this is,
but I need you to tell me
everything you remember
about your attack.
Okay?
Yeah.
You know, about that,
I don't know...
I don't know
what I was smoking.
It didn't happen.
I understand
that you were drinking.
That doesn't give anybody
the right to violate you.
Just drop it, okay?
I really just wanna go home.
Well...
How about I give you
my business card
in case you change
your mind, all right?
There's nothing to change.
And there's no harm
in taking it, either.
So it happened at a club?
I wasn't at a club.
Well, there's a stamp
on the back
of your hand. Look.
The UV Iight
makes it show up.
What part of "drop it"
don't you understand?
Poor girl. I was starting
a new IV on her
when she reported it.
So you believe her?
Yeah.
She was hysterical.
She was drunk.
Had a nasty head contusion,
consistent with an attack.
Or passing out.
No, it was on the top
of her head,
Iike he hit her
with something.
Or rammed her
into a wall during.
Detective,
we've got a situation
with your rape victim.
She got detained
at discharge,
didn't have any ID.
Well, you didn't
tell me that.
Well, she was trying
to work things out
with Nancy in billing
when a guy comes in,
starts to harass her.
Who?
By the way she reacted,
I think it could be
her rapist.
Oh, my God, Nancy.
Someone, call security.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
What happened?
A guy started
to drag her out
without paying.
I tried to stop him
and he cold-cocked me.
Where's Chloe?
Oh, he pulled her
out the exit,
kicking and screaming.
Witness saw our girl
being dragged
into a silver car.
Could've been blue.
Make? Model?
License?
Too dark.
What do we know
about the girl?
Even Iess. The name,
number, address
she gave to the hospital?
AII phony.
How's your partner doing?
She's killing herself.
She was already OT
when she took the call.
She still hasn't slept.
You gotta send her home.
Just give me
a minute.
AII right.
You know what's
bothering me, though?
How did the rapist
track her down?
Maybe he followed
the ambulance?
MUNCH: Maybe she called him.
I'II dump the hospital LUDs.
STABLER: You're thinking
"acquaintance rape"?
It explains the 180.
Date rapes are more Iikely
to drop charges.
So she calls him,
says the cops are on the way.
He sweet-talks her,
convinces her
to Iet him pick her up.
STABLER: Makes sense.
So does a Iittle privacy.
OIivia,
get some sleep.
Not until I find this girl.
FIN: Security photos
from the hospital camera.
In all the pictures
he's got his hat pulled down,
dark glasses
and he knows to be camera-shy.
She doesn't.
She's staring right
at the camera, terrified.
We know where
the ambulance
picked her up?
The hospital faxed me over
the ambulance run sheet.
Driver Ieft half of it blank
including the point of origin.
Yes, another underpaid,
overworked civil servant.
It wasn't a city ambulance.
Private company.
FIN: Well, that's the new scam
clubs are running.
They're hiring private buses
to cart off the ODs.
They bypass
police involvement.
This girl had a club stamp
on her hand. An elephant.
Let's run it down.
MAN: I don't know
what else to tell you.
She was passed out
in the street.
MUNCH: What street?
Canal, in Tribeca.
That's a big street.
Between Church
and Varick.
Who called it in?
Anonymous Good Samaritan.
Good Samaritans call 911,
they don't call private
ambulance services.
We know you picked
her up at a club.
Her hand was stamped.
MAN: She was soused.
Probably stumbled out of one,
just can't tell you which.
You can't
or you won't?
You better search
your memory.
This girl was raped
and abducted.
If anything happens to her,
I promise
we're taking you down.
So, one more time,
where'd you pick her up?
Air Bar.
VERA: I comply with all codes.
Even this new,
pain-in-the-ass
no smoking ban. See?
I think the Liquor Board
might be more interested
with how many patrons
are rolled out of here
with acute
alcohol poisoning.
I don't know
anything about that.
Lady, you've got
your own ambulance
waiting for them outside.
I wonder how many
girls Ieave here
with GHB in them?
You know,
a date rape drug
isn't taken voluntarily.
I know clubs
have had people die
in the time it takes
to call 911.
That's why I go
that extra mile
to protect my clients.
You did a piss-poor job
of protecting this one.
Before you poured that girl
into the ambulance Iast night,
she was raped
by one of your guests.
Now a hot spot
Iike this
has to have
a VIP Iist, huh?
You'II need a court order.
Well, the girl
that you allowed
to be raped is missing,
so I don't think
we're gonna have
any trouble
getting that, do you?
Roger, get that ID
they found Iast night.
You knew who she was
the whole time
we were talking?
That's obstruction, Iady.
I just put it together.
You just put it
together, huh?
Jenna Sterling, 21.
Strong resemblance.
It's not her.
It's the ID
she used to get in.
STABLER:
What makes you so sure?
CIeaning crew found it
in the same men's room stall
where she passed out.
Men's room?
I haven't been
to a men's room
since Daddy dragged us
to Hong Kong
and my Cantonese
was still choppy.
When was the Iast time
that you were at
the Air Bar, Jenna?
Never. But I hear
it's fabulous.
Yeah?
Do you mind?
What is that?
Just a Iight.
No stamp.
STABLER: They do wash off.
Where were you
Iast night?
At a gallery opening
in Chelsea.
Can anyone vouch for that?
My parents.
I'm graduating from Wellesley
so we went shopping.
Art? That's a nice
graduation gift.
My gift was a co-op.
But we had to have
something for the walls.
Your daddy
is Marvin Sterling,
that real estate guy.
Is he home?
No. He flew to Frankfurt
this morning.
Is she a friend
of yours?
No. I've never
seen her before.
Really?
'Cause she got into
the Air Bar Iast night
using your driver's Iicense.
You found it?
STABLER: She Iost it.
When?
Like, a week ago,
maybe two.
Jenna's alibi checks out.
The gallery puts her
there until midnight.
Well, that was the DMV.
Jenna did apply
for a new Iicense
a week ago.
Which is about as Iong
as it's been since
you've slept.
Grab a few upstairs.
Hey, guys.
Got an interesting hit
off Air Bar's VIP Iist.
It seems that one
of their patrons
has a prior sex assault
charge two years ago.
Who?
Morris Brandeburg,
a.k.a. Bone Kracker.
That's a pretty
tough street name.
That's a stage name.
He's a rapper.
Now, her guy was disguised,
but he was definitely white.
They don't get any whiter
than "The Kracker."
(RAP MUSIC PLAYING)
Chill, yo.
I gotta Iay it down
while I'm channeling,
you know what I'm saying?
Not a single word.
What went down
at the Air Bar Iast night?
PIayers ball, baby.
Off the hizzy.
I was just parlaying,
kicking it, you know.
Like in the old days,
when you had sex
in the clubs?
There's no Iaw against that.
Actually, there is.
FIN: We're talking
about the time
you Iured
that groupie back here
and you and your manager
double-teamed her.
She didn't sign on for him.
The manager gets
10% of everything.
I thought she knew that.
Skank was
a sack-chaser
Iooking to hit
a Powerball, all right?
Which she did.
Ho settled,
dropped all the charges.
What did she want?
Cuz, you're skitzing, man.
I don't do J.B.
What made you think
she was jailbait?
Shorty she was hanging with.
Who?
A Iittle honey
I met at this charity ball.
Her family's rolling
in bank, right?
Here.
Jenna Sterling,
back on the radar.
This girl was in
the Air Bar Iast night?
No, not that tight-ass biatch.
Baby sister, Vienna.
We need to talk
to your sister.
Vienna's not home
from school yet.
STABLER:
That'd be high school?
Yeah. She's a senior.
Oh, well, that explains
why she swiped
your Iicense.
What? That doesn't
make any sense.
She's Vienna.
CIubs just Iet her in.
VIENNA: Jenna?
Wait till you see
what I got.
You bitch,
you stole my Iicense?
Do you know
what a hassle that was?
What are you
talking about?
Who's she?
I don't know.
You were at Air Bar
with her Iast night.
No, I wasn't.
Really?
What are you doing?
Well, the elephant
says you were.
And they never forget.
Okay, my friend
was having a bad day.
I wanted to show her
a good time.
Well, your friend
was raped.
Now what's
her real name?
Chloe Dutton.
Who were you with Iast night?
No one.
I wanted to dance, she didn't.
When I got off the floor,
she was gone.
I thought she went home.
STABLER: Where's that?
Central Park West.
She wasn't at school today,
was she?
I don't know.
We don't go
to the same school.
She's only in ninth grade.
How old is she?
Fifteen.
But she's really mature
for her age.
Our girl still MIA?
She didn't show up
for school yesterday,
but apparently
that's par for the course.
Well, they didn't even
bother to call the parents?
Mother's out of town
staying at some fat farm,
and the housekeeper said
that Chloe's staying
at her father's this week.
Her father, Phillip Dutton,
is across town
in merger negotiations.
His assistant's trying
to get word to him,
but she swears
it's the mother's week.
Let me guess,
an acrimonious divorce.
Is there any other kind?
Obviously neither
one of them
give a crap
about their daughter.
STABLER: Well, she conned him
for a free night out.
Trust me, when
they're working an angle,
teenagers are
very slippery.
Oh, so now she
deserved what she got?
That's not what I'm saying.
Look, all I'm saying is
that this girl was raped
and kidnapped,
and nobody in her family
even noticed.
Look, OIivia,
you've been at this
for three days.
If anything breaks,
we'II call. Go home.
SVU. Benson.
We'II be right there.
Who found her?
Patrol.
I'd say just after
she washed up on the bank.
Is this your girl?
Yeah.
STABLER:
What did he do to her?
No obvious wounds
or Iigatures.
Going by exclusion,
I'd say drowning.
Contusion to the head.
Might have knocked her out
before throwing her in.
No, she had
that bump yesterday.
It was from the rape.
How about the cut on her Iip?
That's new.
I was right there.
I should have had him.
No broken teeth,
no petechial hemorrhaging
of the gums.
Wait. There's something
down here.
Some kind of business card?
PIease tell me
this guy was stupid enough
to Ieave his name.
No. Yours.
After submersion
she hyperventilated,
aspirating water
into the Iungs
Ieading to pulmonary
edema and hypoxia.
STABLER: She drowned?
Yes, but the question
is where?
Not in the Hudson?
Water from there is brackish,
so I should have found
salt water in her Iungs.
I didn't.
Well, currents
could have carried her a ways.
It's fresher upstream.
Not this fresh.
I ran a diatom test
which should have found
traces of algae,
plankton, krill.
Nothing.
You said that she
swallowed water?
Yes. Containing chlorine,
fluoride and orthophosphates.
Tap water.
With traces of a chemical
composition consistent
with Sparkly Bowl.
The bastard shoved her face
in a toilet.
Finger impressions on the back
of her neck to support it.
Parents are here
to ID the body.
Stall them.
I'II try to clean her up.
Mr. and Mrs. Dutton,
we're very sorry
for your Ioss.
We're the primary detectives
on your daughter's case.
How the hell did this happen?
You were watching her.
You tell them.
It was your week.
I understand this is
a very stressful time,
but we need
to focus on Chloe.
Do you have any idea
who could have done this?
No one I know.
Of course not.
You were never home.
I was closer to her
than you were.
The viewing is done
on closed-circuit
monitor here.
Are you ready?
Why can't we
see her in person?
You should wait to see her
at the funeral home.
It will be easier.
MRS. DUTTON: Oh, God.
Oh, God.
You son of a bitch.
How could you
Iet this happen?
We'II need to talk
to her friends.
WOMAN: Chloe was a Ioner.
Do you have any idea why?
Her parents divorced,
best friend moved away,
puberty...
Cut the Iock.
She was miserable here.
She petitioned
for early graduation
but she didn't have
the grades.
Books, gym clothes,
there's no date book
or photos or anything.
There's something here.
A Iittle note.
A secret admirer?
"Chloe, I've done
everything I can
to help you,
"but you've screwed me
for the Iast time.
"You're dead to me."
Signed B.T.
I'II check the roster.
"You're dead to me."
I meant it figuratively.
And yet, she's dead.
Chloe and I were partners
for the science project.
It's due in two days
and I've done all the work.
The charts, graphs, report,
water sample collections...
Water?
What was the project?
The effects of acid rain
in the urban setting.
I compared rain water
from various points
throughout the city.
Including the Hudson?
You don't wanna know
its pH Ievel.
What about Manhattan
toilet water?
That water's been treated
so it's not relevant
to my study.
It's relevant
to this investigation.
When's the Iast time
you saw her?
Two days ago.
She promised
we'd work after school
on the oral presentation.
I waited outside
and she rides right by
in some stud's sports car.
FIN: Describe him, Bertram.
High school, of course.
Maybe college.
Do you remember anything
about the car,
the make, the model?
Cars aren't really
my thing.
MUNCH: And what
about numbers?
Do you remember any part
of the Iicense plate?
I-L-Four-Four-Two-D.
I Iive for 42 Ds.
We know it's a rental.
What can you tell us
about the renter?
Mr. and Mrs. Stark
from Oklahoma.
Checked in Monday.
He's in oil.
Very particular.
FIN: When's the Iast time
he called down for his car?
Not since Tuesday.
Are you sure
he hasn't used the car
since then?
Actually,
we wouldn't know.
Mr. Stark has chosen
not to use valet service.
Your basic pain-in-the-ass.
Yeah. I mean,
we try to keep
the guests happy.
So we informed Mr. Stark
that he was welcome
to get his own car.
He took his key back.
The first few days
I drove myself everywhere.
Really? Well, most
tourists take taxis.
You ever seen those guys?
It's Iike they're on
a suicide mission.
Zane says
there's plenty to see
within walking distance.
You make any exceptions
the Iast few days?
Hell, no.
They've been keeping
me busy
at the convention anyway.
STABLER: A shame
you're missing
the night Iife.
He hasn't taken you
out at all, huh?
No, not when there's clients
to wine and dine.
Well, where'd you take
these clients two nights ago?
Some supposed hot spot
where the drinks were warm
and the waitresses cold.
PIace got a name?
I'm sure it does, but damned
if I can tell you what.
Well, how'd you get there?
We had a few before we went,
so I can't quite recollect.
Why do they need
to Iook through our car?
Probably just a mix-up.
Can I get that
for you, Mr. Stark?
I got it, I got it.
Probably find
a spare tire in there.
May I?
What's that?
Hell if I know.
These are hospital issues
just Iike the pair
they gave Chloe.
Who in the hell is Chloe?
Sir, you're gonna have
to come with us.
For what?
You cheating son of a bitch!
What have you done now?
BENSON: Hold on.
We just had
the nicest conversation
with your wife.
Boy, once you get
that woman started.
What'd that cow say?
That you've got a problem
keeping it in your pants.
BENSON: And you Iike
them young.
This young.
Get that out of my face!
Is this how you Iike it,
you Iittle freak?
What the hell
is going on here?
I've never seen that girl.
I'm being railroaded.
Who'd want to set up
a nice guy Iike you?
ZANE: You don't know how
cutthroat the oil business is.
Or maybe the ball and chain
finally went off her nut.
Well, Dora says
that you didn't come back
to the hotel Tuesday night.
AII right.
I cheat on my wife.
But where I come from,
that's not a police matter.
So who'd you cheat with?
I don't know her name.
The boys and me
went to one of them titty bars
that never closes.
We went straight
from there to the convention.
Ask the boys.
Oh, we will.
Names and numbers.
And if you're
feeling generous, DNA sample.
Hey, I donate all the time.
AB Negative.
The rarest type there is.
They call me the Tulsa gusher.
Witnesses put Stark at
Peek-a-Boobs all night.
What about 3:30
the day before
when that science geek
saw Chloe in his Jag?
Couldn't have been Stark.
He was too busy
putting a room full
of conventioneers
to sleep
with a Iong-ass speech.
OIivia?
Chloe's rape kit came back.
Stark isn't a match?
To any of them.
There's more
than one doer?
Try four.
She was gang-raped.
Okay, we know
one of our perps
got hold of Stark's Jag.
The question is how?
It was parked at a week-Iong
excuse for a bender.
A couple of drunken
fellow oil men
could have easily
Iifted the keys.
Do you know
how many people crammed
into that hotel
for the convention?
MUNCH: Maybe this
will help narrow it down.
I plowed through the LUDs
from the hospital.
Found an outgoing call
to a cell phone
registered to...
STABLER: Vienna Sterling.
Who swore that she
never talked to Chloe again
after the club.
Odd. It was
a seven-minute call.
Well, what are
all the other names?
At 3:40 a.m.,
Chloe calls Vienna
from the hospital.
That's Iess than an hour
before I got there.
At 3:47,
Vienna calls Andrew Kenworthy
who then calls
Davis Harrington at home,
then his cell,
then five more times at home
until he finally picks up.
Well, that sounds
pretty desperate.
Indeed.
Davis then calls Vienna,
who calls Seth Wolfford III.
And then they ping-pong
back and forth
throughout the day.
Sounds Iike we got
three of our four guys,
Andrew, Davis and Seth.
Pick them up.
MUNCH: Andrew Kenworthy?
Damn it!
A Iittle advice?
Keep your eye on the ball.
Who the hell are you?
Detective Tutuola.
You need to come with me.
For what?
The rape and murder
of Chloe Dutton.
Who?
Come here.
Can you believe
the attitude on her?
I mean,
the girl's a sales clerk.
Hello? A Iittle help, please.
These weigh a ton.
Vienna?
Well, there went
our Iast chance.
They've all Iawyered up.
Well, we still have
one unaccounted for.
I don't suppose
anybody gave him up?
What, and incriminate
themselves?
Not one of them talked.
Or gave up their DNA.
Well, they're not
going to now,
not with their
$1,000-an-hour attorneys.
Yeah, well,
screw their money.
Ask for a remand.
Remand?
I might have Vienna
here on obstruction,
but I don't even have enough
for an indictment on the boys.
What're you talking about?
We've got two of them
on the club's VIP Iist.
Well, it doesn't put them
in the men's room.
Three words, AIex,
"Max Factor heir."
These kids have the means
to flee the country.
Not without a passport,
which my client
will gladly surrender.
CABOT: Well, that's awfully
big of you, Trevor.
On the condition he be allowed
to Ieave the state, today.
For what?
Congressman Sayres,
maybe you've heard of him?
He's expecting me in DC
to start my internship.
Yes, the calling to serve
is strong in this Iad.
He'II do well there.
Here's where Seth
will be staying.
Arlington.
You can go.
What was that about?
STABLER: What are you doing
rolling over for Langan?
He has a client
headed to Virginia.
Thanks to you.
Virginia recently became
the first state
to allow DNA collection
upon arrest.
Conviction not required.
BIatantly violating
constitutional rights.
It will be overturned.
As well it should be,
but hopefully not today.
What are the odds
Seth commits a felony
in Virginia?
Let me make
a phone call.
SERGEANT: He's in here.
Your car is ready,
Mr. Wolfford.
FIN: Traffic's Iight
and it's a fine day
for an extradition.
You set me up.
I assure you,
a Iocal bank was indeed robbed
and a guard was shot.
It wasn't me and you know it.
One of the perps
was a six-foot tall
white man.
Makes you
a viable suspect.
That's bull.
That's racial profiling.
Sucks, don't it?
This is insane.
I'm innocent.
Well, maybe the bank job,
but in accordance
with the Iaw,
Arlington PD
ran your DNA
through the national
data bank.
And you're a dead match
for one of Chloe's rapists.
They had no right
to take my DNA.
Yeah, well,
write to your congressman.
This is preposterous.
Your friend Seth
gave him up.
A court order for his DNA
is on the way,
which you know
is going to match.
DAVIS: The sex was consensual.
ANDREA: Davis, shut up.
There is no such thing
as consensual sex
with a 15-year-old.
I didn't know.
The girl was in a bar
being served alcohol.
My client had no reason
to doubt she was 21.
You can't use
a dispositive defense.
Statutory does not
require intent.
Look, I had nothing to do
with the murder.
And you have no evidence
proving he did.
I have a motive.
A rape conviction
might have tarnished
the silver spoon
he was born with.
I don't know who killed her,
but I swear to God,
it wasn't me.
Convince me.
Start from the beginning.
I was out with Andrew
and Seth that night.
It all started
when we ran into Max.
Who's Max?
He's a friend
of Andrew's.
He said he had
just done this girl
in the bathroom
and she was open for more.
You mean she'd passed out?
I was too drunk
to appreciate her condition.
AII I know was
she was passed out
by the time we Ieft.
Tell me more about this Max.
He's a cool guy, filthy rich.
I think his father invented
Krazy GIue or Post-Its
or something huge Iike that.
Where can we
find him?
Like I said,
he was a friend of Andrew's.
Ask him.
Max Van Horn. I only met him
a few weeks ago.
Okay, so what do you
know about him?
Not much.
He Iet it drop once
that his father works
for the CIA.
I thought his father
was an inventor?
I don't know
about that.
What kind of car
does Max drive?
A black Porsche
and a silver Jag.
So, Max must have picked up
Chloe from school that day.
He met her a few days
before at Vienna's.
That'd be
your girlfriend Vienna?
Yeah.
So then this Max
snatched her up
from the hospital,
so you guys could kill her
to save your own asses.
No. I had nothing
to do with the murder.
It must have been Max.
Well, we've got
a problem here
because Vienna
didn't call Max
at 4:00 in the morning,
she called you.
To warn you
that Chloe was gonna
turn you guys in.
No, to scream at me
for cheating on her.
Cheating?
Cheating, really?
She didn't have a problem
with the bigger picture,
Iike the rape?
You don't know Vienna.
It's all about her.
Oh, what is it
with you people?
What is wrong with you?
Do you have a conscience?
You raped and killed
a Iittle girl!
I didn't kill her.
We've got panicked
phone calls
between you, Vienna,
Davis and Seth,
but not one
to good old Max.
He's not
in the picture, son.
Why is that?
Explain that to me.
Because I didn't
have to call Max.
He was crashed on my couch.
And when I told him
what V said, he booked.
Where can we find him?
BENSON: He's gotta
come home some time.
STABLER: Not if one
of his friends
tipped him off.
These are not
the kind of guys
who would go out on a Iimb
for each other.
You got a point.
What do you think it is,
the money?
Not all rich kids
are Iike this.
Yeah, but these are
trust fund babies.
Everything handed to them.
No character,
no conscience.
You're either born
with a conscience
or you're not.
Oh, no, no, no.
It's all about
how you're raised.
We've got someone approaching.
Max Van Horn!
Hey, Max.
It's the valet guy
from the hotel.
Son of a bitch.
Now, do you prefer
Max Van Horn
or your Iegal name,
Mitch Wilkens?
Just... Just Mitch.
Where'd you get Max?
I thought it sounded rich.
You know, Iike those guests
whose bags I schlep every day.
I just wanted to be
one of them.
BENSON: So you stole
their cars?
I only borrowed them.
And the first time
was a couple of weeks ago,
you know?
I took out a Porsche,
just for a spin,
but, there was this Iine
outside this club.
I mean, you should have seen
the Iooks I was getting.
It was my in.
That was the night
I met Andrew and Vienna.
So what happened?
We clicked.
Even exchanged numbers.
The problem is,
I had to keep up the image.
And the best way to do that
is by raping a 15-year-old.
They set me up!
BENSON:
Your new best friends? Why?
I don't know.
Maybe they're rich and bored
and that's how they
get their kicks.
I mean, they probably sensed
I wasn't one of them.
STABLER:
How'd they set you up?
Andrew asked
if I would pick up
one of Vienna's friends
and we'd all go out.
Did you pick Chloe up
at school?
I picked her up
across the street.
I mean, you saw her.
Would you think she was 15?
Maybe not, but I wouldn't
have gang raped her
in the bathroom.
Andrew pulled me in.
I said, "No way."
They gave me a hard time.
They called me a wuss.
They pressured me into it.
Really?
Because we heard
that you started the party.
It's a Iie!
But, you know, of course,
they're gonna
get away with it.
'Cause they're rich.
So help us out here, Mitch.
Who was with you
when you killed her?
I didn't kill her.
AII I know is
Andrew got a phone call
at, Iike, 4:00 in the morning.
You know, he said
things had turned south,
he needed the Jag
to take care of it.
So how do we know
that you didn't go with him?
Because I panicked
and I took the first bus
to my mom's in Jersey.
That's a bad story,
because we've got
a picture of you
dragging Chloe
out of the hospital.
That's not me.
There are witnesses, Mitch.
Wait...
I know this coat.
That guy... That guy, Seth.
Seth... Seth Wolfford.
Seth was the first one
to roll.
That's why he got a deal.
Do you think we gave it
to the wrong boy?
Does this Mitch
have a record?
No. CIean as a whistle.
If he's telling the truth,
you've gotta yank Seth's deal.
That's why
I don't Iike to make deals
until everyone's
done their job.
We'II check out
his story.
Mitch showed up
at 5:00 that morning.
Oh, he was so upset.
About what?
He said he'd made
some new friends
and that they'd gotten
him into trouble.
Did he tell you
what the trouble was?
Something about a car.
He had taken one
for a joyride
thinking that he could
get it back in time,
but those boys
took advantage of him
and disappeared with it.
Mrs. Wilkens,
did your son tell you
he was involved in a rape?
What?
Oh...
That can't be true.
BENSON: There's no question.
We have his DNA.
I knew
there was more.
You have to understand.
He tries so hard
to impress people.
He's so easily influenced.
The girl he raped
was found murdered
the next day.
Well, I know he had nothing
to do with that. He was here.
We saw him Iater that day
at the hotel, with the Jag.
How did he get it back?
That boy drove it here.
He took Mitch in to work.
What boy?
I think his name was Seth.
(MAN CHATTERING ON RADIO)
You know,
if you'd tell me
what you were
Iooking for,
it'd save my maid
a Iot of work.
Damn it,
this is harassment!
Give me that,
you Iow-Iife piece...
Think Iong and hard
about your next word, Seth.
Harassing a police officer's
a sure way
to get that bail revoked.
Lookee what I found.
Oh.
Just Iike the hospital
security photos.
Oh, my God.
You're framing me again.
Nice shades.
Those aren't mine.
Detectives...
I got traces of blood.
Why, Seth, what pretty
blue water you have.
That was hell.
Seth's attorney
give you a tough time
on cross?
Langan was a cakewalk.
That media circus
was another story.
STABLER: Rich,
pretty boy defendant.
Sells a hell
of a Iot of papers.
This kid's an idiot.
He should have taken
a plea Iike his buddies.
What he got to Iose?
He was the only one
facing murder.
Arrogance. He thinks
he can beat the rap.
And he still swears
he was on his daily 10-K
during the time
of that murder.
POLICEMAN: That's them,
over there.
BENSON: Can I help you?
Yeah.
I know who killed
Chloe Dutton.
Excuse me?
You arrested the wrong boy.
That's the one who did it.
That's Mitch Wilkens.
Yeah.
That's probably
what he calls himself now.
But his real name
is Eric Wayne Proctor.
And how do you
know this?
Because he murdered my son.
Okay, maybe we should
have a seat.
Yeah.
No.
It said in there
you cut him a deal.
That means he could get
two years this time.
What do you mean
"this time"?
Twelve years ago,
he Iived down the street
from us.
He and his mother.
Eric Ied my Iittle boy,
Tommy, into the woods.
Eric was 10.
My Iittle guy was only three.
Take your time.
Why don't we have
a seat here?
Eric tortured my son.
He molested him.
He poured gasoline on him.
They said that
when he set my guy on fire,
he was still alive.
Was this Eric ever convicted?
Yeah, but not as an adult.
He went
to a juvenile facility,
for kids, and that's all
the information I got on him.
So you haven't had
any contact with him
since the trial
over a decade ago?
No, sir.
How can you be sure
that this is the same person?
Because you never forget
the face of the monster
who killed your son.
STABLER: They couldn't
publish the killer's name
because of his age,
but I'm telling you,
it was the most
gruesome murder
in Bedford,
New Hampshire's history.
We talked
to the Iocal police.
They said that
he was always a psycho.
He's been collared five times
for breaking and entering.
His juvenile records
were sealed and then expunged
when he was released.
When did he get out?
BENSON: Three years ago,
when he was 19.
He was supposed to be in there
till he was 21,
but he got out early
for good behavior.
Of course he did,
because he's a sociopath.
He gets a clean slate,
a new name
and then he moves here.
Where he kills again.
CABOT: You're going
on a hunch.
AII you have is
his prior bad act,
which I can assure you
is not admissible in court.
AIex, I'm telling you,
you've got the wrong kid
up for this murder.
If we've screwed up,
then fix it,
preferably before the end
of Seth's trial.
BENSON: I'm sorry.
Which did you prefer?
Was it Max or Mitch?
Or was it
Eric Wayne Proctor?
I think I had
the most fun as Max.
So, Eric, tell me,
you had three jerks
to choose from.
Why frame Seth?
I didn't frame anybody.
But if I had,
Seth did have the most money,
the best Iooks,
the brightest future.
Who could resist?
Well, Seth denies
that the hat,
the coat and the sunglasses
are his.
You planted them.
Now how could I get
into his house?
The same way you got
into Stark's Jag.
You stole the key
and you made a copy.
A boy gets quite
an education in juvie.
You're right.
But I didn't do this.
Oh, you're good.
You got your own mother
to alibi for you
and to tell you the truth,
we believed her.
She's a bigger sociopath
than you.
Everyone assumes
she did something awful to me.
But she didn't.
You're a Iiar.
She's never
abused me once.
You're a Iiar.
Not physically
or psychologically.
You're a Iiar.
That woman did something
terrible to you, boy.
I wish.
Poor old thing.
She got hate mail,
death threats,
people spit on her
in the street.
She stuck it out there
just to see me.
Now that's Iove.
No. That's denial.
You think that your mother
can't be broken?
You think you're in
total control of her?
You just watch me.
Bring it on, bitch.
(LAUGHS)
As I said,
there's nothing to break.
But do go easy
on the old girl.
I've put her
through so much already.
He ruined your Iife.
You Iost your job,
your friends, your husband.
You stood by him.
He's murdered again.
Only this time
he dragged you into it.
You perjured yourself,
you obstructed justice
and you could go to jail.
I didn't Iie.
He didn't kill that girl.
Her name was Chloe.
She was only 15.
Of course, that's five times
older than his first victim.
Eric was only
a baby then.
He didn't know
what he was doing.
He thought
it was a game.
A game?
This is not a game.
Your son is sick!
No! They cured him!
Nine years
he spent in that prison.
It was a juvenile facility.
It was his entire childhood!
He had counseling
that whole time.
He did so well
that they Iet him out early.
He played them.
He showed them
exactly what they
wanted to see,
just Iike he does with you.
Oh, you don't know him.
He's a good boy.
He's got a job.
He Iives in
a beautiful brownstone.
And he Ied Tommy Leggatt
into the woods to his death,
just Iike he Ied this girl
into the men's room
to be gang raped.
But he didn't kill her.
Mrs. Wilkens,
a mother knows her son.
Now you know that that's him,
dragging her from the hospital
to her death.
Before he dumped her body
into the river,
he shoved her face
into the toilet
and he held it there
until she was dead.
That's how much regard
he has for human Iife.
And when he gets out,
he's gonna kill somebody else.
You're wrong.
He didn't do this.
Oh, my God.
EIIiot, Iook at this.
The bracelet.
She was wearing it
when she was dragged
out of the hospital,
but not when she washed up.
He took it.
Mrs. Wilkens,
where'd you get the bracelet?
CABOT: Mrs. Wilkens,
you'II have
to speak up, please.
Where did you get
the bracelet?
MRS. WILKENS:
My son gave it to me.
CABOT: When?
It was a Friday.
It was the first week of May.
That was one day
after Chloe Dutton was killed.
Did you see your son
the day before,
the actual day of the murder?
No.
Why did you tell
Detectives Benson and Stabler
that you did?
My son asked me to.
What exactly
did he ask you to do?
He said that some boys
had found out about his past
and they were going to
use it against him.
He said that they
had done something bad
and they were going to
make everyone believe
that he had done it.
Did you believe him?
No.
Why not?
Every mother knows her son.
That bracelet that he gave
to me,
he took off
the dead body
of Chloe Dutton.
I'm so sorry.
Eric should never
have been Iet out
after he killed Tommy Leggatt.
Objection! Your Honor...
That judge had no choice,
but you do.
He's sick.
If you ever Iet him out again,
he will kill again.
Mrs. Wilkens...
No! Listen to me!
There's no fixing him.
He was born bad,
and he's gonna die bad.
There's just...
There's nothing anyone can do.
LARSEN: Has the jury
reached a verdict?
We have, Your Honor.
On the count of kidnapping,
how do you find?
We find the defendant,
Mitchell Wilkens, guilty.
On the count of murder
in the first degree
how do you find?
Guilty.
LARSEN: Sentencing will be
imposed June 4th.
The jury is excused.
(BANGS GAVEL)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Mitch.
This is a capital
offense, Mitch.
Looks Iike you're
going away forever.
Don't worry. I'II write.
Well, we did a Iittle digging.
You don't own that brownstone
where you were Iiving.
You never paid rent,
you had no Iease.
It's owned by an elderly woman
called Emily Owens.
No family, most of
her friends have died.
And we can't find her.
Eric,
everybody including
your own mother
believes you're beyond
redemption.
That's not true.
This woman deserves
a proper burial.
You know
that's the right thing.
Where is she?
Gee, I don't know.
I guess I'm going away
for a while
so I should
probably give notice.
BAILIFF: Let's go.
Do Iet me know
if you find her.