NARRATOR: In the criminal
justice system,
sexually based offenses
are considered
especially heinous,
In New York City,
the dedicated detectives
who investigate
these vicious felonies
are members
of an elite squad known
as the Special Victims Unit,
These are their stories,
Excuse me,
where's the baby formula?
It's around the corner.
I'II show you.
These are on sale.
My brand. Great.
Thanks.
No problem.
Emma? My baby!
Where's my baby?
What's wrong?
Oh, God!
Somebody stole my baby!
Stay right here.
Emma! Emma!
Baby girl, six weeks,
name's Emma Daricek.
White undershirt,
one piece Iong-sleeve
red jumper,
purple socks and sweater,
white booties.
Enough brown hair
for a pink bow.
How Iong did the mother
Ieave the kid alone?
She swears it was
Iess than seconds.
That's all it takes.
The store have a protocol
for missing kids?
Security says it took
about three minutes
to close off all the exits.
We're searching
aisle by aisle now,
getting names and addresses
of employees and customers
before they can Ieave.
Okay. How many other mothers
were in here when it happened?
Seven. Mrs. Daricek eyeballed
every one of those babies.
Where is she now?
Back in the manager's office
beating herself up.
Husband's on his way.
STABLER: Witnesses?
Nobody saw it happen.
Baby snatchers travel Iight.
Perp Iifts the kid out
of one cart, sticks her
in another. Two seconds, done.
OFFICER: Detectives.
What's up?
Motor Vehicle office down
the street. They found
something in the Iadies' room.
What do you got?
She found these baby clothes
in the garbage can here.
Snatcher probably
disguised the girl as a boy.
Afraid that the baby would
get recognized on the street.
What's all this?
OFFICER: We got an eyedropper
and some capsules.
It's Librium.
Sedative.
Perp could be an alcoholic
trying to control the shakes.
Dissolve some in water,
feed it to the baby
so she doesn't cry,
calmly walk out of the store.
And then give her a haircut.
I just walked away
for one moment
and she was gone.
How could this happen?
Did you notice anyone
in the aisles watching you?
I don't remember...
Did anyone stop to talk?
Well, did anyone
pay unusual attention to Emma?
I don't know! Will you stop
asking me questions
and just go find her!
Michele, you gotta
try to calm down
so we can help you...
Calm down? I Ieft her alone!
But torturing yourself
isn't going to bring
your daughter back.
Michele!
Tony.
Hey. Hang on now.
How did it happen?
I took my eyes off her.
I'm so sorry.
It'II be okay...
It's way past Emma's feeding.
I know she's hungry. PIease.
You've got to find her!
We're doing everything
that we can. May I
speak to you one minute?
I'II be right back,
sweetheart.
Michele.
TONY: You're gonna
find Emma, right?
Every second counts.
That's why we need your help
to calm your wife down.
I've been trying to do that
ever since Emma was born.
And what does that mean?
One minute everything's okay,
the next Michele's crying
and throwing things.
This is the first time
she's been out of the house
with Emma.
I'm worried.
Is your wife
taking any medication?
I can't even get her
to see a doctor.
I gotta get back there.
Mr. Daricek, I have
four children of my own,
so I can't even imagine
what you're going through,
but I...
What are you saying?
I don't want to jump
to any conclusions here,
but it sounds Iike your
wife's going through
postpartum depression.
Yeah. Okay.
She's stressed out.
Look, if I thought
Emma was in any danger,
I swear I'd take her away.
You think if Michele
harmed her baby she
would be rational enough
to plant the clothes
and hair in the bathroom?
Can't rule it out.
This was pretty well planned.
Felt more Iike
somebody desperate for a baby
who couldn't get one
the Iegal way.
Well, either way,
the clock is running.
We don't find Emma soon,
she's gone for good.
That's why I called in
the mobile command post.
We'II save time
working from here, all right?
EIIiot, if you think
she knows something,
find out. Fast.
Michele, was she wearing
anything else
besides the jumper?
It was cold.
She was sleeping
wrapped in a blanket.
Emma cries
when she gets cold.
You know, when my
first daughter was born,
I was working the midnight
to 8:00 a.m. shift,
my wife worked days.
So when I got home
all I wanted to do was sleep,
all my baby
wanted to do was cry.
I nearly Iost my mind.
I could barely function.
It's so hard.
Michele, I know
what you're going through.
The first baby
is always the toughest.
I feel blessed every day
because I have Emma.
I Iove her so much.
Am I ever gonna see her again?
(CRYING)
We make the proper
notifications?
Airports, train
and bus stations
are all covered.
Photos of Emma
are going out
to every toll booth
and police department
within a 100-mile radius.
We're also checking on
any attempted snatchings
where the baby's sex
was disguised.
Anything from your canvass?
Only thing we came up with
is a woman with a suitcase
in her shopping cart.
Get with store security,
see what they got
on the videotapes.
FIN: You have someone
watching this all day?
SECURITY GUARD:
This isn't a Vegas casino.
Here it is.
So mom checks out
the merchandise.
Mystery shopper Iifts the kid,
and it wasn't the mother.
Damn it, can't see her face.
This the only angle
you have on this?
Yeah. That part
of the store, yeah.
What about the front doors?
We got cameras
on the entrance and exit.
MUNCH: Get the exit tape
from that time of day
and hurry up.
What kind of woman would steal
somebody else's kid?
Could be maternal instinct
run amuck or maybe
it's strictly business.
Not her. Not her. Not her.
Pause it.
Kid would be screaming
if she was in that suitcase.
Unless she's already
been doped up.
Nobody saw her
take Emma out of the store.
Why risk stopping to change
the baby's appearance?
Nobody's Iooking
for a Iittle boy.
EIIiot's still with
the Dariceks. So Iet's rule
Michele out for the moment.
Did our mystery Iady...
Thank you.
...buy the suitcase
in the store?
About half an hour
before the snatch.
Paid with a credit card
in the name of Susan Young.
Works downtown
at Social Services.
AII right. Go.
My purse was stolen
this morning.
Where?
Substance abuse center
where I work.
I filled out a report
at the precinct in Chinatown.
You guys found it already?
No, but we think this woman
used one of your credit cards.
AIicia.
You know her?
I saw her
a couple of hours ago.
She's one of my clients.
I don't believe this.
Does she have
access to Librium?
She's not taking it.
She could get some
from someone at the clinic.
AIicia's a crack addict.
She was doing so well, too.
Hadn't used since
she got pregnant.
When did she have the baby?
Last week.
Stillborn.
It's a real tragedy.
Where does she Iive?
10th Avenue, the 50s.
I can call my office,
get the exact address.
Start in the kitchen.
Must have found herself
a nice job.
Or a sugar daddy.
I'II take the bedroom.
No sign of a kid here.
She's back on the pipe.
Must be feeding
her habit with this.
Found it in the closet.
AII 100s.
There's a couple
thousand dollars.
(DOOR OPENS)
BENSON: Stop! Police!
Get off me, bitch!
Get your hands off me!
Let me go!
Shut up! Shut up.
AII right. Where's that baby?
My baby is dead.
You took that baby
from the store.
Now where is she?
I gave her away.
You sold that baby
for crack money!
I had to.
I promised him my baby,
my baby died...
Okay, AIicia.
Who did you promise
the baby to?
A Iawyer.
I put her up for adoption.
Give me a name.
I can't tell you.
Huh? You can't tell me?
Look at me.
Now, you tell me a name.
Mark. Mark Sanford.
I took the baby
to him in Chelsea.
(BABY COOING)
You hear that?
Yeah.
WALLER: Who's down there?
Upstairs.
Police. Open up.
The police are here.
Who was that?
The police.
I thought you were burglars.
What are you doing?
The Iast number
you just dialed wasn't 911.
Who are you?
I take care of the babies.
You're gonna wake them.
Which one's Emma?
These children
were all given up
for adoption...
One of these babies was stolen
from her mother this morning.
I didn't do anything wrong.
Emma. Right here.
Look, I didn't know.
Ma'am, you are under arrest
for kidnapping.
But I didn't kidnap anybody.
It's okay.
Two girls and one boy.
Six weeks to two months old.
Pediatrician says they were
well taken care of
and in excellent health.
Peddling sick babies
would be bad business.
We know who the peddler is?
The brownstone where we
found the babies was rented
to Adoptions Incorporated.
The Iease was signed
by a Mark Sanford.
Well, I had Fin
notify Michele Daricek.
Do we have any idea
who the other kids belong to?
We don't even know
if they were kidnapped
or sold.
ACS is coming to take custody
of them. We'II get their
photos out to the media.
You know somebody's
gonna come forward.
Yeah, every couple
who'd Iove to adopt them.
TONY: Where is she?
BENSON: She's right here.
(BABIES CRYING)
WOMAN ON PA:
Nurse practitioner
to delivery,
Emma.
Got her.
Oh, baby. Oh, my baby.
I'II never Iet you
out of my sight again.
MICHELE: She's okay?
She's perfect.
TONY: Can we take her home?
Yeah. You just sign her out
right there, she's all yours.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Michele's gonna see a doctor.
That's good.
Okay. Good Iuck.
Thank you. AII right.
The nurse give anything up?
Only "I'm just the babysitter"
routine.
Well, Munch and Fin are
interrogating her right now.
You two check with the FBI
and the Center for Missing
and Exploited Children.
See if they have any reported
snatchings that could be
our other two babies.
I'm a registered nurse.
I was hired to care
for the infants.
Babies tucked away
in an otherwise
empty brownstone
and you didn't think
that was odd?
They're kept there
until their adoptive parents
come for them.
Who brings you the babies?
Mr. Sanford.
FIN: The guy you called
on your cell phone.
When you Iied and said
you were calling the police.
Mr. Sanford is a wonderful man
who places unwanted babies
in Ioving homes.
Tell us where this Sanford is
or you're an accessory.
He's a Iawyer. His office
is out in Kew Gardens.
(POLICE SIREN WAILING)
Going somewhere, Mark?
Look, I have nothing to say
without my attorney present.
We'II have him meet us
at the precinct.
Mark Sanford,
you're under arrest
for kidnapping.
You have the right
to remain silent.
Anything you say can
and will be used against you
in a court of Iaw.
You have the right
to an attorney.
I have never knowingly
put a stolen child
up for adoption.
My client
is a distinguished member
of the Iegal community.
To whom babies
are just product.
Those babies were
signed over to us
by their birth mothers.
And you bought
Michele Daricek's baby
from a crackhead for $10,000.
AIicia Brown gave up her son
two years ago for adoption.
She contacted me
when she was pregnant again.
I had no reason to believe
the Iittle girl wasn't hers.
And that pile of cash
you Iaid on her?
It's reimbursement
for expenses related to
the pregnancy and the birth.
I mean, it's how it's done.
And in your role
as humanitarian,
what's in it for you?
Well, Mr. Sanford receives
a modest fee for his services,
Iike any other attorney.
How much?
It's $20,000.
SORENSEN: He is not
in the business of buying
and selling children,
It's your call, Counselor.
Unless we can establish
he knew what AIicia was going
to do, kidnapping's a stretch.
Prove he sold Emma
and it's grand Iarceny.
Emma's a human being,
not stolen property. Grand
Iarceny's the best you can do?
We can hold Sanford
for six days
on the kidnapping charge.
You think you can
make a case by then?
We're searching his home
and office, seizing his files
and computers.
There must be something
in there that'II nail him.
If you two are done
surfing the Web...
Sanford's website.
"Happy Homes."
Listen to this.
"Laura, blue eyes.
A tiny bundle of Iove
to share with you."
Three marriages, no children.
You ever consider adopting?
The kindest thing
I could ever do
for a kid is not adopt.
What do you got on Sanford?
Born and raised in Brooklyn,
graduated Buffalo State
in '76,
Law School
of the Ozarks in '79,
admitted to the New York
State Bar in '85 and never
set foot in a courtroom.
Anything in his records?
MUNCH: We haven't
found the official
adoption papers yet,
but he kept this Iedger
of his transactions
for each year.
This one's 1989.
Baby boy born January 19th,
baby girls born on April 7th,
April 14th, April 23rd,
another baby boy, June 2nd.
John, give me
that Iast date again.
1989, June 2nd.
Where are these kids' names?
There's a page number
to the right of each entry.
Each page has
the pre-adoption stats
on every child.
CRAGEN: Page 42.
What's going on, Captain?
Stephen Talmadge.
Back in '89, a woman
named Jennifer Talmadge
was found murdered
in her apartment,
Iigature strangulation.
Her four-week-old son,
Stephen,
was missing from his crib.
Case is still open.
The murder
or the missing kid?
Both.
You didn't know Max Greevey.
He was my sergeant
when I ran the 27.
He caught the case,
worked it Iike his
own kid was missing,
until he was murdered
on the job in '91.
This thing's been kicking you
in the ass for a dozen years.
Stephen is still alive.
It's really gotten to you,
huh?
It's not just about Stephen.
Jennifer Talmadge's parents
call once a year
on his birthday
and ask if I had any news.
The calls stopped coming
three years ago.
I could use your help on this.
With all due respect,
Captain...
"I don't usually work cases"?
You're right.
This is different.
Oh, my Lord. Come in.
Herbert!
HERBERT: What is it?
It's Captain Cragen.
You have news?
There's been a development.
You found Stephen?
You caught Jennifer's killer?
There's a Iead.
That's all for now.
I thought the investigation
was on hold.
I thought you'd given up.
Come in, Captain.
Let us show you something.
We celebrate
Stephen's birthdays, buy him
presents every Christmas.
MARGARET: This is his room.
So you see, Captain.
We never Iost hope.
If your client
is willing to cooperate...
Where's Stephen Talmadge?
Who?
What, you forgot
to tell your new
hotshot Iawyer
you kidnapped a baby
after killing the mother?
What, are you crazy?
It's all right here
in your book.
We're willing to deal
in exchange for information.
No. You can't prove
that I kidnapped
or killed anybody.
Not now and not then. No.
Actually, we have specific...
The offer's good
for 10 more seconds.
You don't have a case.
CRAGEN: Oh, really?
After I tie you
to the Talmadge kidnapping
and murder,
I'm gonna nail your ass
to the wall.
(DOOR BUZZING)
What the hell was that?
Well, you weren't
getting him to talk,
so I had to give it a shot.
What?
With the macho cop routine?
I could have used
the kidnapping charge
as Ieverage
if you'd just given me
the chance.
I gave you your chance.
You Iost your cool.
You are too
emotionally invested
in this case.
Damn right.
I read all of Greevey's files.
He interviewed
a Iot of people who said
what a wonderful person
Jennifer Talmadge was.
Too bad none of them
can give us any Ieads
on her murder.
What about forensics?
Only one set of prints
at the murder scene
unaccounted for.
I ran them again,
no match in the system.
Try this.
What is it?
Max's notes. His widow, Marie,
gave them to me Iast night.
You are on a mission.
I've been on this
for 1 2 years.
I want some closure.
Where are we
on Sanford's other babies?
We talked to the couple
adopting the boy.
They're getting him tomorrow.
The baby girl
goes with her new parents
the day after that.
Both adoptions are Iegal?
According to ACS,
Sanford followed
all the rules.
Social worker sent
to do home studies,
the parents had to take
medical exams to rule out
Iife-threatening illnesses.
The birth mothers
and fathers all consented.
The papers were signed,
notarized, witnessed,
registered in court.
As far as we can tell,
there's no indication
he's put any other
snatched babies
up for adoption
besides Talmadge and Daricek.
So what's his scam?
Sanford's triple-dipping.
He promises one baby
to three different families,
then he tells two of
the families that the mother
changed her mind,
keeps the money.
How much?
$30,000 a couple.
And none of these victims
call the cops?
FIN: They're desperate.
They're afraid if they snitch
and word gets out,
no other baby brokers
will deal with them.
You get anywhere
on Sanford's files?
Found his phone bills
for 1989.
Phone company's
getting us the names
of all his outgoing calls.
These files are at Ieast
a three-person job.
This is interesting.
What's that?
Greevey has a note
in here about Jennifer's
college roommate, Rebecca.
Says he was supposed to
talk to her in England.
There's nothing
in the case file
that says they ever spoke.
Well, that means Max
never talked to her.
Let's track her down.
MUNCH:
Were you and Jennifer close?
In a college roommate
sort of way. We shared
a suite at the dorm.
Then you must have known
if she had any boyfriends.
Just one. Broke her heart.
Who was he?
A guy named Rob.
Met him at a party and,
you know,
they dated a couple of times
before she brought him
back to the suite
to stay over.
The first time I saw him,
I knew he was trouble.
Why?
Well, I warned Jen that I had
seen him walking on the campus
with another girl,
but, you know...
Jen, she was a Iittle naive.
She was in Iove with him,
you know,
I think he was her first.
MUNCH: How Iong
did they go out?
About two weeks
before he broke up with her.
He give a reason?
Guys never do.
Did you know
Jennifer was pregnant?
Not at first, but, you know,
she couldn't hide it for Iong.
She knew Rob
had to be the father.
What's Rob's Iast name?
Cook.
Robert Cook.
Any idea if she told him?
Yeah. She sent him a Ietter.
Thank you.
CRAGEN: Robert Cook?
Can I help you?
NYPD,
Captain Donald Cragen,
Detective John Munch.
Just be a second, boys.
It's the future of baseball.
Well, you know, for now
we're just trying to win
one Little League game.
But you didn't come here
to watch us play.
We're here about your son.
He's what? About 12?
The older one, Brandon, is,
but I don't understand.
Do you have
his birth certificate?
His mother's got it.
Where is she?
She's up in Mahopac,
we're recently divorced.
What the hell's going on here?
We're gonna have to ask you
and your son to come with us.
Excuse me?
I don't even know
what this is about.
Jennifer Talmadge.
From college?
She was murdered 12 years ago.
Yeah, I know that,
but what's that
got to do with me?
Her son disappeared.
We think you're the father.
I read about Jennifer
in the paper,
but I swear in a million years
I never thought
that child was mine.
We only slept together
a few times.
Sixth grade sex ed.
Once is enough.
So, you had a fling
with Jennifer,
and then you dumped her.
It was college.
My girlfriend Linda and I
were on the outs,
so I was dating Jennifer.
But you didn't count on
knocking her up.
Jennifer showing up with a kid
would've put a crimp in your
big plans for the future.
I broke up with her, I didn't
kill her. I didn't even know
she was pregnant.
Her roommate said
that Jennifer sent you
a Ietter.
I never got any Ietter.
Mr. Cook, can you prove
Brandon is your son
with your ex-wife?
Of course I can.
You think I killed Jennifer
and then somehow
adopted my own child?
I broke up with Jennifer
because Linda told me
she was pregnant.
We got married
as soon as the semester
was over.
Brandon is our son.
We're going to need DNA
from all three of you.
You have Brandon's
birth certificate.
Is this really necessary?
I'm only complying
with the court order,
Mrs. Cook.
Linda...
Don't.
If you kept it
in your pants...
We were kids...
And now we're
murder suspects.
This is not the time.
I resent being dragged
in here, having to prove
my son is my son.
Mrs. Cook, you're next.
LINDA: No. I want my attorney.
Your attorney
is going to tell you
if you don't comply,
we're gonna be ordered
to arrest you
for contempt of court.
I have plenty of contempt
for this. Make it quick.
Done?
Thank you
for your patience.
Let's get out of here.
Mitochondrial DNA
on Cook's 12-year-old
doesn't match
Jennifer Talmadge's mother.
Meaning he's not
Jennifer's son.
He is, however,
the son of Linda
and Robert Cook.
99.9 % probability.
Captain, you better
take a Iook at these.
Where'd you get this?
From what we found stored
in Mark Sanford's basement.
Why?
Stephen Talmadge's
adoption papers.
Signed by his mother.
It's not possible.
We have copies
of the adoption papers.
But Jennifer changed her mind.
At first she was ashamed.
You know, she thought we were,
too, but we said we would
support her financially.
We'd watch Stephen
during the day
so she could finish college.
May we see those papers,
please?
This isn't
Jennifer's signature.
Are you sure?
Yes.
Do we still have
Jennifer's passport.
Let me see.
Did Jennifer tell you
who the father was?
No. She said
she tried to contact him,
but he never responded.
Here. See for yourself.
It's not even close.
You think this has
anything to do
with Jennifer's murder?
That's what we're
gonna find out.
Thank you.
CRAGEN: Adoption papers.
Passport.
Signatures don't match.
You're screwed.
I didn't forge any papers,
I didn't steal any babies,
I didn't kill anyone.
You defraud couples
desperate for children.
When we present your scam
in court, a jury will convict
you of murder and kidnapping.
What's your offer?
No jail time,
he makes restitution to
all the couples he defrauded.
And you give me
Stephen Talmadge.
A woman came to me
with a baby,
purporting to be the mother.
She had the boy's original
birth certificate. I didn't
know she was an imposter
and then I saw
Jennifer Talmadge's picture
in the papers, and...
And you couldn't risk
going to the cops.
You give me the name
of the family
that adopted Stephen. Now.
DANIEL: Line drive into center
field. Looks Iike it's over
the second baseman's head.
But BIake makes
a brilliant catch,
ending up the game.
Hello?
Thanks, we don't want any.
It's the cops.
Mom, the police are here.
Oh, for heaven's sake, Tyler,
where are your manners?
Come in, Officers.
Danny, Brian, Tyler, outside.
Hey, you guys Iooking
for Tyler? The way he played
second base was a crime.
ERIN: How can I help you?
Mrs. BIake,
Captain Don Cragen,
Detective John Munch.
Is Tyler your son?
Yes, of course.
What's going on?
Did you adopt him
through Mark Sanford?
Yes. How did you know
he was adopted?
Was Tyler born
on June 2nd, 1989?
Why are you asking
all these questions?
Kidnapped?
Are you sure?
Sanford admitted
what happened.
A DNA test will confirm
he's Stephen Talmadge.
What am I gonna tell
my husband and Tyler?
Do you have to take him?
You can come with him.
We didn't do
anything wrong.
We know.
He's been missing
for 12 years.
Tyler.
I'm not going.
I don't wanna Ieave!
Go upstairs and get changed.
I'II call your dad at work.
We'II go together.
Hey, you're not in trouble.
Is it definite?
The DNA is conclusive,
Mr. Cook.
Tyler is your biological son.
How can I ever explain to him
what happened?
Why I wasn't there for him?
When the time is right,
you'II tell him the truth.
He's almost a teenager.
There's still plenty of time
for you to get to know him.
The family who raised him,
they did a good job,
didn't they?
Oh, he's had a good Iife,
wonderful mother and father.
I'm his father.
I never would have
abandoned him.
He belongs with me.
We fed him, we clothed him.
He's Iike our own flesh
and blood.
Mark Sanford told us
it was all Iegal.
Tyler's biological father
never consented
to the adoption.
That nullifies it.
For God's sake,
he's our son!
You can't just take him away
after all these years.
I know how hard
this must be for you...
We are the only parents
he has ever known.
We were a happy family
until you came along.
How could you do this to us?
We can't play Solomon
and split the child.
I can't get him into
a foster home
until tomorrow morning.
I hate to do it,
but I think Tyler's
gonna have to
spend the night
at the Laight Street Shelter.
Why put him in that hellhole
when his grandparents
have right of
natural guardianship?
I don't Iike it
any more than you do,
but the Iaw doesn't
give grandparents
automatic custody...
Just forget the Iaw
and just for one minute
think about
what's in the best interests
of this child!
Don't you think I am?
Right now everybody
wants a piece of Tyler.
Maybe the best place for him
is somewhere neutral.
Why don't you tell that
to his grandparents?
Right this way. Thank you.
You know how Iong we've waited
for this moment, Captain.
Our daughter was taken away,
and now you're telling us
that we can't have
our grandson?
I can't release Tyler to you
unless a judge says I can,
but you can apply
for temporary custody.
We have to go to court?
What about permanent custody?
Tyler's biological father
is probably going to claim
his parental rights,
and as Iong as
he's deemed fit,
his rights supersede yours.
His mother was our only child.
You gave us our hope back.
Now how can you just
take it away from us
Iike this?
So what happens to me?
Well, you'II have to go
to a temporary home
until a judge decides.
I wanna just go home
with my parents.
I know you do,
but your adoption was illegal.
So what?
They never hurt me
or did anything wrong.
They Iove me.
I know they do.
Tyler...
I'm sorry,
but what I did today
is my job.
I didn't want to take you,
but I had to
because the Iaw says so.
But the Iaw also says
that I have to protect you
from anything bad
and that's a part of my job
I Iike. Okay?
AII right.
Hey. Your mother's parents,
your grandparents,
they wanna meet you.
Are you ready?
I guess. Do I have to
hug them or anything?
Hey.
You just do
whatever you feel, all right?
Stephen.
My name is Tyler.
Nice to meet you,
Tyler.
PIease... PIease don't cry.
AII right.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Got a minute?
Only if you promise
not to tell me
you told me so.
You were just doing your job.
Following the Iead
of a 12-year-old crime.
And now Tyler BIake's
the victim and I don't know
how to fix it.
Then Iet me help.
You have any suggestions,
I'm all ears.
Tyler's going to need
a Iaw guardian
for the adoption hearing.
There's a three-week backlog
on court-appointed attorneys,
so I'II volunteer.
Well, that's a hell of a
gesture, AIex, but the Iaw
favors the biological parent.
The Iaw also says
that Tyler is old enough
and mature enough
to know who he
wants to Iive with.
If I'm his attorney,
I have to fight
for what he wants,
and he wants to Iive
with the BIakes.
Tyler is an articulate,
intelligent 12-year-old.
CABOT: You've talked to him,
you've read the reports.
What's your conclusion
about how Tyler functions
in his world?
That he's well-adjusted.
He gets excellent grades
and he has Iots of friends.
And what did this indicate
to you about his home Iife?
That Tyler is the child
of Ioving parents,
the product of a happy home.
CABOT: If Tyler was
forced to Iive
with his biological father,
how do you think
this would affect his Iife?
That would be akin to
waking up in the morning
and Iearning that his parents
had been killed
in a car crash.
A sudden traumatic Ioss.
CABOT: And what could be
the consequences?
Children that experience
a sudden Ioss
of a parent or caretaker
often suffer from
behavioral problems.
Not to mention the depression
that a child his age
often goes through
after something so traumatic.
In your opinion then, Doctor,
would you recommend
that Tyler be placed
with his biological father?
No.
That would be asking him
to make too huge a transition
at a time in his Iife
when he's the most vulnerable.
Thank you, Doctor.
Mr. Stern?
I have no questions.
This is Tyler's
first birthday.
We squeezed 100 people
into the house.
You've got
a Iot of pictures there.
Tyler's been the center
of our Iives
since the day we got him.
What kind of Iife
has he had with you?
We don't have a Iot of money,
but he doesn't want
for anything.
Especially our Iove.
We've tried to be
the best parents we can.
Mrs. BIake, did you know
12 years ago that
the adoption was not Iegal?
Did you know
about the death
of Tyler's mother?
Of course not.
We did everything
Mr. Sanford told us to do.
And now that you do know?
We're terrified that we're
going to Iose Tyler.
We can't imagine
being without him.
PIease,
don't punish our family
for someone else's crime.
Thank you.
I'm sorry for the tragedy
you and your husband
are going through right now.
And Tyler. He's been
our son all his Iife.
And you've done
a wonderful job raising him.
Thank you.
And can you imagine
how Mr. Cook feels then,
all these years he Iost
not knowing Tyler was his son?
Mr. Cook has other children.
Tyler is all we have.
Mrs. BIake,
if your child was Iost,
and a nice family took him in
and raised him well,
and then you found him,
wouldn't you want him back?
Yes.
I wasn't there to give Tyler
the Iove and attention
the BIakes did,
because I was robbed
of the chance.
You're recently divorced,
you already have two sons.
How can you convince
this court that you can
take care of a third child?
Just Iook at what I've done
with my sons.
Tyler would have
a brother his age,
a devoted father
who could more than
provide for him.
And he has his mother's
parents. I want them
to be a part of his Iife.
Mr. Cook, Tyler has grown up
with a mother and father
who Iove him.
Do you think his Iife
would improve
Iiving with you?
I know I am now
a single parent.
I wish it were different,
but Tyler
is my flesh and blood.
You've spent time with Tyler.
What do you think of the job
the BIakes have done
as parents?
Just as good as I
could've ever done.
Can you imagine, then,
what they must be
going through?
You can't imagine
how hard it is for me
to make them go through it.
You just finished
a bitter custody battle
with your ex-wife.
She was seeking full custody
of your two sons,
is that correct?
Yes.
Mr. Cook,
how would you have felt
if she'd won,
and you weren't able
to see your children
anytime you wanted?
It would've crushed me.
I'm sorry.
How's it going?
Ripping my guts out.
These are all good people.
We finished talking
to the birthmothers
who gave their babies
to Sanford for adoption.
AII Iegit.
If Sanford stole babies,
we can't find them.
Your faces tell me
there's more to this story.
His ex-wife, Linda Cook,
gave birth to her oldest son
at Long Island Jewish
a month before
Jennifer Talmadge
gave birth.
Linda's hospital roommate
was a client of Sanford's.
Says she recommended
Sanford to Linda.
STABLER: We compared
Jennifer's signature
on the adoption papers
to Linda Cook's signature
on the release forms
for her DNA.
Let's get Linda Cook in here.
LINDA: Robert and I
are divorced.
Whether he gets
to keep his Iove child
has nothing to do with me.
Why am I here?
CRAGEN: 12 years ago,
Jennifer Talmadge wrote
a Ietter to your husband
telling him
she was having his baby.
So?
Well, he never got it,
because you intercepted it.
That's how you found out
about Jennifer.
Is this some fantasy
you concocted?
When you gave birth
to your son,
why did you ask
your hospital roommate
about her adoption attorney?
I knew Rob was fooling around
on me. I didn't know he'd
ask me to marry him.
And when he did,
you realized it would
be better for everybody
if your husband didn't know
he had a Iove child.
Where are you
getting this from?
Jennifer's signature
on the adoption papers.
That's your handwriting.
You get the Ietter,
you go to see Jennifer.
Something happens.
She's dead.
And now you're gonna find
some place for the baby,
so you impersonate her
and you give Stephen
to Mark Sanford for adoption.
Now just tell me that you
didn't plan to kill her
and I can help you.
I want a Iawyer.
SERANI: Most of the children
who come through this court
have nobody who wants
or Ioves them.
This case is
so much more difficult,
because all the parties
have only acted
in the child's best interest.
Mr. Cook, it's clear
that you never intended
to abandon Tyler
and that you're
more than suitable
to make a home for him.
Mr. and Mrs. BIake,
you're Ioving,
excellent model parents,
an example to follow.
But the Iaw recognizes
the right of the
biological parent as paramount
as Iong as that parent
is deemed fit.
Therefore, I have no choice
but to award custody
of the child to Mr. Cook.
Mr. Cook, I urge you
in the strongest
possible terms
to continue to act
in Tyler's best interest
with regards to his
adoptive parents.
(GAVEL POUNDING)
We're adjourned.
Tyler.
We'II see you when you
come over to get your stuff,
okay, buddy?
Prosecuting's easier.
At Ieast then you know
who the bad guy is.
You okay?
They're talking. It's a start.