NARRATOR: In the criminal
justice system,
sexually based offenses
are considered
especially heinous,
In New York City,
the dedicated detectives
who investigate
these vicious felonies
are members
of an elite squad known
as the Special Victims Unit,
These are their stories,
Syd.
Oh, this isn't gonna work.
Oh, what...
What the hell are you doing?
If you want me to stay,
this is not gonna be...
Syd.
Oh, my God.
Where's Dr. Warner?
Melinda's at an ME conference,
so you're stuck with me
till the end of the week.
So what's on the menu
for today, Justin?
Looks Iike
autoerotic asphyxiation.
Sydney Green, early 30s.
Husband found her.
STABLER: And he is where?
He was flipping out.
So the unis drove him
to your precinct.
We cut her down?
Husband did.
Said he turned off
the music, too.
Dead how Iong?
Rigor was just setting,
so three, four hours tops.
Okay. Any fluids?
None apparent, but I don't
expect to find any.
Autoerotics Iike to fly solo.
Is that why you're Ieaning
toward accidental death?
Skin pics, plus the sex toys
and the mirror. It's a gimme.
But it's not official
till I cut her open.
Well, until then, Iet's work
it as a sexual homicide.
Female asphyxial deaths
are on the rise
across the country.
If that's what this one was.
I'II Iet you know.
No sign of a break-in
or a struggle.
The candles, the music,
that strikes me as
a seductive scene.
Maybe she wanted
to treat herself.
Most women don't go this far,
but they do Iike to
self-serve.
STABLER: I guess you want
something done right,
you gotta do it yourself.
How Iong has your wife
been asphyxiating?
No, that's crazy.
Look, Sydney had never done
anything Iike that before.
She's not that kind of person.
And how Iong were you married?
Six months.
We were having problems.
We decided to separate.
How Iong were you together
before you got married?
Just a few months.
That's quick.
That's why we separated.
Look, I...
It's only been a couple of
weeks. I just went over
to get a few things,
and that's when I found her
Iike that.
Where were you before that?
Working. I'm an artist.
I have a Ioft
over in AIphabet City.
And how come
you two weren't getting along?
Irreconcilable differences.
STABLER: What does that mean?
Cheating?
No.
Look, just 'cause two people
Iove each other doesn't mean
they can Iive together.
Why? Why are you asking me
these questions?
I mean,
somebody killed my wife.
Who wanted the divorce?
We hadn't decided to file,
but I wanted the separation.
We got married too fast.
So then it is possible
that your wife hid
her sexual practices from you.
Our sex Iife wasn't
the problem. When... Can I...
Do you know when
you'II release my wife's body?
We'II Iet you know.
Any alarm bells going off
on the husband?
Several.
He's hiding something.
Getting off while choking
isn't something you share
with friends and family.
People are always shocked
when they get
that kind of news.
I still think the victim
was entertaining.
She had a new man,
or hubby got there
earlier than he said.
Well, if she had a partner,
it's manslaughter,
whether the ME rules it
an accident or not.
Did the victim have
any visitors
besides the husband?
The visitors' Iog Iisted
a Pam Adler and Amelia Chase,
arrived around Iunchtime.
Pam Adler,
the criminal attorney?
Yeah. Rose, Adler & KIein.
She cross-examined me
on a drug bust
where a cop got killed.
Accused me
of police brutality.
Don't tell me the perp
went to the hospital.
Drug dealer's still alive,
the cop isn't.
We'II take the Iawyer since
Fin's got history.
Go.
It's terrible. Did she suffer?
STABLER: We really
can't answer that.
Were you two close friends?
Yes. We met at Vassar.
We had our whole Iives
ahead of us.
And now she's dead.
I just can't stop thinking
about her. First the divorce
and now this.
We heard it was
a trial separation.
Six-month-old marriage
and nothing but fights.
Sydney couldn't take it
anymore, so she called
an attorney I know.
Have you seen Sydney recently?
She was supposed to meet
Amelia and me for Iunch.
When she didn't show,
we went over to her apartment.
Sydney said that she
wanted to be alone,
but I think she had company.
What made you think that?
She had on a robe.
Candles were burning,
music was playing, and
the bedroom door was closed.
Do you have any idea
who might have been with her?
No. The divorce was hitting
her hard. She was depressed.
Andrew was no prize.
STABLER: You don't Iike him?
He's an artist
with questionable talent
who married a meal ticket.
They met on
a Caribbean vacation.
AIthough where
the Iittle bastard got
the money, I'II never know.
I at Ieast convinced Syd
to sign a prenup.
Is there anything else
that you can tell us
about her husband?
Is there something
I should know?
Are you thinking foul play?
Cause of death is still
pending so the Iaw says
we treat it as a homicide.
What you know about the Iaw
I could fit
in the palm of my hand.
How much was Mrs. Green worth?
I don't have a clue.
But call her divorce attorney,
he should have
a complete Iist of her assets.
Thanks for waiting. This was
sudden, just a tragedy.
What was Sydney Green's
financial status?
She made a killing
in junk bonds but Iost
her shirt in the tech market.
There's nothing Ieft?
Apartment's mortgaged,
Iife insurance
will cover her debts.
The husband
might clear 50 grand.
That's still a Iot of money.
In Manhattan? Don't kid me.
Would he have walked away
empty-handed
had your client Iived?
Absolutely. There was a prenup
and tax returns show
a Ioss after they married.
Was Andrew Green aware of his
wife's financial situation?
She handled the money,
so I don't see how.
Her secretary said
she should be done by now.
These day traders
Iive pretty good,
short hours, spa days.
What the hell
is she doing in there?
Beauty treatments take time.
Mud bath,
cellulite dissipation,
an exfoliating facial.
Time and money, some women
Iearn early how to waste both.
Your ex-wives made you bitter.
Not bitter, just resigned.
The receptionist said
the police
were Iooking for me.
You the detectives?
Yeah, we'd Iike to talk to you
about Sydney Green.
I still have
some errands to run.
Do you mind if we walk?
How well did you know her?
I met Sydney at OIdman.
She made a fortune in junk
and got out early.
Kept her toe in trading
for herself.
We remained friends, although
she was a Iittle too risque
for my taste.
Can you get more specific?
I'm not interested
in titillating you, Detective.
And we're not here
to carry your bags.
Just speak up and we're gone.
I don't understand.
I mean, when Pam gave me
the news, I just naturally
thought it was an accident.
Why would you assume that?
I mean, she Iived on the edge.
That's how she worked,
how she Iived,
a big risk-taker.
Was she an adrenaline junkie?
Nothing that extreme.
But, you know, she got a rush
from gambling,
risky stocks, kinky sex.
What kind of kinky sex?
Like Iooping ropes
around the neck.
Sick stuff Iike that.
I mean,
she even tried to sell me,
but I wasn't buying.
MUNCH: Doesn't sound Iike
you had much in common.
You know, in some ways
we were kindred spirits.
How so?
There aren't too many women
in our business.
And we both Iike
to make Iots of money
and show up the entitled men
while we were doing it.
Amelia Chase said
our victim was a choker.
Were they close enough for
such an intimate confidence?
Supposed to be kindred sisters
fighting male dominance
in the market.
Yeah. They were so close
she seemed real broken up
by her friend's death.
You think she or the Iawyer
had anything to do with it?
Last people to see her alive,
but what's the motive?
How does the husband Iook?
STABLER: Pretty strong.
He's got a negative
bank balance,
and his credit report shows
Iots of bad debt write-off.
The wife cut
the purse strings?
She may not have had a choice.
She was broke, too.
Why kill her?
Fifty grand's
better than nothing.
Would that cover his debt?
BENSON: And then some.
Have we heard
from the ME's office yet?
FIN: Not yet.
AII right, well,
Iet's get down to the morgue,
Iean on the Assistant ME.
We gotta know. Check with
Green's neighbors, all right?
Find out how he's Iiving.
If he still Iooks good,
bring him in
for a hard interview.
You were drowning in bills.
Did you kill her
for the money?
Money? There was no money.
We were broke.
But you stand to inherit
50 grand from her death.
That's plenty.
BENSON: You said
that she never choked.
You said that she wasn't
that kind of person.
But somebody else tells
a completely different story,
that she did it all the time.
Okay, which is it,
murder or accident?
Now, if she choked,
then you either knew about it
or you killed her outright.
In that case, you're gonna
do some time yourself.
Andrew, the system
will go a Iot easier on you
if it was an accident.
But you need
to tell us the truth.
We told everyone
we met on the islands,
but we really met in rehab.
We just didn't want
anybody to know.
STABLER: Which rehab facility?
NarcAnon.
Addiction to painkillers.
We already knew the worst
about each other.
I would've stood by her side
through anything.
If she would only come clean,
maybe she'd still be alive.
Came clean about what?
Sydney was using drugs again,
Iosing control.
She had a bachelor party,
and she and her friends
attacked the male stripper.
Was it reported to the police?
Yeah.
They were waiting for us on
our doorstep when we
returned from our honeymoon.
BENSON: How badly
was this guy hurt?
They raped him.
That's why we were fighting.
If somebody killed my wife,
it was probably him.
Excuse me.
Looking for Peter Smith.
Is this about...
Yeah.
I'm gonna take a break.
I won't be Iong.
So, did you find out the names
of the other women
who raped me?
Do you know a woman
named Sydney Green?
You know I do.
Have you been
in contact with her?
Have you seen her
since the alleged rape?
AIIeged?
No, I haven't seen her
or talked to her since she
and her friends attacked me.
You sure about that? I mean,
I show your photo around
and somebody from her building
IDs you, I'm not gonna
be so pleasant.
Listen,
you're not here to help me,
so what's this about?
Sydney Green is dead.
And you think I killed her?
You had a reason.
Cops treated me Iike dirt.
They made fun of me,
brought me to the hospital,
told the nurse it was a scam.
I've got reason to be angry,
but I didn't kill anyone.
We need an account
of your movements
two days ago.
I was at the animal shelter
until Iate evening.
Check with my supervisor.
Sydney Green's building
has security. If he did it,
how did he get in?
MUNCH: So, what's the verdict?
Autoerotic asphyxiation.
She tightened the rope
around her neck, Iike so,
and using an arm to support
her weight on the bed,
she Ieaned at a slight angle.
But she miscalculated,
Iost control and passed out.
Her body goes slack
and acts as a counterweight.
We call it
gentle strangulation.
That's comforting.
STABLER: We sure this is
an accidental death?
The Assistant ME's convinced.
He played it out
and it Iooked good to me.
We don't have a suspect.
Peter's alibi panned out.
No sign of a struggle.
No sign of a break-in.
Do you want this
to be a homicide?
I...
I don't know,
but something's off.
You can always take it up
with Warner when she gets back
from her conference,
since you got so much
free time.
Fine. Officially it's closed.
Not quite. We still have
an open rape case.
No.
I already talked to Cragen
who already spoke with Cabot,
and she'd Iike to see us
in her office, so, yeah.
STABLER: Was he drugged?
CABOT: He doesn't need to be.
Was there even a weapon?
None Iisted.
Happened at
the bachelorette party.
Mob attack isn't unheard of.
CABOT: Did the uniforms
follow up on
the suspect's complaint?
They asked a few questions,
and then they dropped it.
Because they didn't buy it
and neither do I.
And more importantly,
neither will a jury.
Well,
if the attack took place,
I'II make sure that they do.
First male rape victim
with female perps, that adds
up to a Iot of attention,
doesn't it, Counselor?
I am not interested in that.
He is the first man
to come forward.
The statute for rape one
was changed in January,
Detective.
What about his inability
to complete the act
against his will?
An erection is
a physical response, EIIiot.
If he was aroused,
he consented.
Well, the Iaw disagrees
with you.
So interview the victim
and get his statement.
Well, it was your predecessor
who declined to prosecute.
So maybe you should find out
why before we chase our tails.
The alleged victim,
Peter Smith,
works as a male stripper.
His shtick is dressing as
a motorcycle cop with a badge
covering the family jewels.
One of the party guests
took photos. Check the file.
So you decided
not to prosecute
because you disapprove
of the victim's profession?
Get off the soapbox, AIex.
The guy claimed three women
cuffed him to the bed
and had a party.
The bride claimed he was a pro
Iooking to score.
Did Peter Smith have
a solicitation history?
No.
Well, then why didn't you
pursue it?
I'm not wasting taxpayer money
on a no-win.
He just wasn't believable.
Even his Iive-in girlfriend
wasn't buying.
The defense calls her
as a witness,
there goes the case.
So the victim reports
the crime, and you just
Ieave him twisting.
If you want to jeopardize
your standing on
a flimsy trial, be my guest.
Okay. I need your notes.
Done.
You clear this with Villani?
I don't have to. Sex crimes
is my purview. See you.
Peter and I broke up
a Iong time ago,
and I wasn't at the party.
So what can I tell you?
We're just Iooking for some
background. That's all.
You don't believe Peter
was raped, do you?
Join the club.
What makes you think
that he wasn't?
He's a guy. Men don't
get raped by women.
Men can be victimized.
Sure.
When I first met Peter,
he was being kept by some
woman 12 years older than him.
She was paying for his tuition
at NYU Drama.
His parents are well off.
Why wouldn't they support him?
Because his father said
he wasn't gonna shell out
25 grand a year
for a drama degree.
Can't say I blame him.
What do you think your ex's
motive is for coming forward?
Attention. Peter cheated on me
with a casting director
to get a part in a play.
He'II do whatever it takes
to get ahead.
Making an accusation of rape
is pretty drastic,
don't you think?
It's not gonna be
easy for him.
The tabloids will pay
big money for the story.
Interviews on talk shows,
pundit commentary on
the evening news.
He probably thinks
it's worth it.
Doesn't prove anything,
EIIiot.
Except maybe we should
keep digging.
Why? Because she told you
what you wanted to hear?
It's not our job
to judge the victims.
That's up to the jury.
I can give you an assessment
of your rape victim,
but bear in mind,
I haven't examined him yet.
How did Peter Smith
Iet three women
get the better of him?
The guy works out.
He takes care of himself.
And yet you tell women
not to fight back.
That's different.
Why?
Because he's a man.
Because he's stronger.
He can overpower them.
Men are taught differently.
You know, "Oh, it hurts,
but don't cry. Be a man.
Internalize the pain."
Does the victim
have any siblings?
Three sisters.
There you go.
A Iifetime of instruction
on how to treat women.
Never hit a female.
No manhandling.
If you're angry, walk away.
Yeah, but if he felt trapped,
if they attacked him,
it's self-defense.
Why not just fight back?
Because he had no control
over the situation.
His self-esteem
and his pride were violated.
I wouldn't be surprised
if there were more
male victims out there.
Female rage
is a growth industry.
The price of equality.
STABLER:
Are you still a stripper?
No.
Not since the rape.
I used to book birthdays
and private parties.
It Ieft me free to audition
during the day.
BENSON: So you're an actor.
I gave it up.
Okay, so you show up
in your cop outfit.
Why don't you just run us
through what happened?
I got there Iate. There were
about 30 women or so,
pretty sauced and hungry
for entertainment.
I danced for them.
Did you have anything
to eat or drink?
Soda.
I asked the bride-to-be
for my payment.
She said to follow her,
the checkbook
was in her office.
Did you feel different
after that drink, you know,
Iike you'd been drugged?
Should I have been?
Do you need a reason
why this happened to me?
Why I wasn't man enough
to protect myself? Would
that make you feel better?
Peter.
What happened then?
We get to the room,
but it was dark.
She made her way to the desk
and turned the Iamp on.
It was a spare bedroom,
and two other women
were waiting.
Did they call
each other by name?
No. One of them had
a Ietter opener.
She tried to stab me.
The other two
were pulling me back.
They cuffed me to the bedpost.
I started yelling, but Sydney
turned the stereo on Ioud.
Then what?
They yanked my pants off
and tossed them.
Underwear, too.
I didn't want to,
but my body...
I can't explain it.
Arousal does not mean consent.
And rapists use the body's
response against the victims
to mess with their head,
to make them believe
that they were asking for it.
Does this type of thing happen
to women, too?
Yeah. It happens a Iot.
What about the other guests?
Where were they?
Still partying,
until Sydney Ieft the room.
I guess she cleared the place.
Did you ever say no?
I yelled it. I screamed it.
I even threatened
to go to the police.
One cold bitch said
that what I knew about the Iaw
wouldn't fit
in the palm of her hand.
Pam Adler was in that bedroom.
Which means Amelia Chase
is probably the third member
of this rape troika.
I'm not so sure
he's being entirely candid.
He was raped, EIIiot.
He's an actor. He's trained
to make us believe.
Three women at the same time,
most guys would
call that Iucky.
So we're saying that men
are sex hounds and only women
can feel violated?
That's gender bias.
Most women don't report rapes.
What's his angle?
We can't ask that question.
Wouldn't ask a female victim.
We question female victims
all the time.
CRAGEN: This pans out,
the press is gonna
feed on this guy Iike carrion.
And maybe that's the point.
Front page splash,
this guy's an instant star.
You think that he's doing this
for the fame?
Some people
will do anything for it.
CRAGEN: Doesn't matter.
He's a complaining witness.
So bring in Adler and Chase
and do a Iineup.
You can't come in here.
FIN:
Consider the market closed.
I can't talk now, Detectives.
But if you'd Iike to wait
in reception...
No. No. No. No.
Not you, KIaus.
Deutsch marks are up
three points. Will it hold?
We need you down
at the precinct, Miss Chase.
I'II call you back, KIaus.
When?
Now.
For what reason?
FIN: A Iineup.
Am I under arrest?
MUNCH:
Depends on what happens.
Then I'm not coming with you.
That's fine, but when
we come back to get you,
it's gonna be midday
on the trading-room floor.
Remember,
Iet me do all the talking.
Don't react to anything
that's being said about you.
Put your poker face on.
You got it?
Counselor, good afternoon.
I'm due in court,
so whatever it is
it's just gonna have to wait.
I don't think so.
What's this about?
Rape in the First Degree.
You're not serious.
Ask for a continuance.
If not, get Bob down here
to sit first chair.
Shall we?
Carolyn Maddox.
AIexandra Cabot
for the People.
So I've read.
People v, Hightower,
You Iost due to shaky evidence
and the inexperience
of a rookie.
Defense counsel of record
was Pamela Adler.
I hope this isn't petulance,
Counselor.
Your main concern should be
the Iineup, Miss Maddox.
Good.
You didn't jump for the bait.
I think you'II make
a formidable opponent.
Let's do it.
Number three.
BENSON: Are you sure?
Take your time.
"What I know about the Iaw,"
remember?
I'm positive, number three.
That's two for two.
Read Miss Adler her rights.
Looks Iike we're gonna be
famous. See you in court.
"File numbers 434, 546 and 47.
"Rape in the First Degree.
Sodomy in the First Degree.
"Unlawful Imprisonment
and Assault in the Third."
Is this accurate, Counselor?
I wouldn't waste
the court's time, Your Honor.
I'm not entirely sure
about that,
since you're trying to set
a very unusual precedent.
My sentiments exactly. Perhaps
someone's Iooking for ink.
Objection.
Save your strength,
Miss Cabot. You'II need it.
How do you plead?
Not guilty.
Are we severing?
Not at this time.
Any objection to recognizance?
None, Your Honor.
Next case.
I admit to having
intimate sexual relations
with the alleged victim,
a venal young man
who wants to be famous.
My only crime is being
a confident,
assertive professional
with a healthy
sexual appetite.
If Peter Smith succeeds,
it will only numb the public
to the real plight
of rape victims everywhere.
By the time she's through,
she'II have victims'
advocates,
feminists and enlightened men
burning you in effigy.
Thanks for the heads up.
This indictment's Iudicrous.
Your client can spin
all she wants. We both know
what happened that night.
The grand jury
believed the victim,
another jury will, too.
You're making a mockery
of women who are
preyed on by men.
They're the enemy,
not my client.
I guess I just heard
your closing argument.
There won't be a trial.
See you in chambers.
You wanted to see me?
AIex, it's a pretty
high-profile case.
You sure
you haven't bitten off
more than you can chew?
I don't think so.
But I guess since I've been
summoned here you don't agree.
Well, I have some doubts.
May I ask why?
Using a male stripper
in the first real test
of the rape statute
is not a very
judicious choice.
His profession is irrelevant.
Are you asking me
to dismiss the charges?
No.
But I hope you won't mind
if Stan sits first chair.
You say that as if
I had a choice.
Oh, come on. We'II tag team.
I just want you handling cross
on the female defendants
if they elect to testify.
I don't want to Iook Iike
Rick Lazio bullying Hillary.
You want me to run
for coffee, too,
or am I just the female
attorney by your side
for the cameras?
You're a highly skilled
attorney.
I have every faith
in your abilities.
But I'm still sitting
second chair.
You also have a personal
history with Pam Adler.
People will question
your motives.
I Iost an important case
to her once.
That does not mean
I have an agenda.
I don't Iike to play politics,
but we can't be naive.
If they find a way to use it,
they will.
Preemptive strike?
That, and just making sure
that our complaining witness
is protected
and represented
to the best of our ability.
We speak for him, so Iet's
keep our eye on the ball.
They want us to think
it's a motion to dismiss.
They're trying to challenge
the Iaw.
This is a deceptive
attempt by the defense
to argue constitutional Iaw
in front of you.
This should only be heard
in an appellate court.
I intend to prove merit
for dismissal.
The Iegislature saw fit
to change the Iaw
for political correctness.
The old rape statute said
that only a man can be charged
with Rape in the First.
That's gender bias.
People v, Liberta,
A bias pointed out by
a wife-raping convict
trying to get out on appeal.
Mr. Liberta did not win
that appeal and the only thing
the brief accomplished
was to force the Iegislature
to change the Iaw.
And they were so outraged
by the bias in the Iaw
that it took them 23 years
to do it. PIease.
Counselors?
It's still a constitutional
argument,
and it should only be heard
if Miss Maddox
Ioses the trial.
If it's all right with you,
I'II hear the argument anyway.
And trust me when I say,
be prepared,
be diligent and be very brief.
Rape is a violation of body
and mind, a violation that
comes through penetration.
Women can't rape men.
A woman can be prosecuted
for sodomy one by fellating
a man against his will.
She's not the penetrant,
but she's still guilty.
I contend that arousal
implies consent.
A physiological response
does not override a vocal,
"No."
Most men do not
maintain an erection
through fear, Counselor.
But some men do.
What do you propose,
a tumescence exam?
Save the wit for your friends,
Miss Cabot.
Medical studies document
that some female victims
experience arousal
during their attacks.
Rape is not about sex.
Rape is about violence,
and rape is about control.
No woman has ever
been brought to trial
under this charge
because we're the victims,
not the perpetrators.
It was not that Iong ago
that the court reacted
with disbelief
that a mother could murder
her own child.
Now she's the first person
we suspect.
Your Honor, women do not have
the anatomical equipment
to be equal to men
under this Iaw.
The Iaw makes no room
for selective equality
under the First Amendment.
Either women are equal to men,
or they aren't.
Motion to dismiss is denied.
So, this means we go to trial?
It's a minor victory.
Now comes the hard part.
It's already started.
I'm getting harassed.
Nasty phone calls.
Women following me,
shouting at me. Chased
by reporters and cameras.
Well, it's only
going to get worse,
because now the defense
has a chance to dig around
in your background,
poke holes in your story.
So anything
you want to change,
you'd better do now.
My father told me my private
Iife was inadmissible.
Putting the victim on trial
isn't allowed.
It isn't.
But I have to be honest
with you, there are ways
to get around it.
You seem very concerned.
Is there something
you haven't told me?
No.
Okay. Go home, get some rest.
Is there any way
I can get a ride?
I know the vultures
are waiting out there.
Yeah, I'II take care of it.
VILLANI: What time did
Peter Smith show up
at the party, Miss Guevere?
I can't be sure
after all this time.
But around 10:00, maybe.
What happened then?
He did his dance.
He was shaking his stuff
in our faces,
and we'd slide dollars
into his thong. It had
a big badge in the front.
Were the defendants
present at that time?
To be honest,
my attention was elsewhere.
So, when did you notice
their absence?
When poor Sydney came out
and told us all to Ieave.
To Ieave?
Why do you think she did that?
Objection. Speculation.
Sustained.
VILLANI: I'II rephrase.
Was this something
that Miss Green usually did?
I mean, did she usually
invite people over
and then put them out?
No, she'd had parties before
and never acted Iike that.
I thought it was rude
at the time,
but I needed to get home
and relieve the babysitter.
Nothing further.
I have no questions
for this witness.
VILLANI: So, how did
Pam Adler, Sydney Green
and Amelia Chase subdue you?
One of them had
a Ietter opener.
She tried to stab me.
I kept backing up.
I just thought
she'd had too much to drink.
So, did you try to subdue her?
Did you try to get the weapon?
I couldn't. By this time,
the other two
were pulling me back.
I still thought I was okay.
Women get a Iittle drunk,
blow off some steam away from
their husbands for a night.
I usually handle it
and shrug it off.
But this was different?
Objection, Ieading.
What happened to make
this time different
than all the other times
when you had Ieft a job
unscathed?
When they cuffed me
to the bedpost.
It was so quick.
Who cuffed you to the bedpost?
For the record, the witness
is pointing to the defendant,
Amelia Chase.
And nothing further.
Objection.
Approach.
I find an accused rapist
cross-examining
the victim repulsive.
Explain yourself.
Your Honor, Miss Adler
is a member of the bar
in good standing.
She's the co-counsel
of record,
and she's protected
by the constitution
to run her own defense.
This is an intimidation tactic
used to undermine the witness.
She is asking him
to relive the rape.
Objection, alleged rape.
It's an aggressive
psychological ploy.
That may very well
be the case, Mr. Villani,
but I don't have the power
to bar her from cross.
You take one step
over the Iine
and I will hold you
in contempt for the duration.
Step back.
Mr. Smith, do you go to a gym,
work out on a regular basis?
Objection, relevance.
My Iine of questioning
is within the scope.
I can clearly prove
that this man is more than
capable of protecting himself
from three women.
PETROVSKY: Sustained.
Move on, Counselor.
Mr. Smith, did you file
a civil suit for five million
dollars against Sydney Green?
Sir, don't Iook at them.
Look at me.
Did you file a civil suit?
Objection. Badgering.
PETER: I needed information.
ADLER: Yes or no?
That's not how it was.
Your Honor, please order
the witness to answer.
Sir, you have to answer
the question for the record.
Yes.
Defense exhibit, Your Honor.
A copy of the civil suit filed
by the alleged rape victim,
four months ago.
I didn't want money.
I wanted names.
Your Honor, I move
for immediate dismissal.
What went wrong?
Your suspicions
were confirmed, Detective.
We were blind-sided
by a civil suit
filed by our rape victim.
I'm sorry, Miss Cabot.
I didn't think it mattered.
Everything matters.
You jeopardized this trial.
What else did you Iie about?
Nothing.
Now why would anybody
believe that?
Why didn't you tell us
about the Iawsuit, Peter?
Detective Stabler's
been on my ass
from the very beginning,
Iooking for any reason
to drop it.
If I'd have told you
about the suit, he would've
said I just wanted money.
Well, isn't that what
this has been about all along,
a payday for you,
a Iittle media attention?
No. I wanted my
rapists' names. The cops
didn't treat me seriously.
How else was I supposed
to get the information?
If you'd won, you would've
received a monetary award.
If I won, the money
would have gone
to the animal shelter,
and my rapists' names
would've gone
on the public record.
That's very noble.
But I still don't see
how we're gonna prove
that your motives
are anything but venal.
What if we talk
to the civil attorney,
get some corroboration?
Can we put him on the stand?
This is just a spin.
What have you got
against me? I was raped.
Sydney Green
was coming forward.
What? Sydney Green called you?
My Iawyer. After you accused
me of killing her,
I called him.
He said Sydney had agreed
to give me the names,
but the death
nullified the suit.
So what did I do wrong?
Turns out Peter
was telling the truth.
The Iawyer said
he didn't want the money,
just the names.
Did he confirm Sydney Green's
compliance?
The day before her death,
she contacted the Iawyer
to set up a meeting.
STABLER: That's convenient.
BENSON:
Sounds Iike motive for murder.
Saves the trouble
of a high-profile trial,
maybe even a prison sentence.
I re-interviewed Andrew Green.
He didn't know
about the civil suit.
But Pam Adler had a copy
of it. How did she
even know it existed?
The record gets expunged
when abated by death,
so Adler had to have
a prior copy.
Sydney Green calls up
her friends, tells them she's
giving in, they kill her.
I thought the medical examiner
ruled the death accidental.
No harm in taking
a second Iook.
Justin's a good pathologist
but not very imaginative.
You find something?
Female autoerotics are rare,
so it's hard to rule
on cause of death.
Which is why the first
suspicion was homicide.
But in this case,
that's what it should've been.
What did he miss?
Most women don't use porn.
They fantasize.
AIso, autoeroticism is
habit-forming. If your victim
frequently choked herself,
where's her towel
or silk scarf, something
to keep the rope from chafing?
It's vanity. No way to explain
the ring around the collar.
Some women don't use a buffer,
so they'II wear a turtleneck
or a scarf, something
to hide the evidence.
Well, if she were strangled,
wouldn't there be some
evidence of a struggle,
damage to the body?
It didn't take Iong
for the victim
to succumbed to hypoxia.
And the ropes
were tied properly,
so whoever staged this
is a practicing autoerotic.
Okay. Well, Doc,
you wanna take a Iook
at the crime scene?
Sure.
So the phone dump
shows two calls,
one to each woman
the morning of the attack.
She gives them the news that
she's caving in to Peter's
demands to save her marriage.
They decide to kill her.
They come prepared.
Quickest way to do that is
a blitz attack right here,
not in the bedroom.
You be the victim.
Okay.
They say, "Come on, Sydney,
Iet's talk about this.
"There's gotta be another way
that we can handle this,
"so we can deal with it,
okay?"
AII right. You did say
there was no struggle.
Exert a Iittle pressure,
and anoxia would occur
almost immediately.
As soon as she's out cold,
they carry her
into the bedroom.
Truss her, string her to
the fan, and the hypoxia
takes care of the rest.
We're thinking they staged
the scene, candles,
music, sexy teddy?
Maybe they didn't have to.
She was waiting
for her husband.
A Iittle make-up sex.
Looping the ropes
would have taken some time.
Not if you know
what you're doing.
CSU didn't dust for prints.
Not the whole beam.
Just the area around the fan.
This better be good,
Miss Cabot.
It is.
Your client is under arrest
for the murder
of Sydney Green.
So Iet's horse trade.
Depends on what you have.
PIead out to murder two
and all current charges.
In exchange for her testimony
against Pam Adler,
I'II give 12 and a half
for the homicide,
7-to-15 for the rape.
Your generosity overwhelms me.
It's a good deal, Mr. Harper.
Your client would be
advised to take it.
What are you basing this on?
Miss Chase's prints were found
at the crime scene.
My client was a friend.
She's been to the apartment
several times.
Prints will never hold up.
The victim was strangled,
Mr. Harper.
Your client's prints
were found on the bedroom
ceiling above the bed.
We also searched her apartment
and found autoerotic
paraphernalia.
It's all circumstantial.
We're done here.
Ask your client
to remove the scarf
from around her neck.
Oh, now, please...
Stop.
Crunch your numbers again.
By the time I get out of
prison, I'II be eligible for
senior citizens' discounts.
If I take this to trial,
you'II get Iife.
Tell me about the rape.
Sydney was getting married.
Neither one of us
Iiked the guy.
He seemed beneath her.
So Sydney planned her own
shower, booked a male stripper
as entertainment.
CABOT: So Peter Smith
entertained the Iadies
and then what?
Pam pulled me aside,
said she'd worked out
an arrangement with the guy
for a private performance.
I thought, "What the hell?"
He was hot.
What happened then?
Pam and I went into
Sydney's office to wait.
After Peter followed
Mrs. Green into the bedroom,
what happened next?
We cuffed him to the bed
and raped him.
I got his keys out of his
pants pocket and released him
when we were done.
Pam threw some cash at him
and he Ieft.
Thank you. Nothing further.
Do you know
how the Iaw defines Rape
in the First Degree?
Sexual intercourse
through forcible compulsion.
And is it your testimony that
that's what happened?
That's correct?
Yes.
Three women raped a 6-foot,
170-pound man.
Is that what you did?
Yes.
Well, did any of you
have a gun, a knife,
a weapon of any kind at all?
Pam had been waving
a Ietter opener.
Well, was it sharp?
No.
Did my client say anything
to the stripper?
Did she give him orders?
No. She Iunged at him
a couple of times,
and he kept jumping back.
Who handcuffed him to the bed?
I did.
So you raped the stripper,
not my client. My client
paid for his services.
Objection.
Is there a question?
Sorry.
Did paying Mr. Smith
seem Iike the act of a rapist
or that of
a satisfied customer?
Objection.
Was it your testimony
that Miss Adler made
arrangements for Mr. Smith
to have a private performance?
That's what she said but...
And did you see her
give him money?
A simple yes or no will do.
Yes.
On the charge of Rape
in the First Degree,
how do you find the defendant?
Not guilty.
On the charge of Sodomy
in the First Degree?
Not guilty.
Unlawful imprisonment?
And Assault
in the Third Degree?
Guilty.
The defendant is free to go
until sentencing.
Court is adjourned.
Peter, I'm sorry
we didn't get them both.
One's better than none.
Congratulations, Counselor.
You put up a good fight, AIex.
Well, I didn't get the ruling
I wanted, but maybe next time.
(REPORTERS CHATTERING)
You're under arrest for
the murder of Sydney Green.
I'II beat this charge, too,
Counselor. Just watch me.
AII of your
courtroom knowledge
won't get you out of this one.
MAN: How did this happen?
Looks Iike next time's now.
Feel Iike bargaining
over a drink?
My best offer is 25.
Sixteen,
you can pick up the bar tab.
That's crazy.
She'd be out in 12.