NARRATOR: In the criminal
justice system,
sexually based offenses
are considered
especially heinous,
In New York City,
the dedicated detectives
who investigate
these vicious felonies
are members
of an elite squad known
as the Special Victims Unit,
These are their stories,
My wife didn't turn
the alarm on again.
TAYLOR: I never turn mine on
when I'm home.
Wow.
My entire apartment
would fit in here.
Original detail,
huge fireplace.
I have two more of those.
One in the den,
one in the master bedroom.
You should
turn this place
into your restaurant.
Can't be more elegant.
Well, you know,
that's all Jessie.
She's got the sense of style.
She's got an eye...
Jess?
Maybe she's out.
No. She had no plans to...
(JESSICA MOANING)
Jessica?
The phone's over there!
Dial 911!
TAYLOR: Oh, my God.
Honey, I'm here, Jess.
Victim is Jessica BIaine-Todd,
early 40s.
Husband and a friend
found her
raped and bludgeoned.
BIudgeoned with what?
Haven't found it, yet.
He was upstairs, too.
Drawers pulled out
everywhere,
closets emptied.
We're gonna be here
for a while.
Front door Iooks clean.
Come in through a window?
No sign of forced entry
anywhere in the house.
Was the alarm on?
TODD: No.
Not when I came in,
but there's a panic button
in every room.
We just had them installed.
I'm Jessica's husband,
Edwin Todd.
Detectives
Benson and Stabler,
Special Victims Unit.
Did your wife
say anything?
No. Nothing.
Just...
I found her moaning.
And you were with a friend
when you found her?
Yeah. My real estate guy.
We'd just put
a deposit on a space
for my new restaurant.
We went out to celebrate.
How's she doing?
Fractured skull,
drifting in and out
of consciousness.
We're trying to
get the pressure up.
Mrs. Todd,
I'm Detective Benson.
Can you tell me
what happened?
Isn't the sunset beautiful?
She's not
moving her right side,
and her speech is slurred.
BIows to the head
might've caused a stroke.
BP's stable. Let's go.
I'm right with you, Jess.
There's three fireplaces,
could've come through
the chimney.
Maybe we should be Iooking
for a guy in a red suit.
What's the prognosis?
Jessica is paralyzed
on her right side
and can't speak.
They say the next
48 hours are critical.
And are you
up for answering
any more questions?
Anything.
BENSON: Was the door closed
and Iocked when you came home?
Yes.
But Jessica always forgets
to turn on the alarm
when she's in the house.
Mr. Todd, aside from
you and your wife,
does anybody else
have access?
Our cleaning Iady, Katarina.
She knows the codes.
She has a spare set of keys.
As a matter of fact,
I just gave her a new set.
Why? Did she Iose hers?
No, no, no.
There's been
a string of break-ins
in the neighborhood.
That's why I upgraded
the alarm system
and changed the Iocks,
to prevent something
Iike this from happening.
Edwin Todd was right.
Six burglaries in the Iast
month in his neighborhood.
STABLER: Bad guys go
where the money is.
Any of these break-ins
turn violent?
This was the first.
Precinct squad says
their perp usually breaks in
through a window
or door though,
not Iike our guy.
Well, plenty of rapists
start out as burglars.
Maybe he's refining
his act.
No current burglaries
anywhere else in Manhattan
with Iast night's M.O.
Well, make sure we also
run down any old burglaries
where the perps
turned violent
and either made parole
or finished doing their time.
Any chance
she accidentally
Ieft the door open?
Can't.
It's on a spring Iock.
And it Iocks automatically.
What about the cleaning woman?
Her name's Katarina Dinov.
Naturalized from the Ukraine,
no rap sheet.
We're heading out to
talk to her right now.
Well, this started out
as a burglary.
The victim's husband
should know by now
if anything's missing.
Captain, you got a second?
CRAGEN: What's up, John?
Bad timing.
I got jury duty in an hour.
And you're
just telling me now?
Get your ass down there.
It's your civic duty,
John.
The Mayor can do it,
so can you.
I'II go with you to talk
to the cleaning Iady.
Thanks.
Jerry BIaine,
Jess's first husband,
was an investment banker.
He did a deal for me,
made me a Iot of money.
We stayed in touch.
You're not from here?
No, Seattle.
I couldn't make it
to Jerry's funeral,
so I made sure that
the next time I came
to town
I took Jessica
out to dinner.
That must have
been awkward for you
to see each other again
under the circumstances.
No, actually,
we'd never met.
But something hit
both of us that night.
You know, as if we had
known each other always.
I Iost my wife
three years ago to cancer.
Jessica understood exactly
what I was going through.
We married at
her summer house
on Martha's Vineyard
a year Iater.
Can you think of any reason
why someone would want to
hurt your wife?
No. Everybody Ioves her.
Are you missing something?
Yeah. Jessica's watch.
I can't remember if she was
wearing it when we found her.
BENSON: Well, where does
she usually keep it?
Right here
on the night table
when she goes to sleep.
The rest of the jewelry's
in the safe.
Not on the Iist of
what CSU sent to the Iab.
What kind of watch is it?
TODD: Rolex.
What's its value?
35,000.
It's horrible what happened
to Mrs. BIaine.
I thought her Iast name
was Todd.
I can't get used
to her new name.
Mr. BIaine was a Iovely man.
AIways took time
to ask me how I was.
They divorced?
He drowned on vacation
in the Bahamas two years ago.
When did Mr. Todd
come into the picture?
Not Iong after
Mr. BIaine died.
Sounds Iike you mean
not Iong enough.
When Mr. BIaine was alive,
I Iived in their house
five years,
but Mr. Todd made me move out
because he wanted his privacy.
You Iive with someone?
My boyfriend.
He got a name?
Andrei Gorsky.
CRAGEN:
Where was he Iast night?
He's a Iimo driver.
He worked until 4:00
in the morning.
I was at my neighbor's
waiting for him.
Andrei took my keys
by mistake.
I couldn't get in
until he came home.
Yesterday was my day off.
Let's see. Gorsky.
Nope, didn't work Iast night.
You sure?
He's not in the Iog,
he wasn't driving.
Well, does
he have a cell phone,
someway we can find him?
Yeah.
He's the one vacuuming
out his car in the back,
just about to go on shift.
Hey, Gorsky!
You got visitors!
Can we talk to you
for a minute?
Don't even think about it.
Must've been
something we said.
That any way
to treat company?
Where were you Iast night?
This is a free country.
I go where I please.
You know the people
Katarina works for?
Mr. and Mrs. Todd?
Well, I drive them
to the airport.
So you've been
to their house.
How much you get
for the Rolex?
Oh, I don't know
what you're talking about.
Sure you do.
You had Katarina's keys.
You went to
the Upper East Side,
you took Mrs. Todd's watch,
and you raped her.
Rape?
I didn't rape anybody,
and I didn't steal a watch.
I forgot I had Katarina's
keys, man. This is crazy.
And it's the Iast chance
you get to tell us the truth.
Where were you Iast night?
With someone.
Well, you told Katarina
you were working.
Well, I was with
my other girlfriend.
Is she gonna verify that?
'Cause you really don't
want to waste my time.
I'II give you
her phone number.
CRAGEN:
If you didn't do anything,
Andrei, why'd you try to run?
Let me see your green card.
I don't have one.
FIN:
How'd you get in the country?
Student visa,
three years ago.
CRAGEN: And instead of
going to school,
you went to work.
You better kiss
your two girlfriends goodbye.
Immigration's cracking down
on cats Iike you.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
(GROANS)
If I give you information,
can I stay?
We'II tell INS
you cooperated,
if we Iike what we hear.
Mrs. Todd,
Katarina heard her
fight with her husband
the day before it happened.
Mr. Todd,
how have you and your
wife been getting along?
Fine.
We heard you had
a Iittle fight.
Oh,
Katarina must have told you.
The Iast few weeks,
I have spent so much time
Iooking for the right Iocation
for this restaurant,
interviewing managers,
vendors.
I told her that
as soon as we got
this place up and running,
we would have more
time for each other,
and she understood.
Yeah, we have to
ask you this question.
Were you and your wife
intimate before the attack?
The night before. Why?
We'd Iike you to agree
to a simple DNA test.
Oh, is the husband
always a suspect?
It's so the Iab
can differentiate
your residual DNA
from the attacker's.
The test is really
for your protection.
You just tell me
where and when.
(RINGING)
Excuse me.
Hello?
It's nice to know
I'm not the only one
catching grief
for working all the time.
Thank God.
Your wife?
It was the hospital.
She's conscious.
Excuse me.
STABLER: Can she talk?
TODD: No.
But the hospital
gave us a dry erase board
so she could
write everything down.
BENSON: Mrs. Todd,
do you remember me
from the night of
your attack?
(MOANING)
STABLER: We're the police.
Is there anything you can
remember about what happened?
TODD: "Put on robe"'
"Thought Ed"'
You thought I was home?
Why, Mrs. Todd?
What made you think
your husband was home?
TODD: "Heard"'
"Heard key in door"'
She heard the key
in the door.
TREVOR: The only way to
tell if a Iock's been picked
is if the perp forgot to
turn the cylinder back.
The Todd's front doorknob
Iocks automatically
when the door closes.
STABLER:
So there's no way to tell.
If it was picked,
your guy's a pro.
No help there.
This should be.
Computer came up
with a match on the DNA
we found in Jessica Todd.
We have a suspect?
Another victim.
Rape-burglary two weeks ago,
Brooklyn Heights.
My wife told the other
detectives everything.
STABLER: We're sorry to make
you go through this again,
Mrs. Johansen,
but whoever attacked you
Ieft another victim
in Manhattan unable
to walk or talk.
Anything you can remember
might help us get this guy
off the street.
Curtis was out of town.
A merger meeting
in Saint Louis.
I was in the bedroom reading
when I heard a noise.
I Iooked up
and there was a man
standing in the door.
It says on the report that
you couldn't describe him.
I told the detectives
I didn't see his face.
He was wearing
a stocking over his head.
BENSON: Do you remember
what else he was wearing?
Regular clothes.
Jeans, maybe sneakers.
And gloves.
Did he say anything?
When I started to scream,
he put a gun to my head,
and he...
He told me he'd kill me
if I didn't stop.
There was no emotion
in his voice.
He just told me to
take off my clothes.
Then he...
He didn't say another word.
When he was done,
he went out the front door.
And he in no way
tried to hit you?
Isn't what he did to me
enough?
Mrs. Johansen, think hard.
Are you sure that you
didn't hear him come in?
No.
STABLER:
You told the other detectives
the attacker stole
a diamond bracelet worth
$100,000. Is that accurate?
Two-carat stones
all the way around.
I had it made for Denise.
I just gave it to her
for our six-month anniversary.
Mrs. Johansen, is it possible
you Ieft the front door
unlocked or open?
Our security system chirps
if the door is Ieft open
for more than 30 seconds.
And the new doorknob
Iocks automatically.
New doorknob?
We had the Iocks replaced
about a month ago.
I Iost my keys.
We didn't want
to take any chances.
STABLER: Do you have
the name of that Iocksmith?
Parks Safe and Security,
Manhattan.
I checked the computer.
We did both jobs.
Same Iocksmith?
Yeah, Danny Ryan,
he's one of my best.
What is this about?
Are all your
employees bonded?
Yeah. Fingerprints and
thorough background checks.
The whole works.
You wanna tell me
what's going on here?
It's just part of
an investigation.
Where could we find Ryan
right now?
Well, he's out on a job.
58 and Broadway.
Monday night?
I was studying
in the Iibrary
at the Jefferson College
of Criminal Justice.
You coming to
the Police Department?
Actually,
I'm shooting for Iaw school.
I'm a Iocksmith
during the day,
go to school at night.
Anybody see you
cracking the books
in the Iibrary?
The woman at the front desk
when I showed her my ID.
I didn't talk to anybody.
I mean, I go there
to study, not socialize.
How about two weeks ago
Iast night?
Are you kidding me?
I can't even remember
what I had for breakfast
this morning.
What do you say
you try a Iittle harder?
Look, any one of us
would be crazy to break
into a customer's house.
I mean, they checked me
out for criminal record,
bad credit,
everything, before
they Iet me do this job.
Look, I put the Iocks
into those two brownstones,
but I never went back.
The DNA on Edwin Todd is in.
He's clear. It's not a match.
What about Ryan?
No rap sheet,
not even a speeding ticket.
Benson.
We canvassed the Iibrary
at Jefferson.
Guard doesn't remember Ryan
checking in Monday night.
Maybe that's
because the Iab
just found his prints
at both the Todd
and Johansen crime scenes.
That doesn't help us unless
they found them somewhere
other than the front door.
Yeah, how about
both front doors,
plus the Todd's kitchen
and the Johansen's bedroom?
Go pick him up.
I told you,
I don't wear rubber gloves
when I install Iocks.
Of course my prints
were in both houses.
BENSON: Denise Johansen
was raped in her bedroom.
Your prints were also
found in her bedroom.
That's a Iong way
from the front door, Danny.
The place in Brooklyn Heights?
The Iady asked me
to take a Iook
at the Iockset
in the master bath.
Said it was sticking.
I fixed it for her.
Guy Iike you, good-Iooking
women alone in their houses,
they must come on to you
all the time, right?
It happens,
but I'm not into that.
She make a move on you?
I'm telling you, no.
I didn't make a move on her,
either.
BENSON: Well, what about
when you did the Todd's house?
Hey, she wasn't even there!
Just the husband was home.
She was raped
and nearly beaten
to death in her kitchen.
Again, your prints
found all over the place.
Were you fixing
a Iock in there, too?
I was thirsty.
I asked for a glass of water.
I had it in the kitchen.
Just ask him.
You can count on that.
Now, what did you do
with the Rolex
and the diamond bracelet
you stole from those houses?
Hey, I don't know
what you're talking about.
But I swear,
I didn't rape
or beat anybody.
I'm trying to
become a Iawyer.
Why would I ruin my Iife?
He'd make a good Iawyer.
He's got an answer
for everything.
I wish it was that easy.
We're bringing
the victims in
for a Iineup.
Cancel it.
Why?
Neither of them saw
their attackers' faces.
We've heard that before.
Then they come in,
Iook at the Iineup
and remember
more than they thought.
And when the victims
can't ID Ryan
and we take him to trial,
it's exculpatory evidence
and he walks.
Well, he's gonna walk
a Iot sooner
if we don't come up
with a reason to hold him.
Jessica Todd
barely survived.
His next victim
may not be so Iucky.
Fingerprints should be
enough to get warrants
for Ryan's DNA
and his apartment.
STABLER:
No watch or bracelet.
That was a waste of time.
If Ryan fenced that jewelry,
you couldn't tell
from that dump.
No keys. No mask.
And he doesn't
have a car.
Where else could he be
hiding that stash?
You're wrong about Ryan.
I told those
other detectives,
he's a good kid.
So help us clear him.
This is unit three.
This is the one
he drives.
Is this his alone?
Well, 8:00 to 4:00.
Two other guys drive it.
4:00 to midnight,
and graveyard shift.
Are you sure
you wanna do this?
Yeah. We need you to
sign this affidavit
giving us permission
to search the vehicle.
Yeah. Knock yourselves out.
You're not gonna
find anything.
Great. Thank you.
I'II take the front.
STABLER: Here we go.
BENSON: What you got?
Ryan's toolbox.
Find anything inside?
Tools.
Good. Well,
I've got coffee cups,
candy wrappers,
half-eaten sandwich.
They should
really think about
cleaning this place out
once every two years.
OIivia.
What?
Panty hose.
That's not something
you install a Iock with.
Neither are these.
CLERK: "Number 423154:
People v, Daniel Ryan,
"Two counts Rape
in the First Degree.
"One count Attempted Murder
in the Second Degree.
"Two counts Grand Larceny"'
The defendant's plea,
Miss Emerson?
Not guilty.
I'II take that to mean
on all charges.
What can I do
for the People today?
Given the violent nature
of the crimes,
we request the defendant
be remanded without bail.
JUDGE: This isn't
a murder case, Miss Cabot.
One of the victims
may not walk or talk
normally again
because of the beating
she took from Mr. Ryan.
My client has no previous
criminal history, Judge.
He's not a flight risk.
CABOT: Mr. Ryan
installed the Iocks
on both of the homes
of the victims
and made duplicate keys.
There could be
more keys out there
that we don't know about.
He is a risk on the street.
It's his first offense
so I'm not going to remand,
but I agree with you.
Bail is set at $500,000,
cash only.
Ten minute break
until the next case.
Half a million?
I can barely make my tuition.
Don't worry, I'II have
you out by tomorrow.
That's optimistic.
Your detectives
blew their search.
Not Iikely.
They had permission.
From the wrong person.
So he bought the tools
and toolbox himself.
I don't see the problem.
People v, Cacioppo,
Your Honor.
Mr. Ryan Iacks the standing
to make the motion
because he Ieft
his belongings
in a vehicle
belonging to
someone else.
With whom he had
a business relationship.
People v, Laws,
My client's work ID badge
was clipped
to the toolbox handle,
and the police
should have checked
whether the toolbox
belonged to him.
Sounds Iike the police
acted in good faith.
Your Honor,
if I get permission
from the owner of a company
to search an employee's
office,
I still can't
open up a Iocked desk
even if that desk
is company property.
A vehicle is different.
People v, Keegan,
Put your personal property
in someone else's car
without a precaution
to safeguard it,
there is no reasonable
expectation of privacy.
Miss Emerson,
if your client had put
a $5 Iock on his toolbox,
we'd be out of here.
There were no exigent
circumstances.
What would
have been the harm
if the police had come
to Your Honor
and asked
for a search warrant
before they opened
Mr. Ryan's personal property?
Miss Cabot?
We had ample probable cause
for a warrant.
Which I never had
the chance to scrutinize.
Your Honor...
I'm going to err
on the side of caution.
The evidence inside
the toolbox is out.
Why didn't anyone call me?
To tell you that
we had permission
to search the van?
Would you have stopped us?
CRAGEN: Let's stop
throwing blame around.
We got screwed
by Iegal maneuvering.
We still have
Ryan's fingerprints
and his DNA is not back yet.
Anyone besides me
got a problem
with any of this?
CRAGEN: What are you saying?
Well, those Iocksmith vans
run 24 hours a day.
Why would Ryan put
$135,000 worth of jewelry
in a place he knew
someone else could
find it?
'Cause it wasn't Ryan.
DNA?
FIN: Report's back.
It's not his.
He didn't rape Jessica Todd,
Denise Johansen
or anybody else.
Which means someone went to
a hell of a Iot of trouble
to set him up.
Maybe whoever planted
the evidence Ieft prints
on Ryan's toolbox.
AIong with the other two men
who drive the truck
and God knows who else.
Same problem.
Well, I think
it's worth a shot.
How fast can you
spring Ryan?
I can have him in court
by tomorrow morning.
Toolbox is
still in our custody
at the property clerk.
We need the Iab to dust it
and everything inside
for prints.
Be sure you get Ryan's
permission this time.
No way.
I wouldn't even be in here
if it weren't for you people.
We're gonna have you
out of here within the hour.
I don't believe you.
Look, man,
somebody set you up.
We busted you, which means
we got set up, too.
Don't you
want to find out
who did this to you?
FIN:
Anybody got a beef with you?
Work, friends, family?
No.
I mind my own business.
Anybody at work
talk about Ieaving,
going on to something else,
maybe coming into some money?
Most of the guys are Iifers.
Only one talking
about getting out is me.
I give you permission
for the toolbox,
you'II find out
who wanted me in here?
It may be the only way.
We found dozens of prints,
inside and out.
The ones that
aren't Ryan's match
seven other
bonded employees
of Parks Safe and Security.
The judge is never gonna give
us warrants for all their DNA.
You may not need it.
Let me show you something.
STABLER:
Where's the partial from?
One of the diamonds
on Denise Johansen's
bracelet.
You found a surface
big enough to hold
a print?
Those are two-carat diamonds,
not enough surface
for a 10-point print,
but I put the partial
into the computer,
it spit out
a six-point match.
Ed Todd's prints are on
Denise Johansen's bracelet.
There's no way
Ed could've handled it
unless he knows the perp.
Son of a bitch
must've hired someone
to rape Denise
and his own wife.
But a hired gun isn't
gonna be careless enough
to Ieave his DNA behind
unless it's window dressing.
Well, Iet's say
this hired gun rapes
Denise then Jessica.
Now, he doesn't hit Denise,
but he beats Jessica
nearly to death.
I mean, come on,
Ed Todd wants his wife dead.
But not Denise,
she doesn't have a scratch,
which means
Denise has to be in on it.
FIN: And the two of them
set up the Iocksmith
as fall guy.
Attractive woman
in her 30s Iike Denise
marries a 67-year-old CEO,
it's gotta be for his money.
Why hook up with Todd?
Well, Denise figures
that she and Todd,
they kill Jessica,
she's gonna get rich
a hell of a Iot faster
than waiting for
Curtis Johansen to die.
And Todd probably thinks
he wiped that bracelet clean.
Let's test him.
It's not the Iocksmith?
His DNA wasn't a match.
He's still out there.
Well, couldn't it
be somebody else
from the Iocksmith company?
Yeah,
we're checking into that.
Do you remember touching
Ryan's toolbox?
(COUGHING)
Here, sweetie.
The Iocksmith took
a bathroom break,
and I borrowed
his screwdriver
to tighten one of
the kitchen cabinet doors.
Aside from the bathroom
and the entry foyer,
was Ryan in any other
part of your house?
No. Not that I remember.
Why are you asking
these questions?
Because they have to, honey.
That's their job.
I am so sorry, but she had
a rough morning in rehab.
We won't take up
any more of your time.
Sorry to bother you.
Now, did I see Todd blink
when I asked him about
that toolbox?
Spooked him enough
to make him admit
that he touched it.
And now he's saying Ryan
went to the bathroom.
This guy
is telling so many Iies,
he can't keep them straight.
I wonder which one
he told Jessica
to get his hands
on her fortune.
Let's check out
the source of the money.
Jerry's estate was worth
about 10 million.
He Ieft every cent
to Jessica.
She was the Iove
of his Iife.
She still have it?
AII but 2.5 million.
We just sold off
some stock for her.
With the market
as Iow as it is now,
she must have taken a bath.
Believe me, I tried
to talk her out of it.
Especially when she said
that she was investing
in her husband's
new restaurant.
Yeah, now,
is it such a bad risk
with someone Iike Ed Todd?
I mean,
he does have experience.
Had a Iot of experience.
Todd came to us
about two years ago
Iooking to sell
his restaurant group
in Washington State.
Jerry handled the deal.
Todd said that
Mr. BIaine made him
quite a bit of money.
After our cut,
about $35 million.
I'm surprised
that he would want to
get back into the business.
Especially here.
Why is that?
The city's economy
after September 11,
you would have to
have Emeril himself
running the place
in order to break even.
And besides,
a guy Todd's age,
with his money,
he should spend
his days playing golf.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
What's up?
We just spoke to Ed Todd.
The real Edwin Todd.
AIive and well?
STABLER:
Seventy-two years young,
enjoying his retirement
in his mansion
on Puget Sound
just outside Seattle.
Hasn't been to New York
since the mid-'80s.
And he isn't married
to Jessica.
I just talked to CSU.
They say somebody SIim-Jimmed
open the driver's side door
of Ryan's van.
Checking for prints now.
That's not gonna help us
with the phony Edwin Todd.
Ran that partial
from the bracelet,
both State and Federal,
no hits.
Todd has two bank accounts.
One personal,
one for his company,
Culinary Equities.
Combined balances,
148,000 and change.
Well,
that doesn't sound Iike
enough to open a coffee shop,
Iet alone
a high-end restaurant.
Well, he had more,
but not much more.
Todd paid first
and Iast months' rent,
plus two months'
security for the space.
Total, 40,000.
AIso wrote another
160,000 in checks
to vendors, food,
restaurant equipment,
furniture.
Problem is,
we've been trying
to call these vendors.
We can't find them.
And Jessica Todd's account?
She deposited the 2.5 million
from her stock sale Iast week.
Then put a check
for $200,000 to
Culinary Equities.
Explains why fake Todd
hasn't taken off.
He doesn't have
all the money in.
Is there any
solid connection between
him and Denise Johansen?
Well, Todd made
cell phone calls to
an apartment in the Village.
The same Village number
was dialed regularly
from a pay phone
right down the block from
where the Johansen's Iive.
Fin and I will
check out the apartment.
You two pay Mrs. Todd a visit.
I think it's time
she got a reality check.
JESSICA: Well,
Edwin's been wonderful.
He's spent
almost all his time
here since this happened.
(CLEARING THROAT)
I don't know
how he's going to open
his restaurant on schedule.
And how much money have
you given your husband
so far for the restaurant?
$200,000.
Did he say when he needs
the rest of the money?
Next week.
What are you getting at?
Mrs. Todd,
we believe your husband
has been planning
for some time now
(SIGHING)
to steal your money.
We checked his bank accounts.
The money you gave him
is gone.
Well, of course it is.
He had to pay his vendors.
Those checks were written
to dummy companies.
They don't exist.
I don't believe you.
Does your husband have access
to any more of your money?
When I die, he's the sole
beneficiary of my will.
STABLER:
When did you sign that will?
Two weeks ago.
BENSON:
Before you were attacked.
Was it your husband's idea?
No.
It was mine.
So, you see,
you're wrong about Edwin.
How much will he get?
Everything.
My entire estate.
Mrs. Todd, your husband
sent someone to kill you
for your money.
How can that be?
I can't take care of myself.
Edwin's waiting on me
hand and foot.
He's changed my diaper.
He wouldn't do that
if he didn't Iove me.
CRAGEN: You recognize them?
Sure, Mr. and Mrs. Brown, 3B.
Seen the Browns
around Iately?
Nope, but that doesn't
mean anything.
They keep weird hours.
Salespeople, you know,
always on the road.
Yeah. Thank you.
So what's the plan, Captain?
Call CSU for a search team.
Make sure they send
a print tech
and the Photo Unit.
I'II get Cabot
started on a warrant.
Nothing in here.
Anything in the bedroom?
The closet and the dresser
are both empty.
Some Iadies' thongs
in the bed sheets.
Wait a minute.
What you got?
Looks Iike the Browns
forgot something.
Canada West boarding pass
to Winnipeg,
name of Edwin Todd.
Dated Iast week.
That's just before
Jessica was attacked.
Let's call the Winnipeg
police.
See if they can
help us find out
what Todd was doing there.
Talked to the airlines.
Todd, or whatever his name is,
took three trips to Winnipeg
in the two weeks
before Jessica
was attacked.
If he had a record
in Canada,
explains why
we couldn't get
a hit on his prints.
Call CSU,
have them overnight
all the prints we found
in the apartment
to the Royal Canadian
Mounted Police.
Hey, we might get Iucky.
We still got a problem
with the DNA.
It's not Ryan or Todd's.
If Denise faked
being attacked,
how did she have
the DNA in her
that showed up
on the rape kit?
By having sex
with her husband.
STABLER: She takes
the rest of his semen,
plants it on Jessica,
makes it Iook Iike
the same guy raped them both.
Talk to Curtis Johansen.
You want me to
take a DNA test?
I feel Iike I should
be calling my attorney.
You're not a suspect,
Mr. Johansen.
In fact,
you might be a victim.
I think you better tell me
what's going on here.
Okay, before you Ieft
for your trip,
were you and your wife
intimate?
Sex is not Iacking
in our marriage,
Detective.
Is this necessary?
I'm afraid it is, yes.
That afternoon.
Denise called me
and told me
she had a romantic
send-off planned,
that I should come home early.
When I got to the house,
we made Iove.
What does any of this have
to do with her being raped?
Your wife reported the rape
right after you Ieft,
Mr. Johansen.
We think that she faked it.
Why in the hell
would she do that?
To cover up a crime.
She planted your semen
on the other victim
after almost
beating her to death.
I don't believe any of this.
What proof do you have?
STABLER: Well, your DNA test
will tell us for sure.
She knew that
we wouldn't Iook
at you as a suspect
because
you were out of town.
My God.
She set me up? Why?
She's hooked up with a man
who calls himself Ed Todd.
The restaurateur?
Yes, do you know him?
Do I know him?
I've committed $250,000
to his restaurant project.
Denise's idea.
That's their game,
Mr. Johansen.
They want to steal your money.
I don't go into
a business venture
half-cocked.
I've seen the Iocation.
I've been over
the business plan,
met most of the other
investors,
including Todd's wife.
The other rape victim.
STABLER: Labs are back.
BENSON: It's Curtis Johansen's
DNA in both women.
So Jessica was signing
her own death sentence
when she made out that will
Ieaving everything to Todd.
We gotta pick him and Denise
up before they carry it out.
You know that's a problem.
That partial print proves
this is Todd all the way.
Proves it to us.
It's only
six points of similarity.
It's useless in court.
Well, this won't be.
RCMP came through.
Todd's real name
is Edward Crandall,
formerly of Toronto.
Did three years in Kingston
Penitentiary for fraud.
What about Denise?
CRAGEN:
Real name is Denise Cormier,
born in Quebec,
arrested with Crandall
and did her time
in Maplehurst.
Where do Jessica and Curtis
stand on cooperating?
Johansen is on board.
Jessica won't believe it.
Well, we're gonna
have to change her mind.
JESSICA: What's this?
What are you showing me?
Your husband.
He has a prison record
in Canada for fraud.
You're trying to trick me.
Sorry, Mrs. Todd,
but it's the truth.
This woman
is his partner.
We think she attacked you,
staged your rape and her own.
Take me back to the hospital.
I don't want to
talk about this anymore.
You should see these first.
What's this place?
They share an apartment
together in the Village.
Both of their prints
were found there.
Edwin's been so good for me.
I trusted him.
I never thought
I'd get married again,
and then Edwin came along.
Then a few months
after Jerry died,
Edwin called,
said he was in town,
asked if he might
take me out to dinner.
Well, he said
all the right things.
Told me I was beautiful,
Jerry was a Iucky man.
He said
he knew he could
never take Jerry's place.
Oh, but I'd already begun
to fall in Iove with him.
And when he asked me
to marry him,
I said yes.
Mrs. Todd,
if you help us,
we will make him
pay for this.
I can't.
Why not?
Edwin confessed to me
Iast night.
He told me everything,
the whole scheme.
He asked me to forgive him,
and I did.
Edwin and his partner
put you in that wheelchair.
JESSICA: He never
meant for this to happen.
He admitted he had had
an affair with that woman,
but he said it was over.
He said she beat me
out of jealousy.
Mrs. Todd,
they're in this together.
This is not about jealousy.
This is not about Iove.
This is about
stealing your money.
And if you don't help us,
they're gonna
get away with it.
Edwin's Iawyer called me
this morning.
He said I could never testify
about what Edwin had told me
because I'm his wife.
I feel so stupid.
BENSON: Curtis Johansen
got the same phone call from
Denise's attorney this morning
after she confessed
to him Iast night.
Protected themselves
by marrying their victims.
These two are real pieces
of work.
Tied our hands
and our victims'.
CABOT: And we can't
prove any of it
beyond a reasonable doubt.
What about Curtis Johansen's
DNA?
Put that to a jury,
and they'II think
Johansen raped
Jessica and Denise
even though he has an alibi.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Come in.
We have battered wives
testify against the husbands
who beat them all the time.
How is this different?
Those women testified about
what their husbands did,
not what they said.
Those wives
still cannot reveal
confidential communication
between themselves
and their husbands.
Well, there's got to be
a Ioophole for a situation
Iike this.
I checked the case Iaw.
There has never been
a situation Iike this.
What is it?
Marriage Iicenses.
Edwin Todd
to Jessica BIaine.
Curtis Johansen
to Denise Carlson.
Thought her name was Cormier.
Pick up Todd and Denise.
For what?
False names
on their marriage Iicenses.
They finally made a mistake.
Are you kidding me
with this charge?
Don't you worry. We got
better ones on the way.
I don't see how.
You really think
you can get away with this?
You don't have to use that
tone with me, Detective.
STABLER: Your real name
is Denise Cormier.
So what?
Well, on the certificate
of marriage,
it says Denise Carlson.
Where are you going
with this?
Your client Iied
about her name.
And because you Iied,
your marriage to
Jessica BIaine is void.
PIease, how many times do
I have to tell you about
your tone of voice?
Oh, I'm sorry.
If my manners bother you,
Iet me use your real name
for this.
Edward Crandall,
you're under arrest for
conspiracy to commit murder,
attempted murder,
robbery and grand Iarceny.
If you're going
to use his real name,
you better use Edwin Todd.
Excuse me?
What's this?
Mrs. Johansen's
Iegal name change
to Denise Carlson before
she married Curtis Johansen.
It's Canadian.
How do I know
it's not a forgery?
Because that's a copy
we ordered from
the Registrar of Records
in Winnipeg,
where the original is on file.
Note the seal at the bottom.
So why'd you change
your name, Edwin?
Don't answer that.
Oh, come on,
what's the harm?
Sorry.
I'm gonna have to go
with my Iawyer on that one.
How we doing?
FIN: We found the money,
courtesy of our friends
at the RCMP.
Five accounts
in Winnipeg Crown Bank
under the names
of the vendors that
Todd wrote the checks to.
He's the signatory
on all the accounts.
Waited for
the checks to clear,
then made cash withdrawals,
Ieaving each account
with $1,000.
So he gets the money
out of the country,
then converts it to cash
so we can't trace it
any further.
This guy is good.
Now what about Denise?
Well, I can't find
any accounts in her names,
but the RCMP is still Iooking.
I put a uniform detail
on Jessica,
just to be on the safe side.
AIso got one
on Todd and Denise
in case they decide
to cut their Iosses
and run back to Canada.
What the hell's this mean?
STABLER: What do you got?
It's a credit card
statement
in the name
of Edward Crandall.
Some hotel in Acapulco
a year and a half ago.
It's in Spanish.
Well, resorts are a great
place to pick up a mark.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
"Luna de miel"
means "honeymoon"'
Son of a bitch.
Why would Ed and Denise
be staying
in the honeymoon suite
of that hotel?
We're not going to allow
the continued harassment
of our clients.
Why are we here?
The honeymoon's over.
What does that mean?
It's in Spanish.
You want to clue us in?
Yeah, it's your clients'
Mexican marriage Iicense.
I told you we should
have gotten a divorce.
Shut up, you stupid bitch.
You see,
this is the Iast time
I'm gonna take care of you.
It was all his idea.
And they can't
prove any of it
if you keep
your trap shut.
What's the matter,
Counselors,
you didn't know
they were married
to each other?
CABOT: Unless you can produce
divorce papers
preceding your clients'
respective weddings
to Jessica BIaine
and Curtis Johansen,
it's as if those marriages
never existed.
No. Jessica needs me.
You see,
I do everything for her.
She's not going to
testify against me.
Mrs. BIaine.
No.
Her Iast name is Todd.
Now you know my wife is ill.
You have no right
to bring her here.
Hi, sweetie,
you should be resting.
Sit down, you bastard.
You know what?
This was all a mistake.
Yes, I stole your money.
She was only supposed
to take your watch.
You weren't supposed to
get hurt.
You're upset.
We need to get away,
just you and me, huh?
Anywhere you want to go.
The only place
you're going is to hell.