NARRATOR: In the criminal
justice system,
sexually based offenses
are considered
especially heinous,
In New York City,
the dedicated detectives
who investigate
these vicious felonies
are members
of an elite squad known
as the Special Victims Unit,
These are their stories,
(ALL CHATTERING)
(RICK LAUGHING)
RICK: Oh, God, how old
is Peyton anyway?
Don't you dare ask.
(BOTTLE CLATTERING)
What was that?
Peyton? Max?
Oh, wait,
it might be a burglar.
We need a weapon.
Oh, we're armed.
Max.
Max?
RICK: What's he doing?
Max!
ED: Max?
DIANE: Oh, my God!
ED: Oh, my God, Peyton!
It's okay.
Thank you so much.
Friends came to set up
a surprise party.
Husband was supposed
to keep the wife out
until 10:30.
What happened,
they come home early?
Or they never Ieft.
They had an 8:00 reservation
at AIain Ducasse.
Call came in at 10:07.
What was our perp
doing with them
for over two hours?
Putting on a show.
Complete with
a captive audience.
Husband gets
a front-row viewing
of his wife being raped.
She gets to watch him
get beaten to death.
(CAMERA CLICKING)
BENSON: Back door was open?
Yeah.
Party guests said
they heard something
crash in the kitchen.
Could be this beer bottle.
Perp got spooked
when he heard them come in.
Left through the service door.
Yeah, but how'd he
get in here?
Well, the Iock wasn't jimmied.
Had a bag of spilled garbage
out here.
STABLER: Could be a push-in.
Wife's probably only alive
'cause our guy
got the munchies.
Preserve and voucher
that food for saliva
and bite marks.
You're gonna want to
get this, too.
Some birthday, huh?
Multiple orbital fractures,
clean breaks
through the zygoma,
shattered mandible.
Seems your perp had
a real problem with the way
this guy Iooked.
Pistol-whipped, huh?
A few dozen times.
Perp goes to the trouble
of bringing a semi-automatic
with him,
why not just shoot the guy?
Where'd the fun be in that?
Well, how do you know
it's a semi?
It Ieaves an L-shaped pattern.
See this rectangular outline?
Common among
semi-automatic grips.
As opposed to revolvers,
which are rounded.
I don't suppose
you can narrow it down
any further?
If you Iook closely,
you'II see the slip grip
was cross-hatched.
Oh, it's a waffle pattern,
Iike a ping-pong paddle.
Exactly.
That distinct texture,
coupled with the size of
the grip are consistent with,
here it is, a Ruger P94,
9 millimeter.
She's good.
Victims have a pet?
Not that we know of.
Found some hairs
in the adhesive residue
on his skin
from the duct tape.
Probably dog or cat.
STABLER: This should make
your job easier,
cut along the dotted Iine.
Most Iikely had bypass surgery
sometime within the Iast year.
Medical magic saves this guy
from death, only to make him
suffer through this hell.
Max smelled tuna fish.
We were already running Iate,
but he insisted
on taking it out.
If only he'd just Ieft it.
BENSON: We saw the bag
in the service hall.
When Max came back in,
a man in a ski mask
had a gun to his head.
STABLER:
Can you describe him at all?
Height, weight?
Average.
Eye color?
BENSON: Then what happened?
Oh, he threw
a roll of duct tape at me.
He made me bind and gag Max.
I did it as Ioosely
as I could.
But after he put me up
on the table, he re-did it.
He hit Max so many times.
Then he'd stop and rape me.
Max struggled so hard.
Then he'd beat Max again.
Oh, it seemed to go on
for hours,
but finally
Max stopped struggling.
There was a Iockbox
broken into in the closet.
Can you tell us
what was in there?
Just some cash.
$10,000 or $15,000.
BENSON:
And in your jewelry box?
AII my grandmother's jewelry.
STABLER: We'II need you
to describe those pieces
to a sketch artist.
Now Mrs. KIeberg,
think very hard.
Did the man say anything
that would make you think
that he knew you
or your husband?
He didn't say one word
the entire time.
Had some trouble
a while back
with a homeless guy,
kept sneaking in behind cars
as they entered the garage.
What'd you do with him?
Woke him up,
kicked him out.
Seen him Iately?
Not since management
sent tenants a notice,
"Look behind you
when you're coming in."
Your other two break-ins
occurred when tenants
were out.
Must be a coincidence.
Wonder how the guy knew.
Oh, that's right,
you gave him the key.
You knew
when they were supposed
to be gone, didn't you?
If you're Iooking
at me for this,
you must have gone
to detective school
on a special yellow bus.
So I'm gonna help you
out here.
You do that.
A while back, this guy comes
Iooking for the doctor, Iike,
crazy, pissed.
FIN: You get his name?
No, it was months ago.
So I buzzed the doctor.
He got all nervous,
said to call the police
if he didn't Ieave.
MUNCH:
What was the guy's beef?
Said the doctor
was a mad scientist,
ruined his Iife.
What kind of doctor
was that again?
Urologist.
BENSON: We're Iooking
for the Chief of Urology.
Dr. Karr,
the two detectives are here.
He'II just be a minute.
Thank you.
Lara? Right.
How well did you
know Dr. KIeberg?
He was one of the best
surgeons here.
I still can't believe
he was murdered.
BENSON: We heard he had
a problem with one of his
patients earlier this year.
Might have caused a scene?
Oh, right.
The guy from the doctor's
clinical trials.
STABLER:
CIinical trials for what?
Impotency.
BENSON: You remember his name?
Martin something.
I can check the files.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
I'm Dr. Karr.
Hi.
I've got a meeting
in the north wing.
Do you mind walking with me?
Well, Iife doesn't make sense.
I thought we Iost Max
six months ago
with the CABG.
Cabbage?
Coronary Artery Bypass Graft.
Peyton was an angel,
nursed him back to health.
He was good as new.
No, better. More alive.
He specialized in impotency?
Well, a urologist's bread
and butter is prostate cancer,
urethral dysfunctions,
congenital anomalies,
kidney transplants.
Max specialized
in sexual dysfunctions,
incontinence, penile implants
and, of course, impotence.
Now, we understand that
Dr. KIeberg was testing
new treatments in that area.
An impotency cream,
a nitric-oxide analog.
It's a novel delivery system
to create vasospasm
at the base of the penis
to keep the corpus
cavernosum engorged.
An erection.
Precisely.
Viagra was the fastest-selling
drug in history,
so you can imagine
the interest in this one.
So how rich
was Dr. KIeberg gonna be
once that got FDA approved?
Oh, it doesn't work
that way.
AII Max got
was a minimal finder's fee
for every patient
he brought into the trial.
Now, we understand that
he had at Ieast
one dissatisfied customer.
First name Martin?
I'm sorry, I can't comment
on that case.
Medical case or Iegal case?
It's our policy
not to comment on either.
Now, if you'II excuse me,
this is my meeting.
Wait. If you know something
that will help us
find KIeberg's killer,
you're gonna
need to tell us.
Look, all I can say is
the participants
in Max's trials
suffered extreme
physical impotence.
Men out of options
before they ever
walked in here.
(WOMAN CHATTERING ON PA)
Sounded Iike someone
with something to hide.
Yeah. I say we have
Cabot see a judge
about getting past it.
I found the file.
His Iast name is Welker.
Martin Welker.
I made copies for you.
Thank you.
Power. Control. Humiliation.
He shows
all the outward features
of sadistic behavior.
We're talking sexual sadist?
He needed to inflict pain
for excitement.
He raped her
in front of the husband
he spent a good Iong time
beating to death.
How's that for pain?
CRAGEN: This guy took
periodic snack breaks.
A cold predator who feels
in complete control.
He never said a word
the entire two hours.
Well, it could be
fear of detection,
especially if he's known
to these people.
HUANG: Or sensory depravation.
His victims need to Iook
for cues of what to do
in order to survive,
and he never gives them a one.
He knows that it's gonna
intensify the terror.
Sociopath.
You're Iooking for someone
who has a history of violating
the rights of others,
who's numb to the world,
who has aggressive sex,
drugs, fights.
BENSON: Captain.
Join the party.
What do you got?
Martin's file,
theirs and ours.
He participated
in the hospital's trial
for impotency.
He stopped abruptly
in the 12th week when...
He was arrested
by Brooklyn SVU
for attempted rape.
Attacked a woman
in the subway,
30 years old.
And then he bashed in
the skulls of two guys
who tried to help her.
Aggressive sex,
fighting, violating
the rights of others.
Pay him a visit.
Martin Welker?
What do you want?
Why the Iong puss?
Dr. KIeberg's dead.
Your problems are solved.
Oh, no, no. That wasn't me.
Didn't say it was.
Must be your
guilty conscience speaking.
Where were you Tuesday night?
I was at group.
What kind of group?
What are you,
12-stepper, AA, NA?
No "A." Group therapy.
I keep things bottled up.
UIcers.
Quiet guys
are the most dangerous.
Loner, keeps to himself.
FIN: Yeah. One day
he explodes on the subway.
Suddenly he's up
for attempted rape,
assault and battery.
Oh, no. That wasn't my fault.
KIeberg never told me
about the side effects.
Before the cream,
I couldn't even
talk to a woman.
That's why when you were
raping Mrs. KIeberg,
you never made a peep?
I don't know
what you guys
are talking about.
Doctor Rise-and-Shine
ruined your Iife. You spent
six months in prison.
Now the only job you can get
is cleaning up pigeon crap.
AII he had to do
was tell the jury
that it was the cream,
that it wasn't me.
But he wouldn't do it,
would he?
He sat up there and he Iied.
He said that I have
violent tendencies,
that it had nothing to do
with the medication.
Somebody had to pay though,
didn't they, Martin?
We checked.
We know you filed Iawsuits
against the hospital and
the pharmaceutical company.
But you didn't file
against Dr. KIeberg.
What's up with that?
My Iawyer said
he was judgment-proof.
MUNCH: What does he
mean by that?
Son-of-a-bitch didn't have
a penny to his name.
FIN: So the doctor was broke?
Well, it's much more
complicated than that.
So is subpoenaing records,
but we'II do it.
Dr. KIeberg's, yours.
Max had a heart condition.
Even before his bypass,
no medical malpractice
company would cover him.
And he wanted to continue
practicing medicine,
but to do so, he had
to protect his assets.
I recommended
he move everything
into Peyton's name.
It was completely Iegal.
What kind of money
are we talking about?
AII told, $5 million.
That's a Iot of hidden assets.
Anybody else Iooking for them?
No one who could be
involved in this.
Why don't you
just run it by us,
Iet us be the judge?
Well, Max had
a Iittle trouble
with his son.
MUNCH: I didn't know
he had a son.
Jesse.
From Max's first marriage.
We had to cut off
his trust fund.
When was this?
Last week.
Why?
Again, it's complicated.
Max and Jesse have been
estranged for years
ever since he married Peyton.
Why'd he cut him off?
Well, Jesse broke
into the co-op
a few weeks ago,
and Max caught him
trying to steal
his stepmother's jewelry.
I'm sorry you had to come
all the way out here.
I'm inconveniencing
so many people.
I couldn't face
going home yet.
PIease, we understand.
Mrs. KIeberg,
what can you tell us
about your stepson?
Jesse?
Mmm-hmm.
I haven't seen him
in several years.
What about him?
Well, he didn't go
to his father's funeral.
No.
We understand that
he broke into your apartment
a few weeks ago.
He didn't break in.
He has a key.
There's been an estrangement,
but he has
always been welcome.
Well, you can't be thinking...
He did try to steal
your jewelry before.
It wasn't Jesse.
Your attacker wore a ski mask
and he never spoke.
No!
STABLER: Your husband
had just cut off
his trust fund.
Only until he could Iearn
to be responsible.
You know, kids in college,
they mismanage.
He wouldn't do
something Iike that.
He is Max's son.
Mrs. KIeberg, you said
that your attacker was of
average height and build.
How would you describe Jesse?
How's Jesse adapting
to dorm Iife?
At Ieast here his Gestapo
stepdad isn't searching
through his things,
violating his basic
human rights.
Taking a civics course
this semester, are we?
I'm applying at Stanford Law,
after which I plan
on working for the ACLU.
Civil Iiberties, good.
Lawyers, bad.
Hate to think Jesse was alone
when he heard about
what happened to his dad.
Happen to know where
he was that night?
I think you gained access
under false pretenses.
Why don't you just Ieave
a card for Jesse?
Why, Jesse got
something to hide?
No. Not that you even have
a right to ask.
Actually, the first amendment
gives him the right to ask.
The fifth amendment gives you
the right not to answer.
And just what do you think
I'd be incriminating
myself about?
Let's say you had knowledge
of stolen goods
being stored here, accessory.
What?
IIIegal substances,
possession.
I don't do drugs,
neither does Jesse.
Right. Well, if he's not
snorting his family fortune,
where's it all going?
MAN ON PA: Last call for
the third race,,, Last call,
There he is.
AII right.
$500 Perfecta on the 2-5 box
and a $500 straight.
I'm sorry,
can I see some ID, please?
What?
Do you have ID on you?
Look, man, I've been
betting here all day.
Not at this window, sir.
It's a minute till post,
all right?
PIease step aside
so the gentleman can...
Stop jacking me around
and run my freaking bet!
Hey, what are you doing, man?
What...
Saving you $1,000.
Salutation and Jake's Delight
are useless on turf.
It's okay. We got this.
Drugs, I get. But the ponies?
You really see that Ieading
to rape/homicide?
If he's a compulsive gambler
he Iacks impulse control.
It's consistent
with the degree of overkill
in your homicide.
Compulsive gambler?
He's 18.
AImost six percent of kids
even younger than Jesse
have a serious
gambling problem.
BENSON: Well, that adds up.
He started stealing from
his parents four years ago.
STABLER:
Probably playing Iotteries,
betting on football pools.
Do you gamble, EIIiot?
Only with birth control.
Kids who come from
a non-gambling environment
are Iess Iikely to become
gamblers themselves.
CRAGEN: How Iikely are they
to rape their stepmothers?
Maybe tying into some feedback
Ioop of taking more risks,
needing higher stakes?
No. That's unrelated
Oedipal complex.
But you know,
studies are Iooking
to identify
the abnormal
neurobiological mechanisms
in pathological gamblers.
Linked to violent behavior?
Well, nothing's cut-and-dried.
I'II know more
after the interview.
STABLER: High roller, huh?
BENSON: How'd you start?
My parents made me,
Your parents forced you
to gamble?
My mom and stepmom
were both charity junkies.
Since when is charity
a game of chance?
Look, you know
what the biggest
fundraising gimmick is?
Casino nights.
So they made you bet
until it hurt?
Look, my mom
organized the game
since I was, Iike, 12.
She'd give me
a bushel of chips and say,
"Go have fun."
It's just a short hop
from there to the OTB.
In high school,
I would make a poker game,
then it was road trips
to Atlantic City.
Well, you got to be 21
to get in those casinos.
I never had any trouble.
So how deep in are you?
$100,000.
(WHISTLES)
Yeah, I got behind
with my bookie
and Iaid 50 grand
on the Giants game.
Probably gonna have
my Iegs broken.
This bookie, would he go
after your parents?
It's a first-name business.
How would he know
who they were?
Jesse, why didn't you just
ask your parents for help?
I did.
After my dad
caught me breaking in.
And?
And he didn't believe me.
Thought it was...
He thought it was drugs,
just Iike my freaking stepdad.
You know, people are gonna
hurt me, and he wouldn't
give me a dime.
Where were you
Tuesday night, Jesse?
What? Oh, you guys are crazy.
You went back for the money.
You got even with your dad.
No. No, no, no! No.
I'm Jesse's attorney.
This interview stops now.
Hey, Jesse never
asked for a Iawyer.
Who called in the dragon Iady?
Mother.
Who, Peyton?
Nope, the biological mother.
She's in with the Captain.
More good news. Martin Welker,
the disgruntled patient,
DNA cleared him.
Captain Cragen,
I put Max KIeberg
through medical school,
and as soon as that bastard
became a doctor,
he deserted us.
From his grave,
he's still hurting Jesse.
Detectives,
this is Marilyn Dunlap,
Jesse's mother.
These are...
The two that arrested my son.
Do you have any idea
how much money I give to
that Police Athletic League?
Ma'am, if this was
a traffic citation,
we'd probably Iet it slide,
but it's a rape/homicide.
It's false arrest.
Nobody's been arrested.
We're just talking to him.
He had nothing to do with it.
Mrs. Dunlap,
I'm sure that you know
more than anyone
how much resentment
your son had for his father.
He had 18 years
to deal with the fact that
he had a rotten father,
and if this is about
resentment, you should be
talking to Peyton.
Hers was good and raw.
What kind of resentment?
Ever since
Max's heart attack,
he'd been nailing
just about anything
that moved.
Did Peyton know?
She knew when I ran into her
at the Covenant House
fundraiser Iast month. Yes.
BENSON: Well,
how did she find out?
I told her.
Did you give her names?
Look, I don't have anything
against them, just Max.
That's very noble,
but we're still gonna
need that Iist.
Well, I know for a fact
that he was doing
his boss's secretary.
A doctor smiles at you
around here, people make
a soap opera out of it.
Oh, so you weren't
having an affair?
After the operation,
Max was a different person.
He was Iike a teenager,
you know? He was funny
and sexy and...
It was a fling.
FIing. When did it end?
Months ago.
But we stayed friends.
If there was anything
I could do to help
find his killer I would.
That's why I gave you
that file.
Well, it wasn't him.
So if you still wanna help us,
why don't you
start by telling us
who he was sleeping with
at the time he was killed?
You make him sound so dirty.
It wasn't Iike that.
STABLER: So how was it?
There was a month
after his recovery
where he went a Iittle crazy.
Who was he crazy with,
after you?
Judy Trahill in Radiology.
I'm a married woman.
Well, your husband
the jealous type?
If he cared enough about me
to kill, I wouldn't have
cheated on him.
Is that why Dr. KIeberg
cheated on his wife?
'Cause she didn't care enough?
Just the reverse.
She cared too much.
How do you do that?
During the two months
he was recuperating,
she nursed him, bathed him,
waited on him hand and foot.
He felt Iike an invalid.
The only thing he wanted
to do was Iive.
BENSON: So you two
did some Iiving.
One weekend. Six months ago.
Okay, so who was next
on his rounds?
A nurse in Neonatal,
but it was over before
anything really happened.
CIinical exhaustion.
Peyton made a surprise visit,
caught them flirting.
STABLER: What'd she do?
Bitch-slapped the nurse.
So the doctor has an operation
where they apparently give him
a wandering heart,
after which he sows
the gross national product
in wild oats.
Two months and then
the trail stops cold.
Think he mended
his evil ways?
I think after his close call,
he Iearned
how to cover his tracks.
Speaking of tracks,
we've been following
the wrong one.
Jesse all too willingly
volunteered a DNA sample.
He's not our guy.
FIN: CIose the door
and open the window.
LUDs to the doctor's
cell phone
and Iast month,
he got about 1,000 minutes
to one number.
Lara Todd.
Boss's secretary.
She told us their affair
ended months ago,
just Iike the others.
Well, I doubt
he was calling her at home
for urine results.
Go talk to her.
Ten will get you 20
if she claims he just called
to cry on her shoulder.
Good friends, my ass.
That's blood, OIivia.
It's fresh.
Door's open.
Lara?
Lara, you in there?
Oh, my God!
(GROANING)
Hey.
How you doing?
I've been better.
Lara, do you know
who did this to you?
No.
Can you describe him at all?
I don't know.
I never saw his face.
He was wearing a mask.
Tell me what happened.
I was just coming in
the door from work,
and he pushed in
behind me.
I closed my eyes
and tried to go someplace else
and when he finished,
I thought, "Thank God,
I got through it."
But then he came back
in the room
and started again.
Lara, if you want us
to catch him,
you're gonna have to be
straight with me.
I'm not making this up.
I was raped!
I know that.
I'm talking about
seeing Dr. KIeberg.
I knew the papers would
add it to the story
and make him seem all sleazy,
and he deserved
better than that.
Does his wife know
about you?
Not until the very end.
She showed up
at my apartment building
and said that if I didn't stop
seeing Max,
she would ruin both our Iives.
And when was this?
Three days before
Max was killed.
We might have a problem
with Peyton.
Peyton the rape victim?
BENSON:
Peyton the wronged wife.
She'd just found out
that Max was still seeing
Lara Todd.
Tracked her down
and threatened her.
Crime of passion.
I could buy it
if Mrs. KIeberg
hadn't been bound,
gagged and raped
for over two hours.
Let's not forget
the Miller case.
Phony rape
at the Thorpe Palace
so she could sue the hotel.
Dr. KIeberg and his mistress
were beaten to a pulp.
Peyton suffered
only relatively minor battery.
Which is odd,
it being the same perp.
Lara's rape kit
isn't back yet.
How do we know for sure?
The crime Iab compared
the scenes and found cat hairs
on all the victims.
The color patterns
are consistent with a tabby.
Great. So we're Iooking
for a guy with a cat?
AII right. Has any of
Peyton's jewelry
surfaced at
any of the pawn shops
we've checked?
FIN: Not a blip.
Well, this is heirloom stuff,
right? Very distinctive.
But if she staged this
as a robbery,
she probably still has it.
Well, her apartment
is still a crime scene.
Why don't we just go
poke around?
Because the type of attorney
Mrs. KIeberg can afford
would have anything
we found there thrown out
before his morning
squash game.
We do this one by the book.
We don't have enough
for a warrant.
So we go fishing.
Have Cabot pull his financials
and grab a pole.
THURMAN: These are all
their accounts and holdings.
MUNCH: Thanks.
The worst things happen
to the best people.
FIN: You knew the KIebergs?
Peyton and I sit on a few
of the same committees.
PIease Iet me know
if there's anything
I can do to help.
She has a safety deposit box.
Maybe she stashed
the jewelry in there.
Subpoena doesn't
cover that.
Excuse me, Mrs. Thurman?
Yes?
Do you keep an entry Iog
for the safe deposit boxes?
Yes, of course.
Could you check and see
when the KIeberg's
was opened Iast?
I don't have to.
Peyton was in a few days
before it happened.
For what?
She took out
her Tiffany diamond necklace
and ring. Stunning.
Has she been here since?
No.
How do you know
what she took out?
We talked.
Max wanted her to wear it
to the Fire and Ice Ball
next week.
Really?
Yeah. It's so sad.
It was going to be
their first major event
together since his surgery.
I don't get it.
If she was planning this,
why take the jewelry out?
Ever hear of
insurance fraud?
She's stinking rich.
Even before her husband died,
all the money was in her name.
You can never be
too thin or too rich.
Especially when you take out
chunks Iike that.
$10,000, eight days
before it happened.
In cash.
Could be enough
for a hit man.
Let's just hope it's enough
for a warrant.
Detectives. Come in.
This is a warrant allowing us
to search your apartment.
A warrant?
Why do you need to
search my home?
I'm sorry.
I have to ask you
not to disturb anything.
But I don't understand.
What are you Iooking for?
Stay with Mrs. KIeberg
until we're through.
Thank you.
Hey. Breadbox rule.
They Iook so happy.
If a container
could not possibly hold
the item in question,
you are prohibited
from examining it.
This is Iast New Year's.
Do any marriages Iast?
I don't know,
but the warrant
only covers jewelry.
God, you've been married
for 17 years, haven't you?
Stop.
Sorry.
No, stop Iooking.
Try smoking this.
We're going this way,
Mrs. KIeberg.
What is that woman doing here?
Did I do okay?
You did great.
She Iooks crazy, didn't she?
They stormed into my home,
tore it apart.
I apologize if you
or your property were
in any way mistreated.
They treated me
Iike a criminal!
If you were almost
anybody else,
you would have been arrested
for insurance fraud
on the spot.
Let's just clear things up.
Okay.
How did your jewelry wind up
in the cigar box?
I don't know.
You'II excuse my being blunt,
but that really doesn't
clear up anything at all.
I don't know how it got there.
But it's my jewelry.
Why is it any concern
of yours?
It became our concern
when you filed a false claim.
I didn't file a claim
for anything.
Our business manager
takes care of those things.
Mrs. KIeberg...
And I don't understand
why Lara Todd
is sitting out there.
She was raped.
We believe by the same man
who raped you
and killed your husband.
What?
You withdrew $10,000
on the 23rd.
Can you tell me
what that was for?
Even for you,
that's a Iarge sum of money.
Why did you need it in cash?
So Max wouldn't know.
Wouldn't know what?
(SIGHS)
That I hired
a private investigator.
How do you think
I found out about Lara?
MUNCH: Ken Voltz?
You're blocking
my Iine of vision.
Where's your manners?
Aren't you
gonna invite us in?
Look, I'm on the clock.
Everything I had on the case
is in there.
You, by any chance,
own a cat, Mr. Voltz?
Two dogs, Jack Russells.
We were wondering
if Mrs. KIeberg didn't maybe
have a second job for you,
night of the 23rd?
I don't eliminate husbands,
I just put them
in piping hot water.
FIN: You can account for
your whereabouts that night
between 8:00 and 10:00?
I was following a guy
out to a Iittle Iove nest
in Jersey.
I keep toll receipts
for tax purposes
if you'd Iike them.
How Iong were you on KIeberg?
Two weeks.
Two days said it all,
but I Iike to be thorough.
Oh, damn it,
almost missed my guy.
(CLICKING)
Got a guy in the background
of two of these.
Different Iocations.
He's eyeballing Max.
Like he's tracking him.
BENSON: Have you seen
this man before?
It's Vincent.
Is he a friend of yours?
No, he Iives right below me
in 4B.
Why do you have his picture?
He just came up
during the investigation.
He a violent guy?
Vincent? No, he's harmless.
Maybe harmless Vincent
isn't as harmless as he Iooks.
We've been thinking
Lara was attacked because of
her relationship with Max.
Now maybe Max was murdered
because of
his connection to Lara.
She said the apartment
right under hers.
She said 4B, right?
Vincent.
Yeah?
Hey, what's your name?
Chloe, get back inside.
That's a cute cat.
Could we ask you
a few questions?
No.
CRAGEN: Vincent Boyd is
a former guest of the state.
Robbery and assault.
He Iives directly
below Lara Todd,
our second rape victim.
FIN: Who was the mistress
of the Iate Dr. KIeberg.
BENSON:
Husband to rape victim
number one.
STABLER: Peyton, the one
with motive but no direct
connection to Vincent.
Well, we do have Peyton
in Lara's building,
also Vincent's building,
three days before the murder.
So what,
she bumps into him
on the elevator
and hires him
to off her husband
and mess up the mistress?
Well, the rape kits came back.
The same man who raped Lara
raped Peyton.
AII right, Iet's set Peyton
aside for a minute, here.
Is there any chance that
there was a relationship
between Lara and Vincent?
Well, she says that
she barely knew him.
But, you know,
only to pass in the hall.
Could've been
a committed relationship
in his mind.
How many times have we seen
that behavior with stalkers?
Vincent sees the doctor
making house calls,
thinks he's been wronged
and seeks revenge.
Yeah.
And Peyton gets caught
in the crossfire.
So what about the food
at the KIebergs? Right?
Was there any DNA
from the saliva?
There wasn't any. Crime Iab
says he didn't take bites.
He tore pieces off.
Lot of arrows
you got up there.
FIN: But no way
to connect Vincent.
Well, you know
who does connect
with everybody?
CRAGEN: CIeo.
Tabby hairs were found
on all three victims.
And Vincent owns a tabby.
CABOT: Circumstantial.
You can't prove the hairs
came from Vincent's cat.
AII his attorney has to do
is parade 50 tabbies
through the courtroom.
He's still got
reasonable doubt.
Well, if we got the DNA
from the damn cat,
would that be enough
to get Vincent's?
Sure, but New York State
doesn't have
that kind of technology.
In fact,
I only know of two cases
in the entire United States
where they've used cat DNA.
What do you say
we make it three?
If Vincent comes back,
buzz us.
I don't see no cat.
That doesn't mean anything.
They're freaky
Iittle creatures. They Iurk.
Well, keep Iooking.
I'm gonna check in on Lara.
Here pussy, pussy, pussy.
You're kidding, right?
This is not
my area of expertise.
(CAT MEOWING)
Oh, come on.
Where is this cat?
There you are,
you demonic Iittle fur-ball.
Come here, sweetheart.
That's a good kitty.
What happened?
Nothing.
Those are fresh bruises.
I'm fine, really.
Lara, we know what's going on.
If you don't work with us,
we can't help you.
There's nothing
to help me with.
You were raped.
STABLER: Now we know
about Vincent.
Everywhere you go,
there he is.
BENSON:
He's very possessive,
isn't he?
Lara, we don't think
that you're safe here.
Is there anyone, anywhere
that you can stay?
No. I don't have anyone.
I know a women's shelter
near where you work.
I'm gonna take you there.
Okay?
Okay.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Are you the zoological
geneticist?
This had been a royal pain.
Do you realize
we had to have
special panels FedExed
from a genomic Iab
in Maryland?
No, but we appreciate it.
Are we close?
AImost.
But you will be able
to tell us today
whether or not the hairs
came from CIeo?
Do you have any idea
what you're asking?
For starters, it's a cat.
So right there,
we're not using the standard
13-marker test.
So you can't get it?
No, I got it. It's your cat.
Pick up Vincent,
I'II bootstrap a warrant.
(GUN FIRES)
Go ahead.
STABLER: Lara?
Just put down the gun, honey.
Put down the gun.
I shot him.
BENSON: I see can that, Lara.
I just need you
to hand me that gun,
all right?
I had to. He wouldn't stop.
It's okay now.
Lara, the gun, all right?
Got it?
Ruger P94.
I moved in three years ago
all by myself.
I didn't think I could
carry up one more box
when Vincent came over
and started helping me.
After that, he was just
always there.
It became romantic?
I told him
I just wanted to be friends,
but he was so persistent
and sweet. He wore me down.
He didn't stay too sweet.
I came home Iate
from work one day
and he'd burned my clothes.
Why?
He accused me of cheating.
Said I was a whore,
then started hitting me.
Why didn't you report him?
He apologized,
swore it would never
happen again,
promised to make it up to me.
He said
I was the most beautiful girl
in the world.
But then he did it again.
I don't know how many times.
Were you two together
when you started seeing Max?
Vincent punished me
for two years of infidelities
I never committed.
I thanked God
when I found Max.
How'd Vincent feel
about that?
LARA:
He followed me everywhere.
He had a key.
He'd come into my apartment
in the middle of the night.
But I was finally
strong enough, because of Max,
to say no.
Why didn't you
get out of that building?
Max was just about
to Ieave Peyton.
We were gonna
get a place together.
(SNIFLES)
Vincent came into my apartment
that night and told me
we could be together again.
Max was dead.
BENSON: Lara, why didn't you
call the police?
You don't know Vincent.
He'd kill me.
No matter where I went,
he would find me and kill me
Iike he killed Max.
You were at the shelter.
You were safe.
Why did you go back?
He was waiting for me
outside the shelter.
I couldn't believe
he found me there, too.
He must have followed us.
But I don't understand.
Why did you go
back to the apartment?
He forced me.
He started to rape me again,
and I couldn't
Iet it keep happening.
I made it to his gun
and shot him.
CIassic battered
woman syndrome.
CABOT: Yeah,
but there's a hitch.
She's got the numbness,
the Iow self-esteem,
the fatalism,
and the physical injuries
kind of speak for themselves.
What's the hitch?
It's not clear-cut
self-defense.
She shot the man
that killed her Iover.
A jury could very easily see
that as an act of revenge.
She was beaten,
raped and terrorized.
In her mind
there was no escape.
Look, if she had shot him
in her own apartment
during the rape,
we wouldn't even have
to have this conversation.
As it stands now,
all we've got is he-said
she-said, he's dead.
Battered women
rarely report abuse.
They are conditioned
to believe that no one's
gonna help them.
Okay, I want to be
able to close this
in good conscience.
Build me a case
against Vincent
that would put him away
for Iife if he weren't dead.
Yeah.
Munch.
Forensics came back
on the Ruger. They found
Vincent's prints all over it.
They took it apart
and found some of
Dr. KIeberg's skin
embedded under
the grip screw.
Lab work back?
Vincent's DNA matches
the fluids from Peyton
and Lara's rape kits.
CRAGEN: AII that's missing
is the bow.
I want you to go back
over Vincent's apartment.
For the bow?
Yep.
I don't know
what he expects us
to find in here.
CSU's already been through it
with a microscope, Iiterally.
Diaries, journals,
pictures, Ietters.
Yeah, CSU would never Iook
for anything Iike that.
They missed this.
Triple-X porn.
How's that apply?
Open it up.
Commercial jacket,
home-made video.
Bag it.
They said I had to
sign something?
Yeah. Come in.
This is the statement
you gave to police.
I just need you to review it,
make sure it's accurate
and sign it right there.
Okay.
Is that it?
No. Actually,
there's one more thing.
LARA: Sure.
Come on, Vincent,
If you won't do it for me,
do it for the $15,000,
That doctor's wife,
right?
So?
Why don't you want
to be with me?
Look, if you don't have
the balls to do it,,,
No, no, no,
No, I'll do it,
Good,
You need to be waiting
at his service door at 7:45,
Get there early,
You didn't know he made
that video, did you?
He Ioved you,
but he didn't trust you.
I was in Iove with Max.
Vincent was only supposed
to kill Peyton.
There never was any
relationship with Vincent,
was there?
He followed me around
Iike a puppy dog.
He'd do anything for me,
but he wasn't supposed
to kill Max.
Why did you stage
your own rape?
I didn't.
Once he killed Max,
he owned me.
I couldn't go to the police.
Rape by blackmail?
Do you have any idea
how horrible it was?
A jealous psychopath killed
the Iove of my Iife,
and I couldn't even
go to the police!
Sweetheart, the reason that
you couldn't go to the police
is because you're the one
that hired him.
That wasn't my idea.
Where do you think
I got the $15,000?
And who do you think
hid the jewelry?
It was Max.
Once Peyton was dead,
he was gonna marry me.
How could Max be
with somebody Iike that?
It was the heart attack.
It changed him.
But things were finally
getting back to normal.
He broke it off with her
after I found out.
That's why she had him killed,
isn't it?
Mrs. KIeberg...
I'm so sorry,
but your husband planned
this whole thing.
Oh, that doesn't
make any sense.
Why would Max set up
his own death?
He wasn't supposed to die.
You were.