NARRATOR: In the criminal
justice system,
sexually based offenses
are considered
especially heinous,
In New York City,
the dedicated detectives
who investigate
these vicious felonies
are members
of an elite squad known
as the Special Victims Unit,
These are their stories,
FRANK: I'II get a cab.
How's it going?
Is it a Iove connection?
I don't think he Iikes me.
That's crazy. You're adorable.
Definitely Steve's type.
Talk to him.
Sorry. I didn't mean...
It's fine. It's all right.
I'm just really nervous.
Me, too.
I think we both need to relax.
I know this great piano bar.
(GUN FIRING)
Get out of here. I'II call.
Hold it!
Let me see your hands!
Now!
Okay.
My name's Phil.
I sleep here.
Detective Nathan?
Steve.
OIivia, this is EIIiot.
Your John Doe's a white male,
early mid-20s.
Caught a slug in the gut.
Crime scene's an alley
off of a bar called Puffy's.
I'm not sure, but I think
I saw the victim inside.
Inside the bar?
I was on a date.
Set up by friends.
Made a great first impression.
Do we suspect a gay bashing?
Can't say for sure.
Victim was gang-raped.
That's why I called you.
Doctors found copious fluids.
Witness?
Name's Phil Kastner.
Brick chip caught him
in the cheek
from the ricochet.
CIaims he just got there
wanting to bed down.
STABLER: What,
you don't believe him?
Sounds good, but he's pretty
clean for a street sleeper.
Uniforms took him for a meal
but I'II make sure
he gets to the squad.
Okay. Thanks for your help.
You need anything else,
you can reach me at the 25.
Okay. You know, Steve,
if you want
a Iittle discretion on this,
we can try
and keep you out of it.
I don't broadcast,
but the brass already knows.
Thanks for asking, though.
Okay. Take it easy.
BENSON: I'II need
to see the wound, please.
It's an old scar.
Doubt he uses that hand much.
Okay. No other wounds,
no tattoos.
So, just this scar?
Yeah.
And a wedding ring.
Well, if he was
in a committed relationship,
we might be able to get a hit
off Missing Persons.
He's in a meat market bar.
Let's hope his partner's
more committed than he is.
Thanks for the shower
and the clothes.
I do Iaundry on Thursdays,
so I'II wash these
and I'II bring them back.
STABLER: Yours to keep.
No, no, no, no.
I appreciate that
but I've got plenty.
I'II give them to somebody
who needs them.
You a junkie, Phil?
Sugar gave me away, huh?
How Iong you been clean?
Sixty-four days,
five hours, twelve minutes,
six seconds.
Seven, eight, nine...
Sebastian, he's my counselor.
He gave me the watch.
Said I needed to tell time
to know how precious it is.
It's precious agony.
Yeah.
Okay, the alley outside
of Puffy's, is that
where you usually rest?
Yeah. The gays, they treat
me human, so I stay there
when I can't find a bed.
Where do you usually stay?
Mission on 10th
when I'm not in rehab.
You see the shooter, Phil?
It was dark, but I got
a good Iook at him
when he broke the alley.
Brown hair,
between 5'10" and 6 feet.
I didn't see his eyes, though.
You see the gun?
Snub-nose revolver.
Probably a.38.
I was a master sergeant,
Parris Island.
It was a Iifetime ago.
You know, Phil,
veterans are eligible
for Uncle Sam benefits.
You know that, right?
Not without an address.
The waiting Iist for housing,
oh, it's awfully Iong.
How much of this addict's
statement can we believe?
I'd say all of it. He was
Iucid enough for details.
If we find our shooter,
Phil's testimony won't hold up
in court without help.
It's putting the proverbial
cart, don't you think?
Get him to agree
to a blood test.
If his tox screen
shows he's clean now,
the Iawyers can't argue Iater.
Good thing you know
the drug business.
GIad I could bring
something to the table.
I didn't mean that.
Forget it.
Look, get on it before
we Iose Phil to the street.
What's with him?
What's the word
on our John Doe,
and what the hell was he doing
in that alley?
No solicitation, hits.
Vice couldn't ID him
from the photo or the prints,
so he's not a known pro.
Doctors found three different
blood types in the semen.
This Iooks Iike
a rape gang-bang.
Good money's on a hate crime.
Perps are usually hetero,
or closeted and in denial.
Well, there was a ring
on his finger. So, maybe
he's cheating, wanted out.
Picked up the wrong guys
in the meat market.
John, you're on missing
persons.
While you two canvass
that bar, see if our John Doe
introduced himself around.
Looked a hell of a Iot better
than that Iast night.
Did you catch a name?
No. I'm not his type.
Pretty boys tend to
stick together.
Did you see someone with him?
Yeah, one of our regulars,
but he's not into
working guys over.
Well, we'II still
need to talk to him.
This regular have a name?
Being gay doesn't mean
being violent.
Whoever did that was straight.
As a matter of fact,
gay bashers
Iook a Iot Iike you.
Look, we really don't want
a hassle, but this is how
it's gonna play out.
We come back here
with a warrant,
we go through your receipts,
and while we're doing that,
we close down your bar.
Name's Willem. I know him.
He didn't do this.
They had a drink at the bar.
Will passed him
a thick envelope.
Did you see
what was in the envelope?
No, and I didn't overhear
any conversation, either.
Music here gets pretty Ioud.
Did they Ieave together?
Your guy Ieft alone.
Hard to believe,
with a body Iike that.
STABLER:
What about this Willem?
Left at Iast call.
Okay. We'II need to
hear that from him, so,
do you have an address?
No, but you can find one
from the credit card receipts.
(DOORBELL BUZZING)
Yes?
You Willem Mueller?
No. Ray Borland.
Willem's my houseboy.
What's he done this time?
We just need to talk to him.
Is he in?
He's picking up my Iaundry.
What's this about?
Have you ever seen this man
with Mr. Mueller?
No, I haven't. I'm pretty
sure he'II be back soon.
Okay. Have him give us a call
when he comes in.
Thank you, Mr. Borland.
Houseboy?
Guess that's what
they're called these days.
He fits the witness
description.
Willem Mueller? We'd Iike to
talk to you about Iast night.
Seven years in Sing Sing.
Possession with Intent
and assault two.
I've changed my evil ways.
Not in this Iifetime.
Recognize him?
Had a couple drinks. So what?
He was found worked over
in that alley
in more ways than one,
and you were the Iast person
seen with him.
I didn't touch him.
Not even for fun.
What's his name?
Peter Ivanhoe.
That for real?
It's what he said.
What was the envelope for?
I was paying for a job.
What was he running for you,
coke or crystal meth?
Not that kind of job.
I'm out of that business.
Well, what, then?
I plead the fifth.
He pleads the fifth.
You're not on trial.
BENSON: Yet.
Terence Moore,
representing Mr. Mueller,
who is done talking
unless you're charging him.
He's free to go
after we get his DNA.
You're gonna need a warrant.
Not a problem.
Known violent ex-con
who just happens to be
the Iast person
seen with the victim.
We're just waiting for
the Iab tech, so why don't you
have a seat, Counselor?
Have an orange juice.
Natural sugar's
better than a candy bar.
Oh, thanks.
We're holding a suspect,
so if it pans out,
we'II do a Iineup.
You know where to find me.
You're thinking
about it right now,
just using one more time.
AII day, every day.
And one more time
will kill you, Phil.
You know that, right?
Smoker doesn't know
which cigarette
will give him cancer.
Drinker doesn't know which
cocktail will give him
cirrhosis. It's a compulsion.
You gotta stop making excuses.
Take this.
We get Mueller's DNA?
It's on its way to the Iab.
Anything on the victim
from Missing Persons?
National Center for
Missing & Exploited Children
got a hit.
In Cedar Creek, Arkansas,
a 17-year-old boy
Wesley Jansen
went missing in 1993.
STABLER: Juvenile records?
No. Part of the kids'
fingerprint program.
You contacted his parents?
They're flying in.
What's the connection between
the runaway and the ex-con?
Well, Mueller played dumb
on the envelope, but he's been
in the drug trade,
so it's a dope payoff
or money to make a buy.
If he's making bank selling
drugs, then why's he doing
Ray Borland's Iaundry?
I checked with Narcotics.
Borland's a player.
Got caught holding on a couple
of big-time possession beefs.
Bought his way out from under.
He was connected. The real
Iaundry is cleaning money.
So, Mueller fronts as
Borland's man on the street.
Wesley Jansen, a.k.a.
Peter Ivanhoe,
is either a dealer...
Thanks.
...mule or a client.
Hospital just called.
Our victim is awake,
so go ask him nicely.
STABLER: Who's Wesley Jansen?
If that's the name
of my roomie, he's gone.
Do you know where he went?
He didn't talk to me.
Well, what time did he skip?
About 30 minutes ago.
He Iost it
when the nurse told him
the cops were on the way.
You Iet John Doe just walk
out of here with a gut wound?
He's ambulatory,
but just barely.
The dressing
has to be changed. He needs
round-the-clock antibiotics.
This guy will be back
with a staph infection.
Did he have any visitors
coming in or out of here?
Not a soul. AII he did
was yak on the phone.
"I Iove you. Don't worry.
See you soon."
Well, the idea
of talking to the cops
spooked him so much
that he runs with
a bullet wound in his gut.
Someone had to pick him up.
We'II dump his phones
and find out who.
Open up. Police.
TV's on. It's a good sign.
Oh, God. What?
Wesley Jansen?
Yeah.
Can we come in?
Nice place.
Sure beats a hospital room.
Yeah. I'm gonna pay
for that bill, I swear.
This isn't about the bill.
It's about your assault.
Yeah. Okay.
We'd Iike you to come down
to the station
so we can take your statement,
or we can take you back
to the hospital.
Look, I don't have
any insurance, and I didn't
see the guy who attacked me.
So, I was mugged.
It happens all the time,
right?
So, why are you packing?
I just thought I'd take
a break from the city.
You seem a Iittle jumpy,
a Iittle nervous. Even scared.
I was attacked.
How should I act?
Is someone after you?
No.
You being threatened?
BENSON: Wesley,
we know about the rape.
That's crazy.
Well, we've got semen
from the three different men
and a gun shot wound here.
What are you doing out of bed?
You're gonna kill yourself.
Hi, Daddy.
Hi, baby.
JAINA: Are you the police?
Yeah. We're here about
Wesley's assault.
I'm Jaina, Wesley's wife.
This is our Mara.
Here's your pills.
Thanks.
JAINA: So, did you
catch that mugger?
No, sweetheart,
I told them that I'd be okay.
We're still gonna want Wesley
to come down to the station
to answer a few questions.
Maybe when
he's feeling better.
Precinct or hospital,
your choice,
but we need a statement now.
Like I said,
the whole thing is a blank.
We appreciate your time,
anyway.
I'II show these people
to the interview room.
This way.
What's going on?
Captain wants to see you.
About what?
Parents are here.
Wesley.
Mom, Dad.
(CRYING)
No. Take it easy.
What happened, son?
Nothing. I'm okay.
It's been eight years.
I'm just so happy
to see you're alive.
STABLER: Are you ready
to talk, Wesley?
Why'd you call my parents?
I don't want them here.
Why'd you run away?
They do something to you?
I don't want to talk about it.
Fine. We're only interested
in your assault and the rape.
No one raped me.
Then how do you explain
the semen inside of you?
Was it consensual?
I'm married. I've got a kid.
Look, Iots of people hit for
both teams. Now, either you
were forced or you weren't.
Okay, I'm bisexual.
Are we done?
No, who shot you?
You're hiding something,
and we're trying to help you.
No. You can't.
We take rape
and assault very seriously.
We keep investigating
with or without help.
AII right. I was hit
outside the bar, all right?
I was knocked on the head,
and the rest is a blur.
What do you want from me?
Why don't we start
with the truth?
There's no evidence
that you were knocked out.
There's no contusions
to the back of your head.
Well, I don't know
what to tell you.
Any aliases?
No.
Your husband's got two names.
You sure you don't
want to amend that?
My name is Jaina Jansen,
formerly Jaina Tobias
of Cedar Creek, Arkansas.
Just ask my mother-in-Iaw.
When did you Iast see your
husband before his attack?
That afternoon. He'd gone out
to run some errands,
and when he didn't come back,
I called the police.
They said
I had to wait 48 hours.
Which precinct?
You don't believe me?
BENSON:
Wesley, it's really hard
admitting that you were raped.
You feel guilt.
You feel shame.
But you've gotta deal with it,
for yourself
and for your family.
Okay, I will.
Is the Iecture over?
No. What was in the envelope
Willem Mueller
passed you in the bar?
Payments for working
on Ray Borland's house.
AII of it in cash?
Yeah.
How much?
$4,500, which was stolen
when I got mugged.
That's an awful Iot of cash.
Must've been a big job.
Do a Iot of construction
with that bum
right hand of yours?
My other one works just fine.
Then, why use an alias,
Peter Ivanhoe?
I don't know. I made it up
when Jaina and I ran away.
I thought my parents would be
Iooking. I just got
in the habit of using it.
Well, what about
Jaina's parents?
They're dead. Her father
killed her mother in front
of her and then offed himself.
Nobody Iooked out
for her except for me.
Maybe you knew your hubby
was making a drug deal
and you don't call that
into the police.
Oh, my God.
You've got Wesley involved
with drugs?
No, I don't,
but it's just Iike you
to blame me for this.
He never gave us any trouble
until he met you.
Yeah, I suppose I seduced him,
too. Got pregnant on purpose
so he'd marry me.
I wouldn't put it
past a slut Iike you.
MUNCH: Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Now cut it out, you two.
Wesley Ioves me!
Ms. Jansen, wait in
the Captain's office or Ieave.
You park it and chill out.
What the hell is going on?
That Iady called Mommy a slut.
What does that mean?
Wesley.
CHESTER: Son, wait.
Let's go.
What...
Wesley.
Well, that was a hell
of a family reunion.
I had a mother-in-Iaw
Iike that, I just might take
a swing at her myself.
We checked with Cedar Creek PD
about the murder-suicide.
Jaina was 10
when it went down.
She moved in with an aunt
whose boyfriend
sexually assaulted her.
The parents said
that Wesley's always had
a soft spot for Jaina.
He even tried to get
his parents to take her in.
Let me guess, they passed.
After that, he went from
college-bound to truant.
It became all about Jaina.
Mara's seven years old,
so Jaina ran
when she was pregnant.
To a city where the predators
know a victim
when they see one.
But where are we on the rape?
Without a complaining witness,
it doesn't exist.
I don't know why
this guy is holding back.
But being this scared,
he knows his attackers.
Still got attempted murder,
unless you want to
hand it off.
Have I ever?
AII right, here's what we got.
Borland claimed that
he didn't know Wesley
when we showed him his photo,
but Wesley was paid by Mueller
for Borland's
alleged home repairs.
It's got to be
a drug connection.
Well, Iean on Borland.
We'II get an explanation.
Lab report says
Mueller's DNA is a match.
Any takers on Borland
matching, too?
We can't get a warrant
for his DNA
unless Mueller gives him up.
STABLER:
Let's bring them both in.
My client is willing to
cooperate fully.
But if the questions
go outside the scope,
I'II bury you in paper.
Well, we dream in triplicate,
so Iet's cut
the chest-thumping.
Wesley Jansen says
that he works for you.
We're acquaintances.
Then why'd you Iie to us
when you said
you didn't know him?
Most people don't want
to get involved.
I'm no different.
Sodomy in the First, along
with his convict history.
What do you think, Munch,
18 to 25?
Minimum.
I didn't rape anyone.
We're not allowed
to talk to you.
You asked for a Iawyer.
This is a no-brainer
with the DNA match
in Wesley Jansen.
Damn, I hope the perp
can do this kind of time.
He wouldn't have to
if he cooperated.
The D.A. Iikes to make deals.
What kind of work
did Wesley Jansen do for you?
Odd jobs,
You lied to us
about knowing him,
and you're lying right now,
He was gang-raped
by three men,
and we've ID'd one of his
attackers as your Iive-in,
Willem Mueller.
That's it. Interview's over.
What are the odds
the DNA sample from you
will match the evidence?
Get a court order,
otherwise hold your breath.
Mueller's facing
some pretty serious time,
so he's across the hall,
probably giving you up
right now.
There's nothing he can say
to incriminate me.
So, where you think
he'll do his time,
Dannemora or Sing Sing?
$100 on the big house
in Ossining,
He's got old friends up there,
You got to show me
the cash first,
We were making a movie.
Nobody got raped.
You can't talk to us
without your Iawyer.
I'II sign a release
if it'II get me out of here.
Hancock the bottom.
What kind of movie?
Gay porn.
I produce films.
I sent Willem Mueller
to pay Wesley
for his services.
One of the best group scenes
we've ever shot.
And why should
we believe that?
Well, I could screen
the film for you,
if you'd Iike.
So, Wesley's one of your
gay porn stars?
Don't be ridiculous.
He's not gay.
Gay-on-straight
sells a Iot of videos,
especially if it's bareback.
Wesley's strictly gay-for-pay
at 1,500 bucks a bang.
Well, now we know
why Wesley wasn't cooperating.
He didn't want us
digging into his background.
He's either ashamed
or he's afraid of somebody.
A straight guy wouldn't
want the world to know
he's doing gay porn.
Maybe he's in trouble
with the mob.
Porn is a multi-billion dollar
mom-and-pop industry now.
The mob got out of it
a Iong time ago.
And wise guys never walk away
from that much cheddar.
Your victim was shot
in the gut,
not in the heart or the head.
That is a slow, painful
way to die. The motive's
got to be personal.
You think it's a jealous
gay costar who bought
into the make-believe?
If it is a criminal element,
we can offer
Wesley protection.
Just remind him, whoever
shot him could come back
for another try.
Excuse me,
we're Iooking for the Jansens.
No one's answering their door.
Is he dead? I called
the ambulance. They got here
pretty quick, considering.
What happened?
I didn't mind
Iooking in on Wesley,
but the second time I went up,
he was out cold,
so I called 911.
Do you know which hospital?
Probably St. Martin's.
You know, no insurance.
Where's Jaina?
Well, she had to work.
She Ieft me this number.
I called her.
It was some management
company, and they said
they'd give her the message.
STABLER:
Pornography isn't illegal.
Making it isn't illegal.
Now is there some reason
you neglected to tell us?
It's none of your business.
Who shot you, Wesley?
I told you I wasn't raped.
I told you I wasn't gay.
So, why won't you believe me
when I say I don't know?
Because our experience
has been someone Iies once,
they make it a bad habit.
I didn't Iie.
Okay, omitting the truth
is the same thing.
I see the way you're
Iooking at me.
I'm scum because I make money
having sex. So, why do you
care who shot me?
Because it's our job.
I got nothing else to say.
Look, if somebody's after you,
then no one in your family
is safe.
Where's your wife?
You Ieave her out of this.
BENSON: Either you tell us
where she is,
or we will find your wife
and find out
how much she knows.
PIease don't involve Jaina.
You don't understand
what you're doing.
Then you start explaining
to us, because we're
running out of options here.
May I help you?
Jaina Jansen.
She in some kind of trouble?
If you could just wait,
I'II Iet them know
back there...
OMAN: Come on, Jaina. That's
it, honey. That's it, good.
Pick up the pace a Iittle.
Joey, just kneel down behind
her. AII right. A Iittle more
to the Ieft. Good. Good.
(STABLER WHISTLES)
What are you doing here?
You ruined my shot.
Who are you?
Police.
We need to talk to Jaina.
AII right, no, no, no,
everybody just relax.
We're not doing anything
illegal here, okay.
I'm Cal Oman,
the director of this film,
and I assure you
everything's in order.
Look, this isn't about you.
Can we do this Iater, please?
No, Jaina, you need to
get dressed,
because we need to talk.
Well, actually, she doesn't
have to, because
she's not under arrest.
We're making a movie here.
Time is money.
AII right,
stand over there, please.
Now, you know that Wesley's
back in the hospital?
Yeah, he called.
I was going to call him
back on my break. Is he okay?
He's fine.
Look, if I don't work,
I don't get paid,
and we need this money.
Look, am I gonna
have to call a Iawyer?
Give me the phone.
Why don't you call two?
They'II both tell you
to stay out of it.
Look, get a warrant
or get Iost. AII right?
This is my building,
and I don't want you here.
Mommy, can I have quarters
for the soda machine?
Jaina, I'm sorry.
I tried to get her,
but I couldn't stop her.
What in the hell
is your daughter
doing on a porn set?
Can I see my daughter, please?
She needs me.
You couldn't find
a baby-sitter?
No.
Wesley's sick.
I had to take her with me.
What about your in-Iaws?
Why not ask them?
So they can teach her
to hate me?
Besides, nobody
can take care of Mara
except me and Wes.
Yeah? Why's that?
I need to get her home.
You're not going anywhere,
and neither is Mara.
I didn't do anything wrong.
We're charging you
with child endangerment.
You took your daughter
to a porn set.
It's not exactly a healthy
and safe environment for kids.
PIease, don't do this.
If I go to jail,
who takes care of Mara?
Either Children's Services
or your in-Iaws.
She has cystic fibrosis.
She needs constant care.
I'm doing the best that I can.
There's doctor visits
and shots, pills.
Wesley's the only one
that knows how
to do her chest therapy,
and somebody has to
bring in a paycheck.
Okay, we'II consider
putting you on notice.
That means Children's Services
will check in on you
from time to time.
What's the catch?
Well, it's pretty obvious that
Wesley doesn't care about
his own well-being. Do you?
I can't help you.
Jaina, somebody tried
to kill your husband.
You cooperate with us,
and you can walk
out that door.
You're gonna have to
arrest me.
We threaten to take her kid,
and she still won't talk.
It's not a threat.
She endangered a child.
That's enough to remove
a minor from her care.
Jaina is obviously terrified.
If the mob is connected,
we're just adding
more pressure.
And the daughter's terminal.
I don't want to put
a sick child
with Children's Services.
Can't the grandparents
take custody?
Well, that's not gonna help
Wesley and Jaina.
Somebody's squeezing them
to keep quiet, but aren't we
just doing the same thing?
They're jerking us around.
If we have to force them
to cooperate,
I'm fine with that.
Yeah, Wesley got very agitated
when we told him
we were going to Jaina.
Maybe she's been
the target all along,
and he just got in the middle.
If we're thinking mob,
check into this pornographer,
Cal Oman,
see if he's a connected guy.
Ten minutes, then I gotta
block the next shot.
Vice gave us an earful about
you. Lots of charges
from extortion to blackmail.
Lots of trumped-up charges,
but no convictions.
Yet.
You ever thought about
doing a movie?
You Iook Iike
you'd be a real natural.
You still work for
the Santuccis?
Having friends
from the old neighborhood
is not a criminal offense.
I am a filmmaker, not a hood.
Who finances those movies?
Look, why don't you just quit
fishing and get to the point?
Okay, you're pretty small
potatoes in the porn industry.
Jaina Jansen's
your only big star.
Yeah.
STABLER: For such a big draw,
she doesn't work that much.
Her husband get in the way?
The Iess she works,
the more the public wants her.
Wesley moonlighting, I mean,
that must've pissed you off.
Why? I don't use him
that much,
and now with
the bareback-riding thing,
I won't use him at all.
Yeah, but married couples
don't use condoms,
so he's putting your star
at risk.
You know, if Jaina wants
to play Russian roulette,
that's her business.
I made her a star. I can make
another one just Iike her.
Yeah,
but wouldn't it be easier
just to get rid of Wesley?
Look, I hate to disappoint
you, but I didn't shoot
the bastard.
Okay, so, where were you
that night?
Right here. Prepping a movie.
Who were you with?
I was rehearsing one of
the new girls, Delia Sarton.
Just Iike I used to with Jaina
in the old days.
You and Jaina were involved?
Long time ago,
but I've moved on.
Jaina's got mileage.
Who wants to be with a chick
that's been with
a hundred guys?
So, where can we find
Delia Sarton?
She's getting a body wax.
My receptionist
will tell you where she is.
Hi.
Hi, Delia Sarton?
Yeah, that's me.
Cal said you wanted
to ask me questions.
Yeah. Did he mention why?
No, he didn't tell me
what to say,
if that's what you mean.
Where were you two nights ago?
From 8:30 to 1:00,
I was with Cal on set.
Do you always rehearse
that Iate?
AII the time.
How'd you get home?
I took a cab.
What cab company?
It was yellow.
What'd you do
before you went to rehearsal?
Who were you with?
Where'd you go?
I don't remember.
Did you know that
you can be charged
with obstruction of justice,
giving a false statement to
a police officer and perjury,
if this goes to trial?
Sixteen months to three years
in Bedford Hills prison.
Delia, do you want
to change your statement?
I didn't mean...
I just want to be a star
Iike Jaina. Cal gives her
all the best parts.
Is that what he promised you
if you vouched for him?
He set up a gang-bang
for Jaina in Vegas.
300 guys in 10 hours.
She's gonna be
on Howard Stern.
Cal's crazy about her.
What do you mean, crazy?
He says she belongs to him.
PIease don't tell on me.
If Cal finds out...
Don't worry.
"File no 745243.
People v, Jaina Jansen,
"One count,
child endangerment.
"One count, unlawful dealing
with a child."
Objection. Unlawful dealing
covers minors in bars,
obscenities and prostitution.
That isn't the case here.
Pornography is a form
of Iegal prostitution.
The minor's physical,
mental and emotional welfare
was corrupted.
I agree. How do you plead,
Mr. Schoenfeld?
Not guilty and request ROR.
The defendant
is a porn actress.
She took her daughter to work,
exposing her to an environment
of wanton sexual activity.
The minor child was confined
to an area where all members
of the cast are clothed.
My client did everything
to shield her daughter.
CABOT: Except to
get a baby-sitter.
The defendant's in-Iaws were
in town and were never called.
SCHOENFELD: The Iittle girl
suffers from cystic fibrosis.
She can't be Ieft
in the care of just anyone.
Then your client
should have thought of that
before she took an
innocent child to a porn set.
Your client has endangered
the welfare of a minor.
For the privilege
of her freedom,
I want $5,000, cash or bond.
Next case.
CLERK:
"Docket number 28763..."
We know Cal's connected
and we know he's got
a thing for your wife.
He tried to kill you.
Next time you're not
gonna be so Iucky.
Next time it might be
your daughter.
But maybe that's
what you want, huh?
I mean, you must be awful
tired of being saddled
with a sick kid.
You just calm down. Calm down.
AII right.
Now, you've just assaulted
a police officer
and I'm gonna frisk you,
just in case any of Cal's
friends are hanging around.
And then I'm gonna arrest you
unless you start
talking to us.
If I say anything,
Mara gets hurt
and I can't risk it.
Then give us your statement
so we can put Cal Oman away.
We can protect you.
No, you can't.
Jaina already tried to Ieave.
He said that he made her
and that she wasn't
going anywhere.
So he shot you
to prove it to her?
We never thought
he'd go that far.
He would've killed me
if that homeless guy
hadn't shown up.
So, stand up and say that.
My daughter is dying.
We do porn to pay
for her bills.
Do you understand that?
There is nothing
that I wouldn't do for her.
I'm going to bail my wife out.
If you keep coming after us,
you're just gonna
make it worse.
He's boxed in pretty tight.
Since Cal Oman
Iied about his alibi,
maybe we should bring him in
and do a Iittle two-on-one.
Well, it sounds Iike fun,
but that'II give him
a heads-up
and too much time to be
working out another
explanation with his friends.
Okay, so we pull our witness
in and do a Iineup.
He IDs Oman, we Iock him down,
with no way out.
That's if Munch
and Fin can still Iocate Phil.
What a surprise,
Phil's back in rehab.
His ID won't be any good.
That's for Cabot to decide.
It's a waste of time. What?
Don't you think you're taking
Phil's relapse too personally?
He's jeopardizing the case
and making my job harder.
I always take that personally.
Early on,
I had a partner Iike you
used to get worked up.
What happened?
He ate his gun.
I need you to focus, Phil.
I've got some pictures
you need to see.
Okay. I'm hurting bad.
We need you to identify
the guy you saw
do the shooting.
What shooting?
That's it.
I think we're done here.
Where's the fire, AIex?
We need this.
Is it against the rules
to remind him of the incident?
Jog his memory about what he
went through and nothing else.
How'd you get that scratch
on your face, Phil?
It hurts.
Phil, you wanna be a stupid
dick and kill yourself,
you go right ahead.
I need you to Iook
at these damn pictures.
You gave me orange juice.
You're a nice guy.
Yeah, I'm a nice guy.
Look at the pictures.
You see anybody?
Brunette. Snub-nose revolver.
I can't take these to a judge.
Your witness
is coming off of heroin.
He was clean
during his statement.
We got a tox screen,
thanks to my partner,
so we're covered.
Can't you call in a favor?
After working with this unit
I don't have that many Ieft.
Move! Move!
COP 1: CIear.
COP 2: CIear.
It's Cal Oman.
Okay. Get me an evidence bag.
I want Prints and Ballistics
on this.
Tell the Iab. Make it a rush.
Entry wound's through
the back. He was running away.
Well, that tends to happen
when you're facing
the barrel of a gun.
AII right, take it easy.
We got a sick child in there.
COP 1: CIear.
CIear.
COP 2: CIear.
They're running.
With Wesley's prints
all over the murder weapon,
this goes out citywide,
he becomes a mark.
Well, they're broke,
so they can't get that far.
We know where his parents
are staying. Let's go alone.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
My son didn't do this.
WESLEY: Mom, you have to do
this three times a day, okay?
She will whine.
She'II say it hurts.
You can't Iet that stop you.
She will die if you don't.
Say you understand.
I understand.
On your feet, Wesley.
PIease. Just give me a second,
please?
There's six positions.
Chest, back,
both sides, all right?
Five minutes each.
Try to make her cough after.
If she gets a fever,
call her doctor,
Dr. Lawrence Baylord.
That's her pulmonologist.
See she takes pancreatic
enzymes also.
Don't worry.
I'II take good care of her.
(CRYING) Don't go.
Sweetie, sweetie.
AII right, Iisten.
Grandma's going to finish,
because I have to go
with the police.
Daddy, please!
Okay, we're not gonna cuff you
in front of her, but you
have to come with us now.
I Iove you, honey.
Wesley.
It'II be okay.
PIease don't go.
(MARA CRYING)
Come on, Mara, be a good girl.
PIease, Daddy, don't go!
PIease.
Daddy, I'm gonna miss you.
You have the right
to remain silent.
You have the right...
Daddy, please!
Daddy!
(COUGHING)
My parents took out a second
mortgage on their house
for Mara.
She's on the transplant Iist.
She's gonna be
in the hospital for awhile.
Jaina didn't need to do
the gang-bang anymore.
So, I just went over there,
and I tried to reason
with Cal.
Reason with the man
who shot you?
It sounds more Iike
a motive for murder to me.
Well, that's not true. I mean,
I'm in enough trouble
as it is,
why would I need to Iie?
Because it's the difference
between parole
and a Iife sentence.
I didn't mean to kill him.
We fought,
and he pulled the gun,
and we struggled with it,
and it went off.
Are you claiming self-defense?
Yeah. Well, yeah.
That's how it happened.
Well, the evidence doesn't
support your story.
There were no signs
of a struggle in that room.
And if it went down Iike
you say, the prints on the gun
would be smudged.
Where's Jaina?
She's taking care
of a few things.
She's moving back to Arkansas
with my parents.
She's gonna Iive there.
Okay.
You need to change your story,
and you need to do it now,
because once we walk out
this room, we're gonna
recommend to the prosecution
that they go for the maximum.
But if you tell us the truth,
we will try
to get you Ieniency.
Our phone was ringing
off the hook.
Guys were calling
from L.A. and Vegas.
They wanted to sign her up
for bigger and better stunts.
You know, just Iining up
to turn her into
a sideshow freak.
So, you shot him?
I just wanted her out.
I didn't mean for him to die.
"File number 565429.
People v, Wesley Jansen,
"Manslaughter
in the First Degree."
How do you plead?
I'm guilty, Your Honor.
The defendant confessed to SVU
detectives and signed
his own statement.
We're satisfied
with the facts.
Fine. Remand until allocution.
Next case.
CLERK:
"Docket number 51 28763."
Take some.
Detectives.
Look, is there anything
you can do for my son?
Mr. Jansen, your son
has confessed to homicide.
There's nothing...
It's completely
out of our hands.
You know,
it's just not in him.
STABLER: Well,
with all due respect, sir,
you haven't seen your son
in a number of years.
I know my son didn't do this.
This is her fault.
You keep blaming Jaina
for Wesley's bad judgment.
Well, where the hell is she?
She told us she's not
going back to Arkansas.
Wesley's going through hell.
She's nowhere to be found.
Is Mara going with her?
Mara's going to Iive with us.
Well,
even if we wanted to help,
the preliminary Iab report
shows your son's prints
on the murder weapon.
I know people change,
but my son
didn't shoot anyone.
I hunt. I have rifles.
Wesley, he never touched them.
Never.
Did you find any other prints
besides our perp's?
None. No smudges
and no partials,
but I did find prints
belonging to the victim
on the other rounds
inside the weapon.
That doesn't make any sense
unless you wiped it clean.
Can you tell us which hands
made the prints?
His right.
That's a tight trigger.
Wesley doesn't have the
dexterity to fire that gun.
So, why did he wipe it off
and put his prints
all over it?
Who has he been protecting
from day one?
You Ieaving?
I've got a bus to catch.
You weren't in court today.
I just couldn't deal with it.
Your husband's going
to prison. Don't you care?
Of course I care,
but I have to accept it
and deal with reality.
I gotta start over.
They have porn in Arkansas,
or are you just giving it up?
Porn isn't what you think.
A Iot of it's fake.
And there's no way
I'm going back
to where small town people
with small minds judge me.
So, where are you headed?
Vegas, then L.A.
It's my Iast chance.
I really need this.
If I'm not a star
before I'm 30,
I can forget about
being a producer,
a director Iater on.
What about your daughter?
She's gonna stay
with my in-Iaws.
I'II make enough money
and send it back
till I get a nice place,
and I'm gonna hire
the best Iawyer for Wes.
So, you get to be
the porn queen
while your husband takes
the fall for a crime
he didn't commit?
You think he's innocent?
The evidence proves
that he is.
Thank God.
When's he getting out?
Why don't we go inside
and talk about it?
Yeah, Iet's go back inside.
Have you fired a gun recently?
No.
Then you'II agree
to a gun shot residue test.
Why?
If we find traces of gunpowder
on your skin
or on your clothes,
you're gonna need to
explain that to a judge.
Gunpowder doesn't wash off
right away, so if there
are traces, we can find it.
We're gonna need
the clothes you were wearing
the day Cal Oman was shot.
So, are they in this bag here
or on the floor?
This isn't happening.
The court will probably go
easy on you.
Terminally ill child.
You were a minor
who was coerced
into child pornography.
There won't be a dry eye
in the house.
We know you shot Cal Oman.
We just have to get you
to the Iab,
and we can prove it.
He slapped me around.
He threatened me.
I had to shoot him.
He was shot in the back,
Jaina, trying to escape.
You didn't know him.
I had to defend myself.
So, then you Iet Wesley
make the sacrifice.
I was a wreck.
I told him what happened.
And I didn't ask him to,
but he knows Mara needs me.
But you're not going
to Arkansas to be with her.
You're Ieaving your child
with her grandparents.
You don't understand
what it is Iike
to be trapped with a sick kid,
doing three guys at a time
to pay off my debts.
I have a $50,000 contract
waiting for me in Las Vegas.
And Cal would've
taken all of it.
He was never gonna Iet me go.
Well, neither will
Bedford Hills. At Ieast
not for 15 years minimum.
What happens to Jaina now?
Your wife's pled not guilty.
She's going for self-defense.
What are her chances?
Doesn't Iook good.