In the criminal
justice system...
sexually based offenses
are considered
especially heinous.
In New York City,
the dedicated detectives
who investigate
these vicious felonies...
are members of an elite squad
known as
the Special Victims Unit.
These are their stories.
So you going Britney Spears
on me now or what?
Eartha Kitt.
Who?
I gotta run.
Hi. Where's Mom?
Took the twins to Joey Stemple's
birthday party. That your boyfriend?
No.
Introduce me.
How long has he been
out of prison?
Dad, stop.
What's his name?
Ryan Witherspoon.
Witherspoon?
He go to your school?
He's going to post
next year, okay?
Okay, I guess he's cute.
On the LIE
a multi-vehicle accident
just before
the mid-town tunnel...
has traffic clogged up...
Is that a tattoo?
No.
Where'd you get it?
Well, you've got tattoos.
I was 18 and in the service.
It's henna. It washes off.
Why didn't you
just tell me that?
I just did.
You're such a cop.
Yeah, wait till you have kids.
All the little Witherspoons.
Move.
Stay here, lock the doors,
roll up that window.
Stabler, Manhattan SVU,
watch yourself.
Hurry up, there's someone
under there.
Get it out!
All right, call it in,
secure the scene.
Don't look at that.
It's all right.
Capt. Cragen...
one of your detectives
reports while bar hopping...
picking up a suspect
and having sex with him.
Another confesses to fantasies
about killing suspects.
Just what kind of unit
are you running, Captain?
I was told that,
whatever the results...
that, the actual content of these
psych evaluations would be kept private.
Doctor-patient privilege
is sacrosanct.
Promiscuity
and fantasies of murder?
Detectives Jeffries and Stabler
will undergo further evaluation...
and will submit formal
explanations to this committee.
I have assigned prosecutor A.D.A.
Cabot to adjudicate SVU cases.
You will apprise A.D.A. Cabot
of your case file asap.
If I...
Robbery unit next.
Capt. Cragen?
Miss Cabot.
Alex.
Yeah, right, of course.
Let's not start off
on the wrong foot.
My assignment to SVU preceded the
behavioral problems under your command.
Behavioral problems?
I'm trying to be polite.
Tiptoeing around
the road kill?
Where there's smoke.
Who do you sleep with,
Miss Cabot?
Are you so new at this...
that you haven't run into somebody
you'd like to skip due process with?
I'll apprise you asap
if asap can be tomorrow.
You understand,
I have behavioral issues.
Certainly.
Breakfast, then?
Two unis and a robbery
detective from the 17
were kicked over
to Public Affairs.
Reevaluation stinks.
Truly. Best crime stats in 30
years and they're reevaluating?
It's how it works. We get rid
of the criminals they fear...
they start fearing us.
Public hates tough cops,
until they need one.
Jeffries, my office.
You told the psychologist
you slept with a suspect?
What? No, that's not
what I said.
Well, that's how
they interpreted it.
I'm gonna limit
your field time.
You're giving me desk duty?
You need time to prepare a formal
response for the Morris Commission.
I am not explaining my sex
life to the Morris Commission!
That's enough! I don't
like it either, Monique...
but yelling at me is
not gonna solve anything.
Jimmy Buffet in town?
I was taking Maureen home
from the beach...
see two uniforms fighting this
fire up by Black Bank Marsh.
I stop to help...
turns out to be a body,
gunshot wound to the head...
flames leaping off the crotch.
My daughter sees the whole thing.
Is she all right?
I don't know, Kathy picked her
up. I was on the scene all night.
In Queens?
Dump job. Looks like the victim
was shot in his West Side apartment.
Elliot.
Off to a scene.
Now.
You okay?
What possessed you to tell the
shrink in your psych evaluation...
that you fantasized
about killing suspects?
Wait a minute.
I said perps not suspects.
Well, the Morris Commission doesn't
see a distinction. They're inquiring.
Inquiring into what?
My private thoughts?
They're supposed to be house-cleaning
the department of rogue cops.
My job at risk?
Yeah.
Victim's Andrew Croft, 42.
Dumped vehicle may be a Lexus. DMV
has one registered to this address...
it's missing.
Was he packing or unpacking?
He was transferred here
a month ago...
by his new company,
Radial Velocity.
Radial Velocity?
Yeah.
Edge-of-the-envelope defense
contractor? What's he do for them?
I'm still on his home life. He's
single, lived with his son, Michael...
approximately 16. Neighbors
say that they argued a lot.
Serious feng shui problem.
Neighbors hear this argument?
Everyone was out.
Beach, the park.
This the son?
Probably an old picture. I found
some books labeled MacArthur High...
so I called, but there's
no Michael Croft registered...
but the books are
all bar coded.
I'll take Radial Velocity with Jeffries
if Cragen will let her out of the office.
What?
Morris Commission.
Okay, what the hell's
going on?
The psych evaluation?
Yeah?
I said I felt like
killing child molesters.
Okay, so how can they
have a problem with that?
The commissions are all cops.
Yeah, well...
when was the last time one of
them stood in a room like this?
This belonged
to Michael Croft?
This is Michael Goren's book,
he's absent today.
You want to speak to his
guidance counselor, Miss Scheider.
Okay, thank you.
I need a release
from Michael's guardian
to give you his file.
Mrs. Scheider, Michael's
father was murdered yesterday.
Mr. Croft?
Yes.
Mr. Croft wasn't
Michael's father.
Foster parent?
Guardian.
You can see the problem with
getting his signature then.
Right. This is terrible.
What happened
to Michael's parents?
I don't know.
He was born in Belgium...
that's all that's there.
You have a current photo
of him?
No, Michael's a new student. We don't
take school pictures until homecoming.
He's an AIB student.
He could be a straight A
student if he made an effort.
Why, is he lazy?
Withdrawn.
I feel like Michael's in some pain that
makes him gravitate to troublemakers.
Yeah? Like who?
Primarily, Jason Sloane.
What's with
the beach bum look?
It's casual Monday.
Cops do that?
Michael Goren.
You know where he is?
I don't know.
When was the last time
you saw Michael?
Saturday. He stayed
at my house.
So you guys are close?
No, but he hates going home to the
creep, and I've got an extra bed.
What creep?
Andrew.
Andrew was shot yesterday,
he's dead.
Excellent.
Well, he was a bad guy. I've
seen him slap Michael around.
So where's Michael now?
Didn't I say I don't know?
You don't know where he is, but
you're the only friend he's got?
He has friends. Some girl
calls him from wherever.
Wherever?
Yeah. Wherever.
I'd love to help you do your job,
but I'm a high school student.
Thanks.
Detectives. I'm Craig Prince.
I was Andrew Croft's
supervisor. This is Ralph Noble.
Security.
It's a sad day for us.
I wish I could say more. Anyway, this
is everything from Croft's office...
except what's classified.
Was Mr. Croft's job
classified?
He was a guidance system
analyst, that's all I can say.
He just transferred here.
Can't be more specific.
Who was to be notified
in case of an emergency?
Detective, it's classified.
Please, the man
had a son.
If something happens,
who looks out for him?
That's not our concern.
Do we have to get
a court order?
Well, you can try.
What are the odds
you have a picture...
of Senator Joseph McCarthy
tattooed on your ass?
Leave the dolly in the garage.
Radial Velocity's redacted
1,200 pages of documents...
down to
the occasional adverb.
There's not a complete sentence
in anything Craig Prince gave us.
It is national security.
We're looking
for a murderer...
and the victim's missing kid
and Craig Prince is giving us:
"Here's your hat,
what's your hurry?"
You'd think they'd want to
help us catch Croft's killer...
instead of burying everything under
the rubric of national security.
It's too convenient, there's
something else going on here.
It's Munch. No, I want to see
your spook ass now.
What do you want, Munch?
Anything I can get...
on a couple of missile geeks
from Radial Velocity.
Who?
Craig Prince.
He's no geek,
he's a suit.
Well, what's his story?
We've been looking
at Prince.
Why?
Kickbacks. Guy's living
way beyond his paycheck.
New co-op on Central Park
West, new A8 in the garage.
He disperses classified money.
Ralph Noble?
Head of security.
Yeah?
Vietnam vet, Purple Heart...
Silver Star,
Medal of Honor.
Anything else?
He was hoping for an Oscar,
but he's not in show business.
Man's a war hero, Munch.
Andrew Croft?
Guidance systems. This guy's
the king of the missile geeks...
but I got nothing.
Croft's a black hole.
Who does that?
DOD, NSA.
Why?
We can fire a missile off
a ship in the Gulf of Oman.
20 minutes
and 600 miles later,
it's entering the front door
of a Hezbollah safe house...
in Al Basrah, doesn't even
touch the doorframe.
Anybody can build a bomb, Munch,
but nobody delivers them like we do.
Guidance systems, John.
What are we willing
to pay for them?
Anything. Erase your enemies,
erase your past.
Like I said,
Croft's a black hole.
Why the interest?
Croft's dead.
Michael, his 16-year-old ward is
missing. Prince and Noble aren't talking.
How'd Croft buy it?
Bullet to the head,
Bunsen to the crotch.
Ouch.
Yeah.
What's the matter?
The fire.
Come here.
The fire, Daddy, the fire.
It's okay, it's all right.
Look, the recidivism rate for rapists
and child molesters is far more onerous...
than that of murderers.
The public knows that.
The public cares
about victims' rights.
And live victims give better
sound bites than dead ones.
They vote, too.
I don't.
I used to, but, well,
look at the choices.
I don't much care for
city politics these days.
The mollifying,
the scapegoating.
That's why there's a Morris
Commission. That's why you're at SVU.
I gotta tell you
something, Alex.
I really don't see
why I should trust you.
Captain.
I intend to stand on your shoulders
to reach a broader Constituency.
Why would I do anything
to shorten my grasp?
Okay.
Maybe this could be the beginning
of a beautiful friendship.
Our open cases.
According to the M.E.,
Andrew Croft was killed...
by a. 38 slug, behind
the left ear, point-blank.
Burning was post mortem.
You got a weapon?
It hasn't turned up yet,
but Croft owned a. 38.
What about the boy?
Still missing,
along with Croft's Lexus.
Maybe the kid is dead.
Why do you say that?
My contact at the G says that
Croft's supervisor, Craig Prince...
is being looked at
for kickbacks.
So what?
Well, maybe Croft had evidence,
maybe Croft was involved...
and they had
a lethal disagreement.
Looks like sexual homicide...
not an assassination.
Very clever,
to throw us off track.
I gotta hand it to you. When you go with
a theory, you really go with a theory.
You think this stuff
doesn't happen?
No, I'm not saying...
Let's just keep our heads...
in the game here, all right?
Now the connection between Prince and
Croft warrants further investigation.
But in the meantime, we've
still got a missing kid...
and until I know otherwise, I'm
going to assume he's still alive.
Now you guys, find the Lexus,
find the boy.
Munch, Jeffries, let's find out
how good this new ADA really is.
We need a search warrant
for Radial Velocity.
You want me to secure
a search warrant
for the offices
of a defense contractor...
to search classified national
security files for evidence...
in a sexually
motivated homicide?
Yes, you got a problem
with that?
Judge Harriman, please. This is
Alex Cabot in the DA's office.
Uncle Bill? Good.
Look, I need a little favor.
You've got to be
kidding me.
You said we should try.
You do not just barge in here
without proper notice.
Read the fine print. Now step aside, or
I'll have these officers restrain you.
Great, thank you. That was the state
police. We've located Croft's Lexus...
upstate Millbrook,
right outside Poughkeepsie.
Croft transferred
from Poughkeepsie.
Locals are surveilling it
till we get there.
Great. Find something.
Blood. Pop it.
Nobody home. House belongs
to Richard and Darlene Sadler.
They own a hardware store
over on Elm street.
Their daughter, Denise,
attends the high school.
Well, looks like we found
the girlfriend from wherever.
Slow down!
Denise is in
her fourth period class.
We were hoping that she might be
able to help us locate Michael Goren.
Leave the spurs home
next time.
Great kid Michael.
What do you mean locate?
He's been missing
since Sunday.
Michael's not missing.
He's in our mentoring program.
Let's go, Jimmy. Nice Job. Good
job. All right, everybody...
just like Jimmy,
use the inside of your foot.
Michael.
This is about Andrew,
isn't it?
Do you understand
these rights?
Yes.
Do you understand that you don't have
to talk to us without your lawyer?
I wanna talk.
Go ahead.
I killed him.
He hit me, I hit him back.
First time I did that,
he went crazy...
got his gun,
said he was gonna kill me.
I tackled him and then
I heard this loud pop.
When I looked down,
he was laying there...
dead.
Then what?
I wrapped him in the sheets
and dragged him to the car.
The next thing I knew
I was driving back home.
To Millbrook?
Yes.
Michael, what's going on?
It's nothing.
I'm okay, Denise.
It's okay.
This can't be right.
Step back...
Not Michael.
Step back, people,
give us a little room please.
Michael, we're all
behind you on this.
Give us a little room,
please.
What are you doing? They got
a confession, made an arrest.
That can all go back
to Radial Velocity.
Too tidy.
Can't stand letting go
of a theory, can you?
It's not theory, Olivia.
Confession, next case.
I don't buy it.
Heat of the moment murder
is one thing...
but taking time to set fire
to the victim's crotch.
What'd you call that, Elliot?
Sexually motivated homicide.
You bet. Perpetrated by a child
on a guardian. Text book...
except for the little matter of the
blank pages, thanks to Radial Velocity.
I want to know
where they stand on this deal.
Me, too.
You have an appointment.
Look, Captain, you know, this
time of day, Skodas' office...
it's gotta be
an hour drive.
Elliot,
this is must do, now.
The good news is that
he's around the corner...
doing some outreach work
at Christ's Church.
He's happy to see you now.
Thank you.
I'm not talking to you.
Fine.
I'll just sit here.
You know, I may lose my job because
of the last shrink I talked to.
Why?
Because she violated
her ethical obligation...
to keep my confidence.
If we believe a patient might do violence
to someone, we're legally bound to...
I have never done violence
to anyone.
Why would she think you would?
Ask her.
Det. Stabler,
we've talked before.
Come on, give me the benefit
of the doubt, will you?
I'm sorry,
I haven't slept a lot lately.
Why not?
I'm worried
about losing my job.
I'm angry.
At?
Are we really gonna
do this dance again?
I mean, what do you want me to say?
That I fantasized about killing the perp?
Did you?
Yeah, you're damn right
I did...
and this time I fed him my gun
and I pulled that trigger.
Until I caught him and then
there he is, he's just...
He's a kid, he's a good kid. He
tutors Down syndrome children.
He's a straight A student,
he's a star athlete...
he's Millbrook township's
favorite son.
Now how that jives
with cold-blooded murder...
How long have you been
on the force?
14 years.
In all those years, how many
murders have actually made sense?
None. But...
some I understood.
But this one...
you let get
under your skin. Why?
This one, my daughter saw.
Hey, how'd it go?
I talked too much, again.
Where's Jeffries?
Her turn on the couch, and while
you were probing your inner child...
we did some probing of our own.
Sent Croft's prints to NCIC.
You printed the corpse?
So?
And?
Nothing.
So?
I mean nothing, nada, bupkis.
Zip. No parking tickets,
no birth records.
Nothing to prove he
even existed before 1991.
The year he went to work
for Radial Velocity.
So, we're going through the stuff
we got from the search warrant...
we find this passport issued
10 years ago from San Diego.
We call the local PD, ask them
to run him, bang, we get a hit.
But not to Andrew Croft.
Then who?
George Kazinski,
a convicted sexual predator.
Andrew Croft,
a. k. a George Kazinski.
Little George
liked little boys.
Andrew Croft's been
one busy guy.
11 arrests...
five aliases,
four convictions.
How'd you track him?
San Diego PD faxed us his rap sheet. We
followed his priors back from there...
department by department,
conviction by conviction.
Only the feds
can erase a file.
Radial Velocity is the feds.
That's why they're called
a military-industrial complex.
You're accusing the Federal government of
sanctioning the sexual abuse of a child.
Please tell me
you have a motive.
Where did you find these?
That's classified.
There's only a handful of people that can
calibrate the trajectory of a missile...
to within a hair's breadth
of Saddam's mustache.
Andrew Croft was one of them.
Couldn't let a little thing like
pedophilia undermine national security.
If a child is ruined
in the process?
That's not our concern.
Detective...
there are many things that take a back
seat to national security. However...
if I had known Croft was a pedophile,
I never would have hired him.
Right, and there were
no Nazis in NASA.
Mr. Noble will see you out.
You don't talk much,
do you?
Not much fight left
in the old soldier?
Don't you question
my patriotism, mister.
That's Mister Detective
to you.
Take a little bit of tarnish
off that Medal of Honor.
We can find
our own way out, thanks.
Why're you provoking him?
Guy's a war hero. Put his life
on the line for principle.
He's gotta be gagging
stonewalling Croft's pedophilia
to protect Radial Velocity.
Assuming he still has principles.
War was a long time ago, John.
Principles die harder than people.
I want a shot at what's left of his.
Wonder what he's doing
for lunch?
My parents died in a car wreck
when I was eight.
The only other family
I had was Nana.
She was old and in a hospital.
Andrew offered
to take care of me.
You're Belgian and Andrew's
American. How did you two hook up?
Andrew used to hang out
at soccer practice.
Whose soccer practice?
Mine.
And this is when you
were 8 years old?
Yeah.
He and Dad worked at NATO in
Brussels. Dad was a janitor.
He was proud to have a rocket
scientist as his friend.
Said I was lucky to have such an
important man take an interest in me.
How did he
take an interest?
Andrew said
I was a natural athlete.
Yeah, we saw your trophies.
He got me sailing lessons,
tennis lessons...
My dad couldn't afford them.
After your parents died,
Andrew brought you to America?
First Bosnia, Israel,
then Millbrook.
I finally made some friends.
Yeah, you even
had a girlfriend.
Denise.
Bet you weren't too happy
about leaving her.
I never felt like that
about anybody.
I mean, not just her,
her parents...
They felt like a real family.
Michael, did you know
that in 1990...
Andrew was convicted of sexually
assaulting an 11 year-old boy?
No.
When was the first time
he assaulted you?
He didn't.
What are you talking about?
Well, in my experience, child
molesters, they don't stop.
You were a child.
He didn't touch me!
Michael, you were
in a bad situation.
You're safe now.
You don't have to lie anymore.
I'm not lying! I'm not!
He didn't touch me.
He didn't.
Thanks for the heads up.
I think I've got
the EED defense.
Not unless your client
changes his tune.
Are we working
for the defense now?
Yeah. You don't volunteer to do
hard time because you're embarrassed.
This kid is hiding something.
Okay, maybe an accomplice.
Maybe somebody who scares him
more than Andrew.
At what point did courage and
integrity buckle to income?
Don't ever get in my face
about money.
If I cared about money I
wouldn't have been in the service.
What do you care about?
Protecting the reputation
of a dead pedophile...
part of
national security now?
I'm not protecting
Croft's reputation.
What are you protecting?
Croft's missile guidance expertise
was critical in the Gulf War.
You erase sodomy convictions
for national security?
We didn't erase
his convictions.
What? Is there another way
to say it?
Croft's felony record red-flagged
him every time he crossed a border.
A day's delay was a lifetime
in a war moving that fast.
So Radial Velocity
erased his past.
We were depleting
our arsenal of smart bombs...
at more than $1 million
a minute.
At that price the Pentagon
wanted pin-point precision.
A complaint was filed
in the State department.
A firewall was built around Croft
so Immigration wouldn't red-flag him.
When the war ended
the wall should've come down.
I can't tell you why it
didn't, I just don't know!
Meanwhile, a convicted
child molester...
applies for guardianship
of an 8-year-old and...
No red flags. I'm sorry.
My God!
Eleven arrests,
four convictions...
more than we knew about,
one in Canada.
This is despicable.
Get me Todd Earl at Justice.
Justice?
We need to secure
the chain of evidence.
We didn't bring this to you so
you could make a federal case.
What about Michael?
What about him?
He's a child. A child raised
by a pedophile for eight years.
He was molested.
He denies it.
There's no evidence here
to contradict that denial.
Are you saying
he wasn't abused?
I'm certain he was.
However,
absent Michael's admission...
you're asking me to soft-pedal
premeditated murder.
You're protecting
your won-loss ratio.
Elliot.
It's okay, Captain.
Stabler's judgment is clouded by the
stress of the Morris Commission's review.
And the fact that Michael did what he
fantasizes about. Kill a perpetrator.
It's not my fantasy, and I
stand with Det. Stabler on this.
The kid had choices.
He could have walked away,
told a teacher, told a cop.
Instead he murdered.
We let him skate on this...
what kind of choice will he make the
next time he faces an untenable situation?
All right, but either
he corroborates the abuse...
or I ask the grand jury for
an indictment on murder two.
No.
Michael, please...
Michael...
Andrew Croft abused at least
11 other children.
He's a sexual predator.
Michael, he can't
hurt you now.
You don't understand.
I won't. I can't.
You're a victim.
No, I'm not!
I'm not! I told you what
happened. I will stay in jail!
I will, but, please,
leave me alone.
It's murder two. He's
returning his own indictment.
Sorry, Captain.
Dad?
What are you doing up?
Couldn't sleep.
What's the matter?
You got nightmares?
You have to sleep
to have nightmares.
Right, what was I thinking?
Want something
to drink?
No.
Dad...
what that boy Michael
did to that man...
That man was supposed
to take care of Michael...
and instead he molested him.
He abused him physically, he betrayed
his trust, and I think Michael...
just had enough.
So what happens now?
He's probably gonna
go to prison.
All he's gotta do
is tell the truth.
What is it with you kids?
It's hard to talk
to adults.
Why?
You're always judging us. You
expect us to be like you...
and you get mad
if we're not.
It's just easier
to talk to our friends.
What if you
don't have any friends?
Everybody's got friends.
Yeah? Well,
who do you talk to?
Dad.
You talk
to Ryan Witherspoon?
More than you talk to Mom.
Could the wound
have been inflicted
during a struggle for the gun?
Not likely.
Why not?
The size
of the entry wound...
the force at which it entered
suggests close range.
But there was no stippling.
Stippling is?
When lead leaves the muzzle, it's followed
by the charge that fires it, the gunpowder.
At close range it leaves a residue,
point blank it embeds in the skin.
That's stippling.
The size and force of the
entry and the lack of stippling
lead you to conclude?
The gun was three to four feet from
the victim's head when it was fired.
The victim's reach was only 32 inches.
He couldn't have held the gun...
three feet from his skull, much less
fired it into the back of his head.
The body was discovered
wrapped in a sheet.
It was blood-soaked from a head wound
and the genital region was on fire.
Where?
In the dunes about 50 yards
off Cross Bay Boulevard...
a medical bracelet on the victim indicated
he lived at West 83rd in Manhattan.
Blood splattered the headboard,
wall, and lamp in the master bedroom.
Did the blood pattern
indicate anything to you?
Yes, that the victim had been
shot while lying in the bed.
Any signs of a struggle?
No.
Forced entry?
The victim's car
was missing?
State police located it
in Millbrook, New York.
The murder weapon
was found locked in the trunk.
Who had the keys?
Michael Goren.
How'd it go in there?
The kid's toast.
I've been thinking about
something Maureen said last night,
something about friends.
What about them?
You up
for taking a little ride?
Denise, how long
were you seeing Michael?
What should I say?
I really want to help him.
You can help him
by telling us the truth.
We were dating
about three months.
He ever talk
about Andrew?
Denise?
Did he?
Please.
They didn't get along.
My dad would let Michael stay in our
spare bedroom when Andrew was out of town.
My parents really liked him.
Sometimes Michael lied about Andrew
being gone, so he could stay over.
Did Andrew ever find out?
I think he knew.
He object?
Not after that thing
with Danny.
Who's Danny?
Danny Burrell.
Michael's best friend.
What happened?
I don't know.
But it had to be bad.
I mean, one day
they're best friends
and the next day, it's like
they hate each other.
Heads up, Mueller!
Heads up! Danny Burrell!
Yeah?
Front and center.
We're not friends anymore.
Why not?
Guy's weird, that's all.
What do you mean?
Weird, how?
Just weird.
Did Andrew Croft
attack you?
Did Michael
tell you that?
Why don't you tell us
about it?
Man, he swore!
I'm sorry
I can't talk in front of her.
That's okay.
Mike and me played ball.
Okay.
We went to his house
afterwards to clean up.
He said that Andrew was gone, so I
used his shower, and when I got out...
he was standing there.
Andrew?
Yeah. He was naked.
He was touching himself.
He wanted to dry me off.
He's just a creep.
Anyway, he said that Michael was too
swarthy but I was perfect for him.
He grabbed me, I fought him
off, I screamed for Mike...
and I finally got the door
open, and Michael was...
He was just standing there.
So, I just grabbed my clothes
and I ran. I forgot my Nikes.
You and Michael talk
after that?
No way. I told the guy
to leave me alone.
I think it's disgusting
what he and Andrew were doing.
You think
Michael liked it?
What do you think? I mean, Michael's
6 foot, guy benches, what, 220 pounds?
He could kick his ass if he
didn't like him doing him.
He was eight years old
when Andrew started doing him.
Eight-year-olds
can't fight back.
Now you tell me where a
16 year-old's gonna turn...
when his best friend
turns on him?
You said the gun went off
in the midst of a struggle?
Yes.
The police found no signs of a
struggle. How do you explain that?
I don't know.
That's because there was
no struggle, was there?
We struggled.
Over the gun?
Yes.
And it went off?
In both your hands?
Yes.
The Coroner found no trace of
gunpowder on the deceased's hands.
I told you
what happened.
Who is Danny Burrell?
He's my friend.
Did you witness the deceased
sexually assault Danny Burrell?
No!
Danny will testify the
deceased sexually assaulted him
and that you witnessed it.
Are you saying
he's lying?
Did Andrew Croft sexually
assault Danny Burrell?
Yes.
And you, too?
Since I was eight.
You shot him to stop him
from molesting you?
No!
I hated it,
but I was used to it.
I shot him because he was
bringing over his friend.
What friend?
In Millbrook, this guy
came up sometimes.
Andrew made me
do things with him.
When we moved here,
I thought it was over.
But then I come home
from school and he's there!
I mean we moved right
across the street from him!
Andrew was bad enough,
but both of them...
I begged him.
Who is this man?
He'll kill me.
He can't hurt you.
You don't know his powers.
Michael, you're in the custody of the
City of New York. He can't get to you.
He can get to anybody.
And he will
to protect his secret.
A child molester only has power
as long as his secret is kept.
You tell the truth, his power is
gone. What's his name, Michael?
I heard them talk about it.
Nobody did anything.
Talk about what?
Who, Michael?
Andrew and...
and Craig Prince.
They killed that boy in
Belgium and nobody did anything!
When did this happen?
What boy?
I was eight.
It was in the papers there.
Nobody did anything.
Craig Prince can get away
with anything.
You're gonna protect me?
Write-offs in the third
quarter adjusted by the...
Craig, good news!
Excuse me,
this is a classified briefing.
Yeah, Croft's ward, Michael.
The grand jury voted man two.
DA's willing to cut him a deal.
I don't see
what that has to do...
Even better news,
you're under arrest...
for sexual abuse, sodomy, assault and
endangering the welfare of a child.
You're hurting me!
Not our concern.
Craig Prince, you have
the right to remain silent.
If you give up that right, anything you
do or say can and will be used against you.
Capt. Cragen?
This little boy's mother stuck his hands on
a frying pan until his fingers burned off.
This rape victim...
required 12 hours of surgery to
have a steel plate into her head...
after her attacker pummeled
her with a claw hammer.
This one didn't make it.
Is there anybody on this panel who
doesn't share Det. Stabler's anger...
for the perpetrators?
This man is a good cop.
As his commanding officer,
I stand with him...
and every good cop who faces
these horrors day after day...
and has the strength to
keep their impulses in check.
Now if you can look at these
pictures and not understand that...
the problem here
isn't Elliot Stabler, is it?
Yeah, that's done.
Hello?
All right, yeah, go get
the kids dinner... Yeah.
Kathleen!
Sure.
Dickie, Elizabeth, dinner's ready!
All right tomorrow. Captain...
thanks for the support.
Well?
The Morris Commission
cleared me.
Capt. Cragen?
Not now.
Monique Jeffries.
Maybe I can help?
Fin Tutuola,
I've been re-assigned.
You're here for my job.
This is awkward.
Well, try my side
of the moment.