In the criminal
justice system...
sexually-based offenses
are considered
especially heinous.
In New York City,
the dedicated detectives...
who investigate
these vicious felonies...
are members of an elite squad
known as
the Special Victims Unit.
These are their stories.
911 emergency operator 307.
What is your emergency?
I'm in the Lincoln Tunnel.
I haven't moved in 45 minutes.
You reporting
an accident, sir?
It's almost midnight. What
the hell's up with the traffic?
911 emergency operator 307.
What is your emergency?
There's a rape. Right now.
88 West Franklin.
Now, get down!
Get away from me!
I said get...
Hello?
Two-seven-Charlie,
respond to a 10-34.
Assault in progress
at 88 West Franklin.
No suspect description. Line
disconnected. Respond Code 3.
What've you got? 911 didn't
get an apartment number.
Probably a cell phone call.
We're knocking on doors.
Perp may still be in there?
Yeah, if there is a perp.
Wouldn't be
the first prank call.
You guys from Special Victims? Yeah.
Found this under
the fire escape.
"Lori. "
Got her. 3-B.
Special Victims. Benson,
Stabler. How you doing?
I heard some crying. The door's
unlocked. She's in the shower.
I started to go in, but she started
freaking out on me, so I backed off.
Thanks.
Stay away!
Lori?
Gina?
It's Olivia.
It's filthy in here. That's
okay. I'm going to help you.
Lori?
Please don't come in here.
This place is filthy.
Lori?
Hey, how long you been
in the shower?
This drain...
I want this stuff out
of here. What stuff?
The stuff he washed off me.
I want it out of here.
Lori, the stuff is long gone.
You've already washed it all away.
It's okay.
Give me your hand.
There you go.
This is really happening,
isn't it?
Come on.
"Is this how you like it?
"Is this how you like it?"
That's all he kept saying to me.
The man who made you dirty?
Yeah.
There you go. Got her?
Stay with me.
Back in one second, okay?
He washed her. Asked her,
"Is this how you like it?"
His favorite neighborhood, his
type, blonde, petite, single.
Bastard's at it again.
Why am I not surprised?
It's him.
It has to be him.
Not so fast.
It's been a year since we had
Cleary in here as a suspect.
Same M.O. Probably came in
off the fire escape.
He rapes them, asks them if
they like it, he bathes them...
and then he steals a piece
of jewelry as a memento.
It's him. Kenneth Cleary.
We had him and we lost him.
We couldn't keep him.
Not our fault.
You want to tell
the victim that?
Hey.
We're going to go in here.
Lori, did you open the window? Yes.
The night, it was cool. I like
to sleep under heavy blankets.
He pulled my blanket off me.
My shirt was over my eyes.
A button got caught
in my mouth.
He hit me.
Then what happened?
He tried to kiss her.
He tried to kiss me.
He yanked that button
out of my mouth...
and kissed my neck.
His lips were dry.
My necklace, he ripped off.
He was inside me.
He pushed hard.
It hurt.
But he kept saying...
"Is this how you like it?"
He...
finished.
Then he brought me
into the bathroom.
He made me take a shower.
My shirt got wet, heavy.
Did you see his face?
My shirt was over my eyes.
He told me not to look.
None of his victims
could ID him.
Nothing from Forensics. There
never is with Kenneth Cleary.
When he heard the sirens,
he pushed me back and...
I hit my head on the tiles.
Heard the sirens?
Did you call the police?
No.
We got a witness.
You move slow.
We go after Cleary off this,
he'll be out the door again.
But not too slow.
Move slow as fast as you can.
There's a rape. Right now.
88 West Franklin.
Now, get down!
Get away from me!
I said get...
So maybe two witnesses.
Three, if you count the dog.
Where'd the call come from?
Pay phone on Franklin.
You call back?
Pay phone blocks
incoming calls.
Lori Thatcher's apartment
is on the third floor.
You can't see into her
apartment from here, though.
So who can?
Two apartments
could see to the rape.
Look at that.
Who is it?
Mrs. Walton, New York Police.
Detectives Benson and Stabler.
Can I see your badge, please?
What's wrong?
We're investigating an assault
in the building across the way.
Last night.
I heard the sirens.
No one's home next door.
No, they're on vacation.
How long have they been gone? A week.
They're very nice.
They give Hank...
his last walk of the night
for me when they're here.
I hate it when they're gone.
Your apartment looks into the
apartment where the assault took place.
I'm blind, Detective.
Yes, ma'am.
But was anybody here
with you last night? No.
Billy was here, but just long
enough to take Hank out for me.
And what time was that?
Oh, gosh, I don't know.
The news was on.
Which news?
The 24 hour news.
Okay. And Billy is?
Billy Smith. The young man
down in 1-G. He's a doctor.
Thank you very much.
You know, if he's not in his
apartment, you might try the roof.
I thought
I could hide up here.
Mrs. Walton gave you
up there, Dr. Smith.
I'm not a doctor yet.
Did you walk Mrs. Walton's
dog last night? Yeah, Hank.
What time?
11:00.
Could it have been
closer to 12:00?
Could have been 3:00 a. m.
for all I know.
I got sleep deprivation,
light deprivation, time.
If I don't pass this exam...
When you walked Hank, did he
bark or lunge at a woman...
using the pay phone that's
right down in front there?
He's a guide dog.
He's trained not to.
Why don't you try the news
stand at the end of the block?
Ginger, quiet!
Down.
Sorry about that.
He can't be good
for business.
No, but he's great for theft.
Yeah, I bet.
Last night...
did he attack a woman at the phone
booth at the end of the street?
He never touched her.
I had him on the leash. She's
got no business calling the cops.
Actually, sir, we're
investigating another matter.
Think you could describe her?
Blonde.
Age? Thirty, maybe.
Thin, but not too thin.
Could you describe her
to a police sketch artist?
I didn't get a look
at her face.
I was too busy trying to
get Ginger into the car.
You remember
what she was wearing?
Yeah. A black sweater,
and black slacks...
and thong panties.
You didn't get a look at her face but
you know she was wearing thong panties?
I saw the panty line.
She had a nice ass, which is more
interesting to me than her face.
I'm an ass man,
I don't apologize for it.
So we have the dog, but not the
witness. Maybe the dog can ID Cleary.
We don't know
that it's Cleary.
Like hell we don't.
We can't make him for it yet.
You have to stay open to the
possibility it's someone else.
Come on, Captain.
The M.O. matches.
The victims
are identical types.
Their injuries
are virtually identical.
At least he's not
getting rougher.
How is Miss Thatcher?
She coming out of shock, going
into numb. Staying at her parents.
911 call terminated
at 12:03:39 a. m.
And at 12:04 another call was
made from the same pay phone.
To?
A Gramercy Park brownstone owned
by Mr. and Mrs. Kenneth Cleary.
Let's go.
Hold on.
Cleary's raping Lori
at the same time...
somebody's downstairs
calling his house?
I'm on it.
Cleary sees you and Stabler again
you're done before you start.
Mrs. Cleary?
Yes.
Detectives Munch and Tutuola.
Did you receive a call
around midnight last night?
It's about time.
I've been after the phone
company for the past two months...
to do something
about these calls.
You've had other calls?
Some woman's harassing me.
What does this woman say?
"Your husband's a rapist. "
Last night, she said, "He's
raping someone right now. "
Last night there was a rape
in the building...
by the pay phone
that call was made from.
Was your husband home
last night?
My husband's not a rapist.
Was your husband home
last night?
Yes.
He didn't walk the dog?
We all walk the dog.
Your phone rings, someone tells
you your husband's raping someone.
Then what?
I went back to sleep.
You didn't call the phone
company? I went back to sleep.
You didn't tell your husband?
We don't both have to be awake
for a harassing phone call.
But he was here?
Yes.
I called the phone company
this morning.
Did they offer to put a
trap on your line? Yes.
But my husband
doesn't want that.
They could listen
to our personal conversations.
And he's involved with
private financial matters.
This woman is ruining our
lives. Why don't you stop her?
Check Cleary's phone records?
What we're doing.
Mrs. Cleary alibi
her husband?
Yeah, but she was
choking on it.
Okay, Mrs. Cleary notified the phone
company after each harassing call.
They all track to pay phones.
She said she ignored the first
call thinking it was a prank, right?
That's what she said.
Just went back a month.
Found a number
in our case file.
That first call came from
one of Cleary's victims...
Harper Anderson.
Looks like she's stalking
him. Sorry, Olivia.
You should be
at his place, not mine.
Harper, you can't
stalk Cleary.
Stalking is illegal.
I survey from
a legal distance.
Playing with semantics here
can be very dangerous.
I saw him go into the alley.
By the time I got to it,
he was gone.
And I saw the fire escape.
Did you see him
on the fire escape?
No.
But it's how he got
into my place to rape me.
But you didn't see him go up it.
You didn't see him rape anyone.
No.
And yet you called 911.
First I circled the building
to make sure...
that there was no way
I could've missed him.
Then I thought about the probability
that he was raping someone.
Then I called 911.
Why didn't you stick around?
Because he ran out the service
entry right after the sirens.
I considered waiting for you
guys, but I've been down that road.
So I shadowed him.
Shadowed him?
Not to be confused
with stalked.
And this is art not to be confused
with obsession or a target?
It goes with the room.
Have some wine.
We're working.
6:00 p. m. Work day's done.
You can have a glass of wine.
No, thank you.
He's a workaholic.
He won't leave the office
till 8:00.
We can chat
for another hour and a half.
You couldn't identify him
in a lineup.
How do you know
he's the man that raped you?
I was at his sentencing for
possession of stolen property.
When he left the court...
he winked at me.
Winked.
So who did he rape
this time?
He raped someone. Otherwise
you wouldn't be here.
Maybe a Scotch. Vodka?
No, thank you.
You don't have
to be so tense.
I don't expect anything
from you.
We did everything
that we could.
You couldn't ID him,
so we couldn't hold him.
You could have followed him.
You knew he would rape again.
I'd like to follow every guy that I
know that has a propensity to rape.
Poor police. So overworked!
Harper, you're not equipped
to deal with this.
I'm equipped.
I don't approach him.
I'm doing what any private
investigator would do...
and I don't need a license
to do it for myself.
You're harassing his wife.
Give me a break!
She's enabling a rapist.
And you're too busy
to deal with him, so I will.
Harper Anderson is dangerous. I'm
not certain that she's dangerous.
She's stalking Cleary.
He raped her. She's following
him to catch him at it.
We almost got him on the Lori
Thatcher rape because of her.
You buy into her distinguishing
between stalking and following?
The system failed her...
so she's operating it herself
as best she can.
I mean, Cleary doesn't know
that she's there.
She doesn't approach him,
she doesn't threaten him.
Mrs. Cleary feels threatened.
Sooner or later she has to face the
fact that her husband's a rapist.
Why? She doesn't have to
face it unless we prove it.
And we don't want her pushed
there by Harper Anderson.
Street justice
is always bloody.
Munch, Fin, bring Harper in
here for a blunt talking-to.
Captain... No, you're too close to her.
You and Elliott
get in the Clearys' faces.
Let them know we're onto them.
It may not go to making a case...
but I want to diffuse this
tinderbox before it blows.
Elliott, look!
Those are mine!
You stop it right now!
Get out!
You can't do this!
My son will see these! He'll
know where he comes from.
You bitch! You're
sleeping with a rapist.
Mrs. Cleary...
Get out of my neighborhood!
You're enabling a rapist.
Harper, stop it!
Mrs. Cleary, listen to me.
Calm down.
Take a breath, okay?
What's going on?
She's putting these
everywhere. Look.
Detective Stabler.
Yeah.
Two nights ago, a woman was
raped. I was home with my wife.
You're lying. I saw you.
Every time a woman is raped
you're going to come to me?
Not every time, no.
How long do I have
to bear the brunt...
of this woman forgetting
to take her lithium?
She's obviously damaged.
Hey! Drop it.
Don't make me cuff you.
Perfect! Arrest me!
Not the rapist.
We have anything else on
Lori Thatcher's rape?
She could do a voice ID.
But Cleary ain't coming down
here to see us on his own.
We need probable cause.
Harper can place Cleary exiting
Lori Thatcher's building.
Her building,
not her apartment.
After that stunt Harper pulled with
Cleary's car, she's zero as a witness.
And there's still the problem
of Harper stalking Cleary.
Harper's taking control
of her own life.
Please.
As long as Cleary's out there,
so's his next victim.
He'll stay out there
until we can make a case.
We need to pick up
where Harper left off.
I'm all for that.
I can't authorize overtime
to follow Cleary.
Anyone asking for it?
Are you with us? He's likely
to call in lawyers.
If you don't interfere with
his conducting his life...
I'll field any motion he files. Bingo.
So you take care of
that part of it. Okay.
Don't forget.
What are you doing here?
We're going to go
see your boss.
Got a problem with that?
No.
Around the corner
on the left.
We're investigating
a serial rapist.
What can you tell us
about Kenneth Cleary?
What's he have to do
with that?
Is he a good employee?
Is he involved in a rape?
What's he like to work with?
He's a workaholic.
One of our top earners.
So he works late?
He's here when I arrive
and he is here when I leave.
We lost two assistants who couldn't
keep up with him in Philadelphia.
We're opening a branch there.
He go there a lot?
Spends half his time there.
You think he raped someone?
He has
a misdemeanor conviction...
for possession
of stolen property.
He spend the night in Philly?
Yes. We have
a corporate apartment.
Could we see
his travel records?
Had to tell the boss I was convicted
on possession of stolen property?
Public record, pal. You're
trying to get me canned?
I brought the company in
$58 million last quarter.
He'll live with
a misdemeanor conviction.
And a rapist?
Let me ask you something,
one hungry man to another.
Is there anything better than
gorging on a fresh caught meal?
You won't be
eating out anymore.
Going back six months.
Three rapes in Philadelphia
have Cleary's signature.
June 13.
He was there.
The 10th to the 20th.
August 26?
There, the 23rd to the 28th.
September 15.
There.
They got him booked on Amtrak
to go there tomorrow.
Who booked to go where?
Cleary to Philadelphia.
Then you're going too, John.
What a coincidence. Why?
You found rapes that
match Cleary's M.O.? Three.
You're interviewing
the victims face to face.
Something wrong
with the facts?
Philadelphia's SVU is under review
for dumping rapes as unfounded.
So, yes, there's absolutely
something wrong with the facts.
I don't trust them.
There he is.
Hey, Ken Cleary.
A little jumpy this morning?
Love to talk, Det. Munch,
but I've got a train to catch.
Yeah, Philadelphia club car.
We're going coach.
But if you feel the need to talk
to me, I'm willing to upgrade.
What's the agenda here,
gentlemen?
You trying to make me crazy?
Hell, no.
Way too late for that.
And you are? The knot in
the pit of your stomach.
Hate to disappoint you. But I don't
mind the company or the attention.
So there's no need to ask.
Is this how you like it?
What have we got? A list
and description of jewelry...
stolen during rapes,
matching the Cleary M.O.
Three here,
three in Philadelphia.
Munch just faxed these
from the Philly P.D.
For what purpose?
Show Mrs. Cleary. See if
she has any of these pieces.
If she's an accessory,
she'll deny it.
What are the odds that
she's an accessory to rape?
I agree, they're remote. The
odds are that she's in denial.
Who wouldn't be?
But it's still risky.
What about the issue
of spousal privilege?
I'm not going to ask her anything
about her husband's rapes.
I'm going to show her
that list.
If she's unwittingly in
possession of stolen property...
it might turn up the heat at
home. We've pressed him at work.
We've run out of plays
to make here.
So, what, a Hail Mary?
Okay.
She's going to be defensive.
I'm sensitive to that.
And you are?
Taking some
quasi-personal time.
I called Harper last night because I
felt like I dropped the ball with her...
so I'm going to meet her
for coffee.
Where? Westside Range.
I'll see you later.
You're meeting her at firing
range? I know. She's permitted.
Detectives Munch and Tutuola
are from New York City.
They may have a lead
on the man who raped you.
I know it's difficult but if
you can tell your story again.
I woke up choking on a pillow.
He told me to keep
my eyes closed...
and then he took the pillow
out of the case...
and held the pillow case
over my eyes.
He held my T-shirt
He pulled my nightshirt over
my face so I couldn't see him.
He asked,
"Is this how you like it?"
After he raped me,
he made me shower.
My hot water was broken.
He washed me.
He had me in a cold shower...
washing his semen off me.
I asked him if his mother knew
what he was doing.
He said his mother
just wanted him to be happy.
Mrs. Cleary, Detective Stabler.
I don't want to talk to you.
Mrs. Cleary...
rape victims aren't just
the women who are attacked.
Rape victims include
their families...
and the rapist's families.
I am not a victim.
And I don't want you
standing on my stoop...
shouting "rape"
through my door.
Yes, ma'am.
You're harassing me. Destroying
my family. When does this stop?
Right now.
This is a list of jewelry and
the dates they were taken...
during rapes
we suspect your husband in.
My husband makes money. He doesn't
need to steal to give me jewelry.
I'm talking about
a sickness here, Mrs. Cleary.
Serial rapists
very often take items...
so that they can look at them
and remember.
Your trophies,
like your jewelry...
allow your husband
to relive the rapes...
so that he can
become excited.
I am sorry to put you
through this.
I know this is
a terrible ordeal for you...
but it is worse
for the victims.
And quite frankly, I don't
know where else to turn.
I won't bother you again.
Nice grouping.
What are you using?
.50 caliber, double action
Desert Eagle. 14-shot clip.
Took me a month to learn
how to hold it level.
This sucker's nearly 40 ounces
with a full load.
Harper, a 14-round clip
is illegal in New York.
Here.
Didn't know that.
Eight is plenty.
That gun's pretty extreme.
Why?
A.50 caliber semi-auto
with a 14-round clip?
It's practically
an assault rifle.
I just gave you the clip.
You're something else.
What? You think I'm Velma Vigilante...
stalking Cleary, waiting for
the perfect moment to shoot him?
That's not who I am.
You're not the same person
I knew six months ago.
I was a rape victim
when you met me.
I finally have control
over my life back.
I'm not interested in revenge.
I'm not even interested
in justice anymore.
Then why follow Cleary?
Because I'm afraid of him, and
he's the last thing I'm afraid of.
If I can get over that I will
have my life back completely.
You want to go for a drink?
There's a little Spanish place
around the corner.
Tapas and Sangria?
I would have bet the new old
Harper to be a Whiskey Park girl.
I haven't cruised a chichi
date bar since I was raped.
I was just writing you a note. Really?
I'm sorry for what
happened to you.
You didn't do it, Mrs. Cleary.
But you said
I was enabling a rapist.
I shouldn't have.
He's my husband.
I feel responsible for...
I feel guilty.
I want you to know that.
What made you
change your mind?
My husband has always
surprised me with his...
no-special-occasion gifts.
A silver ring
next to my coffee cup.
That opal ring on my pillow.
He'd get so excited
when I tried them on.
I thought it was romantic.
Six of the pieces match.
The rest?
He gave them to me the
same way. don't want them.
Did your husband ever discuss with
you how he came by the jewelry?
Don't answer that.
Spousal privilege.
Excuse me for a moment.
Do you want some privacy?
No.
I'll just take a second.
I can't take it. Come home.
No, you have to come home now.
He'll be on the next train
from Philadelphia.
I can't tolerate
any more of this.
You follow me to work, you
follow me to Philadelphia. Fine.
But you make my wife hysterical
and that, my friends, will cost you.
I'm gonna call my lawyer
and the Police Commissioner.
You might want to stick with
just your lawyer for now.
Kenneth Cleary,
you're under arrest.
You have the right
to remain silent.
Anything you say can and will be
used against you in a court of law.
You have the right
to an attorney.
If you cannot afford an
attorney one will be appointed...
Are you ready?
Yes.
Can I close my eyes?
Would you have them each say, "Is
this how you like it?", please.
Is this how you like it?
It's him.
Very entertaining.
How many more shows
are there today?
Is this how you like it?
Bastard.
That's him.
That's him. It's Number 4.
We have one more.
I don't have to be here. I'm
sure your report will be accurate.
See you in court.
"File number 492276.
"People verses Kenneth Cleary.
"One count rape
in the first degree...
"one count sexual abuse
"one count robbery
in the second degree...
"and three counts
criminal possession
"of stolen property
in the fifth. "
Quite a list.
How do you plead?
Not guilty.
Exactly how much we planning
to charge the defendant...
to get out of jail, Ms. Cabot?
Remand without bail,
Your Honor.
Put away your claws,
Counselor.
My client is not
a flight risk.
He's a pillar
of the community.
If you define pillar
as a seven-figure salary.
And if he can afford you,
he can afford to fly.
Mr. Cleary is willing to
surrender his passport, Your Honor.
Your Honor,
he is a menace to women.
His crimes are not confined
to the State of New York.
The People have had my client under
surveillance even across state lines.
Their continued harassment
should assuage their fears.
Is that true, Ms. Cabot?
No.
SVU detectives went to Philadelphia
to interview Mr. Cleary's victims.
Objection.
Be quiet.
I still need a number.
$500,000.
Let's double that.
No objection.
Is that the best
you could do?
You shouldn't be here, Mrs.
Cleary. You're my witness.
I thought maybe there
was a chance I was wrong.
I saw how he looked at you, and I knew.
We should get together soon so
I can prep you before the trial.
I'm staying with my family
in Long Island.
Is there anything
I can do for you now?
You know
a good divorce lawyer?
I don't know
if she can do this.
A moment, Ms. Cabot.
I'm Harper Anderson,
Mr. Klein.
Your client raped me.
I know how famous you are.
Yes?
You're going to
burn in hell.
I'm Jewish, Miss Anderson.
There is no hell.
Excuse us.
Save me the bedtime reading.
How many motions are you filing?
Omnibus. In limine, to
suppress, and spousal privilege.
See you in judge's chambers.
Yeah.
Spousal privilege
is inviolate.
Discovery was made
through the wife.
Give me a good reason
not to throw out the jewelry.
It doesn't fall
under privilege.
Nobody asked Cleary's wife
where he got the jewelry.
Would anyone care for lemon?
Communication between a husband
and wife is not limited to speech.
The police went
to the Cleary home...
with the express purpose
of discovery.
They should have handed
the list to Mr. Cleary.
He would have
turned over the items.
He gets his gifts from various
sources, which he would have revealed.
But in an effort
to disrupt his family...
the police went to his wife to induce
her to violate spousal privilege.
The court can't support that.
The jewelry has to be excluded.
The police did not ask
Mrs. Cleary any questions...
regarding
her husband's activities.
They presented her
with the list of stolen items.
She discovered she had several
pieces of jewelry on that list.
And she turned them in.
Please, Ms. Cabot.
Don't you consider him giving
her jewelry an activity?
Limit the scope to receipt
of the jewelry and by whom.
But Your Honor, it's...
Next item.
Voice ID.
This is a stretch under
the best of circumstances.
But a terrified victim...
hearing the breathless voice
of an aroused perpetrator...
during the commission
of a violent act?
I don't think so.
You'll have your chance to undermine
the identification during cross.
More tea?
That's how I knew it was him.
Thank you.
You identified the man who
raped you, is that correct?
Yes. Kenneth Cleary.
But you didn't actually
see him, did you? No.
You identified him by
voice, is that correct? Yes.
I'd know
that voice anywhere.
Is this how you like it?
Do you recognize this voice,
Ms. Thatcher?
No.
I can play it again.
Objection. Asked and answered.
Hearing this surprised
the witness, Your Honor.
Maybe she'd like to hear it
again to make sure.
Go ahead.
Is this how you like it?
Do you recognize the voice?
Does it sound vaguely
familiar? Objection.
He's badgering.
Sustained.
Yes, Your Honor.
The man on the tape
is a co-worker.
You talk to him every day.
Robert.
You don't recognize his voice,
how can you recognize...
Objection!
Sustained.
Back off, Mr. Shoenfeld.
How did you come into possession
of this garnet necklace?
It was a gift from my husband.
He gave it to me...
Wait for the next question.
Your answers need to be
very narrow and very specific.
Why are you only asking about how I
came into possession of the jewelry?
I can't ask about
anything else.
Why not?
Communication between husband
and wife is inadmissible.
It's as privileged
as priest and supplicant.
You aren't going to ask me about
how excited he got when I wore them?
How he insisted I wear them
before we had sex?
I can't.
I wish I could but I'm not
allowed to ask about that.
Do you understand?
The jewelry is important,
Mrs. Cleary.
Because we need to connect
the timeline to the rapes...
so that your husband
won't be able to duck...
by claiming that
he purchased swag...
from some guy
on Canal Street.
He wants joint custody of our
son. And he's not going to get it.
If he gets off...
One thing at a time, okay?
Okay.
How did you come into possession
of this garnet necklace?
My husband gave it to me.
Was it a special occasion?
No.
Do you remember
when he gave it to you?
Kenneth gave it to me
on his return...
from a business trip
to Philadelphia.
September 6.
Objection.
The witness couldn't possibly remember
the dates of every gift she received.
Mrs. Cleary, how is it
that you recall this date?
It was our son's
first day of kindergarten.
Kenneth made sure
he was home for that.
He left the necklace
on my pillow the night before.
Overruled.
Did you know this necklace
belongs to a woman who was raped...
on September 5
in Philadelphia?
Objection. Relevance.
Sustained.
You're on thin ice Ms. Cabot.
Stick to the scope.
Mrs. Cleary,
do you recognize this ring?
I do.
And do you remember how you
came into possession of it?
My husband gave it to me.
Do you remember when?
Yes.
I remember because we were
dressing for a charity event.
He asked me to try it on...
and then he got so excited,
he had to have sex with me.
Objection.
He'd get so excited...
Mrs. Cleary, stop.
...if I wouldn't have sex
with him he'd masturbate.
Objection.
Mrs. Cleary...
You had me wear
your trophies...
so that you could get off?
You sick, twisted bastard!
I move for
an immediate mistrial.
The witness
is clearly hysterical...
and has done irreparable
harm to the jury. Granted.
Ladies and gentlemen
of the jury...
you are excused.
I'm sorry.
Approach.
I'm so sorry.
I hold you responsible,
Ms. Cabot.
You knew the limits
set before you.
You prepped your witness.
You knew she was in a
severe and emotional state...
and you now have
the pleasure of starting over.
In the interim...
I sincerely hope you acquire
some professionalism.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
You're not having any?
AA.
How are you holding up?
I felt like I was 10 years
old today getting yelled at...
for playing
in my mother's make-up.
We can't do this again.
Why?
We've got no case.
The dream team blew holes
in the victim's IDs.
And Mrs. Cleary... I think
she sabotaged us on purpose.
What would she hope to gain
by doing that?
I don't know.
Kenneth Cleary walks, and
the People get a black eye.
So it's all about you?
I don't need this, Cragen.
No?
While you're whining
about your case
seems you forgot
about Harper Anderson...
Lori Thatcher,
the women in Philly.
Don't forget Mrs. Cleary.
The biggest victim of all.
You think she suffered more
than her husband's victims?
She has to deal with him the
rest of her life. She has his son.
What?
We're on our way.
I just came by to get
a few things for my son.
He hit me. Kept hitting me.
She didn't have a choice.
He wouldn't stop.
Who tried to clean up?
I did.
Meredith was hysterical. She didn't
want the blood to seep into the floor.
Does it make a difference?
You know it does, Harper.
Bleach ruins
the gunshot residue test.
Really?
Who shot him?
I did.